<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quotes on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/quotes/</link><description>Recent content in quotes on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 19:45:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programmer Quotes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/19/programmer-quotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 19:45:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/19/programmer-quotes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>On StackOverflow, there is a question asking for the &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/58640?sort=votes#sort-top">greatest programmer quotes&lt;/a> you know. In the top 3 quotes are the following two quotes which I think hold much truth:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>_**"Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live."**_ - Rick Osborne&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>**_"Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it."_** - Brian Kernighan&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These two quotes are briliantly summing up the usual rant I always use. &amp;quot;if my phone rings at 3 a.m. for a prio 1 production issue, I want to be able to easily read the code. And I'm not going to be awake or cheerful at that time of night.&amp;quot; I guess at that time of night, it's easy to awaken the violent psychopath in me, and so it better not be &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; code. &lt;a href="http://stuvel.eu/archive/42/blame-support-in-eclipse">CVS blame support&lt;/a> anybody?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A-Team Quotes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/03/05/a-team-quotes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 21:21:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/03/05/a-team-quotes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As I'm recording A-Team episodes, stripping the commercials and transferring them to my PSP for later viewing on the plane, I came across some funy quotes:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
Hannibal:
&lt;td valign="top" >Now. We can do this the hard way or the easy way. In about a minute, I and my three friends are gonna unleash on you your worst nightmare. You’re gonna wish the earth opened up underneath your feet and swallowed you whole.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Bad Guy:
&lt;td valign="top" >What's the easy way?
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Hannibal:
&lt;td valign="top" >That was the easy way.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
Just after the tires of the Van are shot by a local gang, the Scorpions:
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
Scorpion:
&lt;td valign="top" >Car trouble?
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Hannibal:
&lt;td valign="top" >No thanks. We got some.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
Bad Guy:
&lt;td valign="top" >You’re all dead men.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Face:
&lt;td valign="top" >Really? Gee, I didn’t think I would feel this good after I was dead. I want to thank you all for coming to the funeral.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
Almost Monty Python like quotes, and that for an American Television Series! Nice. You like it or you hate it.
&lt;p>Pssst. If you haven't got the themesong yet, The A-Team soundtrack torrent is &lt;a href="http://torrents.thepiratebay.org/hashtorrent/3496737.torrent/The_A-team_Official_Soundtrack.3496737.TPB.torrent">here&lt;/a>...&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>