<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>smb on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/smb/</link><description>Recent content in smb on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 01:00:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/smb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choose: AFP or SMB</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/11/choose-afp-or-smb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 01:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/11/choose-afp-or-smb/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afp-or-smb.png">&lt;img src="afp-or-smb.png" alt="Choose AFP or SMB, not both.">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently upgraded the operating system on my trusty &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2006/09/20/tryout-mac-mini-as-fileserver/">Mac Mini G4 home fileserver&lt;/a> from Tiger to Leopard. In addition to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Machine_%28Apple_software%29">out-of-the-box backup&lt;/a>, I no longer have to use &lt;a href="http://www.hornware.com/sharepoints/">SharePoints&lt;/a> to manage my network shares. In Leopard, I can just right-click them and arrange the sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In doing so, I decided to switch on both SMB and AFP sharing for all shares. The idea was that my Macs all would use AFP automatically, and all Windows machines would see the SMB mounts. After a few hours, iTunes began acting up on me, because it decided to switch between the SMB and AFP protocol (or so it seemed). Finder also seems to have some trouble listing network shares if the exact same name on the same server is shared with two different protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because there are people on my network with Windows machines, I decided to switch off the AFP protocol and only go with SMB. I haven't had problems since.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're sharing drives like I'm doing, go for SMB. It may not be the technically superior solution, but it will &amp;quot;just work&amp;quot;. You can easily switch to AFP when the world is freed of Windows machines. ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OSX 10.5.2 Solved SMB problems (for me)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/1052-solved-smb-problems-for-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 20:47:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/1052-solved-smb-problems-for-me/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/11/16/osx-1051-update-still-smb-problems/">previous post&lt;/a> on this blog, I indicated that the 10.5.1. update of Apple's OSX did not fix my network and SMB problems with my Iomega drive. In the comments underneath, some readers kindly pointed out that &lt;a href="http://download.iomega.com/english/storcenter_home_firmware-k104w11.bin">Iomega's K104w11 Firmware update&lt;/a> is available for the Iomega drive I have. Now that 10.5.2 is out, I reconnected the Iomega drive to my network. And suddenly the world changed...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I didn't upgrade the drive, because I thought that was rediculous. It works with Windows, it works with Tiger, why shouldn't it work with Leopard? Right now I'm glad that I didn't go through the trouble of upgrading my drive:
&lt;p>With the OSX release 10.5.2, my Iomega drive is accesable, and I can drag files on and off as I like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have created a &amp;quot;sparse bundle&amp;quot; disk image on the drive, so that I can copy files onto it which are bigger than 4GB, and have (very very) long names. So it's finally there: A network mounted 500GB HPS+ partition to which I can backup my backups using an rsync script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that everything works, I might even be tempted to do that Iomega software upgrade, but then again: &amp;quot;if it ain't broke, don't try to fix it&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next thing on my list to find out: What if I upgraded my Tiger fileserver to Leopard, and had TimeMachine running there. Could I rsync the TimeMachine disk to an off-site location without sending the double-hardlinked files twice?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>