<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 19:29:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove formatting from clipboard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/05/remove-formatting-from-clipboard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 19:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/05/remove-formatting-from-clipboard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In Windows, there is a great tool called &lt;a href="http://www.stevemiller.net/puretext/">&amp;quot;PureText&amp;quot;&lt;/a> which sits in your tray, and can remove formatting from copy/paste actions if you want to. In stead of pasting into notepad, and then copying it again, you now can use the Windows-V combination to paste without formatting. It works in any program, and I'm a fond user of this little gem at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In OSX, you can do this with a key combination, Option-Shift-Command-V. Besides being the silliest and most awkward key combination ever to do a simple paste-action, it does not always do the job properly. I found this &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/simx/technonova/C488455530/E20071125225334/index.html">great tip&lt;/a> where a simple applescript removes formatting from the items in your clipboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->If you don't know how to save this script, do the following:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Open the Apple Script Editor (use Spotlight if you don't know where to look for it)
2. In the editor window, paste the following text:set the clipboard to «class ktxt» of ((the clipboard as text) as record)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>beep
3. Click &amp;quot;Compile&amp;quot; and then select &amp;quot;Archive -&amp;gt; Save As...&amp;quot;
4. Save the script as an application (anywhere you think is appropriate)
5. Drag the resulting app into your dock to have it handy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks like a lot of work, but these are the absoluut smallest steps I can help you with. It's really simple. When you're done, select any text you want to copy, and press Command-C to copy it. Then, before pasting, start the app you just made. You'll here the system beep indicating that it's ready. Now you can use Command-V and presto, plain text, no formatting!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use this a lot to copy text from mails and documents into my Evernote, and it works fine. The only small irritation is the extra mouseclick.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>