<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iphone on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/iphone/</link><description>Recent content in iphone on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 21:03:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iOS7 hidden features</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2013/09/28/ios7-hidden-features/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 21:03:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2013/09/28/ios7-hidden-features/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QS4xIrTYDWU">&lt;img src="ios-7-logo.png" alt="ios-7-logo">
&lt;/a>If you've just installed iOS7 and like it as much as I do, you are probably interested in all the new features of it, and where to find them. On behalf of Apple, I'll be happy to point out where all those neat new features are, and share my happiness about this wonderful new magical market-leading mobile OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**Easy-Steal (tm)**
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="easy-steal-e284a2.png">&lt;img src="easy-steal-e284a2.png?w=113" alt="Easy-Steal (™)">
&lt;/a>**Remember how in iOS6, you can not just steal an iphone because of the &amp;quot;find my iPhone&amp;quot; feature? Thieves had to put your iPhone in a metal container so it could not tell the owner where it is. Because thieves are people too, we now introduced &amp;quot;Easy-Steal (tm)&amp;quot;. When a thief wants to steal your phone, all he has to do is swipe up, press the little airplane button, and nobody will hear from your iPhone again. Want to disable that? Easy. Hand over your flashlight, calculator, timer, and iPod controls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Separate is the new Integrate&lt;/strong>
Remember how we beautifully integrated FaceTime with the Phone app? How Podcasts could be played from within iTunes? Well we think that's not the future. So we created a separate FaceTime app, and a separate Podcasts app. So you can have more icons on more screens, making it harder to find stuff. We'll let you in on a little secret. Our next big thing? A Separate device for each function. It will be great! You can just take the device you need and leave all the other ones charging on your desk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New sounds. And Old Classic ones.&lt;/strong>
Remember how software developers always say you should not use terms as &amp;quot;Old&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;New&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; in your software because putting a &amp;quot;New&amp;quot; sticker on a banana will not prevent it from going stale? Well we're not so sure about that. So now, in the old (sorry, new) sound settings, you will find all the same behavior of the old settings, but with new sounds. We've even changed all the sounds your phone makes right from the upgrade. If you would like to revert to the old sounds, don't bother searching in the sounds list. Scroll through the &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; list. You know, because on the first screen, there is a list of sounds, and in the second list, there will be... err... a list of sounds. But old. Get it? Did we say it was completely new? We lied. Sorry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Camouflage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="icon-rainbow.png">&lt;img src="icon-rainbow.png" alt="icon rainbow">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All icons are now devoid of those pesky shading and lining that made them visible on all backgrounds. So now, no matter what background color you use, there will always be at least one icon which will blend into the background. We even removed the shading on the text, so you can make that disappear with a simple white background. And did you notice the gradients? Some are light-to-dark, and some are dark-to-light. Why? Because at the new Apple, we hate consistency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Square.&lt;/strong>
A new picture mode. Because you want to make photos. videos, and... err... squares?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Look-at-Me (tm)&lt;/strong>
To make the phone look faster, we made the icons zoom and pan to show how the operating systems moves to help you complete your tasks. It was tested on 500 Dwarf Hamsters and we are pretty sure we made a good job of making people look at your screen while you're using your phone. At least half of those people will get &lt;a href="http://www.tech-recipes.com/rx/44165/how-do-i-prevent-motion-sickness-when-using-ios-7/">motion sickness within 15 seconds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Applications&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="new-apps.png">&lt;img src="new-apps.png" alt="New Apps">
&lt;/a>
The seasoned iOS6 user will have immediately spotted it: We've got new Applications! Get more accurate timing in your iPhone with the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tourbillon">Tourbillon&lt;/a> app. Make your own weather predictions with the Barometer app, and create stunning graphics with the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandelbrot_set">Mandelbrot&lt;/a> app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Puzzles&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_&lt;a href="clickable-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="clickable-puzzle.png?w=450" alt="Clickable Puzzle">
&lt;/a>_&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can now have hours of fun trying to figure out what is tappable or slidable. Is it the text? Is it the color? Is it the icons? Who knows? We've put great care in removing all visual clues, so start taping and sliding!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update process has also become more fun. Because we love our non-US iPhone users, we've made the &amp;quot;Purchased&amp;quot; icon a letter &amp;quot;P&amp;quot;. Level up! The dark arrow pointing down ads to the fun when you tap it and... it slides to the left, which reveals your purchases to the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="updates-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="updates-puzzle.png" alt="Updates Puzzle">
&lt;/a>And did we say one update? We'll list all the past updates too, so you can have more useless info on the screen. For good measure, we even added fun blue dots next to the updated apps you did not open already. How useful is that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="installing.png">&lt;img src="installing.png" alt="Installing..">
&lt;/a>Progress indicators are now even more fun. During updates, your app is named &amp;quot;Installing...&amp;quot; Can you guess what this icon is? If you guessed the application was updating, can you tell if it is at 25% or 75%?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the real advanced puzzlers, we've hidden some controls. Can you make the &amp;quot;Today&amp;quot; widget just display your calendar item without-arbitrary-text-around-it-which-makes-your-content-harder-to-view-at-a-glance? Can you slide your &amp;quot;Stock Options&amp;quot; widget below the &amp;quot;Tomorrow&amp;quot; widget?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="message-center-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="message-center-puzzle.png?w=169" alt="Message Center Puzzle">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A new lock screen&lt;/strong>
People like lock screens. So they can put functions on them for which you don't have to unlock. Smart, right? Now, people can start playing with your phone without unlocking it, weather you like it or not. Because there is no option to disable that. To make everything easier, we've put more icons on the lock screen, making gestures more finicky. Because we know what &lt;del>Android&lt;/del> iPhone users like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="lockscreens.png">&lt;img src="lockscreens.png?w=450" alt="LockScreens">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And 6789 more features&lt;/strong>
There is much more to discover. The camera app is on 2 locations in the home screen. The message center is as confusing and inconsistent as ever. The new &amp;quot;dots&amp;quot; signal strength indicator, the network operator name, the wifi icon and the new &amp;quot;gprs&amp;quot; icon are now even wider, so they'll never fit the top bar. Sliders switches look bulkier, slide less, but they do change colors as if they were a bulb. You decide what it's supposed to be, let your imagination run wild! A white dot? Is it a slider or just a dot? Who needs aluminum, Try it out!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you'll excuse us, we're going to sue Sony because they made their Xperia look like our market-leading mobile OS. See?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ios7-because-when-you-paid-for-an-iphone-we-know-you-actually-wanted-android">&lt;strong>iOS7. Because when you paid for an iPhone, we know you actually wanted Android.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>P.S.&lt;/strong> Jony, I'm not sure how much you're involved in the UI design, but if you need help, or a better sparring partner, or I need to come rescue you from the bozos that made you do this, the iPhone 5Cheap with it's non-right-angle old-school injection molded back and the gold iPhone, let me know. You're better than this, and maybe we can still fix things. You know how to contact me. Hang in there buddy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toyota (Corolla Verso) iPhone Bluetooth connection</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/08/04/toyota-corolla-verso-iphone-bluetooth-connection/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/08/04/toyota-corolla-verso-iphone-bluetooth-connection/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2QawYoignHI">&lt;img src="toyota-iphone-bluetooth.png" alt="Connect your iPhone to your Toyota's Bluetooth system">
&lt;/a>My sisters in law bought a beautiful 2006 Toyota Corolla Verso. They could not get the iPhone to pair with the car's Bluetooth system. The dealer told them that this was an iPhone problem, but after some fiddling, it turns out there is a simple workaround. If you want to pair an iPhone to your car, and the car says &amp;quot;pairing failed&amp;quot; as soon as you tap on your iPhone, this simple trick might help for you. This article contains detailed steps for the Toyota Corolla Verso, but on other cars this might work too.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * &amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;Start the car (don't start driving), and take out your iPhone.
* On the iPhone, tap **&amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot;**, **&amp;quot;General&amp;quot;** and **&amp;quot;Bluetooth&amp;quot;**. Make sure Bluetooth is switched on. Leave the iPhone on this screen.
* Press and hold **&amp;quot;mode&amp;quot;** on the steering wheel of the car.
* When the car says &amp;quot;Setup Menu&amp;quot;, say **&amp;quot;Pair Phone&amp;quot;**
* On the iPhone, tap the **&amp;quot;TOYOTA&amp;quot;** network.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The car will almost immediately say &amp;quot;Pairing failed&amp;quot;. On your phone, the password prompt will show. Do not do anything, let the phone stay on this screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="interior-2008-toyota-corolla-verso-bourgas-pic-2-334.jpg">&lt;img src="interior-2008-toyota-corolla-verso-bourgas-pic-2-334.jpg" alt="Toyota Corolla Verso Dashboard">
&lt;/a>This is because the iPhone probably tries to connect with a default password like &amp;quot;0000&amp;quot;, the car immediately aborts, and doesn't allow a second try. The phone detects the connection failure and will popup a &amp;quot;password&amp;quot; screen for you to enter a number that does work, but the car has already given up. Not to worry, read on:&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Press and hold **&amp;quot;mode&amp;quot;** on the steering wheel again.
* When the system says &amp;quot;Setup Menu&amp;quot;, say **&amp;quot;Pair Phone&amp;quot;**
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The car enters pairing mode for the second time. Because the phone is still in the &amp;quot;Password prompt&amp;quot; screen, it is already past the detection phase,  and will not try to send the default password. Now you can enter your password and the connection will succeed on the &amp;quot;first&amp;quot; try as seen from your car.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * With the iPhone still in the password screen, enter **&amp;quot;1234&amp;quot;** (or whatever password the car tells you) press **&amp;quot;Connect&amp;quot;**.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Congratulations, your phone is now paired.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Month view Redesign</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/10/14/month-view-redesign/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 21:35:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/10/14/month-view-redesign/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="weekcal-design-icon.png" alt="A day in my week">
True to their tradition on the Mac, the Calendar and Addressbook applications on the iPhone are, let's say &amp;quot;lacking finesse&amp;quot;. As good as Apple can design products and user interfaces, their focus is clearly not on calendars and address books. I've read somewhere that &amp;quot;iCal is proof that Steve does not maintain his own calendar&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After trying out various replacements on the iPhone, I finally stuck with a pretty darn good calendar for the iPhone called &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/week-calendar/id381059732?mt=8">&amp;quot;Week Calendar&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. The main reason for switching to that app is that it actually has a week view, but when I started using it more intensely I found myself using the month view the most. Until somebody at Apple stopped the show.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->First of all, let me explain why I like Week Calendar's original month view by comparing it to the original iCal (these are actual screenshots from my actual phone):
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ical-vs-weekcal.png" alt="iCal vs WeekCal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the left, we see Apple's iCal. Apple places a dot on a day where I have appointments. This not very useful for people who have appointments on each day, as you can see. On the right, Week Calendar's colored dots tells me how many appointments I have, and in which Calendar they are (my green calendar is work, my red calendar is private).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other big improvements in Week Calendar's month view are more room for the events of the selected day, the week numbers on the left, the end times of appointments, and the little icons indicating recurring appointments and alarm settings. All huge usability improvements, clearly outperforming Apple's iCal. But suddenly the month view disappeared from Week Calendar. Many users of Week Calendar complained, and the response from UtiliTap was rather surprising:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>"Apple forced those changes upon us, since they have full control over your iPhone and over developers apps. They claim the Day and (old) Month views look to similar to theirs."&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Clearly, somebody at Apple had misinterpreted the rules, and broke a very useful application by using &amp;quot;the force&amp;quot; for no good reason. UtiliTap quickly came out with a release with no less than two month views, the Mini-Month view (which I don't like that much) and a replacement for the original month view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The replacement month view is not as nice as the first one, and I find that it puts more strain on my eyes when I'm using it. I miss the old month view. I had a whole blogpost ready with a rant about how Apple would now have to sue each Calendar maker in the world because their month view looks too much like Apple's month. But I think nobody at Apple is really going to pay much attention to my little rants on this little blog, certainly not now people are grieving over Steve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I decided to think different:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="weekcal-month-design-v2.png">&lt;img src="old-month-vs-redesign.png" alt="Old Month vs Redesign">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the left you see the redesigned month view by UtiliTap after Apple bullied them. It's really amazing how quick they were in redesigning this part of the app and releasing it to the app store. But it's clearly a rush job. It doesn't look as polished as the first version, and I think it needs a redesign.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the right you can see my feeble attempt at a redesign. Apart from the obvious cosmetic changes, there is one feature I added: The dots in the top row of a day are before noon, and the dots in the bottom row are after noon. So now you can not only see how many appointments you have and in which calendar they are, but you can also quickly glance over your month to see if you have a free afternoon or morning. Clever, no?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I sent the design to UtiliTap before writing this blog post, and I really hope they use (some parts) of it. I've told them they can use any part of this design free of charge. Because they provided us with an excellent app for an excellent price, and they didn't deserve to be treated by Apple like this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm looking forward to the next release of Week Calendar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The €2800,- Roaming Gigabyte</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 20:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjf-6p76rhA">&lt;img src="burnmoney.jpg" alt="T-Mobile is scum">
&lt;/a>We all know the stories about how vacationing smartphone users became the victim of high &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roaming">roaming&lt;/a> charges, resulting in monthly bills sometimes exceeding €1000. To put an end to this, the EU has come up with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_on_roaming_charges_in_the_European_Union">rule&lt;/a> stating that carriers can no longer charge more than €50 per month for roaming, and are obliged to warn the user before reaching this limit. That all sounds nice and consumer friendly, but I recently tested this, and received an &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; monthly bill from T-Mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I've got an iPhone 4, and like many Dutch iPhone users, I got mine with a T-Mobile contract. I always used Vodafone because it has much better coverage, but when the iPhone 3 came out, T-Mobile was the only way to go and after some hesitation, I switched providers. To this day, the network coverage is not as good as Vodafone's, I miss calls even when I have full bars, and even if I can get "3G", the speeds are not nearly as good as friends with iPhones on the Vodafone network.
&lt;p>Having said that, my contract is an old contract which means I have a truly unlimited data plan, for a reasonable price. That is, until you cross the border.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks ago, we went to France for a week of Eurodisney with the kids and grand kids. Because of the project stress at work, and de possibility to share pictures with my parents, I decided to enable roaming on my iPhone. I did try to check the T-Mobile site for data plans and bundles, but these were either not meeting my needs (day passes), or were too hard to compare with each other. I checked my contract and the roaming charges seemed only slightly higher than the blocks, box-packs, travel-smurf, stack-bundles, or whatever convoluted pricing schemes these carriers were trying to trick me in to. I decided to reset the usage info on my iPhone and keep an eye on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2117-all.png">&lt;img src="img_2117-all.png" alt="Welcome to France">
&lt;/a>I crossed the border and received the usual SMS, about rates everybody ignores. I did see that data was €2,- per MB (yes mega-byte) but it looked more like a typo to me, surely they didn't mean mega-byte, did they? During my stay in France, I got he absolute worse network coverage and data speeds you can imagine. No matter where I was, reading text-only email turned into a chore taking sometimes minutes to load. Twitter feeds were barely coming through, and sending a downscaled 100kB image actually took several retries, and multiple minutes. It was horrible. And then, on day 4, it all came to a halt. No SMS, no warning, no mail, no phone call, just total data shutdown. I could still make &lt;a href="http://www.rense.com/general79/metal.htm">robot-voice calls&lt;/a>, but all data traffic stopped and I had no idea how to get that going again. And that turned out to be a good thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2114.png">&lt;img src="img_2114.png?w=100" alt="Data usage">
&lt;/a>I checked my usage, and guessed that I must have crossed the €50,- mark somewhere, and the carrier shut me down to &amp;quot;protect me&amp;quot; from high roaming charges. I tried to SMS a few people to let them know I was still alive, and that was that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks after I got home, I got the bill, and yes, there it was: I had reached the €50,- mark. It was an expensive experiment, and well worth this blogpost. Here's why. On my home &lt;a href="http://www.xs4all.nl/consument/internetbellen/start.php">entry-level 8Mbit ADSL connection&lt;/a>, I have free VOIP, and unlimited data. I checked our ADSL traffic and my family seems to be doing about 20GB a month combined. My monthly bill is €45,- so if I don't use the phone you could say that a GB of traffic costs me (€45 / 20 GB) &lt;strong>€2,25 per GB.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="factuur_30082011.png">&lt;img src="factuur_30082011.png" alt="The amazing T-Mobile roaming charges">
&lt;/a>As you can see in my data usage screenshot on the iPhone, and the bill on the right, I hardly made use of voice or sms. So we can roughly do the same calculation, assuming that 99% of the bill is data. The monthly bill was €89,45, and that got me 31.450MB of data (yes, again: mega-byte). So the price of a roaming Gigabyte in Europe is (€89,45 / 0.031450 GB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>€ 2844,20 per GB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you see is no typo. Almost €3000,- per GB. So what the Phone company is telling me here, is that even though the networks in all countries are reaching right up to the border, and we live in an interconnected world where data travels freely across the globe, phone companies charge more than 1000x the regular price to get a bit of information across that border?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think carriers need to be seriously investigated by the EU and Trading committees, because they are using their monopoly to charge us prices which are totally unrealistic. It also proves that privatization of public services like communication networks doesn't work. It nearly always results in a few greedy companies cobbling up a system which delivers crappy service for an outrageous price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step for these leeches is to come back from &lt;a href="http://rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/">whatever cave they were in&lt;/a>, move forward in time to 2011, and replace the &amp;quot;MB&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;GB&amp;quot; on my bill, without changing anything else. That would &lt;em>still&lt;/em> make them 26% more expensive than my internet provider, but at least it would take the roaming charges to an acceptable level, even for the crappy data speeds they blatantly market as &amp;quot;high speed&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why phone companies will fail</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 19:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/phone">&lt;img src="wet-cell-phone.jpeg" alt="cell phone under water">
&lt;/a>I recently had a very unpleasant experience with my mobile phone. Actually, it wasn't so much my mobile phone itself, as it was the sharing of my private mobile phone number between colleagues. Seemingly harmless, but with great consequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my colleagues, in his innocence and with nothing but good intentions, shared my phone number with another colleague. As I was sitting in the hospital, the second colleague called me with questions about estimates I made for a project, which at that time &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rolfje/status/545010403512320">intensely frustrated me&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I had the whole weekend to cool down, I was still pretty pissed the following monday. Some unpleasant conversations followed. I think everything is solved now but I can only hope somebody actually deletes my number when he says he does. Which got me to think about the old fashioned and spectacularly broken addressing model phone companies are still using.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->When I was little, there were no mobile phones (yes, I'm that old). People had a single line into their house, with a single number. This situation lead to some "number sharing etiquette": If person A asks for the phone number of person B, instead of giving it, you asked for A's phone number instead, and passed that to B. This way, both parties have control over sharing their number, without you compromising anybody's number without their consent.
&lt;p>Nowadays, it seems that only my &amp;quot;smarter&amp;quot; friends find this etiquette normal to be used in sharing email addresses and other address information. Sadly, this is not the case for the younger generations. Sharing email addresses and phone numbers without asking is common practice. With modern communication methods this is not a problem, because the receiver is in control of the inbound traffic. Messages can be blocked, filtered or re-routed. Mails can be routed to different folders or straight into the trash with a simple mail rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much unlike unlike messaging, routing incoming calls is not possible on your phone. Why? Because the phone companies have created a problem when they introduced caller-ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of protecting the receiver of the call, they chose to protect the caller by hiding his number if he wishes to do so. This simple oversight results in the receiver not being able to route calls based on caller-ID. I can not block anonymous incoming calls without knowing if I am missing important calls, say from the hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to fix this, I propose we do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. We still keep (or re-introduce) the sharing etiquette described above, because I think it is good courtesy to handle other people's data with respect. It's also a workaround for the inbound routing problem.
2. We create a system where a phone can have multiple numbers, of which the owner can route traffic. Google voice is already doing this, but european phone companies are not allowing that to happen over here (guess why).
3. We loose the whole &amp;quot;anonymous calling&amp;quot; idea after implementing 2. As with MSN and Google Talk, I get to see who is calling me, and I can choose to block future calls or add you to my &amp;quot;buddy list&amp;quot;.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Having said all this, I think phone companies are dying. Sure they're doing okay now, but they keep holding on to old landline business models and apply them to new technology. It will fail like it is failing for the music and film industry right now. Unless phone companies act up and start behaving more like reasonable &amp;quot;data/Internet providers&amp;quot; they will be replaced by internet providers putting up cell towers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until then, we need to put up with (but protest against) ridiculous data plans, absurd roaming charges, single-provider GSM towers with coverage problems and the recent &amp;quot;round up to nearest minute&amp;quot; method of over-billing customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I expect all this to happen not earlier than world peace, let's be careful about sharing each others numbers, shall we?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Car Buying Story</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2010 22:50:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-04-om-21-22-13.png" alt="">
Stephen needs a new car. Being dilligent and a car lover, he takes the time to write down all criteria for a great car. When he finishes the list, he notices that the only car matching all his criteria is a Ferrari. Well, he always loved a Ferrari so that makes sense. To make things more realistic he adds another criteria, called &amp;quot;price&amp;quot;, and starts looking for alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The first car he looks at is practical, but hasn't got the speed of a Ferrari. The second car can carry a lot of stuff, but hasn't got the sound of a Ferrari. The third car is really modular, but hasn't got the looks of a Ferrari. The fourth car is very fast, but doesn't handle as a Ferrari. The fifth car is an independant brand, and can be repaired in any shop, but it breaks down much more often than a Ferrari. The sixth car has a cool design-flip-type-clock and integrated MP3 player, but the manual coming with it does not explain how to operate them.
&lt;p>The seventh car looked too good to be true good in the advertisement. The images in the brochure look stunning. It has everything on his list, and also matches the price criteria. Stephen orders it immediately. But when delivered it does not live up to the whole Ferrari design, look and feel. By far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen is not really unhappy and has learned to live with the car's shortcomings. When asked about his new car, Stephen kindly shows it, but the first sentence he regretfuly utters is &lt;em>&amp;quot;but ofcourse, it's not a Ferrari&amp;quot;...&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The moral of this story is: If you don't buy a Ferrari, you'll never own a Ferrari.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: car
replace: mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: Ferrari
replace: iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="the-events-in-this-story-are-fictitious-any-similarity-to-any-person-living-or-dead-is-merely-coincidental-i-cannot-emphasize-enough-how-coincidental-the-fictional-entities-are-to-any-real-life-individual-entity-or-character-for-more-disclaimers-id-like-to-refer-you-to-this-sites-about-pagehttprolfjewordpresscomabout">The events in this story are fictitious. Any similarity to any person living or dead is merely coincidental. I cannot emphasize enough how coincidental the fictional entities are to any real life individual, entity, or character. For more disclaimers I'd like to refer you to this site's &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/about/">about page&lt;/a>.&lt;/h6></description></item><item><title>How to put DVD's on your iPhone (for free)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:19:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-13a1.png" alt="For A Few Dollars More">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of companies like to sell you applications to put DVD's on your iPhone. Usually these apps are just wrappers around existing tools, and are pretty expensive if you consider you can do it for free. And you don't need to be a computer wizard either! The steps are simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Use [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) to rip the DVD to iPhone format
2. Drag the generated mp4 file into iTunes
3. Sync it to your iPhone like all other content
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>To show you exactly how this is done, I've  written up this &amp;quot;babystep-by-babystep&amp;quot; tutorial. Let me show you how I ripped &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Few-Dollars-More-Clint-Eastwood/dp/0792839056">&amp;quot;For A Few Dollars More&amp;quot;&lt;/a> and put it on my iPhone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Disclaimer: **The DVD I ripped is bought and payed for. This article does not relief you of your responsibility to obey the law, so please be careful. And be nice, don't pirate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->What You Need&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) for ripping the DVD
* [VLC](http://www.videolan.org/vlc/), which is used by handbrake for DVD's with encodings not supported by Handbrake. You don't always need it, but download and install it anyway, just to be sure.
* Some patience.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Rip the DVD to an MP4&lt;/strong>
Put a DVD in your Mac, and stop the DVD player application if it opens automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.png?w=128" alt="Select VIDEO_TS folder">
&lt;/a>Start Handbrake. A selection window will open, use it to browse to the DVD, and select the VIDEO_TS folder (just select it, no need to go into it) and then press &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-7.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-7.png" alt="Select Title and Chapters">
&lt;/a>Handbrake will briefly scan the DVD for titles. In the &amp;quot;Source:&amp;quot; section of the screen, select a title and the chapters you want to rip. Usually Handbrake guesses that it's the longest title, with the most chapters you want to rip. Let's go with those defaults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-81.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-81.png?w=44" alt="Presets Selection Drawer">
&lt;/a>Press the &amp;quot;Toggle Presets&amp;quot; button on the top right, and select &amp;quot;iPhone&amp;quot; from the list that pops out on the right side of the Handbrake window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-10.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-10.png?w=120" alt="Select Audio and Subtitles">
&lt;/a>Next, click the &amp;quot;Audio and Subtitles&amp;quot; tab and select the audio and subtitles you want to listen and read in the ripped video. You can NOT change audio and subtitles later on your iPhone, so choose wisely. This is usually the step I forget, which requires me to wait for the whole ripping process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-12.png" alt="afbeelding-12">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure the destination file is where you want it, and press the green &amp;quot;Start&amp;quot; icon. Handbrake will start reading the DVD and create an MP4 file. This can take a while, so you might want to get a cocktail. Handbrake will show a progress bar in the icon in the dock.
 
&lt;strong>Step 2: Import into iTunes&lt;/strong>
After the ripping is done, you can add your mp4 file to the iTunes library by simply dragging the video file into iTunes. There you can set the title, year, genre and illustration exactly as you did with your music files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-14.png" alt="iTunes showing ripped DVD">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 3: Putting it on your iPhone&lt;/strong>
Plug in you iPhone. Go to the iPhone configuration and click on the &amp;quot;Video&amp;quot; tab. Scroll down, and select the video you just imported:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-15.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-15.png" alt="Sync the movie to the phone">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you press &amp;quot;Apply&amp;quot;, iTunes will immediately start copying the movie over to the iPhone, where you can find it in your iPhone in your iTunes library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Advanced Tips:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [![Few Dollars More on iPhone](img_0005.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](img_0005.png)The DVD I just converted (For A Few Dollars More) averaged out to about 3,5MB per minute. That's about 5 hours of video per GB, but your mileage may vary. On average you should be able to take at least one or to movies with you on your iPhone. If your music is in the way, you can &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/">use these tips&lt;/a> to make iTunes organize your music for you.
* Handbrake has an &amp;quot;Add To Queue&amp;quot; button which lets you convert multiple movies in a row. In order for that to work you need to copy the VIDEO_TS folders of multiple DVD's onto a harddrive. Now you can convert multiple DVD's overnight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T-Mobile Network Quality</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/31/t-mobile-network-quality/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 23:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/31/t-mobile-network-quality/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_0003.png">&lt;img src="img_0003.png?w=200" alt="">
&lt;/a>As you've noticed, I bought an &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/">iPhone&lt;/a>. When you're living in the Netherlands, you've got two options to get an iPhone. The first one is walk to an Apple reseller, buy an iPhone and sell your soul to T-Mobile. The second option is to drive to Belgium, convince a reseller to sell you a simlock-free iPhone, and get a &lt;a href="http://www.vodafone.nl/prive/favorieten/Super_SIM_Only">Vodafone iPhone &amp;quot;Super Sim Only&amp;quot; contract&lt;/a>. I went for the first option, and to be honest I kind of regret it. The iPhone is brilliant, but the T-Mobile network in the Netherlands sucks. Bigtime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your life depends on somebodies availabilty, please make sure to check they're not using the T-Mobile or Orange network (the companies merged). Don't let T-Mobile fool you with the &amp;quot;iPhone has bad reception hype&amp;quot;. I can make screenshots like you see here each day. I have &amp;quot;No service&amp;quot; but I can see the Vodafone and KPN networks just fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Although the [GSM coverage maps for T-Mobile](http://www.gsmworld.com/cgi-bin/ni_map.pl?x=0&amp;y=0&amp;z=0&amp;cc=nl&amp;net=t3) indicate that the gsm1800 coverage very good, a lot of customers, including me, will tell you otherwise from personal experience. I think the 3G coverage on the map is also unrealistic to say the least.
&lt;p>Here's a short list of locations I went to the last couple of weeks. Please note that in all of these locations, I could reliably see the Vodafone network, inside and outside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;table style="text-align:right;" border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
Location
Inside buildings
Outside
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Amersfoort](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.151924,5.411625&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=13&amp;sll=52.140231,5.414543&amp;sspn=0.096926,0.12188&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.142549,5.408363&amp;spn=0.096921,0.12188&amp;z=13)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-4.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Amsterdam, VU hospital](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=nl&amp;q=Vu+Medisch+Centrum,+Nederland&amp;sll=52.373812,4.890951&amp;sspn=0.376443,0.487518&amp;g=Vu+Medisch+Centrum,+Nederland&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;cd=2&amp;geocode=FeKSHgMd9h5KAA&amp;ll=52.334775,4.860184&amp;spn=0.011774,0.015235&amp;z=16)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-2.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Beverwijk](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.481735,4.664254&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=15&amp;sll=52.482754,4.662666&amp;sspn=0.02347,0.03047&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.482101,4.663568&amp;spn=0.02347,0.03047&amp;z=15)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-5.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Haaksbergen](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=Elektrostraat&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=FYwjHAMdZfNmAA%3B&amp;mra=mr&amp;sll=52.156785,6.738631&amp;sspn=0.094573,0.12188&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.166562,6.745605&amp;spn=0.094552,0.12188&amp;z=13)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Haarlem](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.384021,4.63696&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=16&amp;sll=52.382384,4.63505&amp;sspn=0.011762,0.015235&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.384689,4.636724&amp;spn=0.011761,0.015235&amp;z=16)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-5.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Haarlem
([Parking Central Station](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.386772,4.63902&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=16&amp;sll=52.386785,4.639728&amp;sspn=0.01176,0.015235&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.386366,4.639063&amp;spn=0.011761,0.015235&amp;z=16))
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-4.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Leusden](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.11457,5.40699&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=14&amp;sll=52.117574,5.418062&amp;sspn=0.047328,0.06094&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.112673,5.406475&amp;spn=0.047333,0.06094&amp;z=14)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
 
&lt;p>Terrible right? In Amersfoort, Amsterdam, Haaksbergen and Leusden I actually had to walk outside to make calls, or to see if I had missed any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that this will improve significantly, otherwise I have to try to unlock my iPone and buy a Vodafone simcard. T-Mobile will then probably hold my phonenumber hostage until the end of my contract just because they can. I've had the same phonenumber for the past 15 odd years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you've got a choice, try to get an iPhone from Belgium, and avoid T-Mobile because you will be frustrated by the lack of connectivity. The only thing you'll miss is the Visual Voicemail, but if your network is good, you don't need voicemail all that much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For now, I'm going to check if my hart surgeon uses the T-Mobile network. If so, I need to switch to a smarter surgeon ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The iPhone buying experience</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 18:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Ok so I've been &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/10/apple-reinvents-phone-ipod-and-userinterface-in-1-go/">blogging about&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/13/see-the-iphone-demo/">the iPhone&lt;/a> and&lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/08/07/cowbell/"> it's &amp;quot;apps&amp;quot;&lt;/a> for a while now. After a lot of consideration and switching between Nokia and iPod touch, doing nothing and buying a 16GB 3G iPhone, I finally went for the latter. What a bittersweet experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->We have no real Apple stores. They're called "Apple authorized resellers" and may look like an Apple store, but they're not. Because they are run by slow Dutch people (I get to that in a minute), and don't have geniuous bars, and can't seem to be of help unless you want to buy something.
&lt;p>In the Netherlands, you can by an iPhone at T-mobile shops, or at the Apple store. At the T-Mobile stores, there are often no iPhones in stock. At the Apple stores (let's call 'em that, to humor them) the employees know nothing of cellphone contracts. Because I like the interiour of the Apple store better, I decided to get my iPhone there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went for the black 16GB 3G model, because the white one is just a bit to &amp;quot;girly&amp;quot;, and is easy to spot 100 miles away for any bad guys out to steal iPhones. I came prepared with copies of my passport and old SIM card. The guy behind the counter went into the storage room to get one. Then something strange happened: a &lt;a href="http://www.parallels.com/">Parallels&lt;/a> session was started up, and an Internet Explorer browser opened to show a HTTPS page at which we could fill in a contract form. It took ages to start up, and the T-Mobile &amp;quot;special registration form&amp;quot; was teribly slow. The Apple salesman was not very fast either, I had to correct him more than once because he didn't read the instruction on the screen. All in all I spent 37 minutes (measured) in the store to get everything registered and payed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I am still wondering why the T-Mobile registration page could not have been opened in Firefox or Safari on OSX.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a week, T-mobile sent a letter saying that my old number could not be ported. I called customer support and as it turned out, the guy at the Apple store still didn't fill in the form correctly (I wonder what he missed after staring at 2 html forms for 37 minutes). After being on hold for over 28 minutes at the T-Mobile helpdesk, they solved everything and my original number got transfered within 3 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here I am, with an iPhone. Prepare to read a lot about it. ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn your iPhone into a Drive</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/10/turn-your-iphone-into-a-drive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 06:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/10/turn-your-iphone-into-a-drive/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/04/27/homezone-start-isync-automatically/">Nokia 6300&lt;/a> behaves like a flash or thumb drive when I connect it to a computer using an USB cable. I think this should be standard functionality nowadays. Cellphones are replacing the Filofax and MP3 players. I can read mail on my cellphone, take pictures and movies. It contains an 4GB memory stick, sometimes even more. So why do I need to carry this silly thumbdrive with me?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->If you have an iPhone with the 2.0 firmware, unlimited dataplan, and maybe even [MobileMe](http://www.apple.com/mobileme/), you may already have found a solution for carrying all kinds of data with you. If you haven't, maybe [DataCase](http://www.veiosoft.com/) is something for you. It will allow you to turn your iPhone into a (network) drive and put stuff on there to take with you.
&lt;p>Please note that at the time of this writing, DataCase is in closed Beta testing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cowbell++;</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/07/cowbell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 06:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/07/cowbell/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.pocketpicks.co.uk/latest/index.php/2008/07/17/iphone-app-of-the-day-3-more-cowbell/">&lt;img src="cowbell.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>I just came across this great post about &lt;a href="http://www.copyblogger.com/more-cowbell/">creating captivating content&lt;/a>. The punchline: It's not about getting the scoop, it's about finding the cowbell and amplifying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More funny cowbell references:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Alex Johnson's version the popular [playstation game](http://i44.photobucket.com/albums/f14/AlexJohnson123/cowbell-hero.jpg).
* The [wikipedia page](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/More_cowbell) on the cowbell sketch
* The [Cowbell project](http://www.geekspeakweekly.com/cowbell/)
* And... The More [Cowbell app for your iPhone](http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=285559215&amp;amp;mt=8) (rock on!)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you'll excuse me, I'm going to &amp;quot;explore the studio space&amp;quot;. No, really. :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Birthday!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 20:36:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I know you've been playing with your ultra-cool iPhones, but did you realize that it only is 6 years ago that Apple showed is the first iPod? It's amazing how fast technology advances nowadays. Today I read that 128GB flashdrives are not far away, so how about an 128GB iPhone, or even a MacBook with a solid state disk? We've got a nice future ahead...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Meanwhile, you can watch Steve announce the first ever iPod, and notice the difference with the existing devices at that time. It's not strange that the iPod changed the way people listen to music.
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kN0SVBCJqLs&amp;amp;rel=1]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPhone opens up to developers</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/18/iphone-opens-up-to-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2007 20:40:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/18/iphone-opens-up-to-developers/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Finally, the word is out. Apple (Steve) has announced at the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/">&amp;quot;hot news feed&amp;quot;&lt;/a> that the iPhone (and iPod touch) will be opened up to developers in February 2008. I think this is a wise decision. In stead of fighting developers, bricking phones and constantly being at the defense, the effort of Apple is much better put to use by working together with the (free, unpayed, expert-level, hours-on-end-concentrating, 24/7) programmers out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>Steve wrote an open letter, which I'll quote here because you can not direct-link to posts in the &amp;quot;hot news&amp;quot; feed of Apple. On 17 October 2007 Steve wrote:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>&amp;quot;Third Party Applications on the iPhone&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Let me just say it: We want native third party applications on the iPhone, and we plan to have an SDK in developers’ hands in February. We are excited about creating a vibrant third party developer community around the iPhone and enabling hundreds of new applications for our users. With our revolutionary multi-touch interface, powerful hardware and advanced software architecture, we believe we have created the best mobile platform ever for developers.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It will take until February to release an SDK because we’re trying to do two diametrically opposed things at once—provide an advanced and open platform to developers while at the same time protect iPhone users from viruses, malware, privacy attacks, etc. This is no easy task. Some claim that viruses and malware are not a problem on mobile phones—this is simply not true. There have been serious viruses on other mobile phones already, including some that silently spread from phone to phone over the cell network. As our phones become more powerful, these malicious programs will become more dangerous. And since the iPhone is the most advanced phone ever, it will be a highly visible target.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Some companies are already taking action. Nokia, for example, is not allowing any applications to be loaded onto some of their newest phones unless they have a digital signature that can be traced back to a known developer. While this makes such a phone less than “totally open,” we believe it is a step in the right direction. We are working on an advanced system which will offer developers broad access to natively program the iPhone’s amazing software platform while at the same time protecting users from malicious programs.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We think a few months of patience now will be rewarded by many years of great third party applications running on safe and reliable iPhones.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Steve&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>P.S.: The SDK will also allow developers to create applications for iPod touch. [Oct 17, 2007]&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that Apple will also open up the iPod cables again, for a minute out there Apple seemed to be forgotten what their initial market strategy was (and should be): Compete by designing the best product.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've found Microsoft products to be restrictive, as opposed to Apple's products being liberating. Microsoft makes me want to pirate stuff, Apple makes me want to pay for the great solution they have. Microsoft tries to charge you bigtime, and in return give you long serialnumbers, &amp;quot;authenticity checks&amp;quot;, and a lot of problems and bugs along with a piece of software that does not solve your problem or works like advertised (Vista, anyone?). Apple simply offers the best solution you could possibly imagine, (almost) without (noticable) copy restrictions, at a fair price. It will feel like money well spent, and almost always actually works &lt;em>better&lt;/em> than advertised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why all of a sudden Apple wants to be in the restrictive game is a complete mistery to me, and I hope they'll see the error of their ways soon...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>See the iPhone Demo</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/13/see-the-iphone-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 21:26:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/13/see-the-iphone-demo/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Want to see how the iPhone works? Check out the iPone demo page at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">apple.com/iphone&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple reinvents phone, ipod and userinterface... in 1 go</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/10/apple-reinvents-phone-ipod-and-userinterface-in-1-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 21:26:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/10/apple-reinvents-phone-ipod-and-userinterface-in-1-go/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_iphone-cingular.jpg">&lt;img src="o_iphone-cingular.thumbnail.jpg" alt="iPhone">
&lt;/a>I have been watching the &lt;a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/j47d52oo/event/">Macworld 2007 keynote address&lt;/a> for the last 2 hours and all I can say is:...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jup, nothing. I am absolutely amazed by the way Apple has not only reinvented the phone (look ma, no keys!) but also the ipod (look ma, &lt;a href="http://www.steelskies.com/coverflow/">coverflow&lt;/a>!), and maybe the most overlooked, but they reinvented the mouse!!!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago, I was amazed at this &lt;a href="http://ted.com/tedtalks/tedtalksplayer.cfm?key=j_han&amp;amp;flashEnabled=1">new userinterface&lt;/a> Jeff Han presented . It was touchscreen based, and very intuitive. He amazed the crowds with it. At the time me and my collegues guessed that he must have had several computers working in parallel to be able to facilitate this. Now, Apple actually integrated it into the phone!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think a phone without keys sucks, and you think your blackberry is a great device, please take a look at the keynote presentation, I think you will want one of these. If you are too busy to sit for 2 hours watching this amazing device, or even too busy to watch the shortened version (on the same page, as the keynote, above), I'll list some of the highlights:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Large (and I mean LARGE) touch sensitive display all over the front of the phone
* ipod functionality, syncing not only your music, but also your photos, movies and contacts automagically between your Mac and your phone
* Runs [Mac OSX](http://www.apple.com/macosx/leopard/index.html), Apples operating system shipped with all macs. (Yes REALLY runs it)
* Full, 100% normal internet browsing using a new version of [Safari](http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/safari/) (told you it runs OSX, didn't I?)
* Full [Google maps](http://maps.google.nl/) integration (not a crippled mobile phone version), enabeling you to view maps and satelite images on your phone, and integrates with your phonebook and other applications. Lookup where an address is, or search for the nearest Starbucks and directly phone a store from within the Google map (demo in keynote).
* Full rich text IMAP and POP3 email client with very easy to use onscreen keyboard with error correction
* Tilt sensor to enable to view anything in landscape mode by just holding your phone horizontally, providing widescreen movie viewing!
* Gesture based user interface, allowing you to navigate through the phone and zoom in and out on practically anything
* Quad band phone using GSM + EDGE standard. Currently only shipping with [Cingular and AT&amp;amp;T](http://www.cingular.com/home/) and a [free Yahoo! imap](https://login.yahoo.com/config/mail?.intl=us) account. Technically possible to use in Europe using any GSM network provider, but I don't know how the Cingular contract looks for Europe.
* Built in WIFI and bluetooth technology to connect to the internet or any network, and a bluetooth headset, and it does that seemlesly
* Random access voicemail (tap on the voicemail you want to hear)
* Priced at $499 for a 4GB model, and $599 for an 8 GB model, available in June in US, end of 2007 in Europe, and 2008 in Japan.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_iphone_home.gif">&lt;img src="o_iphone_home.thumbnail.gif" alt="iPhone unlocked">
&lt;/a>My list could go on and on, but these are probably the highlights you were looking for. I've seen &lt;a href="http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs">Steve&lt;/a> using the iPhone, and the userinterface is a dream. If you own a Microsoft mouse with the &amp;quot;heavy scrollwheel&amp;quot; you will know what I mean when the iPhone scrolls through the lists by giving it a swing. Amazing to look at. The Core animation of OSX is in the phone, so everything tilts, swoops and zooms like on your desktop and it is really, really nice too look at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guess is that by doing this and patenting it, the next step Apple will take is reinvent the desktop userinterface. Have your screen built into your desk, throw your keyboard away and touch the screen! It has been done before, but after you've seen the keynote you will agree with me that Apple can do it right this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been quite some time since I have been amazed by a product like this, although it will be a while before I own one because I'm afraid it will get stolen because of it's good looks. I'm afraid it will even push the iPod out of the market a little, and Zune will be dead and gone when the iPhone hits the market...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go and see the &lt;a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/j47d52oo/event/">Macworld 2007 keynote address&lt;/a>, and see his Steveness improvise when his &amp;quot;Clicker's not working&amp;quot; just before he announces &amp;quot;Apple Computer Inc&amp;quot; is now going to be called just &amp;quot;Apple Inc&amp;quot;. Maybe Apple should ship this keynote on DVD. Seriously. Even if the only reason is seeing John Mayer perform &amp;quot;Gravity&amp;quot; live and unplugged at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'll hold on to my &lt;a href="http://finance.google.com/finance?q=GOOG">Google&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://finance.google.com/finance?q=AAPL">Apple shares&lt;/a> for a while I guess...&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>