<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DRM on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/drm/</link><description>Recent content in DRM on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:19:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/drm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to put DVD's on your iPhone (for free)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:19:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-13a1.png" alt="For A Few Dollars More">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of companies like to sell you applications to put DVD's on your iPhone. Usually these apps are just wrappers around existing tools, and are pretty expensive if you consider you can do it for free. And you don't need to be a computer wizard either! The steps are simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Use [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) to rip the DVD to iPhone format
2. Drag the generated mp4 file into iTunes
3. Sync it to your iPhone like all other content
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>To show you exactly how this is done, I've  written up this &amp;quot;babystep-by-babystep&amp;quot; tutorial. Let me show you how I ripped &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Few-Dollars-More-Clint-Eastwood/dp/0792839056">&amp;quot;For A Few Dollars More&amp;quot;&lt;/a> and put it on my iPhone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Disclaimer: **The DVD I ripped is bought and payed for. This article does not relief you of your responsibility to obey the law, so please be careful. And be nice, don't pirate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->What You Need&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) for ripping the DVD
* [VLC](http://www.videolan.org/vlc/), which is used by handbrake for DVD's with encodings not supported by Handbrake. You don't always need it, but download and install it anyway, just to be sure.
* Some patience.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Rip the DVD to an MP4&lt;/strong>
Put a DVD in your Mac, and stop the DVD player application if it opens automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.png?w=128" alt="Select VIDEO_TS folder">
&lt;/a>Start Handbrake. A selection window will open, use it to browse to the DVD, and select the VIDEO_TS folder (just select it, no need to go into it) and then press &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-7.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-7.png" alt="Select Title and Chapters">
&lt;/a>Handbrake will briefly scan the DVD for titles. In the &amp;quot;Source:&amp;quot; section of the screen, select a title and the chapters you want to rip. Usually Handbrake guesses that it's the longest title, with the most chapters you want to rip. Let's go with those defaults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-81.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-81.png?w=44" alt="Presets Selection Drawer">
&lt;/a>Press the &amp;quot;Toggle Presets&amp;quot; button on the top right, and select &amp;quot;iPhone&amp;quot; from the list that pops out on the right side of the Handbrake window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-10.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-10.png?w=120" alt="Select Audio and Subtitles">
&lt;/a>Next, click the &amp;quot;Audio and Subtitles&amp;quot; tab and select the audio and subtitles you want to listen and read in the ripped video. You can NOT change audio and subtitles later on your iPhone, so choose wisely. This is usually the step I forget, which requires me to wait for the whole ripping process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-12.png" alt="afbeelding-12">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure the destination file is where you want it, and press the green &amp;quot;Start&amp;quot; icon. Handbrake will start reading the DVD and create an MP4 file. This can take a while, so you might want to get a cocktail. Handbrake will show a progress bar in the icon in the dock.
 
&lt;strong>Step 2: Import into iTunes&lt;/strong>
After the ripping is done, you can add your mp4 file to the iTunes library by simply dragging the video file into iTunes. There you can set the title, year, genre and illustration exactly as you did with your music files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-14.png" alt="iTunes showing ripped DVD">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 3: Putting it on your iPhone&lt;/strong>
Plug in you iPhone. Go to the iPhone configuration and click on the &amp;quot;Video&amp;quot; tab. Scroll down, and select the video you just imported:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-15.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-15.png" alt="Sync the movie to the phone">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you press &amp;quot;Apply&amp;quot;, iTunes will immediately start copying the movie over to the iPhone, where you can find it in your iPhone in your iTunes library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Advanced Tips:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [![Few Dollars More on iPhone](img_0005.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](img_0005.png)The DVD I just converted (For A Few Dollars More) averaged out to about 3,5MB per minute. That's about 5 hours of video per GB, but your mileage may vary. On average you should be able to take at least one or to movies with you on your iPhone. If your music is in the way, you can &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/">use these tips&lt;/a> to make iTunes organize your music for you.
* Handbrake has an &amp;quot;Add To Queue&amp;quot; button which lets you convert multiple movies in a row. In order for that to work you need to copy the VIDEO_TS folders of multiple DVD's onto a harddrive. Now you can convert multiple DVD's overnight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rip and Convert FLAC, M4A, MP3, AAC files</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&lt;img src="afbeelding-8.png" alt="Max Audio Transcoder">
&lt;/a>I recently found an old harddisk which used to be in one of my old PC's. I discovered some &lt;a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">FLAC&lt;/a> files on there, which were rips of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOU8GIRUd_g">old CD's&lt;/a> I used to have. iTunes is not too happy with importing them into my library, and the original CD's are in a box in a deep dark corner of my garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I searched for a converter and found this wonderful converter which can just about convert any audio format out there. It's called &lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&amp;quot;Max&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, it's Open Source, free to use, and available as bundled OSX application. Brilliant! It does have a bunch of options, but as long as you go for the &amp;quot;MP4 Audio&amp;quot; output format, high quiality, 256 bits and VBR, you can't go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to their website &lt;em>&amp;quot;Max can generate audio in over 20 compressed and uncompressed formats including MP3, Ogg Vorbis, FLAC, AAC, Apple Lossless, Monkey's Audio, WavPack, Speex, AIFF, and WAVE&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy transcoding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You are a pirate!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/25/you-are-a-pirate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 23:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/25/you-are-a-pirate/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A briliant post on &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com">xkcd.com&lt;/a> today explains in one single cartoon why DRM is bad:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;400&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Steal This Comic&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/488/">&lt;img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/steal_this_comic.png" alt="Steal This Comic">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I couldn't have made it simpler (although &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/05/04/the-digital-revolution/">I tried&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Digital Revolution</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/04/the-digital-revolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/04/the-digital-revolution/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Nice example of digital revolution and power to the people can be found at &lt;a href="http://blog.outer-court.com/archive/2007-05-02-n67.html">http://blog.outer-court.com/archive/2007-05-02-n67.html&lt;/a>. Let's hope manufacturers understand that people don't want to pay for crippled content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digital copies where copyright is removed are actually better than their DRM protected originals, which makes good willing people move to pirated content, like I &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">stated earlier&lt;/a>. The important sentence here being &lt;em>&amp;quot;If I buy a DVD, I have to watch a few minutes of copyrights notices and commercials, without being able to skip them. If I rip it, and re-write it, these notices are gone...&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Viva la Revolution!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple and EMI follow up</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 21:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">previous post&lt;/a> I told you that Steve Jobs wants to provide DRM-free music through iTunes, but was held back by music companies. Steve must have had a few long and hard talks, because now EMI and Apple are teaming up to provide high quality &lt;a href="http://www.macnn.com/articles/07/04/02/drm.free.music.on.itunes/">DRM-free tracks through the iTunes music store&lt;/a>, priced at $1.30. The same track, in a lower sound quality, with DRM costs $0.99. For &lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2007/04/02/what-those-thirty-cents-buy-you/">30 cents&lt;/a>, you get a track you can actually use, with a higher bitrate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time this could be a trick by Apple to get around the legal issues currently being discussed about iTunes music not being available to other players than the iPod. Smart eh?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PureTracks also gets it!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/23/puretracks-also-gets-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/23/puretracks-also-gets-it/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The DRM discussion that was &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">started by Steve Jobs&lt;/a> is generating some interesting ripples in the music business pond. More people are starting to think DRM is not the answer: &lt;a href="http://www.electronista.com/articles/07/02/22/puretracks.dumps.drm/">PureTracks will sell DRM-free tracks&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Steve Jobs gets it!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 21:25:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Remember my rant on copy protection in the post about &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/archive/2007/01/25.aspx">opening iTunes to other players&lt;/a>? All the things record and movie companies tried the last few years has only encouraged people to rip, copy and distribute illegal media instead. It turns out that Steve Jobs also thinks that DRM is not the answer, according to bloomberg. Steve Jobs has sent a letter to the four largest music companies, in which he &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=20601087&amp;amp;sid=a_m4XNHva3IE&amp;amp;refer=home">Asks Music Labels To End Copyright Protection&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure it might sound bad when you have serious record company stock options, but the idea is not so dumb as it sounds. For years, Apple software has been reasonably priced, and of good quality. You can buy it online without too much hassle. Result: There is not much illegal Mac software out there. This will surprise the Windows user, who is acustomed to running all kinds of illegal software, up until the point they are practically forced to continue to do so, because they have all their content stored in propriatary formats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like Apple's way of doing things much more: Deliver good quality products, ask reasonable prices, and trust your users (up until a point ofcourse ;-). In return, Mac users are often more like &amp;quot;fans&amp;quot; than customers, because they don't feel like they've been &amp;quot;had&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think loosing the copy right protection and then lowering the prices on music is a good thing. The iTunes music store is an easy store to search music or other content in, and does not force millions of tracks onto you (like your friend with the 200GB music library on an USB disk does). Who cares if I have to pay a few cents for a track if I feel like iTunes has helped me find that track? The feeling shifts more to like &amp;quot;paying for the service&amp;quot; than &amp;quot;paying for the track&amp;quot; which is probably what we all look for. As an added value, we have the old &amp;quot;it's my product, I bought it&amp;quot; feeling back, where we can do with the content as we like because we payed for it. We are no longer restricted to stupid things as &amp;quot;you can listen this track only twice on your Zune before it will selfdestruct&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> More information and the response from Norway is &lt;a href="http://www.macnn.com/articles/07/02/06/norway.responds.to.jobs/">online at MacNN&lt;/a>. Norway showing it does not understand iTunes at all, because you can configure iTunes to store the files at a location of your destination, which can ultimately be any (large enough) USB disk, which in turn can be a media player device :-) .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opening iTunes to other players</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today I found an &lt;a href="http://today.reuters.co.uk/news/articlenews.aspx?type=technologyNews&amp;amp;storyID=2007-01-25T155722Z_01_L25510487_RTRIDST_0_TECH-APPLE-ITUNES-NORWAY-DC.XML&amp;amp;WTmodLoc=TechInternet-C3-Technology-2">article about Norway suing Apple&lt;/a> because music bought in the iTunes store could not be played on a non-iPod music player. If Apple looses this legal attack, it would result in an even stranger digital rights management situation than we already have. &lt;!-- more -->First, let me tell you why I think the whole legal case would not be worth persuing anyway:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Music bought through iTunes is in the [AAC format](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Audio_Coding#How_AAC_works), which is an open standard format. Any modern player is capable of playing AAC files. The &amp;quot;problem&amp;quot; lies in the way the songs are stored in an encrypted form invented by Apple, called [Fairplay](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FairPlay). Fairplay resticts the way you use and play the file, but only very limited: You can play a Fairplay encrypted file on your iPod, on up to 3 (three) authorized computers, and (here it comes) can be **copied to a standard audio CD any number of times**. Since when is this called &amp;quot;limiting&amp;quot;?
2. Buying DRM music from iTunes clearly has limitations. Apple is not hiding this fact, as Microsoft is not hiding the fact that WMA has almost the same limitations. Suppose there was no workaround available and you had to play the music on your iPod, you still could not complain. You can almost describe it as not being able to play CD's on your record player. You bough a CD, not a vinyl record, and you knew beforehand that it was not compatible with your record player.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>That said, I think the root cause of these type of lawsuits is often overlooked. It's the way people think about intelectual property and the traditional ways of selling copies where the author received a substantial part of the profits. In a digital age like ours, there is no &amp;quot;physical product&amp;quot;, which makes it very easy for me to give a file I bought to just about an individual out there, without me loosing the original file. The copies of the file are all of the same superiour quality, so re-distributing them is very interesting to anyone wanting to exchange or &amp;quot;trade&amp;quot; music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have allways thought of DRM of crippeling a file because people simply can not behave. The whole proces of crippeling audio and video files has just resulted in me doing the oposite of what the intent was. If I buy a DVD, I have to watch a few minutes of copyrights notices and commercials, without being able to skip them. If I rip it, and re-write it, these notices are gone, but I feel mistreated by the DVD company because I have to de-cripple my DVD's. This makes the ripped illegal copies much more interesting for me, because regardless of the price, I can just pop in the DVD, and watch the movie, like expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same goes for Audio, up to a certain point. When I buy music online, regardless if this is through the or &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windowsmedia/player/stores.aspx?lcid=809">any other WMA selling store&lt;/a>, the store dictates the way I use the audio file. As customer, I feel like I bought a file and I can do with it what I like. As store, they sell you the rights to listen te a recording in a restricted number of ways, a restricted number of times even. That's why I allways try to buy music on a normal audio CD. This gives me the ultimate solution to all problems:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. It is the original regording, in a non-lossy form. I can allways re-rip the audio in any bitrate I see fit for the purpose at hand.
2. I allways have the original and it will last for years as reliable backup. Storing it safely in a cupboard and never using (scratching) it, it will provide me with a 100% safe backup of my digital music library on my Mac, iPod, or USB memory stick player.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If it is not possible to get the music on a normal CD, I can allways resort to people who invent products like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hymn_%28software%29">Hymn (Hear Your Music aNywhere&lt;/a> to remove the DRM for me. As long as I do not copy the file, I see no harm in doing this because the DRM is there to prevent me from doing things I would not easily do anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think crippeling digital content is not the way to protect their content. There will always be people finding methods around this. Furthermore, the prices are very much like the pricing of their physical counterparts, which makes fro very unatractive products. Why would I buy a lossy, digitally crippled version of an audio track I can have on a non-lossy CD for the same price (per track)? The real problem is not being able to proscecute violators of the different copyright acts in various countries. What you actually want to verify is that the user of the audio file has paid some money to the original artist(s). That's the only problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What if the stores selling these audio tracks just gave every song a serial number. No DRM, just a tracking number. The store can administrate which serial number was bought by whom. By doing this, officers at my door can just extract these ID's from my library, upload them to the store and see if I paid for them, or somebody else did. This will probably not be the case for 100% of my tracks (since somebody else could have bought it for me on another computer). To prevent overhead lets say that the law states that 80% of my bought songs should have been bought by myself. If more than 20% of my library is not accountable for, investigation is started and could result in me paying fines for every song in my library which is considered to be an &amp;quot;illegal copy&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole sales model needs to be reinvented, and I think DRM is not the way to go. It has been around for long time, and I have never been tempted enough to buy a track, nor were any of my friends. As music stores go, the iTunes store is about the only store I &lt;em>would&lt;/em> buy tunes from, because this guarantees me that they will be playable on my machine and my music player. Apple is very maticulate about the correct functioning of their hard and software, much more so than Microsoft or any other smack-together-a-WMA-music-store out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somebody should sue CD labels for producing CDs which can not be played on a computer for exactly the same reasons as in all these other lawsuits. I bought music, and the store has no right deciding when I can do what with it or how many times (no pun intended). I understand they don't like illegal copies, but they can not punish me for making illegal copies before actually doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe music should just be free alltogether, and make it &amp;quot;donation-ware&amp;quot; or something alike. Most artists make more money in a single concert than all the years CD profits. You could see the CD as a commercial. Give it away for free, print the concert dates on it and make people go to your concert!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way this is already what higher powers are doing for us. On every CD-writable I buy in the Netherlands, I pay a fee to &lt;a href="http://www.bumastemra.nl/en-US/Home.htm">buma-stemra&lt;/a>, because I could &lt;em>potentially&lt;/em> place (illegal) music on that CD. If I payed for it allready, then why not do it anyway? I have less and less problems with copying digital content with all these organisations charging fees and taxes for things I did not buy or am not intending to do. There was even a discussion going on about &lt;a href="http://www.portablegear.nl/nieuws/2/120/2533/Nederlands_belastingvoorstel_draait_MP3_de_nek_om.htm">adding mp3 taxes to harddisks&lt;/a> because you can place music in mp3 form on a harddisk. Is that sick or what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the issue is covered by many others allready, and there are no new insights in this article. So I'll just return to my iTunes library, make a few backups and hope they'll never make playback of my tracks impossible...&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>