<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kawasaki on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/kawasaki/</link><description>Recent content in Kawasaki on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 16:26:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/kawasaki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pully party</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/01/pully-party/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 16:26:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/01/pully-party/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/2587050">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/2587050_8321757241e43e6a43fa7f8a6d8f378e_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Party today! The rotor puller I ordered last month finally arrived after being in transit for over a MONTH, &amp;quot;thank you&amp;quot; United States Parcel Services! They probably sent somebody to swim accros the ocean with my parcel on his back. Judging by the shipping costs, the swimmer had enough food luxury during his trip. I really hope that Pit Posse selects a different shipping company for international orders soon. I took the torch and heated the rotor until water drops put on it boiled, to soften the retainer (lock tight) between the axle and the rotor. Then I re-tightened the rotor puller, smacked it with a hammer, re-tightened it, and so forth. The fifth hit did it, the rotor popped out. As you can see in the first picture, I had a fire extinguisher close by, because oil and fire do not play well together. I also used gloves so I could grab hot metal parts if needed, and I used aluminum plates to protect the magnet from direct heat of the torch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/2587048">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/2587048_6266ede2067c9de1331717266c355588_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Kawasaki KLR wrenching fanatics will notice the missing balancer chain tensioner (or &amp;quot;doohickey&amp;quot;, as they are sometimes called). Don't worry, it's still in one piece, I took it off to straighten it. It was bent and worn by the holding bolt, and I don't want the bolt to sit or crawl to it's former spot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also checked the valve fittings by putting petroleum in the head. They do not seem to be leaking, and show now signs of abnormal wear. Next week I will be checking the old oil for metal splinters, and putting it all together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotten Rotor</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/02/14/rotten-rotor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 20:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/02/14/rotten-rotor/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3581.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3581.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki KL 650 Tengai crankshaft drawing">
&lt;/a>Last week I tried to pull the rotor by using a rotor puller, and a socket (from a socket wrench set) to block it. The socket burried it's way into the first thread of the crankshaft. After realising this, I tried to fit the rotor bolt, and it wouldn't go in. Since only the first thread was damaged, I carefully drilled it out (only needed to go 2 mm deep), and now the rotor bolt fits nicely again.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3574.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3574.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki Rotor bolt made into Rotor puller stub">
&lt;/a>To prevent this from happening again, I ordered a new rotorbolt, and changed the old one to a stub to rest the rotor puller against. You can see the stub on the left. This is needed because the crankshaft is hollow, and the rotor puller has nothing to press against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This evening, I spent another few hours of battering the crankshaft and the rotorpuller, still nothing. No matter what I do, the rotor does not want to let go of the crankshaft. I even tried heating the rotor up until the point I could not touch it with my hands. I protected the magnets from direct heat of the flame with a strip of aluminium, but I didn't want to take the risk to melt the plastic holding them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3580.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3580.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Rotor puller side view">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="r_img_3579.jpg">&lt;img src="r_img_3579.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Rotor puller after failed attemt to pull kawa rotor">
&lt;/a>In the process, my trusty old rotor puller even almost gave up on me, I think it is time for it's retirement. The thread inside the nut is defintely at it's end, and the handle is bent out of shape from the force applied to try to seperate the rotor from the crank. That, and the beating of the hammer on the inside bolt has turned this rotor puller into a paper weight (almost).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to give it another rest, I'm going to a motorbike exposition/dealer show next friday, maybe I can talk to people there about my problem. Sometimes the experienced bike repair shops have simple but effective tips to solve seemingly impossible problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make my evening productive I measured the valve clearances. They are pretty nice, only 1 valves is slightly low on their clearance. This strikes me as funny because usually the clearance increases because of wear. Maybe the original clearance was allready low, or the disassembly and reassembly of the head has changed the clearing because I tightened the bolts a bit harder, I don't know. I am fairly sure I measured the clearances correctly, and at the correct camshaft angles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clearances are:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >
&lt;/td>
left
right
Allowed
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
exhaust
&lt;td >0.15mm (just enough)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.09mm (0.06 too little)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.15~0.25mm
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
inlet
&lt;td >0.12mm (spot on)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.15mm (spot on)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.10~0.20mm
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
So, I probaly need to buy a 0.06mm to 0.1mm thinner shim for the right exhaust valve cam to be on the safe side, but I will re-measure the clearances once the head is on the bike, to see how much the wrenching influences the measurements.</description></item><item><title>195Nm Victory!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/02/07/195nm-victory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 20:46:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/02/07/195nm-victory/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3569.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3569.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki Rotor Holder (from workshop manual)">
&lt;/a>For some strange reason, my brother's Kawasaki KLR Tengai dead-stopped. After starting it again, it made some strange noises. It also had lost a lot of oil somewhere along the way, so we decided to not run it again before we found the cause of the trouble. A few weeks ago we encountered a funny problem, we couldn't loosen the rotor-bolt. In the Kawasaki KLR workshop manual is a picture of a strange wrench to hold the rotor. Ofcourse we're cheap, so we wouldn't spring for a nifty and probably expensive Kawasaki specialty tool for a very old bike which not worth more than the petrol that's in the tank (okay, okay, but you get the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3565.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3565.thumbnail.jpg" alt="32mm wrench, colored from heating">
&lt;/a>The rotor bolt is tightened to 195Nm. That's a lot of force there, so it's not surprising we couldn't loosen it by holding the flywheeel with our hands. So we set out to create a tool of our own. We even ended up trying to bend an old 32mm Chrome-Vanadium wrench, which resulted in an empty gas can, a very hot workbench and nice colors on the wrench, without it bending even the slightest. We we barely able to heat it to the point it got red-hot, because the metal just conducts the heat away from the point you want to heat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3567.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3567.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Holding the piston to loosen the rotor-bolt (overview)">
&lt;/a>So I started mailing with Vincent, a good friend of mine which happens to be &lt;a href="http://www.zodiac.nl/dragrace/index2.htm">&amp;quot;quite handy&amp;quot; with motorbikes&lt;/a> . He pointed out that you could also stop the rotor from turning by holding the piston. Because we wanted to measure the play in the bigend bearing we needed to remove the sleeve anyway, so I immediately went back to the workshop to do this. After removing the sleeve, I could easily make some wood pegs to block the piston. The wood would have to have a big surface and be strong enough to hould the piston, without damaging the piston or the engine casing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3566.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3566.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Holding the piston to loosen the rotor-bolt (detail)">
&lt;/a>It turned out to work great! I needed to attach a long bar to the socket wrench to be able to apply enough force to the bolt, but in the end I got it! In the picture on the left you can see a detail of how the wood blocks are resting on the engine casing. After loosening the bolt, there was absolutely no visible damage to the piston or the engine. Even greater news is that there is also virtually no play on the bigend bearing, so we don't have to disasemble the crank.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3568.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3568.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Wearmarks from applying 195Nm to the bolt">
&lt;/a>When looking at the bolt, the results of applying so much force to the faces of the socket wrench become visible. We know for a fact that this bolt has been removed once before, so these wearmarks are from tightening and loosening the bolt just two times. I think we can tighten it one more time, but after that it needs to be replaced.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>