<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>walkera on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/walkera/</link><description>Recent content in walkera on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 20:31:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/walkera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Weekend of Crashes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/31/a-weekend-of-crashes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 20:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/31/a-weekend-of-crashes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3413035">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3413035_46466e31d22ffce53207f35d201971fb_thumb.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>This weekend was a lot of fun. Saturday night I got to fly Leo's Walkera 60B electric helicopter. That's one piece of impressive (and scary) machinery. Although it feels easier to fly than my 4#3B, I still &amp;quot;managed&amp;quot; to crash it. Luckaly the blades can be easily replaced, and after tightening a bunch of screws and replacing a pin in the main gear, it was good to fly again. We flew 3 times, and had to repair the helicopter after each flight :-) I hope I can treat you with good shots of the Walkera 60B next time, there are not many high-quality images of it online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3413033">&lt;!-- more -->&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3413033_ea62d55e9fd2d7bf2b3876f1780455d0_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>After getting the hang of the big 60B, I got home and did some flying with my little &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/">Walkera 4#3B&lt;/a>. I can now seem to hover it slightly longer than last week, but I still &amp;quot;landed&amp;quot; the thing in the strangest places. Normally there's not much damage, but this time I broke the tail rotor axle. In the pictures, you can also see the crack in the canopy which I simply repaired with a piece of tape. After I repaired the tailrotor, I crashed it again, this time breaking the rear tail altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third crash this weekend was not mine, but &lt;a href="http://paddocktalk.com/news/html/modules/ew_filemanager/08content/motogp/ducati/gb/motogp-fri-stoner-quickest-641.jpg">Kacey Stoner&lt;/a>'s. In the MotoGP race at Misano, Rossi almost high-sided in the first lap, and that little mistake made the gap with Stoner about 3 seconds. As Rossi was trying to gain, Stoner went down in the hairpin in the 8th lap. I sure would have liked to see Rossi and Stoner battle for the win. All in all &lt;a href="http://www.motogp.com/en/news/2008/Rossi+takes+home+victory+and+75+point+advantage+at+Misano">it was a nice race&lt;/a>, won by Valentino Rossi.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>