<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 17:49:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Voor uw eigen veligheid</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/03/27/voor-uw-eigen-veligheid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 17:49:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/03/27/voor-uw-eigen-veligheid/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/man-sitting-on-wheelchair-3036577/">&lt;img src="man-sitting-on-wheelchair-3036577.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinds 21 maart vraagt onze regering ons om binnen te blijven bij verkoudheidsklachten. Sinds 23 maart last onze regering alle bijeenkomsten en evenementen af. Dat de KNVB denkt dat die regel niet voor hen geldt is nog even tot daaraantoe. Toch wordt onze vrijheid niet zodanig beperkt dat we niet naar buiten kunnen, of zelfs tegen het advies in elkaar kunnen bezoeken. Wat ook niet is veranderd is dat we net als de KNVB vinden dat maatregelen vooral over anderen gaan, en niet over onszelf.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>Over anderen beslissen, met alle goede bedoelingen, heeft grote gevolgen. Op 15 maart, een paar dagen voordat de rest van het land wat dwingender werd geadviseerd, ging het verpleeghuis waar mijn moeder verblijft geheel op slot. Dwingend. Niemand erin, niemand eruit. Zo'n zware beslissing wordt natuurlijk met de allerbeste bedoelingen genomen. Maar het voelt toch raar: Oude hulpbehoevende mensen die niet buiten komen, bijna geen sociale contacten hebben, niet in een drukke supermarkt staan te hoesten, niet lekker met elkaar blijven bootcampen tegen alle advies in, juist die mensen sluit je op.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mijn moeder komt, net als veel andere oudere mensen, door allerlei lichamelijke en geestelijke beperkingen bijna niet meer buiten. Diezelfde beperkingen zorgen ervoor dat ze geen iPad, computer of zelfs een simpele telefoon kan bedienen. Tot nu toe was dat geen probleem, mijn vader was er bijna altijd, en haar kinderen bijna iedere dag. We maakten er een gezellige boel van, en zorgden ook voor een beetje leven in de brouwerij bij andere bewoners en de verpleging. De verpleging doet heel erg haar best om iedereen te vermaken, maar de plotselinge isolatie zorgt nu voor een groot contrast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Als je van de ene op de andere dag op je kleine kamertje moet blijven en geen bezoek meer krijgt, en de hele week erna ook niet, en je begrijpt niet goed waarom, en je hebt zelf geen middelen om contact te maken met de buitenwereld, dan wordt je leven heel erg naar. Het is niet voor niets dat eenzame opsluiting als ergste vorm van gevangenisstraf wordt gezien. En dat is wel precies wat we veel mensen aandoen met deze draconische maatregel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bij het nemen van de maatregel is er vanuit gegaan dat levens moeten worden gespaard. En omdat de rest van het volk niet in de hand te houden is, en de zwakkere mensen al wel in dergelijke huizen zitten, lijkt het logisch om die dan maar te isoleren. Voor hun eigen veiligheid. Maar daardoor krijgen de zwakkeren in de samenleving dan misschien geen COVID-19, maar mentaal wel de grootste klap. En die klappen hadden ze daarvoor ook al gehad, ze zitten immers in een situatie waarvan veel gezonde mensen niet in terecht zouden willen komen. Het enige wat ze nog hadden word ze ontnomen, ze kunnen alleen maar hopen dat ze hun kinderen nog eens zien voordat ze overlijden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Niemand heeft mijn moeder gevraagd of ze opgesloten wil worden. Niemand heeft haar gevraagd of ze misschien liever gewoon haar man en kinderen wil zien met het risico eerder te overlijden. Als ze die keuze voorgelegd zou krijgen, weet ik precies waarvoor ze zou kiezen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Het gaat niet om het aantal dagen in je leven.
Het gaat om het leven in je dagen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> Ondanks &amp;quot;veilige opsluiting&amp;quot; werd ze toch ziek. Ze overleed 5 april. Alleen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 2:&lt;/strong> We kwamen erachter dat de kaarten die we stuurden ongeopend bij haar spullen zaten. Ze heeft ze nooit gekregen, nooit gelezen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 3:&lt;/strong> Iedereen is enthausiast over het &amp;quot;spoorboekje&amp;quot; waarin de regering aangeeft hoe we weer op gaan starten. Iedereen is vol van de kapper en de IKEA want oh oh wat hebben we het toch zwaar, maar we lijken vergeten dat we onze ouders eenzaam hebben opgesloten. Op de website van de rijksoverheid &lt;a href="https://www.rijksoverheid.nl/onderwerpen/coronavirus-covid-19/nieuws/2020/05/06/eerste-stap-nieuwe-bezoekregeling-verpleeghuizen">vind ik een artikel&lt;/a> waarin deze vergeten groep genoemd wordt. Zij mogen deze hele maand nog geen bezoek. Ik vind het walgelijk. Dit is hoe we met onze ouders omgaan. Respectloos.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Even geen donor meer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/14/even-geen-donor-meer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 13:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/14/even-geen-donor-meer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.sanquin.nl/donor/bloedverwant/bloedlinks-nummer2/heldenverhaal-joris-welles/">&lt;img src="menselijk-hart-19208136.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&amp;quot;Niertransplantatiefietsen&amp;quot; worden ze onder artsen wel eens genoemd. Tot nu toe had je grote kans dat je de nieren, longen of andere organen van deze gezonde motorrijder had kunnen ontvangen. Zodra ik me mocht registreren heb ik gelijk aangegeven dat ik volledig donor wil zijn. Omdat ik niet geloof in leven na de dood, en wel geloof in het helpen van anderen.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>Er is een groot tekort aan orgaandonoren, of tenminste, aan mensen die niet de moeite nemen om zich te registreren terwijl ze eigenlijk best donor willen zijn. Moeite die ze misschien wel nemen als ze zelf een orgaan nodig zouden hebben. Best raar toch?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pia Dijkstra was het &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vqv6cvi6eR8">met me eens&lt;/a>. Zo kan het niet langer. Ze is in de positie dat ze daar wat aan kan doen en heeft daar hard voor gevochten, en het is haar gelukt. Maar wat mij betreft op een manier die echt niet kan, namelijk: Zonder expliciete toestemming is iedereen orgaandonor. Naast het feit dat niet iedereen zich dat bewust is, denk aan immigranten en mensen die het nieuws niet volgen, worden je nabestaanden op een lastig moment geconfronteerd met het feit dat de regering over je lichaam beslist, of je daar tenminste een lastige vraag over stelt. Ik vind dat een oplossing die een duidelijke grens overschrijdt, en die zelfs in tegenspraak is met &lt;a href="https://www.denederlandsegrondwet.nl/9353000/1/j9vvihlf299q0sr/vgrnblu821m2">artikel 11 van de Nederlandse grondwet&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik vind dat een persoon het fundamentele recht heeft zelf te beslissen over zijn eigen lichaam, tot en met &lt;a href="https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euthanasie#Euthanasie_waarbij_de_dood_al_of_niet_op_verzoek_van_de_betrokkene_wordt_veroorzaakt">euthanasie&lt;/a>, zelfs als daar geen ondragelijk lijden aan ten grondslag ligt, zolang je daarmee anderen niet mee in gevaar brengt. Jouw lichaam, jouw keuze. Natuurlijk willen we liever iedereen gezond zien, maar meten daar eigenlijk altijd met twee maten: De ander moet zich goed en gezond gedragen, maar zelf mogen we wel alcohol drinken, te vet eten, roken, en mijn grootste angst en frustratie als motorrijder: &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2206162-we-vinden-appen-in-het-verkeer-gevaarlijk-maar-doen-het-zelf-ook.html">appen in de auto&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Je eigen keuzes kunnen voor medische problemen zorgen, en natuurlijk is het goed dat er dan altijd hulp geboden wordt &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/YxGgsZMYGCo?t=229">zonder moeilijke vragen&lt;/a>. Onze regering heeft nu geregeld dat we niet alleen medische hulp krijgen, maar ook de organen van mensen &lt;em>die daar misschien nooit mee hebben ingestemd&lt;/em>. En dat is wat mij betreft een stap te ver.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hoe dan wel?&lt;/strong>
In Nederland heb je &lt;a href="https://www.overheid.nl/zo-werkt-de-overheid/hoe-werkt-de-democratie/grondwet/">rechten, maar ook plichten&lt;/a>. De leerplicht is daar een goed voorbeeld van, maar ook maar ook het houden aan verkeersregels, de plicht om belasting te betalen en de plicht om als getuige op te treden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Die plichten worden wel door de overheid opgelegd, maar de belastingdienst haalt bijvoorbeeld niet zomaar geld van je rekening. Je kind wordt niet zomaar door een ambtenaar meegenomen en op een willekeurige school gedropt. Er zit geen agent naast je in de auto als je autorijdt. Dat heeft te onder andere te maken met vrijheid. Er wordt in beginsel van uitgegaan dat je zelf je plichten vervult, dat je de sociale druk voelt om dat te doen, en als het dan toch niet lukt is er een controlerende instantie die je benadert als je niet aan je plichten voldoet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In die setting lijkt mij de enige juiste donorwet een wet waarin het vastleggen van de keuze of je orgaandonor wilt zijn verplicht is. Als we iedere Nederlander kunnen benaderen voor het innen van Belasting, af kunnen dwingen om een WA verzekering af te sluiten bij het registreren van een motorvoertuig, kinderen naar school kunnen sturen, kunnen we ze ook een vraag stellen met een verplicht antwoord. Het zou een zinnetje in je belastingformulier kunnen zijn: &amp;quot;Wilt u dit jaar nog orgaandonor zijn ja/nee?&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="orgaandonatie.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wat mij betreft zou het zelfs nog een stapje verder mogen gaan: Ben je geen orgaandonor? Dan ontvang je ook geen organen van andere donoren mocht je die nodig hebben. Misschien zie ik iets over het hoofd, maar dat lijkt me wel zo consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik heb nooit geworsteld met mijn donorschap. Als ik overlijd zou ik graag zien dat mijn organen gebruikt worden om mensen te helpen. &lt;a href="https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schenking">Maar de betekenins van &amp;quot;donatie&amp;quot; is &amp;quot;gift&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. Als een inbreker bij mij inbreekt doneer ik geen TV aan hem, dan steelt hij die. Dus mevrouw Dijkstra en al de parlementariers die zelf geen donor waren maar wel voor de wet hebben gestemd maken het mij moeilijk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voorlopig heb ik mijn donorschap even ingetrokken. Niet omdat ik geen donor wil zijn, maar als signaal. Omdat ik het hartgrondig oneens ben met de gekozen oplossing die een stap maakt naar een samenleving waar niet jij, maar de regering over je lichaam beschikt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bij gebrek aan het nieuwe belastingformulier moeten we het voorlopig maar even doen met de online donorregistratie. Zorg ervoor dat je je keuze vastlegt. Dat maakt het voor nabestaanden prettiger, en zorgt ervoor dat de regering die beslissing niet voor jou maakt:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.orgaandonorworden.nl/donorregistratie">Besluit zelf, leg je keuze vast&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ashley Madison in perspective</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/08/24/ashley-madison-in-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 20:42:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/08/24/ashley-madison-in-perspective/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrzMhU_4m-g">&lt;img src="lady-justice.gif" alt="lady justice">
&lt;/a>However I disagree with sites like Ashley Madison and the way its owners scam people, last week I have noticed something far more disturbing. As I understand, Ashley Madison was charging people for their profiles to be deleted, and then did not (promptly) delete them. I guess some of it's &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; got caught up in this and decided to attack Ashley Madison for that. Up to this point, merely a quarrel between two parties which may have better been solved by legal procedure.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->But when the "hackers" get hold of the user database of Ashley Madison things become interesting. The "hackers" threaten to release all the data they took from Ashley Madison. A few days later they actually release all the personal data, conveniently cleaned of their own records. Of course the never sleeping internet sleezeballs make it searchable, immediately turning it into a disproportionate problem for a number of people:
&lt;p>&lt;a href="cm0fb3yuyaazsi8.png">&lt;img src="cm0fb3yuyaazsi8.png" alt="CM0Fb3yUYAAZSi8">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/srhbutts">@srhbutts&lt;/a> eloquently responds:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Indiscriminate, bulk release of sensitive, illegally obtained data is not justifiable. Ever. Don't celebrate this.&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What the &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; did is terrorize and &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/aug/24/toronto-suicides-ashley-madison-hack">destroy the lives&lt;/a> of people they've never met, simply because those people did not live up to their ideas and standards. To me, that is exactly what every terrorist organization does. Yes, that one too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even more terrifying is that instead of condemning the &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot;, the media and its brainwashed bloodthirsty audience feeds on the datadump without so much as a thought about what just happened. A large number of people fall in to the confirmation bias trap where they just define anyone which can be remotely linked to that datadump as guilty of moral sins. And still, nobody seems to notice that the data dump conveniently contains no personal data of the &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; themselves. Remember, that's how this all started, didn't it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole thing has turned into a classic &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrzMhU_4m-g">witch hunt&lt;/a>, where a large group of people vilifies random strangers without trial or evidence simply because they find that person's actions strange or unbecoming. Today, it's called &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/7/30/9074865/cecil-lion-palmer-mob-justice">&amp;quot;Mob Justice&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, but it is in essence exactly the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Social) media is not a replacement for a judicial system, for very good reasons. If you think someone committed a crime, talk to the police about it. [Update: Or talk to Ashley Madison if you have info about the &amp;quot;hackers&amp;quot; and &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/08/ashley-madison-offering-500k-reward-info-hackers/">get a $500k reward&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Destroying random people's lives simply because you don't understand or agree with their ways is dumb, medieval and in modern words plain terrorism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hand me a napkin</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/08/16/hand-me-a-napkin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/08/16/hand-me-a-napkin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-duckduckgo-com.jpeg">&lt;img src="images-duckduckgo-com.jpeg?w=150" alt="wheelchair joke">
&lt;/a>It's not until you or someone very close to you becomes dependant on a wheelchair until you notice that the world is not as wheelchair friendly as you might think. Hotel rooms are wheelchair accessable, but the lobby can only be reached by stairs. People with kids can take strollers all the way up to the airplane seat, but people in wheelchairs need to magically heal themselves and leave the wheelchair at the gate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this is not a rant about inconsiderate travel company employees. This is about helping people with &amp;quot;a challenge&amp;quot;, as our funny American neighbours tend to call it. And no, this is also not a rant about helping in a big way, raising a million for a cause, getting all the local supermarkets to give away groceries to people in wheelchairs, or TV shows selling tear-jerking advertisement minutes while building a house for a familiy who really needs it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, this is about the little things. Things that make you and me different. Things that require only a little twitch of a muscle for healthy people. Quirky things like aligning the napkin to the edge of the table, or petting a cat, or getting a different color straw because it doesn't match the color of your shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine you had to ask somebody to align your napkin to the edge of the table. That person would find you demanding, and because he doesn't see what's solved by doing that, it's very likely that the napkin will never move. Soon, you will stop asking people to do the little things that used to make you who you were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's a tough choice. Loose friends because they think you're too much of a demanding prinsess, or loose friends because you stop being you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you see or know somebody in a wheelchair, remember that their mind still wants to do those quirky things that make them who they are. It's okay to say no, but please consider this little blogpost when somebody asks you to straighten their bracelet or clean their glasses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world does not need one-time big-mouthed Facebook-selfie heroes. The world needs polite people who can discretely hand over a napkin without asking what's it for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replace Evernote with Spidernote</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/02/replace-evernote-with-spidernote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/02/replace-evernote-with-spidernote/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/07/28/AR2010072806141.html">&lt;img src="evernotensa.png" alt="Resistance is futile">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past I have used Evernote extensively, it really helped me in my research for this blog and keeping track of meeting notes, todo lists and even making pictures of whiteboards at work searchable. As a product, there is no note taking app that can beat Evernote. But there is a little problem that has become a deal breaker for me, and that is basically the NSA and the way Americans, and particularly the American government seems to think about people's privacy and online security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evernote is an American company, which sadly has to comply with whatever ridiculous request by the U.S. government to turn over data of innocent people all over the world (yes, even outside the U.S. border, I know, it’s amazing). This, combined with the fact that Evernote clearly can not use zero-knowledge encryption because of the services it provides, makes that all the data you and I put into Evernote are at NSA’s fingertips at all times. If you find that as scary as I do, and you have a Mac, there is a way to solve this.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you use Evernote to sync notes between multiple Macs, you have to solve the syncing problem first. Ofcourse Dropbox is a no-go, because that is an American company storing unencrypted data too. I’m &lt;a href="https://rolfje.wordpress.com/2011/07/03/1355/">using SpiderOak  since 2011&lt;/a>, and it is much better than Dropbox in many ways. Check it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re using Evernote on your iPhone I do not have a solution for you yet. But as for me, that is not a big deal, I thought the iPhone is not the ideal note taking platform anyway as this old man is not very fast on the touch keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="spidy_5407spx_02.jpg">&lt;img src="spidy_5407spx_02.jpg" alt="Spidernote Icon">
&lt;/a>With all that out of the way, let’s migrate away from Evernote and replace it with a smart script and some synced Spideroak folders. I like to call it ”SpiderNote”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Create a folder structure&lt;/strong>
Inside your Spideroak shared folder or Hive, create a ”Spidernote” folder, and in that folder, create a ”notes” folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2: Export all Evernote Notes&lt;/strong>
Start up your trusty Evernote client and select all your notes. From the ”File” menu, select ”Export Notes…” and store them in a folder called ”Evernote”, inside the ”notes” folder you just created. You should now have a folder called Spidernote/notes/Evernote somewhere inside your Spideroak folder, or somewhere locally on your Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3: Getting Spotlight and Finder to work for you&lt;/strong>
Open the Finder and press Cmd-, or select ”Preferences…” On the ”Advanced” tab, under ”When performing a Search” select ”Search the current Folder”. After you do this, you will find that when you open the notes folder in Finder, you can type some text and your old Evernote notes will popup. Look ma, no hands! And no Evernote!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="finder-search-settings.png">&lt;img src="finder-search-settings.png?w=450" alt="Finder Search Settings">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4: Create a new template note&lt;/strong>
OSX comes with a decent richtext editor, named ”TextEdit” which we are going to use for our note taking.Open TextEdit and save an empty file inside the notes folder which is called ”empty.rtf”. This will be your note template, the start of every new note. Remember you can set preferences that are stored with this file, like the default font and colors and tabs if you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5: Script to create a new note&lt;/strong>
Create a file called ”newnote.command” in the Spidernote folder and copy/paste the following contents into it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;bash&amp;quot;]
#!/bin/bash
date=&lt;code>date +%Y%m%d-%H%M%S&lt;/code>
BASEDIR=$(dirname $0)
cd $BASEDIR&lt;/p>
&lt;p>notesdirectory=&amp;quot;notes/${date}&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>clear
echo &amp;quot;Note will be stored in ${BASEDIR}/${notesdirectory}.&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Type title/filename for note (without extension):&amp;quot;
read filename&lt;/p>
&lt;p>if [[ X&amp;quot;&amp;quot; = X&amp;quot;$filename&amp;quot; ]]; then
filename=&amp;quot;note.rtf&amp;quot;;
fi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>mkdir &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}&amp;quot;
cp notes/empty.rtf &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot;
rm -f lastnote.rtf
ln -s &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot; latestnote.rtf
open -a TextEdit &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot;
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should now have a folder structure which looks something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="folder-structure-1.png">&lt;img src="folder-structure-1.png" alt="Spidernote Folder Structure">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6: Add Spidernote to your Dock&lt;/strong>
Drag the Spidernote folder next to your Trashcan in the doc (not IN your Trashcan, of course). Change the settings to have it’s icon show as a folder, and it’s context as a list. All set!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7: Create your first note&lt;/strong>
From the Dock, click on the Spidernote folder and click on ”newnote.command”. A Terminal window will pop up, asking you for the (optional) title of your note (this will be the filename of the *.rtf file, so that it is easier to scan your search results later). After you press ”enter”, TextEdit will come up and you can type away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are done and close the editor, you can easily find your note by searching, or by the ”latest note” link which the script creates for you in the Spidernote folder, so that you always can return to what you were doing when you accidentally close that note.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s it for now. I know it does not OCR scan your images, and it is really a poor-man’s Evernote, but these days your private has become a valuable asset to scrupules people and it has to be protected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that there are a lot of note taking apps out there but frankly none of them work for me. If you have any tips on how to solve the OCR and tagging/organizing stuff please let me know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh and don't forget to &lt;a href="https://evernote.com/contact/support/kb/#!/article/23403793">deactivate your Evernote account and remove all its data&lt;/a>. After all, that's what started all this sad stuff.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iOS7 hidden features</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/09/28/ios7-hidden-features/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 21:03:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/09/28/ios7-hidden-features/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QS4xIrTYDWU">&lt;img src="ios-7-logo.png" alt="ios-7-logo">
&lt;/a>If you've just installed iOS7 and like it as much as I do, you are probably interested in all the new features of it, and where to find them. On behalf of Apple, I'll be happy to point out where all those neat new features are, and share my happiness about this wonderful new magical market-leading mobile OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**Easy-Steal (tm)**
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="easy-steal-e284a2.png">&lt;img src="easy-steal-e284a2.png?w=113" alt="Easy-Steal (™)">
&lt;/a>**Remember how in iOS6, you can not just steal an iphone because of the &amp;quot;find my iPhone&amp;quot; feature? Thieves had to put your iPhone in a metal container so it could not tell the owner where it is. Because thieves are people too, we now introduced &amp;quot;Easy-Steal (tm)&amp;quot;. When a thief wants to steal your phone, all he has to do is swipe up, press the little airplane button, and nobody will hear from your iPhone again. Want to disable that? Easy. Hand over your flashlight, calculator, timer, and iPod controls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Separate is the new Integrate&lt;/strong>
Remember how we beautifully integrated FaceTime with the Phone app? How Podcasts could be played from within iTunes? Well we think that's not the future. So we created a separate FaceTime app, and a separate Podcasts app. So you can have more icons on more screens, making it harder to find stuff. We'll let you in on a little secret. Our next big thing? A Separate device for each function. It will be great! You can just take the device you need and leave all the other ones charging on your desk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New sounds. And Old Classic ones.&lt;/strong>
Remember how software developers always say you should not use terms as &amp;quot;Old&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;New&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Classic&amp;quot; in your software because putting a &amp;quot;New&amp;quot; sticker on a banana will not prevent it from going stale? Well we're not so sure about that. So now, in the old (sorry, new) sound settings, you will find all the same behavior of the old settings, but with new sounds. We've even changed all the sounds your phone makes right from the upgrade. If you would like to revert to the old sounds, don't bother searching in the sounds list. Scroll through the &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; list. You know, because on the first screen, there is a list of sounds, and in the second list, there will be... err... a list of sounds. But old. Get it? Did we say it was completely new? We lied. Sorry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Camouflage&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="icon-rainbow.png">&lt;img src="icon-rainbow.png" alt="icon rainbow">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All icons are now devoid of those pesky shading and lining that made them visible on all backgrounds. So now, no matter what background color you use, there will always be at least one icon which will blend into the background. We even removed the shading on the text, so you can make that disappear with a simple white background. And did you notice the gradients? Some are light-to-dark, and some are dark-to-light. Why? Because at the new Apple, we hate consistency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Square.&lt;/strong>
A new picture mode. Because you want to make photos. videos, and... err... squares?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Look-at-Me (tm)&lt;/strong>
To make the phone look faster, we made the icons zoom and pan to show how the operating systems moves to help you complete your tasks. It was tested on 500 Dwarf Hamsters and we are pretty sure we made a good job of making people look at your screen while you're using your phone. At least half of those people will get &lt;a href="http://www.tech-recipes.com/rx/44165/how-do-i-prevent-motion-sickness-when-using-ios-7/">motion sickness within 15 seconds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Applications&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="new-apps.png">&lt;img src="new-apps.png" alt="New Apps">
&lt;/a>
The seasoned iOS6 user will have immediately spotted it: We've got new Applications! Get more accurate timing in your iPhone with the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tourbillon">Tourbillon&lt;/a> app. Make your own weather predictions with the Barometer app, and create stunning graphics with the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandelbrot_set">Mandelbrot&lt;/a> app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>New Puzzles&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_&lt;a href="clickable-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="clickable-puzzle.png?w=450" alt="Clickable Puzzle">
&lt;/a>_&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can now have hours of fun trying to figure out what is tappable or slidable. Is it the text? Is it the color? Is it the icons? Who knows? We've put great care in removing all visual clues, so start taping and sliding!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update process has also become more fun. Because we love our non-US iPhone users, we've made the &amp;quot;Purchased&amp;quot; icon a letter &amp;quot;P&amp;quot;. Level up! The dark arrow pointing down ads to the fun when you tap it and... it slides to the left, which reveals your purchases to the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="updates-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="updates-puzzle.png" alt="Updates Puzzle">
&lt;/a>And did we say one update? We'll list all the past updates too, so you can have more useless info on the screen. For good measure, we even added fun blue dots next to the updated apps you did not open already. How useful is that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="installing.png">&lt;img src="installing.png" alt="Installing..">
&lt;/a>Progress indicators are now even more fun. During updates, your app is named &amp;quot;Installing...&amp;quot; Can you guess what this icon is? If you guessed the application was updating, can you tell if it is at 25% or 75%?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the real advanced puzzlers, we've hidden some controls. Can you make the &amp;quot;Today&amp;quot; widget just display your calendar item without-arbitrary-text-around-it-which-makes-your-content-harder-to-view-at-a-glance? Can you slide your &amp;quot;Stock Options&amp;quot; widget below the &amp;quot;Tomorrow&amp;quot; widget?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="message-center-puzzle.png">&lt;img src="message-center-puzzle.png?w=169" alt="Message Center Puzzle">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A new lock screen&lt;/strong>
People like lock screens. So they can put functions on them for which you don't have to unlock. Smart, right? Now, people can start playing with your phone without unlocking it, weather you like it or not. Because there is no option to disable that. To make everything easier, we've put more icons on the lock screen, making gestures more finicky. Because we know what &lt;del>Android&lt;/del> iPhone users like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="lockscreens.png">&lt;img src="lockscreens.png?w=450" alt="LockScreens">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And 6789 more features&lt;/strong>
There is much more to discover. The camera app is on 2 locations in the home screen. The message center is as confusing and inconsistent as ever. The new &amp;quot;dots&amp;quot; signal strength indicator, the network operator name, the wifi icon and the new &amp;quot;gprs&amp;quot; icon are now even wider, so they'll never fit the top bar. Sliders switches look bulkier, slide less, but they do change colors as if they were a bulb. You decide what it's supposed to be, let your imagination run wild! A white dot? Is it a slider or just a dot? Who needs aluminum, Try it out!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you'll excuse us, we're going to sue Sony because they made their Xperia look like our market-leading mobile OS. See?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ios7-because-when-you-paid-for-an-iphone-we-know-you-actually-wanted-android">&lt;strong>iOS7. Because when you paid for an iPhone, we know you actually wanted Android.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>P.S.&lt;/strong> Jony, I'm not sure how much you're involved in the UI design, but if you need help, or a better sparring partner, or I need to come rescue you from the bozos that made you do this, the iPhone 5Cheap with it's non-right-angle old-school injection molded back and the gold iPhone, let me know. You're better than this, and maybe we can still fix things. You know how to contact me. Hang in there buddy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How big is 5 Zettabyte?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.spyvsspyhq.com/images.html">&lt;img src="3050431703_spyblack_answer_2_xlarge.jpeg" alt="Spy vs Spy">
&lt;/a>Since the interview of &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/jun/09/nsa-whistleblower-edward-snowden-interview-video">Edward Snowden with the Guardian&lt;/a>, the discussion about privacy and companies storing and sharing unencrypted private data is picking up. Particularly Americans are worried about what it does for their National security and their private data. But that's actually a naive thought, given the NSA stores worldwide data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">recent coverage on theblaze.com&lt;/a> (a rather tabloid-looking news station in the U.S.), the interviewers are shocked to see that the NSA spies on &amp;quot;every American&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a limited view of the world and failing to see the importance of spying on people &lt;em>outside&lt;/em> the U.S., but lets start with technical side of things first. What data are they storing and how big is their hard-disk?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->As you may know, the internet is a [packet switching network](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing). Although people try to mess with the routing and sometimes even [disconnect whole countries](http://www.bgpmon.net/syria-shuts-down-the-internet/), it is hard to make a packet travel a certain route or prevent it from traveling through a certain country. Much of the internet traffic passes through the U.S. regardless of it's source and destination. But even if it didn't, the NSA has that covered. Many companies, Like Facebook, [Google](http://highscalability.com/google-architecture) has [servers all over the world](http://serverfault.com/questions/370385/location-of-google-servers). Since Google and Facebook are companies registered in the U.S. the [NSA could technically indirectly tap into](http://www.breitbart.com/Big-Government/2013/06/09/NSA-Obtains-Data-From-50-Companies) one of their servers in a foreign country which contains data which never travelled through the US in the first place.
&lt;p>According to the &lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/stats.htm">worldwide distribution of internet users&lt;/a>, if the NSA wanted to store data just about Americans, they could have built a much smaller, simpler facility. But they didn't, which make you think. So how big is this facility exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://img.pr0gramm.com/2009/04/funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg">&lt;img src="funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg" alt="Holy Crepe">
&lt;/a>5 Zettabyte**
If you've watched the &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">coverage&lt;/a>, you'll hear James Bamford say that the facility that the NSA is building can hold enough physical machines to store around 5 Zettabyte of data, given current technology standards. It sounds like a lot, but how big is a Zettabyte really?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettabyte">wikipedia&lt;/a>, 5 Zettabyte is 5,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 bytes. If, like me, you can not get your head around a number with 21 zeroes in it, I'll give you some of the calculations I made to understand just how big this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with the Internet Archive. Currently, the Internet Archive and it's &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/59207751">Wayback machine holds 10 Petabytes&lt;/a> of data (10,000,000,000,000,000 bytes). The servers at the Internet Archive crawl the Internet and store all public data they can find in a searchable manner. They provide the public with that data, so you can do cool things like &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.rolfje.com">see how my blog looked 10 years ago&lt;/a>. The Internet Archive is pretty big you might think. With 5ZB, the NSA could store the complete Internet Archive &lt;em>500,000 times&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to world population&lt;/strong>
Ok so maybe the size of the internet, or the size of a Petabyte are not very imaginable. Let's take it to the individual level. At the time of this writing, there are &lt;a href="http://www.worldometers.info">roughly 7.124.855.134 people on the world&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the NSA would wanted to store information on every person in the world, regardless if they were a president or a newborn African child, they would have 701,768,654,374 bytes per person to do so:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperperson.png" alt="5ZB per person">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, they can store 701GB for each person in the world. My personal email archive is around 5GB right now, and I have a 1TB hard-disk containing every (digital or digitized) photo I have ever made. If I would be the standard (which I am probably not), the NSA could very easily store everybody's personal data, worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to the people connected to the internet&lt;/strong>
Not everybody is connected to the internet (in fact that's not entirely true but we'll come to that later). As you have probably already seen on the &lt;a href="http://worldmeters.info">worldmeters.info&lt;/a> site, there are roughly 2,552,435,328 active internet users (at the time of writing). So let's see what the NSA can store if they &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; target the internet users:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperuser.png" alt="5ZB per Internet User">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah that's better. Almost &lt;strong>2TB per Internet user&lt;/strong>. The NSA can now not only store my private data, photo's and videos, but now there is room to spare so I can put a couple of blockbuster movies in there, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the NSA probably does some smart data reduction, like storing an email I send to you just once instead of a copy for each of us, I'm guessing the practical space per user will be more like 4TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YozC8yFrZKI">&lt;img src="p.png" alt="Homer">
&lt;/a>Am I connected to the internet?**
In short: Yes. We are all connected in some way to the internet. Particularly if you are living in a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_world">&amp;quot;Western Country&amp;quot;&lt;/a> you can be sure that in some way you, or at least data about your existance, is online somewhere. Cities store data about their inhabitants and share them with other departments and services to do their work. By default, this data travels accross the internet and we all know how good governements are at protecting and encrypting their data, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's do an interesting thought experiment to see how far this goes. Suppose I have never connected to the internet, and neither have you. I own an old &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota_Corolla_(E70)">Toyota Corolla E70&lt;/a> and you and I stayed with our trusty &lt;a href="http://nokiamuseum.info/nokia-p-30/">Nokia P-30&lt;/a>'s. Now let's say I lend you my car. The NSA would know about that, instantly. How? My car is registered to me. The roads are covered with cameras to detect traffic violations, but in fact, the most governments like to store data about which car is going where. Our cellphones are connected to cell towers, which reveals &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_phone_tracking">pretty accurate data&lt;/a> about where they are. So the NSA can map the time and place of my car to the time and place of my cell phone and all cell phones I've called. They would quickly and easily discover that my car is moving with your cellphone in it. The fact that their data shows that my cellphone is at home means that you are probably driving my car. Based on our cellphone data, it would even be pretty easy to see our daily commutes, see where you and I work and when and where we met in person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conspiracy? &lt;em>Maybe.&lt;/em> Possibility? &lt;em>Yes.&lt;/em> Privacy breach? &lt;em>Absolutely.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different countries have different meanings of the word &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy">&amp;quot;Privacy&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. By definition, gathering of data which is considered to be private (secret or confidential) in the country of origin, is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espionage">Espionage&lt;/a>. This is not surprising, as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_War">old habbits die hard&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I don't care, I have nothing to hide.&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5VAgSdGnSQ">&lt;img src="gollum.jpg" alt="Gollum has something to hide">
&lt;/a>Not so fast grasshopper. You do. In fact, the NSA just introduced the very need to keep your data private and store it locally, indefinitely. In the example above, suppose you used my car to take pictures as a hobby photographer of a crime scene that was in the news. With the data they gathered, the NSA could frame either you or me at that scene, at their peril. Because you and I have no access to the data they are storing about us, it will be very hard for you or me to prove that we weren't, because the NSA will not provide you or the court with data that will prove otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for mail and other communications. Tabloid journalists can explain how to use one email, or once sentence from an email out of context to start a nasty gossip. The NSA could do that too. Suppose you are sharing role-playing stories with a friend over email. Those emails could suddenly look very interesting when placed out of context. Don't think they will not do that. &lt;a href="http://www.whereisthemoney.org/1.1trillion.htm">Power corrupts.&lt;/a> They will, and very likely already have done so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_Make_Me_Think">Don't make me think&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
I've always said that the failure to make stuff user friendly is the single most important reason for brilliant ideas to &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/06/14/nsa-proof-encryption-exists-why-doesnt-anyone-use-it/">fail miserably&lt;/a>. In the light of current events and the power of modern computers, can we at least try to make strong encryption like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy">PGP&lt;/a> stupid-easy to use, and add &amp;quot;coolness&amp;quot; so people will &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to use it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Because much like openness, responsibility and privacy is now more important than ever.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Related material I found while writing this blog post:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la Prison](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discipline_and_Punish) is a 1975 book by the French philosopher Michel Foucault. If he was still alive, Foucault would probably see that after a period of individualism and consumer-centric change, the NSA is the re-introduction the [Panopticon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panopticon), a prison (or society) where the prisoners can not see the guards.
* This Dutch program [&amp;quot;Dare to Think&amp;quot;](http://www.uitzendinggemist.nl/afleveringen/1304898) discusses how Foucault thought, and places it in the modern time. It discusses how modern individualism and a market driven society needs new mechanisms to steer the individual. The theory is in essence that people need to learn to steer themselves and check the self-set boundaries with others from time to time.
* In the source of Windows NT 4 Service Pack 5 a [variable with the name _NSAKEY](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NSAKEY) was discovered which led to speculation that Windows computers could leak private data to the NSA.
* Because few people do, When you decide to use PGP to encrypt your mail, you are likely to gain some attention, particularly from American &amp;quot;authorities&amp;quot;. Because you stand out. If you decide to stand out and encrypt stuff, you better do it right. Gather some information about [Uncrackable Email](http://www.ncmilitia.org/spycounterspy/fs006.html) (yes it's possible). Please note that all your encrypted mails will be stored, so when somebody does find reason to detain you and get your passphrase, deleting your drive will be useless.
* Estimations in the linked articles say that the NSA facility cost $2B to build, has it's own 65MW power station, 60,000 tons of cooling equipment, and an electricity bill of $40M per year (unclear if that includes running their own power station). If you looked closely at the WorldMeters link, you could have noticed that there are almost 4 million Cancer related deaths per year and 35 million HIV related deaths, versus [less than 8,000 terrorism related deaths in 2010](http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/09/global-terrorism-deaths). If the NSA is here to pretect us from dying, they'd better use their budget and intelligence to start investigating other stuff.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Open letter to Keith Lang about Skitch</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/01/03/open-letter-to-keith-lang-about-skitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 22:33:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/01/03/open-letter-to-keith-lang-about-skitch/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://evernote.com/download/get.php?file=SkitchMac_v1">&lt;img src="skitch_logo_lockup_blog.jpg" alt="Skitch 1.0.2">
&lt;/a>Dear Keith,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read &lt;a href="http://blog.evernote.com/blog/2012/11/21/skitch-and-evernote-a-letter-from-keith-lang/">your letter&lt;/a> about Skitch and would like to respond to all that has happened from my end-user perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a long-time Evernote user and fan. Evernote changed note taking by being truly searchable. I can confidently drop all the websites, receipts, todos and ideas in there, and clear my mind of the &amp;quot;I must remember that&amp;quot; burden. The OCR of Evernote works beautifully on photos of whiteboards, making even my whiteboard notes searchable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2010, I discovered Skitch. The simplicity and razor sharp focus on anotating a screencapture and share the anotated image by dragging it anywhere was sheer brilliance. My daily work includes making annotated screenhots and mailing them to team members to discuss improvements. Skitch changed this ugly capture-save-edit-save-attach-send cycle to pure poetry in motion. Dragging images into Evernote even made my screenshots searchable. It instantly became second nature and my go-to image tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->As a software developer, I know that software is rarely "finished". There is always that little bug to fix, that missing functionality to add, or some ugly code to refactor. But Skitch was different. It was perfect as it was. It integrated beautifully with everything in my Mac, including Evernote. Not tightly coupled to anything, yet integrated with everything. As a fellow software developer surely you must recognize the poetry in perfect decoupling like this.
&lt;p>When rumors reached me about Skitch being integrated into Evernote I was very worried. Why integrate Skitch into something? It already integrated beautifully with everything on my Mac. Why tie it to some product? I guess the answer is money. Evernote buying Skitch must have been a financially interesting, but I fully expected Skitch to degrade because of that deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first release of Skitch in the Mac App store confirmed all my fears. Skitch 2.0 was so utterly broken, so alien to all users who used or saw Skitch 1.0 on my machine, so crippled, so devoid of it's original focus. Skitch 2.0 left me and some of my colleagues very dissapointed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, my trusty Time Machine backup had the old version of Skitch and I quickly distributed it to all the poor users who installed Skitch from the Mac App store. But the damage was already done. Frustrated users, underground distribution of the old version of Skitch to a lucky few. To this day I have not figured out what the &amp;quot;advantage&amp;quot; of the &amp;quot;integration&amp;quot; with Evernote is. All blogs and open letters from Evernote and the Skitch team make excuses, link to the old Skitch 1.0.2, talk about how Skitch 2.0 is not Skitch 1.0, but fail to explain what the true advantage is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To me, &lt;a href="http://evernote.com/download/get.php?file=SkitchMac_v1">Skitch 1.0.2&lt;/a> is the version of Skitch that truly integrates with Evernote and every other application in a simple, consistent and easy to understand way. It made sharing easy and understandable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sellout to Evernote was the death of Skitch. Sure, some features were added back into Skitch 2.0.2, but only to make Skitch 2 into a cheap knockoff of the once great Skitch 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that Evernote has bought Skitch, sales people will want to integrate it into Evernote even more tightly, migrate it to all platforms, thereby losing some of the tight integration with the OS that made Skitch so wonderful and effortless. Even with all the Skitch 1.0 fans behind you, you will have to fight a board of directors who never used Skitch and want to change it without truly understanding why people loved the old Skitch. The gold handcuffs in your deal with Evernote will prevent you from restoring Skitch to what it was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can only hope that somebody, somewhere realizes how brutally Skitch was butchered by people who clearly did not see the beauty and simplicity of Skitch's userinterface. I can only hope that this person has the skill, means or pure balls to bring the old Skitch back and release it to the Mac App store, maybe under a different name. Just the &lt;a href="http://evernote.com/download/get.php?file=SkitchMac_v1">Skitch 1.0.2&lt;/a>, as is. Screen capture, resize or crop, annotate, your history on the flip-side, and sharing/saving by dragging. Nothing more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, I have Skitch 1.0.2 backed up in every location I can possibly think of. It is an invaluable addition to my daily workflow, and I dread the day Skitch 1.0.2 will no longer work with a new version of OSX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On behalf of all Skitch users out there, thanks for creating the truly amazing, one and only &lt;a href="http://evernote.com/download/get.php?file=SkitchMac_v1">Skitch 1.0.2&lt;/a>. Come over and talk to us. Bring your 1.0.2 sources. We have cookies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you should not use SOAP Headers</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/12/24/why-you-should-not-use-soap-headers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 18:52:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/12/24/why-you-should-not-use-soap-headers/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="container1.png" alt="container">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the project I am working on right now we use apache XCF and Spring to provide a SOAP service to our customers. As part of the messages, there is a userid/password combo telling the application which user sent the request. I struggled with that today because I think that userid/password info should actually be in the SOAP Header, cleaning up my API, enable me to implement different authentication techniques in the future and generally be more &amp;quot;compliant&amp;quot; to the SOAP standard. Boy was I wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->First I needed to figure out how to get the userid/password info into the Header. Apache has [some information](https://cxf.apache.org/docs/ws-security.html) on this which is supposed to be "very good" according to the web but I had quite a bit of trouble because it misses quite a bit of context.
&lt;p>At first, it took me ages to find out that I need to add this to my maven pom.xml file to actually &amp;quot;get&amp;quot; the security stuff onto my classpath:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode type=&amp;quot;xml&amp;quot; gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
&lt;dependency>
&lt;groupId>org.apache.cxf&lt;/groupId>
&lt;artifactId>cxf-rt-ws-security&lt;/artifactId>
&lt;version>2.5.1&lt;/version>
&lt;/dependency>
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could find NO tutorial online telling me this, so I guess I saved you a good 20 minutes of searching right there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I needed to change the Spring configuration to &lt;a href="http://www.benmccann.com/dev-blog/apache-cxf-tutorial-ws-security-with-spring/">include the mysterious &amp;quot;WSS4JInInterceptor&amp;quot;&lt;/a> of which nobody understands what it does because it is an overdesigned elephant which implements obscure standards nobody seems to be using:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode type=&amp;quot;xml&amp;quot; gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
&amp;lt;jaxws:endpoint id=&amp;quot;myCoolSOAPService&amp;quot; implementor=&amp;quot;#myCoolService&amp;quot; address=&amp;quot;/mycoolservice&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;a href="jaxws:inInterceptors">jaxws:inInterceptors&lt;/a>
&lt;ref bean="wss4jinterceptor"/>
&amp;lt;/jaxws:inInterceptors&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/jaxws:endpoint&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;bean id="wss4jinterceptor" class="org.apache.cxf.ws.security.wss4j.WSS4JInInterceptor">
&lt;constructor-arg>
&lt;map>
&lt;entry key="action" value="UsernameToken" />
&lt;entry key="passwordType" value="PasswordDigest" />
&lt;entry key="passwordCallbackRef">
&lt;ref bean="myPasswordCallback" />
&lt;/entry>
&lt;/map>
&lt;/constructor-arg>
&lt;/bean>
[/sourcecode]
&lt;p>As you can see, the WSS4JInterceptor is configured to accept Usernames and passwords (albeit in deeply, convoluted nested elements adding humongous amounts of XML bloat to your Header).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be able to take the userid/password combo I dutifully started writing my password handler:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode type=&amp;quot;java&amp;quot; gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
public class UseridPasswordCallback implements CallbackHandler {&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> @Override
public void handle(Callback[] arg0)
throws IOException, UnsupportedCallbackException {
// Not implemented yet
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>}
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see that my handle(Callback) method is not implemented. And there is a good reason for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just before implementing all the code, I checked the wiring of all this stuff. The application started up beautifully, and I pointed SOAPUI to the WSDL to generate some example requests. To my horror, SOAPUI did not generate example headers. For some reason, the whole CXF stack just &amp;quot;forgets&amp;quot; to put that info in the WSDL, or maybe the specs don't leave room to have that information in the WSDL, I don't know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I set out to see how to build that Soap Security header. It was nuts. Not only did I need to figure this out from crude and incomplete examples, reverse engineer xsd's, and hand-craft it into the SOAPUI messages, I also had to deal with the awful error messages that gave me &amp;quot;Could not read XMReader&amp;quot; and the very helpful &amp;quot;ns1:InvalidSecurity&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After an afternoon of absolute madness on something that should actually be infinitesimally simple, I gave up. I added the userid/password back into the functional calls (as part of my method signatures). And for a couple of very good reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. The first an most important one: If I as a developer have this much trouble wading to the poorly documented, underutilized, astrophysics-level complexity just to add a freakin' userid/password field to a SOAP message, how can I expect my users to ever accomplish this without rage-calling our helpline every 4 seconds?
2. By making the fields part of the API, they become part of the WSDL, which immediately makes it clear what to add and where. SOAPUI even generates nice placeholders for it.
3. I added an Aspect with an around advice intercepting the userid/password combo, use it to authenticate the user and immediately remove the password from memory. Simple, readable, effective and easily debuggable for any developer on the project.
4. The pom.xml and the Spring configuration immediately become much simpler and gets rid of a few idiot acronyms in the process.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>So there. Want to do SOAP Security as it was intended? Do yourself and your customers a favor: Don't.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortgage Awareness</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/04/01/mortgage-awareness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 16:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/04/01/mortgage-awareness/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This weekend I tinkered around with Apple Keynote. I thought I'd make something useful. In this video I'm trying to show you how much money the bank makes on your mortgage. Banks like you to pay a low monthly fee on your mortgage because it keeps the loan higher for a longer period of time. This way the bank can cash in on the interest rate, and then cash in again at the end of the mortgage contract, when you are still hopelessly in debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;video width=100% controls autoplay>
&lt;source src="Mortgage Awareness with audio.m4v" type="video/mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Financial advisors&amp;quot; working for the bank will throw sand in your eyes, saying that keeping your debt high gives you all kinds of tax breaks. But in the end, it's them who get better of that construction, not you. Don't fall into this trap. Understand your mortgage contract, learn how the model works, and check your model against the bank's model (without that financial advisor or the lady at the helpdesk talking to you). You have more room than you think. Use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join, don't judge</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 22:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</guid><description>
&lt;figure class="float_right">&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ef91za0liTM">&lt;img src="beautiful-restaurant-websites-550x3221.jpeg" width="150"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Like many people, I like to dine in a good restaurant, where the mood is mellow, the waiter is a fine host, and the cook is passionate about good food and nice presentation. The courses are perfectly timed with your appetite, and each shiny polished plate of food contains the best looking, smelling and tasting food with the nicest textures. After desert, you get the best fresh mineral water coffee, and just sit there, satisfied, happy, in good company. The waiter discretely places the check on the table, and you happily pay whatever that check tells you to pay, and add a big tip for good measure, to show you had a great evening.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The next morning, you check your bank account and discover there is not much left. Yesterdays meal cost you a bit more than you anticipated. But the memory puts a smile on your face, and you just decide that it's worth it.
&lt;p>At work you tell a colleague about your great meal in the perfect restaurant. He smiles and listens, and asks directions to this perfect restaurant. He drives to the restaurant, looks at the menu and writes down what you had. Then he goes to the supermarket and buys the ingredients for the perfect meal you had. He goes home, and tries is best to cook everything to perfection in his small 1 bedroom apartment while constantly chasing the cat from the kitchen sink. He removes yesterday's dishes from the kitchen table, lights a candle and eats the food. After he finishes his desert he has his Senseo coffee and enjoys the sound of the dryer beeping that it's finished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next morning, he comes in and tells you that you've been screwed. He goes on and on about how he had exactly the same meal, and maybe even more, for about 1/10th the price you payed at the restaurant. Where you had to listen to pre-selected restaurant music, he could choose his own. Where you had to wait for the waiter to bring your courses, he could just pick them from the kitchen sink at will. His meal was so much better than yours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, each time somebody asks about your wonderful dinner, he butts in to say that that restaurant is a ripoff, and how you can have a much better experience with more choice, more freedom, at only 1/10th of the cost. As soon as anybody so much as mentions this restaurant, he starts is rant all over again about how people should not go to that place. What could have been a wonderful exchange of culinary experiences turns into a holy war, where people think they should &amp;quot;win&amp;quot; a discussion, ruining it for everybody,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, in the real world there are very few people so fanatic, going to great lengths to ruin that moment in a conversation where you can tell about the great restaurant you found. Or are there?
&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >&lt;img src="macbookpro_15inch_pfop_matte_screen.jpeg">&lt;/td>
&lt;td >&lt;img src="screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-13-10-021.png">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td>
&lt;b>Macbook Pro 15"&lt;/b>&lt;br/>
2GHz Intel Core i7&lt;br/>
4GB 1333MHz DDR3&lt;br/>
AMD Radeon HD 6490M 256 MB&lt;br/>
250GB SSD OCZ Vertex 3&lt;br/>
Dual layer DVD writer&lt;br/>
Wifi&lt;br/>
1GB Ethernet&lt;br/>
Webcam&lt;br/>
Bluetooth&lt;br/>
SD Cardreader&lt;br/>
USB 2.0, Firewire 800&lt;br/>
&lt;b>€2499,-&lt;/b>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:right;" >
&lt;b>Dell XPS 15&lt;/b>&lt;br/>
2.2GHz Intel Core i7&lt;br/>
6GB 1333MHz DDR3&lt;br/>
NVidia GeForce GT 525M 1GB&lt;br/>
500GB HDD&lt;br/>
Dual layer DVD writer&lt;br/>
Wifi&lt;br/>
1GB Ethernet&lt;br/>
Webcam&lt;br/>
Bluetooth&lt;br/>
9-in-1 Cardreader&lt;br/>
USB 2.0&lt;br/>
&lt;b>€699,-&lt;/b>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Two laptops. Roughly the same specifications. Still, one of these is almost 4 times more expensive than the other. If you'd own one of these laptops you probably enjoy the choice you've made, for whatever reason. You'd want to tell your colleagues about the wonderful new computer you bought, and how you enjoy working on it, how it looks, how it holds all your music, how easily it edits videos and how it plays HD movies. But most colleagues own their own laptops, and will immediately stop you in your tracks, telling you that you bought the wrong laptop because it's too ugly, can't play a 3D movie, is too expensive or doesn't have that essential megatunderpurplebit connector you've never heard of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isn't it funny how computer enthusiasts often forget that they're taking the fun out of each other's story by disapproving somebodies choice simply because that decision is not based on the same criterea?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcycle riders are often very different in that respect. When you drive a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofDllsEV6hE">BMW GS80&lt;/a>  and pull up next to a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-7gDVmdiDY">Ducati Panigale&lt;/a>, the rider will most likely smile at you. When you compliment him on his beautiful new bike, he will probably return a compliment on the pristine condition of your classic. You can exchange pleasantries about how you enjoy your bikes, without down talking the other guy's bike. He will happily ride along with you for a few miles down a beautiful road, even though he has to make his 195hp supercomputer wait for your reliable mechanical boxer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcyclists &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/13159991">celebrate riding&lt;/a> regardless of sound, style or skill. Cooks celebrate food regardless of price, place or palette. Computer users could learn to celebrate computing regardless of form, function or fan noise. Smartphone users could celebrate connectivity regardless of color, coverage or cpu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respect is only gained by respecting others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Lamy Pico pen</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/23/review-lamy-pico-pen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 21:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/23/review-lamy-pico-pen/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="1300_p630491a.jpeg" alt="">
A few weeks ago I saw this amazing pen design by Lamy, the Pico. I'm a heavy computer user so I don't do much handwriting, but I do like nice tools so I thought I'd get this. Particularly the small form factor when retracted and the sleek design attracted me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some things about the Pico that nobody is telling you, so I thought I'd write a little review.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The pen is nicely packaged and looks really cool in the shop display. I bought it at €35,- which is pretty steep for a ballpoint pen. You can probably find a cheaper seller but I haven't seen prices below €30.
&lt;p>Aston Martin also thinks the Lamy Pico looks cool. It is a standard part of the Aston Martin DB9 interior. If you can't afford an Aston Martin, you can get the Lamy Pico with Aston Martin logo as &lt;a href="http://www.astonparts.com/lamy-pico-compressible-pocket-pen-d160234.html">&amp;quot;replacement part&amp;quot;&lt;/a> so you can show off at the bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When unpacking the pen you immediately notice the plastic feel and light weight, something you might not expect from a pen that looks like it is made of massive steel. The mechanics of the pen work, but with that same plastic sound and feel. The &amp;quot;stroke&amp;quot; for retracting the pen is rather large and sometimes you have to click twice. Holding the pen in writing position feels strange, because it is &amp;quot;Stubby&amp;quot;. It feels like he writing end of the pen is not tapered enough, blocking your view on the paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started writing with it, the black ink would not start to flow immediately. It kept doing this, and it became really irritating. Maybe this pen had been in the shop for a very long time, drying out the ink. It gave me a good excuse to buy a blue replacement cartridge because blue stands out when annotating black printed text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="4014519133803_bum-550.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my dismay, the €2,60 Lamy Pico M22 M replacement cartridge was even worse. The ink does not flow immediately when you start writing, and with this blue cartridge, it stops flowing after 3 words. It actually turns out to be a &lt;a href="http://nopenintended.wordpress.com/tag/lamy-pico/">known problem&lt;/a> with these cartridges. If I had only known beforehand. Here you can see some writing with the Lamy Pico compared with a standard Parker Jotter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3320.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3320.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can clearly see in the &amp;quot;T&amp;quot; that the ink did not start to flow immediately. After just a 2 words, the M22 cartridge just gives up. Mind you that this is a new, fresh cartridge. The black cartridge I mentioned  wrote a couple more words before stopping but was worse in starting the ink flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison, the good old Parker Jotter immediately starts putting down dark blue ink and stays consistent all throughout the page. The Parker actually sometimes leaves a little blob of ink, which sometimes smudges when you wipe over it with your hand. But it writes, and that is not what we can say for the Pico.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3324.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3324.jpg?w=109" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the couple of days I (tried to) use the Lamy Pico at work, I started noticing scratches on the end cap. These scratches are made by the pen itself, from the retracting motion. You can clearly the scratches on the image on the right. This is after just a week of very mild office use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compared to my cheap but very reliable all steel &lt;a href="http://www.parkerpen.com/en/discovery/range/performance/jotter">Parker Jotter&lt;/a> which has survived many years in my Filofax, has a nice steel feel, a firm &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; and the very reliable Parker replacement cartridges, the expensive plastic unreliable Lamy Pico is no comparison.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Good&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Very nice design with a high &amp;quot;cool factor&amp;quot;
* Fits nicely in your pocket
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Bad&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Looks metallic but feels plastic
* Makes it's own scratches on the end cap
* Too slippery and feels too &amp;quot;stubby&amp;quot; to be an all-day writing pen.
* Refills are of very poor quality. Ink will not start to flow, and stops flowing after a few words so you can not even use it to write a complete sentence.
* Absolutely unusable as reliable pen.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you are looking for a reliable pen with good looks, don't buy a Pico. The cartridges are terrible, and will fail you every time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The €2800,- Roaming Gigabyte</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 20:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjf-6p76rhA">&lt;img src="burnmoney.jpg" alt="T-Mobile is scum">
&lt;/a>We all know the stories about how vacationing smartphone users became the victim of high &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roaming">roaming&lt;/a> charges, resulting in monthly bills sometimes exceeding €1000. To put an end to this, the EU has come up with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_on_roaming_charges_in_the_European_Union">rule&lt;/a> stating that carriers can no longer charge more than €50 per month for roaming, and are obliged to warn the user before reaching this limit. That all sounds nice and consumer friendly, but I recently tested this, and received an &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; monthly bill from T-Mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I've got an iPhone 4, and like many Dutch iPhone users, I got mine with a T-Mobile contract. I always used Vodafone because it has much better coverage, but when the iPhone 3 came out, T-Mobile was the only way to go and after some hesitation, I switched providers. To this day, the network coverage is not as good as Vodafone's, I miss calls even when I have full bars, and even if I can get "3G", the speeds are not nearly as good as friends with iPhones on the Vodafone network.
&lt;p>Having said that, my contract is an old contract which means I have a truly unlimited data plan, for a reasonable price. That is, until you cross the border.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks ago, we went to France for a week of Eurodisney with the kids and grand kids. Because of the project stress at work, and de possibility to share pictures with my parents, I decided to enable roaming on my iPhone. I did try to check the T-Mobile site for data plans and bundles, but these were either not meeting my needs (day passes), or were too hard to compare with each other. I checked my contract and the roaming charges seemed only slightly higher than the blocks, box-packs, travel-smurf, stack-bundles, or whatever convoluted pricing schemes these carriers were trying to trick me in to. I decided to reset the usage info on my iPhone and keep an eye on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2117-all.png">&lt;img src="img_2117-all.png" alt="Welcome to France">
&lt;/a>I crossed the border and received the usual SMS, about rates everybody ignores. I did see that data was €2,- per MB (yes mega-byte) but it looked more like a typo to me, surely they didn't mean mega-byte, did they? During my stay in France, I got he absolute worse network coverage and data speeds you can imagine. No matter where I was, reading text-only email turned into a chore taking sometimes minutes to load. Twitter feeds were barely coming through, and sending a downscaled 100kB image actually took several retries, and multiple minutes. It was horrible. And then, on day 4, it all came to a halt. No SMS, no warning, no mail, no phone call, just total data shutdown. I could still make &lt;a href="http://www.rense.com/general79/metal.htm">robot-voice calls&lt;/a>, but all data traffic stopped and I had no idea how to get that going again. And that turned out to be a good thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2114.png">&lt;img src="img_2114.png?w=100" alt="Data usage">
&lt;/a>I checked my usage, and guessed that I must have crossed the €50,- mark somewhere, and the carrier shut me down to &amp;quot;protect me&amp;quot; from high roaming charges. I tried to SMS a few people to let them know I was still alive, and that was that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks after I got home, I got the bill, and yes, there it was: I had reached the €50,- mark. It was an expensive experiment, and well worth this blogpost. Here's why. On my home &lt;a href="http://www.xs4all.nl/consument/internetbellen/start.php">entry-level 8Mbit ADSL connection&lt;/a>, I have free VOIP, and unlimited data. I checked our ADSL traffic and my family seems to be doing about 20GB a month combined. My monthly bill is €45,- so if I don't use the phone you could say that a GB of traffic costs me (€45 / 20 GB) &lt;strong>€2,25 per GB.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="factuur_30082011.png">&lt;img src="factuur_30082011.png" alt="The amazing T-Mobile roaming charges">
&lt;/a>As you can see in my data usage screenshot on the iPhone, and the bill on the right, I hardly made use of voice or sms. So we can roughly do the same calculation, assuming that 99% of the bill is data. The monthly bill was €89,45, and that got me 31.450MB of data (yes, again: mega-byte). So the price of a roaming Gigabyte in Europe is (€89,45 / 0.031450 GB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>€ 2844,20 per GB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you see is no typo. Almost €3000,- per GB. So what the Phone company is telling me here, is that even though the networks in all countries are reaching right up to the border, and we live in an interconnected world where data travels freely across the globe, phone companies charge more than 1000x the regular price to get a bit of information across that border?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think carriers need to be seriously investigated by the EU and Trading committees, because they are using their monopoly to charge us prices which are totally unrealistic. It also proves that privatization of public services like communication networks doesn't work. It nearly always results in a few greedy companies cobbling up a system which delivers crappy service for an outrageous price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step for these leeches is to come back from &lt;a href="http://rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/">whatever cave they were in&lt;/a>, move forward in time to 2011, and replace the &amp;quot;MB&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;GB&amp;quot; on my bill, without changing anything else. That would &lt;em>still&lt;/em> make them 26% more expensive than my internet provider, but at least it would take the roaming charges to an acceptable level, even for the crappy data speeds they blatantly market as &amp;quot;high speed&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Tim Cook</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/20/open-letter-to-tim-cook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 20:04:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/20/open-letter-to-tim-cook/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.thewareaglereader.com/2011/08/portrait-of-new-apple-ceo-tim-cook-as-a-young-auburn-student/">&lt;img src="timcook.png" alt="Our new old friend, Tim Cook">
&lt;/a>Dear Tim,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am certainly not the first, nor the last to congratulate you with your new position at Apple. I'm sure there will be many great things to come for Apple and it's customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple has become the doctor that doesn't fix the pain, but cures the illness and improves our daily digital lives. Please make sure Apple keeps it's focus, perseverance and good taste in the endless search for true quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tell Steve and Jony I said hi, and keep up the good work. If there's anything I can help you with, you know how to reach me ;-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers,
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linked-In not really Opt-in?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/07/linked-in-not-really-opt-in/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 19:14:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/07/linked-in-not-really-opt-in/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opt-out">&lt;img src="linked-in-opt-in-1.png" alt="Linked-In, or Opt-out?">
&lt;/a>Recently there was some &lt;a href="http://www.worldwidewords.org/weirdwords/ww-ker1.htm">kerfuffle&lt;/a> about LinkedIn silently changing privacy settings. In fact, they didn't do that &lt;em>&amp;quot;silently&amp;quot;&lt;/em>, nor was it &lt;em>&amp;quot;recent&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Remember that large chunk of text nobody reads with the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Agree&amp;quot;&lt;/em> button you clicked on? Those were the new terms, and deeply buried in them was this privacy settings stuff. LinkedIn's Eric Heath &lt;a href="http://blog.linkedin.com/2011/06/10/privacy-policy-changes/">blogged about that&lt;/a>, bringing it as &lt;em>&amp;quot;more control over your LinkedIn information&amp;quot;.&lt;/em> Sadly, the default setting for this new &lt;em>&amp;quot;control&amp;quot;&lt;/em> is &lt;em>&amp;quot;rather open&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. But you can change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Just recently, people started to see the effects of the new terms and conditions, as LinkedIn started a new social advertising campaign including profile pictures. Most LinkedIn users felt they did not (knowingly) agree to that. Ryan Roslansky [explains the new ads](http://blog.linkedin.com/2011/08/11/social-ads-update/) on August 11th, and also mentions that LinkedIn is responding to the complaints and will remove the profile pictures from the new ads.
&lt;p>If you want to be sure that LinkedIn does not use your profile in ads in the future ever again, you could always &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/answers/using-linkedIn/ULI/728753-417696">cancel your account&lt;/a>. For people that don't want to cancel their account, there is a setting you can try to change (given that LinkedIn doesn't change it again). Here's a little screenshot I annotated with &lt;a href="http://skitch.com/">Skitch&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="linked-in-social-advertising-1-2.png">&lt;img src="linked-in-social-advertising-1-2.png" alt="How to Opt-Out of social advertising with Linked-In">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might also want to check out some other settings on those tabs. There's no clear overview, and the settings are hard to click through. That's probably on purpose, because well, Linked-In is now cashing in on it's (or: your) data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember: What's not on the internet, is not on the internet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why phone companies will fail</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 19:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/phone">&lt;img src="wet-cell-phone.jpeg" alt="cell phone under water">
&lt;/a>I recently had a very unpleasant experience with my mobile phone. Actually, it wasn't so much my mobile phone itself, as it was the sharing of my private mobile phone number between colleagues. Seemingly harmless, but with great consequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my colleagues, in his innocence and with nothing but good intentions, shared my phone number with another colleague. As I was sitting in the hospital, the second colleague called me with questions about estimates I made for a project, which at that time &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rolfje/status/545010403512320">intensely frustrated me&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I had the whole weekend to cool down, I was still pretty pissed the following monday. Some unpleasant conversations followed. I think everything is solved now but I can only hope somebody actually deletes my number when he says he does. Which got me to think about the old fashioned and spectacularly broken addressing model phone companies are still using.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->When I was little, there were no mobile phones (yes, I'm that old). People had a single line into their house, with a single number. This situation lead to some "number sharing etiquette": If person A asks for the phone number of person B, instead of giving it, you asked for A's phone number instead, and passed that to B. This way, both parties have control over sharing their number, without you compromising anybody's number without their consent.
&lt;p>Nowadays, it seems that only my &amp;quot;smarter&amp;quot; friends find this etiquette normal to be used in sharing email addresses and other address information. Sadly, this is not the case for the younger generations. Sharing email addresses and phone numbers without asking is common practice. With modern communication methods this is not a problem, because the receiver is in control of the inbound traffic. Messages can be blocked, filtered or re-routed. Mails can be routed to different folders or straight into the trash with a simple mail rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much unlike unlike messaging, routing incoming calls is not possible on your phone. Why? Because the phone companies have created a problem when they introduced caller-ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of protecting the receiver of the call, they chose to protect the caller by hiding his number if he wishes to do so. This simple oversight results in the receiver not being able to route calls based on caller-ID. I can not block anonymous incoming calls without knowing if I am missing important calls, say from the hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to fix this, I propose we do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. We still keep (or re-introduce) the sharing etiquette described above, because I think it is good courtesy to handle other people's data with respect. It's also a workaround for the inbound routing problem.
2. We create a system where a phone can have multiple numbers, of which the owner can route traffic. Google voice is already doing this, but european phone companies are not allowing that to happen over here (guess why).
3. We loose the whole &amp;quot;anonymous calling&amp;quot; idea after implementing 2. As with MSN and Google Talk, I get to see who is calling me, and I can choose to block future calls or add you to my &amp;quot;buddy list&amp;quot;.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Having said all this, I think phone companies are dying. Sure they're doing okay now, but they keep holding on to old landline business models and apply them to new technology. It will fail like it is failing for the music and film industry right now. Unless phone companies act up and start behaving more like reasonable &amp;quot;data/Internet providers&amp;quot; they will be replaced by internet providers putting up cell towers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until then, we need to put up with (but protest against) ridiculous data plans, absurd roaming charges, single-provider GSM towers with coverage problems and the recent &amp;quot;round up to nearest minute&amp;quot; method of over-billing customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I expect all this to happen not earlier than world peace, let's be careful about sharing each others numbers, shall we?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Growth is a bad thing. Bad.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/05/17/why-growth-is-a-bad-thing-bad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/05/17/why-growth-is-a-bad-thing-bad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="petri-dish.jpg" alt="">
Quite often I am amazed at people's ability to miss what looks obvious to me. Not only the small things like cleaning up when you spill coffee over the floor, or washing your hands when you get off the toilet, but also bigger things. Like the silly &amp;quot;solutions&amp;quot; to the world's pollution problem for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking to solve our pollution problem by changing people's behavior is one of the things which to me is obvious to fail. Although some behavior may speed up pollution, in the end we all pollute, wether we like it or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the risk of writing a very unpopular blogpost, I'd like to share some thoughts on the ongoing and ever increasing pollution problem. In my eyes, there are 2 real causes of pollution, and ultimately these causes are even self-repairing although you may not like how that works out for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->Growth&lt;/strong>
If you've watched &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Way_Round">&amp;quot;The Long Way Round&amp;quot;&lt;/a> you've noticed that farmers in Mongolia have nothing but their animals and the land they live on. To them, there is a natural balance between people and nature. Having more of one thing (regardless which) disturbs the balance of things and renders pretty immediate problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the &amp;quot;modern world&amp;quot; this balance is less obvious, and the urge to &amp;quot;want&amp;quot; something is not naturally stopped. People always to want have more. Bigger house, bigger car, more money, more kids. It is the constant urge for a &amp;quot;better life&amp;quot;. This urge, combined with the unimaginable stupidity of people in large groups have lead to a system which is based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot;. If you don't believe me, stare at the &lt;a href="http://www.worldometers.info/">worldometers web site&lt;/a> for a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any rational thinking person must see that endless growth results in an infinitely large system. Since the earth has a fixed size, any system based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; is bound to hit the limits of what is physically possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Waste production&lt;/strong>
Every living thing on this planet produces waste. This can be in the form of breathing out co2, or taking a dump behind a tree. Nature has a way to deal with this. Waste is decomposed, and therefore part of the system. In fact, everything on this earth is part of &amp;quot;the system&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to Merriam-Webster's online dictionary, &amp;quot;pollution&amp;quot; is &lt;em>&amp;quot;the action of polluting especially by environmental contamination with man-made waste&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Oversimplified and on a (very) large scale, we can not produce stuff that's not here. Everything is synthesized in some way from existing materials. In my mind, &amp;quot;pollution&amp;quot; is just &amp;quot;waste with a longer recycle time&amp;quot;. Even &lt;a href="http://www.mnn.com/technology/research-innovations/blogs/boy-discovers-microbe-that-eats-plastic">plastic eventually breaks down&lt;/a> and re-enters the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oil">Wikipedia&lt;/a>, oils are &lt;em>&amp;quot;classified as mineral oils because they do not have an organic origin on human timescales&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. So what it says is that Oil is in fact a natural product, but because it took so freakin' long to become oil, we don't recognize it as a natural product. What it says to me is, if we are able to find the balance, we may be able to keep using oil, as long as it's in the same rate as it is reproduced. Mind you, that's an incredibly slow rate, to &amp;quot;human timescales&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to keep the earth as &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot; as it is now, we can introduce the following rule of thumb:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>n x p = r&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>where:
n = number of people on the planet
p = pollution per person per month
r = Earth's natural pollution recycle rate, per month (constant)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>So, if you want to have twice the people, you need to pollute half as much, on average, because the earth's natural recycle rate is fixed. I'm sure this formula is nowhere near a realistic model, but it shows that both increasing consumption and increasing the world's population is not going to work out in the long run. Even if  everybody &amp;quot;sees the light&amp;quot;, becomes an environmentalist, stops driving cars, and cuts down on consumption in general, we can't continue to endlessly grow our population.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Spot the Similarities&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Extrapolated_world_population_history.png">&lt;img src="extrapolated_world_population_history1.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>So now we understand that this &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; system is resulting/has resulted in too many people on this planet, producing too much long lasting waste at a high rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, it get's scarier. Let's look at the growth rate of the human population on this planet. Several graphs, including this one from wikipedia, will show relatively slow population growth until the 1920's. Between 1920 and 2000 we see exponential growth. After that, it is expected that the growth will decline into a more &amp;quot;stationary&amp;quot; phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm now where did we see that before? Remember biology class, particularly the lessons about bacterial growth ? In this next graph, you can see the different phases of bacterial growth, resulting in certain death of the complete population, due to the depletion of resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://onlinebiologybook.blogspot.com/2009/01/microorganism-exam-1.html">&lt;img src="06-14_bacteriagrowth_11.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Guess what we're doing? By getting more and more kids, our population &amp;quot;eats&amp;quot; all the natural resources at a rate at which the earth can not match. It can not produce enough new resources to maintain the population, effectively resulting in a petri dish which also doesn't &amp;quot;replenish&amp;quot; it's resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Again, this painfully demonstrates that any system based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; is a system doomed to fail. Having kids to support your pension might seem like a good idea, but essentially you're sacrificing the life of your kids (or theirs) for your comfortable retirement days. In my (unpopular) opinion, the only (and I mean &lt;em>only&lt;/em>) way to reduce the whole pollution and economic problems is to have less people on this world. Much, much less. In fact, we would see quicker results if particularly modern &amp;quot;western&amp;quot; people shrunk in numbers first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Unpopular measures are... unpopular
As mentioned before, people are loosing the ability to stop giving in to any urge they get. One of these urges (albeit strongly driven by nature itself) is having kids.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please understand that I have nothing against kids, in fact I'm a grandfather myself. It's just that I think it's funny that we actively encourage having kids, while at the same time recognizing that people are the very cause of all these environmental problems in the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We continue to stick our heads in the sand and talk about &lt;em>&lt;em>cough&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Co2 neutral flying&amp;quot;, &lt;em>&lt;em>rhrmhhhrrm&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Bio degradable rubber&amp;quot; and last but not least, the hilarious &lt;em>&lt;em>COUGHcoughcough&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Renewable energy&amp;quot;. What we should really think about is how to at least stop the world population from growing. This may result in imposing all kinds of unpopular/impossible worldwide measures I don't care to get into right now, but killing is of course not one of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since no politician is going to win voters by saying that he wants the whole country to be celibate (or worse), I realize that this will probably never happen, at least not in my lifetime.  The good thing is that our weak minds aren't forced to make these choices, because the system will make the choice for us. Just like the petri dish does for bacteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I'm not the most environmental friendly freak you'd encounter, maybe even far from that with my motorcycle, car, computers, and airconditioner. My point is actually that we probably can keep enjoying a lot, if not all of these things, if we just stop putting more and more people on this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe I can best put it like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;If you love kids, stop having them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Please note that nothing in this post is meant to be personal or offensive to anybody in any way. It's just a silly blogpost in which I think aloud. Use it as food for thought, or discard it, but don't let it spoil your day. Don't worry, I don't have the power to control my kids, or even my cat, let alone the world. I have no intentions to becoming a politician.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Car Buying Story</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2010 22:50:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-04-om-21-22-13.png" alt="">
Stephen needs a new car. Being dilligent and a car lover, he takes the time to write down all criteria for a great car. When he finishes the list, he notices that the only car matching all his criteria is a Ferrari. Well, he always loved a Ferrari so that makes sense. To make things more realistic he adds another criteria, called &amp;quot;price&amp;quot;, and starts looking for alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The first car he looks at is practical, but hasn't got the speed of a Ferrari. The second car can carry a lot of stuff, but hasn't got the sound of a Ferrari. The third car is really modular, but hasn't got the looks of a Ferrari. The fourth car is very fast, but doesn't handle as a Ferrari. The fifth car is an independant brand, and can be repaired in any shop, but it breaks down much more often than a Ferrari. The sixth car has a cool design-flip-type-clock and integrated MP3 player, but the manual coming with it does not explain how to operate them.
&lt;p>The seventh car looked too good to be true good in the advertisement. The images in the brochure look stunning. It has everything on his list, and also matches the price criteria. Stephen orders it immediately. But when delivered it does not live up to the whole Ferrari design, look and feel. By far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen is not really unhappy and has learned to live with the car's shortcomings. When asked about his new car, Stephen kindly shows it, but the first sentence he regretfuly utters is &lt;em>&amp;quot;but ofcourse, it's not a Ferrari&amp;quot;...&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The moral of this story is: If you don't buy a Ferrari, you'll never own a Ferrari.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: car
replace: mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: Ferrari
replace: iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="the-events-in-this-story-are-fictitious-any-similarity-to-any-person-living-or-dead-is-merely-coincidental-i-cannot-emphasize-enough-how-coincidental-the-fictional-entities-are-to-any-real-life-individual-entity-or-character-for-more-disclaimers-id-like-to-refer-you-to-this-sites-about-pagehttprolfjewordpresscomabout">The events in this story are fictitious. Any similarity to any person living or dead is merely coincidental. I cannot emphasize enough how coincidental the fictional entities are to any real life individual, entity, or character. For more disclaimers I'd like to refer you to this site's &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/about/">about page&lt;/a>.&lt;/h6></description></item><item><title>Kilometerheffing? GPS-data NEE!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/24/kilometerheffing-gps-data-nee/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 22:51:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/24/kilometerheffing-gps-data-nee/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="big-brother-poster.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik weet niet welke lobbyist menner Eurlings heeft verteld dat dit een briljant plan is, maar ik weet donders goed waarom onze regering kilometerheffing wil invoeren. Weer een kraantje toegevoegd aan het vat dat &amp;quot;werkende Nederlander&amp;quot; heet, en als bonus nog wat privacy gevoelige GPS gegevens om in rond te neuzen ook. Mocht je de rest van deze post niet willen lezen, reageer dan wel even op de volgende sites, want Eurlings heeft gezegd dat kilometerheffing &amp;quot;bij gebrek aan draagvlak&amp;quot; (welk draagvlak?) niet doorgaat:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [http://www.redonzeprivacy.nl/](http://www.redonzeprivacy.nl/)
* [http://www.kilometerheffingnoway.nl/](http://www.kilometerheffingnoway.nl/)
* [http://www.kilometerheffing-nee.nl/](http://www.kilometerheffing-nee.nl/)
* [http://petities.nl/petitie/kilometerheffing-is-verkeerd](http://petities.nl/petitie/kilometerheffing-is-verkeerd)
* [http://www.kilometer-heffing.eu/](http://www.kilometer-heffing.eu/)
* ﻿[http://www.anwbledenpeiling.nl/](http://www.anwbledenpeiling.nl/) &amp;lt;-- Eurlings gaat deze uitslag gebruiken! (als je de vragen gezien hebt zie je waarom :-/ )
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- more -->Voor mij is het duidelijk dat de regering er niet op uit is om het voor de automobilist goedkoper te maken, maar om banen te creeëren bij de overheid waarvan de salarissen door ons betaald moeten gaan worden. De voor mij vier meest onoverkomelijke bezwaren tegen kilometerheffing zijn:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. **GPS data**
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Voor mij de meest onoverbrugbare hindernis. De regering gaat (ongetwijfeld lelijke) kastjes in onze auto's stoppen, waarbij wij niet weten wat de kastjes gaan registreren, en ook niet weten wat voor data deze kastjes aan de regering gaan geven. Het lijkt me ondertussen duidelijk dat de regering heeft bewezen niet verantwoordelijk om te kunnen gaan met dergelijke gegevens. Denk aan het gemak waarmee de regering maar even denkt te kunnen afluisteren zonder reden. Zo zullen ze ook toegang kunnen krijgen tot onze GPS data, zonder dat wij dit weten. Ook al wordt autorijden de helft goedkoper, dan nog ben ik tegen, om precies deze reden. Geen politiestaat a.u.b.
2. &lt;strong>Onkontroleerbaare verhogingen&lt;/strong>
De regering zal de kilometerprijs zonder onderbouwing kunnen verhogen, doordat deze prijs niet is gekoppeld aan olieprijzen, of werkelijke onderhoudskosten aan de weg. &amp;quot;We komen niet uit&amp;quot; of &amp;quot;het is hier te druk&amp;quot; en de prijs gaat omhoog. Waar nu de belasting nog gekoppeld is aan aanschafprijs en benzinetarief, kan de regering straks met de &amp;quot;psychische barriere&amp;quot; breken en de rekening ongelimiteerd verhogen.
3. &lt;strong>Implementatiekosten&lt;/strong>
Om iedere auto in Nederland van een kastje te voorzien dat, schat ik, minimaal zo'n slordige 40 euro kost, zal een ongeloofelijke investering vragen (7 mln auto's x €40 = €280 mln exclusief versturen en inbouwen), die uiteraard voor rekening van de belastingbetaler (automobilist) komen.
4. &lt;strong>Lopende kosten&lt;/strong>
Na invoering van het systeem moet er een heel administratie apparaat worden ingericht om de data van al die kastjes te verzamelen, rekeningen te sturen, kapotte kastjes te vervangen, en oude kastjes in te vorderen. Daarbij komt er bij de politie waarschijnlijk een last te liggen op kastjes controle, of ze wel in de auto zitten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wat de regering donders goed begrijpt, ook al zeggen ze dat niet, is dat Nederlanders de auto niet uit gaan, al zouden ze dat willen. De sneeuw van afgelopen periode heeft weer bewezen dat als de nood aan de man is, de auto verreweg het meest betrouwbare vervoersmiddel is. Van de trein hoeven we dat niet te verwachten, en over de bus hoef ik niet eens te beginnen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Werkende mensen die op tijd op hun werk moeten zijn hebben vaak geen andere keuze dan met de auto naar het werk te gaan. Ze kunnen ook niet kiezen waar hun baas een kantoor neerzet. De meeste bedrijven vestigen zich in een drukke stad, om allerlei redenen. Geen van die redenen is bereikbaarheid voor de medewerker, dat is namelijk niet het probleem van de werkgever. Als de regering bedrijven zou belasten voor de file die ze veroorzaken zouden de zaken er anders voor staan. Maar dat doet de regering niet, want dan is het fileprobleem opgelost, en dat is financieel niet aantrekkelijk omdat er dan geen spits-kilometerheffing geheven kan worden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daarbij komt nog dat de regering &amp;quot;per ongeluk&amp;quot; hybride auto's heeft gestimuleerd, als publiciteitsstunt naar andere landen toe. De stap naar 100% electrische auto's komt dan snel in het zicht, en dan kan de regering opeens geen belasting meer heffen op brandstof. Dus vandaar dat de voordelen voor hybride rijders worden teruggedraaid, en er een manier wordt geintroduceerd zodat ook electrisch rijden kan worden gemolken ehhh, ik bedoel natuurlijk &amp;quot;financieel gestuurd&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inmiddels is er door veel mensen aangetoond dat Eurlings loopt te liegen als hij zegt dat het zeker niet duurder gaat worden. Daarbij spreekt hij zichzelf tegen, want &amp;quot;als het in de randstad duurder wordt, gaat het gemiddelde omlaag&amp;quot;. Da's grappig, de meeste file's staan in de randstad, dus voor de meeste mensen zal het duurder worden he. Bovendien staan die mensen daar niet voor de lol in de file, meneer Eurlings...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Het mooiste voorbeeld was nog wel de kilometerheffing voor motoren. Als iedereen op een motor zou komen, zouden er geen files meer staan, en zou het asfalt langer meegaan omdat het minder zwaar belast wordt. Hoe kan het dan dat de regering van plan is om motoren ook kilometerheffing te laten betalen? Gelukkig heeft de &lt;a href="http://www.knmv.nl/knmv/nieuws/motorrijders-uitgesloten-van-km-heffing">KNMV&lt;/a> hier een stokje voor gestoken maar het is duidelijk dat de regering op weg is naar een communistische politiestaat, en dat we dit allemaal blijkbaar gewoon laten gebeuren.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ondertussen snoept de regering bij invoering van deze regeling ook nog geld weg bij provincie en gemeenten, en die zijn nu al hun &amp;quot;opcenten&amp;quot; aan het verhogen. Die neemt Eurlings niet mee, dus als hij zegt &amp;quot;goedkoper&amp;quot; dan haalt hij een rekentruck uit die niet alle gevolgen meeneemt voor uw gezinssituatie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Voorspelling:&lt;/strong> Bij het invoeren van de kilometerheffing zal de accijns op de brandstof niet verdwijnen. (Kwartje van Kok, weten we het nog?). Lasten zullen niet verlagen, en het regeringsapparaat zal mensen moeten aannemen om dit alles te runnen, waardoor kosten hoger zullen uitkomen dan voorspeld.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Je eigen kilometerprijs berekenen? Dat kan op een aantal sites, zoals bij de &lt;a href="http://www.anwb.nl/kilometerprijscheck/berekenuwkilometerprijs/kilometerprijscheck">ANWB&lt;/a>, maar aangezien die niet &amp;quot;tegen&amp;quot; zijn zou ik de berekening met een korrel zout nemen, het kan wel eens veeeeel duurder worden dan je nu voorgehouden wordt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slaap zacht.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T(w)inkering</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/06/07/twinkering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 21:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/06/07/twinkering/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Now that the twitter hype is cooling down, and companies tart to realize that it is, in fact, just CB radio in a new asynchronous form, only the &amp;quot;true tweeps&amp;quot; still hang around. And now, it's time to t(w)inker with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_942&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Early 2002, in my dad's old &amp;quot;shack&amp;quot;, we measured the accuracy of a delayed solonoid triggering device I made.&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="02020905.jpg">&lt;img src="02020905.jpg?w=150" alt="Early 2002, in my dad's old "shack", we measured the accuracy of a delayed solonoid triggering device I made.">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some years ago, I did some playing around with CB radio. With my dad being an electronics engineer and a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amateur_radio">HAM radio&lt;/a> operator, it didn't take long before I got my HAM radio license, and start taking apart and putting together all kinds of electronics to play with this medium. We had quite some fun doing this, and I got a lot of great stories out of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the coming of Twitter as the &amp;quot;new CB radio&amp;quot;, a new kind of tinkering came along. Not so much with electronics, but more with the data of twitter itself. Here are some of the funny and/or interesting services I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>WARNING:&lt;/strong> Some of these services show you a very &amp;quot;Twitter like&amp;quot; login form, and ask you to sign in with your Twitter userid and password. Please think very careful about this. Giving somebody your twitter password can render your account useless, and exposes you to possible forms of identity theft. Except for twitpic, none of these services have ever seen my password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitoaster.com/rolfje">Twitoaster&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
One of the problems with Twitter is that you don't always see your conversations. People might only see one half of it, or because of it's asynchronous character, miss essential tweets in a conversation. To solve this, Twitoaster searches your tweets, finds replies, and groups them together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The downside is that you need to follow @twitoaster, which can ruin your &amp;quot;tweet stream&amp;quot;. Having said that, there are not much tweets coming from that account so maybe it won't bother you that much. Although twitoaster.com shows you a login form, you are not required to log in for this service to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://xefer.com/twitter/rolfje">Xefer&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
If you like cool pictures made from your tweeting habbits, Xefer can do that for you. It will display an activity graph which shows you which days of the week and which hours of those days you are most active on Twitter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitterank.com/?u=rolfje">Twitterank&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Some mysterious algorithm places people in a list in a certain order, and calls it a &amp;quot;rank&amp;quot;. Now all of a sudden, people want to be on top. Isn't that funny? The developer of this site had hacked some stuff together, and was soon overwhelmed by people wanting to know their &amp;quot;rank&amp;quot;. This is ofcourse just as silly as measuring your success by the number of followers you have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time of this writing, my twitterrank is 14.26. According to twitterank, this score is higher than 37.68 of the other ranked twitterers. Not knowing what the algorithm is, and not knowing how to influence it, means this number is totally useless and silly. But hey, we like numbers... Yay twitterank!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.twitteranalyzer.com/ms.aspx?userId=rolfje">Twitteranalyzer&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Just another graphing thing to show you when you tweet the most, what words or hashtags you most commonly use, and what kind of clients you use. Nicely done, but not really compelling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetstats.com/status/rolfje">Tweetstats&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
One of my favourites, displays your usage info in nice simple colorful layout. While you are waiting, funny texts as &amp;quot;magic happening&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;there be feries&amp;quot; are shown on the progess bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/status.php?search=rolfje">Twanalyst&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/suggest.php">&lt;img src="hatter.png" alt="Twanalyst logo">
&lt;/a>Always fun to read and always changing (if you keep tweeting), this service reads all your tweets and takes a shot at estimating your personality from their contents. At the time of this writing, it thinks of me as &amp;quot;likeable sociable fair&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;garrulous coherent&amp;quot;. It sums it up as &amp;quot;Poet&amp;quot;. Ahem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I you're not tweeting enough, or there is something else this service thinks is wrong, it will give you some tweeting tips. Very funny. Don't forget to check out the &lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/rolfje/suggest">&amp;quot;suggest&amp;quot;&lt;/a> feature, which will try to find people with a similar writing style youmight like following.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://hashtags.org/">Hashtags&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Tracks hashtags in the global timeline. With this service you can see people's tweets grouped by tags. Very handy if you want to keep up with a particular subject. I personally use it to check &lt;a href="http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday/messages">followfriday&lt;/a> tags every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitterposter.com/nl">Twitterposter&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Shows you a cloud of twitter icons. The bigger the icon, the more followers this account has. The bad news is that it sometimes does not load all icons or avatars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Final thoughts&lt;/strong>
There are many, many, many more twitter services out there, but you want to be careful with sharing your password. For example, &lt;em>Tweetmondo.com&lt;/em> needs your twitter account password, just to tell you if there are &amp;quot;tweeps&amp;quot; close to your location? No thank you, Tweetie on my iPhone already does that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same goes for &lt;em>Localtweeps.com&lt;/em>, which tries to match you and other local tweeps through your ZIP code. I never was even tempted to give them my password, because it's developers seem to think that the world only consists of US, Canada and UK. Nothing to see here, move along...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a twitter account which has enough data to make these services work, you are one of the luck few. An &lt;a href="http://tech.yahoo.com/blogs/patterson/50591/study-top-10-of-twitter-users-do-90-of-the-tweeting/">article on tech.yahoo.com&lt;/a> shows that the top 10% of twitter users do 90% of the twittering. I hope they didn't count those dumb automated tweets, because there are a lot of those...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's funny how companies still seem to think that they can just &amp;quot;connect to a network&amp;quot;, send us spam, and them expect we'll like them. These companies are either loaded, or doomed, because in a few months, they might have to connect to a different network. Like Scoble said: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Networks don't have people. People have networks.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design Gripes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dear Akio Morita,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">&lt;img src="2009-04-08-234308.png" alt="Onion News Network on Sony products">
&lt;/a>Lately I have some small issues with a lot of design decisions being made by the company you founded a while ago. If you look at my irritations seperately they're just small gripes of a grumpy old customer. But the increasing number of design mistakes have me worried about your user acceptance testing and quality assurance processes. Given the sheer size of your company, and the fact that the very same people who are sabotaging your overall product quality can silently delete my complaint, I thought I'd share it with you here, on my very private blog.  Nobody else will read this. Honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me start by saying that I love my Playstation 3. No wait, let me rephrase that. I love playing games on my playstation 3. Because the playstation 3 itself is absolutely not intuitive, logical or even pleasant to use. Both hardware and software wise.
&lt;p>I am very fortunate to have a loving wife who bought a PS3 for me. Because she did not expect to have to do in-depth research about the differences between the models, she bought the 80GB PS3 for me. It was the biggest drive in the store, so she thought that was the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was/am really happy with the very nice present. Not having any PS3 games yet, I slapped in a PS2 game, fully expecting that it would play. Not so. As it turns out, only the 60GB model plays &lt;em>some&lt;/em> of the PS2 games, and most of the time not even perfectly. What's with that? Can this 3-Cell processor huge 80GB machine with metric craploads of memory not emulate the outdated PS2? Did nobody at Sony realize that they can capitalize on people upgrading from the PS2? Not even now that the &lt;a href="http://ps3finder.com/">60GB models actually sell for more money than the 80GB&lt;/a> model retail price?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disapointedly leaving the PS2 compatibility issue, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/">I got a DLNA server running&lt;/a> on my Mac. When I want to view media on that server, I have to use your &amp;quot;X media bar&amp;quot; menu. For some reason, some designer came up with the brilliant idea to seperate music, photo's and video's in that menu. This means that before browsing my DLNA server, I have to decide what filetype I'm going to browse. If I have folders containing both video and photo's of the same birthday party, I constantly have to back out of the photo viewing mode, get into the video mode, browse all the way back to the folder, and view the video. It's like having to fill in a form to flip the channel on your TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what's with the forgetting of discovered DLNA servers? The PS3 takes ages to re-discover my DLNA server on the network each time I turn the PS3 on, or return to the menu from a game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it even more cringeworthy, the PS3 scares the crap out of me each time I browse to a folder to see that &amp;quot;There are no files...&amp;quot;. The PS3 is lying ofcourse, what it means is that there are MPG's and AVI's there, but I'm in photo viewing mode. The whole X-media-bar design must have never been usability tested by random customers. It's a very common practice nowadays which I can really recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By now, I had scored some PS3 games (&lt;a href="http://www.ps3home.nl/products/playstation-3-games/alle-games-a-tot-z/moto-gp-2008-ps3.htm">Moto GP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.tombraiderunderworld.com">Tomb Raider: Underworld&lt;/a>). After a nice evening of gaming,  I discover that the controller battery is running low. So I connect it to the PS3, and put the PS3 in standby mode, expecting my controller to be charged the next morning. To my huge disapointment, the controller does not charge when the PS3 is not fully on. That strikes me as really strange. To charge my wireless controller, I have to connect it during gaming. Now how did someone on your design team did not notice that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a big old Phillips Matchline TV which worked fine, but was getting a bit dated. The thought of being able to play games in full HD 1080p resolution was very tempting, so I bought a new model Sony Bravia 40 inch TV, thinking that it would interface nicely with the PS3. To my absolute horror, the PS3 video signal looked horrible on this new TV. As it turned out, you are shipping this full HD 300+ dollar gaming machine with a crappy composite video cable. Oh boy. Now I know why people think the difference between a Wii and a PS3 is not that huge. Another obvious commercial win down the drain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and I discovered that HDMI is the best way to go. I bought an HDMI cable and connected the PS3 to the TV with that. The TV manual said it could use some HDMI protocol to discover HDMI connected devices. Surely enough, my brandnew Sony Bravia does not recognize my Sony PS3. How nice is that? Luckaly, after some manual fiddling with the absolutely horrid X-media bar-like menu's in the TV and the PS3, I got everything to play in full HD. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What strikes me as another design flaw is the size of the screen fonts. On my big TV everything looks nice, but I can imagine that the paperboy who emptied his piggybank to get a PS3, and connects it to his little TV in his room, can not read any of the menu items. I take it that the Sony testing department only has Full HD TV's with HDMI cables, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there's the whole casing design thing. Come on. Rounded top? I can not even place a controller on there, it slides off. The ventilation holes are on the side, which makes it imposible to put the PS3 with it's right side against the cupboard. The USB ports are recessed in such a way that if you place the PS3 low to the ground (which happens most), you can not see the ports without having to lie down on the floor eyeballing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you're down there, you can als see the rediculously thick and sturdy mains cable. It can transport enough current to power my microwave. Does the PS3 really use that much current? Now be honest. You could have selected a thinner, more flexible mains lead, and maybe it would even have been cheaper. The current lead almost pushes the PS3 out from the wall. Good thing the PS3 is so heavy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When waking the PS3 from it's sleep mode, there is another interesting thing that strikes me as odd. There is a green and a blue led next to eachother on the top of the button pannel. Not only are those two colors looking horrible next to eachother, and the fact that I have come to loathe any product with a blue led, there is absolutely no way that colorblind people are going to notice the difference in color, which makes them pointless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said, this is just a selection of the gripes I have with the design. For instance, the fact that game makers are allowed to play sounds and video as soon as a game is inserted, is just terrible. It scares the crap out of me each time I insert &lt;a href="http://www.racedrivergrid.com/">Race Driver:GRID&lt;/a>, and there is no way I can turn it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="photo.jpg">&lt;img src="photo.jpg" alt="Sony Bravia remote button misplacement">
&lt;/a>The nicest example of hardware design failure by Sony is the remote control of the Sony Bravia TV. The buttons you use most are in fact unreachable when holding the remote in your hand. The least used buttons are right there by your thumb. What was this designer thinking? Oh and never mind pressing the buttons, because this TV, which can interpolate frames of a 24fps source into 100fps fluid motion while dynamically adjusting sound and backlight, has a very hard time to display a menu or react to the remote. This is absolutely mind boggling to me. It's like a race car which can go from 0 to 300mph in 2 seconds but takes 5 seconds to react to the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I bought all this Sony stuff. I know, I could have bought something else. But there are reasons for me to put up with all this crap. OTHER manufacturers make such great stuff for Sony devices. The games on the PS3 are absolutely beautiful and brilliant. Watching video on the PSP on an airplane is great. Looking at a bluray at 100Hz 1080p on the Bravia is eye-popping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, dear mr. Morita, please, please make the people at Sony aware of these details. They're important. Solving them will set your product apart from the competition in a large way. People may not be able to tell why, but they will like your product better. This is what good designers do. Make a product have a good &amp;quot;feel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will also rid you of online video's describing your products as... well... you've already seen &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">that video&lt;/a>, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading this rant.
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LED's in your livingroom?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/03/08/leds-in-your-livingroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 21:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/03/08/leds-in-your-livingroom/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In some countries, there is some talk on &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase_out_of_incandescent_light_bulbs">banishing the classic (incandescant) lightbulb&lt;/a>. I think this whole discussion is needless. The only reason why it exists, is that the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluorescent_light">fluorescent&lt;/a> bulbs are often of mediocre quality, and certain people are here to enforce their bad tastes upon us &amp;quot;for a greater purpose&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don't get me wrong, I really like trees and birds around my house, and I would be more than happy to install &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/">energy-efficient appliances&lt;/a> in my home, even if they cost me slightly more. But especially if I'm paying more, I expect to get a certain level of quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the inefficiency of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incandescent_light_bulb">incandescent&lt;/a> bulbs, and the number of bulbs in my household, I decided to look around for energy efficient solutions. Particulary LED lighting caught my interest, because it is not only energy efficient, it's also dimmable with normal (cheap) floor dimmers. They even stay cold enough so that children touching them do not burn their fingers.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**The Search
&lt;p>**I went online, and looked around for LED bulbs which would fit in a normal E14 (small) socket. It was a long and hard search, because information on LED lighting is sparse, as if manufacturers don't want to sell them. I found this &amp;quot;Parlat&amp;quot; lamp at &lt;a href="http://www.ledgloeilamp.nl/LED-Gloeilampen-E27-E14/LED-lamp-E14-kaarsvorm/productdetails.tpl.htm">ledgloeilamp.nl&lt;/a> which promised to be &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot;, with a color temperature of 3000 Kelvin. Some Googling learned that a 2 Watt LED lamp is considered to be roughly equal to 30 Watts of incandescent light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**The Test Results
**&lt;a href="img_1203_text1.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1203_text1.jpg?w=72" alt="LED lighting, side-by-side comparison">
&lt;/a>In the picture on the right, you can see the result. The topmost bulb is a normal Phillips 25Watt &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot; lamp, which produces the expected &amp;quot;Incandescent&amp;quot; lighting. The wall behind is yellow by the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bottom bulb is a 25Watt &amp;quot;Terracotta&amp;quot; lamp, also from Phillips. This is the warmest color you can buy, and it's even slightly to yellow for my taste, but better than the normal white bulb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The middle bulb is the Parlat &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot; 2Watt LED lamp. As you can see it is nowhere near &amp;quot;warm&amp;quot;. It produces an ugly green-blue-ish color which has a colder color temperature than the incandescent &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot;. The 2 Watts is not nearly enough to even maka the wall behind it light up in the photo. Because of the plastic LED housing in the bottom of the bulb, it is unable to produce an even light pattern, and results in ugly shades in my lamp cover.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Additional Field Work
**&lt;a href="img_0384.jpg">&lt;img src="img_0384.jpg?w=117" alt="LED lighting on display">
&lt;/a>Last weekend I got a tip from my dad, a local shop had some LED bulbs on display. To rule out the possibility of having bought a faulty lamp, I drove to the shop to take a look for myself. The result: I didn't even buy a lamp, I snapped a picture with my iPhone instead. The dark banding is caused by interference between the camera and the light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the left are fluorescent bulbs, which look quite ok. On the right: LED lighting, again in the ugliest of all colors, even more blue than the one I ordered online. The lamps in the middle are also LED lights, but have more LED's in them and produce more light, and are slightly less &amp;quot;blue/gray&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**How to Improve
**I think the lighting industry needs someone with authority who can think, has authority, and some taste. LED lighting would be(come) a lot better if it did:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Laboritory employee, proudly showing LED lamp: _"Look boss, we made this beautiful lamp. Here, let me turn it on for you"_
&lt;p>&lt;em>-plink-&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Ehm. right. What kind of color did you say this was?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Employee, looks at the lamp and tries to lie at his boss the same way he is planning to lie to the customers: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Warm white ofcourse. We measured it at 3000K&amp;quot;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;It's not &amp;quot;Warm&amp;quot;, it's not &amp;quot;White&amp;quot;, it's not &amp;quot;3000K&amp;quot; and it's not beautiful. Do you know what this is?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Employee, feeling like he has been caught: &lt;em>&amp;quot;No, what boss?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;The reason you are fired.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/blockquote>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Final Thoughts
I think LED lighting is the future, and I really hope that it becomes a lot better. But until then, you have been warned. Don't buy LED (or any other) bulbs &amp;quot;unseen&amp;quot;. Don't go by the temperature or &amp;quot;equivalent watts&amp;quot; crap. Use your eyes and your brain.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For now, I'm holding on to my beautiful incandescent lamps, and I will buy boatloads of them if the Dutch governement is stupid enough to think about banishing incandescent lamps without accurate, usable, affordable alternatives.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are you a Wise person?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/18/are-you-a-wise-person/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 01:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/18/are-you-a-wise-person/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="duckedit.jpg" alt="Rubber Duck">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Ducks migrate for the winter, they are able to have their brain &lt;a href="http://news.softpedia.com/news/Can-Birds-Sleep-While-in-Flight-74549.shtml">partially asleep&lt;/a>. This comes in handy when you have to fly hours on end in a pack, without restbreaks. Aparently, people have started to adopt this habbit. Yes you've read that right. I've seen some very good examples of people using only one half of their brains.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me give you an example. Do you have healthcare insurance? Does that insurance company make nice promises about actually helping you get better? Does the commercial include smiling people being helped immediately by loving, caring, smiling people of the insurance company? Probably the answers to all those questions are yes.
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Machine has no brain">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those of you who were unfortunate enough to actually have had to collect healthcare, know it's different. First of all, they require you to go through lengthy procedures with lots of forms which take sometimes months to process. Never mind if you lost your hand and can't fill them in, you'll get them anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, the hospital wants to get paid, so you need to use your life savings to do that, hoping you will get it back from the insurance company later, which is somethimes very unlikely. And although they make you think otherwise, insurance companies actually start blabbering about insuring the &lt;em>cause&lt;/em>, not the &lt;em>damage&lt;/em>. Now what customer cares about that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All these people could actually know how you're feeling, but they choose not to. They might even know how to really help you, but that part of their brain has been in sleep mode for years. They hide behind the rules and procedures, and lie about being &amp;quot;unable&amp;quot; to bend them. You could be one of those people, maybe even without knowing. Can you figure out what the intention was behind the rules and procedures, instead of just folowing them? If you're wise enough, you could probably find a way to actually understand and help your customers, maybe even without bending rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_our_loss_of_wisdom.html">&lt;img src="afbeelding-11.png" alt="Barry Schwartz on losing wisdom">
&lt;/a>So, are you a wise person? Barry Schwartz has a very good and &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_our_loss_of_wisdom.html">inspirig TED talk&lt;/a> about this. It is a brilliant 20 minute talk, and I couldn't have said it better. Please find some time to watch it, it's available free of charge, in high quality, also as podcast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's lead by example.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tweet Week</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/rolfje">&lt;img src="twitter-logo.png" alt="Twitter">
&lt;/a>About a week ago, I was a bit bored and decided to see what Twitter is all about. I created an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje">account&lt;/a>, and I Tweeted for a week. I tried to keep to the original idea, where a Tweet should answer the question &amp;quot;What are you doing&amp;quot;? Looking back, my tweets include &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1198486833">Coffee&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1199748992">Podcasts&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1200610213">Global frustration&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1203692363">Small joys&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1206502512">Small irritations&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209317512">Re-tweets&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209634779">Replies&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Twitter is a service were you can send short texts of 140 characters or less, called "tweets". These texts end up on a webpage, resulting in a micro-blog for all to read. Think of it as SMS-ing to your blog. One of the fun parts of Twitter is that people find really creative ways to express themselves in 140 characters or less. This allows you to follow an amazing amount of people, getting short messages about what they're doing, such as ["is relaxing with the wife and kids..... at home"](https://twitter.com/richard_hammond/statuses/1209417438)  or   ["Great meal at Michael Minna with my best gal"](https://twitter.com/ev/statuses/1211691640).
&lt;table border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["at"](afbeelding-1.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Should you find a "Tweet" you think is interesting, you can reply to that person (not to the tweet directly) by starting your tweet with an "@" and the username of the person you want to reply to. 
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["hash"](afbeelding-2.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >You can even "tag" your Tweets by using a "#" and a word. So for instance "#rolfje" would add the tag "rolfje" to my Tweet. You can then easily [search tweets with this tag](http://hashtags.org/tag/rolfje). Tags are sometimes used to create something of a "communications channel". For instance, the [#followfriday](http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday) tag is used to tweet about people you think are worth following.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
Starting in the US, Twitter is becoming increasingly popular all over the world, now taking over Europe. [BBC had an item](http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/7287536.stm) on English television about twitter, massively increasing the number of English twitterers. 
&lt;p>And ofcourse, where there are people, there are money-sharks to spoil the fun. Some companies are showing up, and are clearly not understanding what Twitter is about. They start a twitter account and twitter promotional messages, product releases, etc. The problem with this (for the company) is that for this to be succesful, people must follow you. If there's nothing interesting to read, people will not follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This same problem occurs with people who have their staff update their twitter accounts. This makes for really uninteresting, unpersonal tweets, and replying to them will almost never result in a nice conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com">&lt;img src="http://laikaspoetnik.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/twitter-addicts.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**What I used:
**During my Tweetweek, I tried different OSX and iPhone clients. There are a lot of clients out there, but none of them are good enough to be your &amp;quot;single client of choice&amp;quot;. Here's what I think of them, in short:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl&lt;/a>: Done in Adobe AIR, multi-platform and consistent accross OS's. Good for a Windows app, terrible for an OSX app. Settings are in strange places, not clear what the &amp;quot;narrow&amp;quot; column mode is for. Ugly but probably the best twitter client out there, with twitpic and tinyurl integration all out of the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetdeck.com/beta/">Tweetdeck&lt;/a>: Also done in Adobe AIR, mutli-platform and consistent. Works fine, has multiple columns for monitoring your tweets, search results and profiles. Feels a bit funny, for instance the same icon is used for &amp;quot;show input window&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;send tweet&amp;quot;. It works, but it doesn't fit the &amp;quot;clean and simple&amp;quot; design I think a twitter client needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific">Twitterific&lt;/a>: Nice design, clean. Not much features, too overpriced. If Twitterific had tinyURL and twitpic integration, and sold for about $5, it would be a huge hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=296415944&amp;amp;mt=8">Tweetie (iPhone)&lt;/a>: The funny thing is that &amp;quot;Tweetie&amp;quot;, the iPhone twitter client is way better than any of the clients I tried on a normal computer. Tweetie wins hands down. The best twitter client for the iPhone, simple and clean, camera integration, GPS integration. This also fits way better in the twitter philosophy, Tweeting whatever you are doing, wherever you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I learned:&lt;/strong>
Twitter is for everyday people, like you and me, and feels like a mix between &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens'_Band_Radio">CB radio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texting">texting&lt;/a>. Twitter is all about you and who you follow. It's definetely not about your followers. Ofcourse you can try to get as much followers as possible, but I think that does not guarantee a nice twitter experience. Some people think it's rude not to follow back if they're followed, and will tweet to let somebody know that they're being &amp;quot;un-followed&amp;quot;. I think that's not how the system is supposed to work. There's also no real relationship. Follow or unfollow, it's not like you're devorcing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just Tweet, and see what happens. There's no currency, only small text messages from people around the world for you to read and reply to. Or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bill's Mosquitoes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.png" alt="Bill Gates Releases Musquitoes">
&lt;/a>Bill Gates found a very good way to get the news reporters to pay attention to the malaria problem. In his talk at the TED conference, he released a few mosquitoes, stating that malaria should not be just for poor people to experience. People who did not see the whole performance may react shocked, because when placed out of context it sounds like an outrageous thing to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that's the case, you should maybe &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">have a look at his talk&lt;/a>, available (for free, without registering) at TED.com. You'll see that the audience is actually laughing when he releases the mosquitoes, and at the end of the talk Bill gets a standing ovation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the malaria problem, Bill also makes a very good case about how important good teachers are, and what we can do to help teachers become just that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get well soon</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/30/get-well-soon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 23:16:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/30/get-well-soon/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="bouquet-brights.jpg" alt="bouquet-brights">
Dear Steve,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Congratulations on the 25th aniversary of the Macintosh. I was sorry to hear that you are not feeling well and took some time off. Try not to worry about work, enjoy the time with your family and take care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get well soon,
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Buddha had a stroke</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/21/buddha-had-a-stroke/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 22:03:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/21/buddha-had-a-stroke/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.drjilltaylor.com/">&lt;img src="a3e21e0649e9184e84173c7c12eb10cd.jpeg" alt="Dr. Jill Bolte Taylor">
&lt;/a>Here's Jill Bolte Taylor. She's a brain scientist, studying schyzofrenia, and the micro-circuitry in the human brain which causes these (and other) mental illenesses. On the morning of September 10, 1996 she had a stroke. Amongst all other things that went though her head, she realized that this was a tremendous oportunity because she got to study this phenomena first hand. Luckaly, she fully recovered, wrote a book about it, and did a very impressive presentation about it at the 2008 TED conference, called &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/jill_bolte_taylor_s_powerful_stroke_of_insight.html">&amp;quot;a powerful stroke of insight&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having watched this presentation, I realized that Zen monks already figured this out a long time ago, without knowing that they were talking about left or right brain halves. Here's a short recap of what your left and right brain halves do:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**Right Half**
&lt;p>&lt;img src="human-brain.png" alt="Real Human Brain, held by Jill Bolte Taylor">
The right half of your brain is a paralel processor. It processes all the information coming in from your bodies' sensory system. It is concious of your body, it's current dimensions, it's current position. Your right half connects you to the world around you. It does not care about where you were 5 minutes ago, or where you are going. The right brain half lives in what Zen monks are calling &amp;quot;the here and now&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Left Half&lt;/strong>
The left brainhalf is a serial processor. It processes the information gathered by the right half, and stores it into memory. It is very linear and methodical. It associates the information of the right half with memories it stored, and projects things into the future. It's your left brain half which is reminding you to pick up the laundry, or go to the dentist. Your left half is also considered to contain your &amp;quot;ego&amp;quot;, and opposed to your right half, it is seperating you from the rest of the world. The left brain half contains the things Zen monks consider to be less usesful, like &amp;quot;regret&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;want&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enso">&lt;img src="496de0282ed5598be80c6ab014a5b104.jpeg" alt="Enso">
&lt;/a>When Jill talks about what she sees as &amp;quot;Lalaland&amp;quot;, I think it has a great resemblance to what Zen monks believe to be &amp;quot;enlightenment&amp;quot; or &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bodhi">&amp;quot;Bodhi&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. It is a state in which the mind is freed from suffering and worries. Without maybe realizing, Zen monks know how to disconnect their left and right brain, or at least shut down a large part of their left brain. This has even &lt;a href="http://www.pubmedcentral.nih.gov/articlerender.fcgi?artid=2518618">measured in an MRI experiment&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zen Buddhism, is largely based around a story, which describes how a normal man called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gautama_Buddha">Gautama Buddha&lt;/a> reached this state of enlightenment. After that, he set out to tell other people how to do this, and this has more or less lead to the whole Zen culture we know now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Combining the story about Gautama Buddha and Jill's talk, I think we can say that Jill was &amp;quot;uncontrolled enlighted&amp;quot; taken one step further than what we would consider to be practical. I also think that we have to consider the posibilty that Buddha just had a stroke, survived, and lived on to tell about it, just like Jill.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro Victories</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/11/micro-victories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 20:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/11/micro-victories/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="trophy_icon.gif" alt="Trophy">
The last few weeks I was frustrated about not being able to write any code for the project I am on at work. My days are filled with email, &lt;a href="http://discuss.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?joel.3.276499.40">spreadsheets&lt;/a>, documents, discussions and distractions. All important stuff, I'm sure, but none of it has got to do with actual coding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried to write code during the evenings for that project, just to get my kicks. Two things happened:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Frustration grew, because I feel that this is the kind of work I should be doing during the day. 
2. As I worked the late night hours, I realized I could never get it all done because the blocks of work were simply to large and required too much research to be done during a few evenings.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- more -->In the midst of this all, I held a presentation about Coding Quality at work. The presentation was all about taste, caring for a good product, and putting some love and care into your code. That, and the whole [continuous integration](http://clintshank.javadevelopersjournal.com/ci_build_game.htm) and [unittests](http://junit.sourceforge.net/doc/testinfected/testing.htm) stuff ofcourse. During the questions session, the [FindBugs](http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/) plugin for Eclipse came up. This is a plugin I have installed, but I rarely find/make the time for working through the warnings it genereates.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://video.google.de/videoplay?docid=7209282843949564567&amp;amp;q=insect+animation">&lt;img src="spider.jpg" alt="Bug and Spider">
&lt;/a>I did a small demo of Findbugs, and it sure worked. There they were, the stupid mistakes in my code, on the beamer, in front of all my collegues. Ofcourse Murphy says that any beamer will always be at it's sharpest and brightest when your slide has an error on it. In my case, even the people in the far back could clearly read the tiniest font in my edit window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back home, I knew there is no way I can get these fixed during working hours, so I created a seperate Eclipse installation at home running Findbugs. As I started fixing some of the most humilliating little bugs, I found out that I couldn't stop. I spent the whole evening tinkering with the code, and it fealt great. Today I suddenly realized why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Findbugs presents me with little things I can do within 5 minutes each, and when done, there is that next one looking at me. Not surprising, this is also the recipe for &lt;a href="http://www.gamegirl.com/article/105406/top-7-addictive-video-games/">addictive video games&lt;/a>. You can pick the game up and get right in, and you can stop at any time, but you don't want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every 5 minutes, I solve a bug, run unittest, commit to CVS and feel good about having done that. It's a string of Micro Victories which are really thrilling and relaxing at the same time. There's &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/carl_honore_praises_slowness.html">no time pressure&lt;/a>, no requirements, just me, my good taste and a good feeling for each little bug solved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brilliant TV</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/08/brilliant-tv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 22:46:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/08/brilliant-tv/</guid><description>
&lt;p>People who know me know that I'm not a big fan of commercial TV. It hasn't got any depth, it usually underproduced, overmarketed and makes an insulting assumption on the viewer's intelligence. (Wow, all in one sentence :-) )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I usually get my information elsewhere. Most of the stuff I find interesting is provided through &lt;a href="http://antipattern.wordpress.com/2008/11/08/software-engineering-is-my-profession-programming-is-my-hobby/">RSS feeds&lt;/a>. Some of it is made available through &lt;a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/">audio podcasts&lt;/a>, which is brilliant when commuting. As for video, youtube looked promising, but the messy interface and sheer overload of people making silly movies with their mobile phones has made it hard for me to find actual interesting video there. The rating system with YouTube did improve the past week, but it's still hard to find stuff that interests me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter the TED talks. These are brilliant video's mostly of a &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/raul_midon_plays_all_the_answers_and_tembererana.html">presentation&lt;/a>, or sometimes &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/raul_midon_plays_all_the_answers_and_tembererana.html">music&lt;/a>. But generally, the TED talks are just that tiny bit more interesting than TV, without commercials, and with real contents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just now I finished watching Mena Trott's entertaining presentation on &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/mena_trott_tours_her_blog_world.html">how blogs are building a friendlier world&lt;/a>. The &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/">TED.com&lt;/a> site is really clean, easy to browse and contains tons of video's about remarkable people with very interesting stories to tell. If my TV died, the only way I'd notice is when I switch on my PS3 to play a video game.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monkeys: How to get rich.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/23/monkeys-how-to-get-rich/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 10:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/23/monkeys-how-to-get-rich/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently got an email with a brilliant little fairytale about how to trick people into happily giving you all their money. I wanted to share with you, but it was in Dutch, and the origin was cleary not the original author.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I was &lt;a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/rummaging">rummaging&lt;/a> around the internet to see if I could find the original author, and I did. I found out that the Dutch story was freely translated from an English source. Here's the original story from that English source, unaltered (and with reference):&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;blockquote>**Monkeys**
&lt;p>Once upon a time in a village, a man appeared and announced to the villagers that he would buy monkeys for $5 each. The villagers seeing that there were many monkeys around, went out to the forest and started catching them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man bought thousands at $5 and as supply started to diminish, the villagers stopped their effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He further announced that he would now buy at $10. This renewed the efforts of the villagers and they started catching monkeys again. Soon the supply diminished even further and people started going back to their farms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The offer increased to $15 each and the supply of monkeys became so little that it was an effort to even see a monkey, let alone catch it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man now announced that he would buy monkeys at $50. However, since he had to go to the city on some business, his assistant would now buy on his behalf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the man’s absence, the assistant told the villagers “Look at all these monkeys in the big cage that the man has collected. I will sell them to you at $45 and when the man returns from the city, you can sell them to him for $50 each.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The villagers rounded up with all their savings and bought all the monkeys. Then they never again saw the man nor his assistant, only monkeys everywhere!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And THAT ladies and gentleman is how the stock market works…&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(by John Sinteur,
as published on October 25th, 2008
on &lt;a href="http://weblog.sinteur.com/2008/10/monkeys-2/">&amp;quot;the Daily Irrelevant&amp;quot;&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Design by Management</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/29/design-by-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/29/design-by-management/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A lot of great ideas start in the heads of creative minds. Unbound by budgets, planning, and customers, these ideas are passed around, and some of them turn into projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As soon as companies and managers get involved in realizing great ideas which are not really theirs, things can go very wrong. The least that can happen is that something isn't built. Tomtom on an iPhone? A brilliant idea and &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/topNews/idUSB46553120080609">technically possible&lt;/a>, but &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/journals/apple.ars/2008/06/11/latest-iphone-sdk-agreement-limits-gps-software-capabilities">non-technical people get in the way&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->What's maybe worse is that something actually does happen. Adding "mail document" to Ms Word for instance. Or putting a Calendar application in the dashboard of a Prius. This we call ["feature creap"](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_creep) or ["scope creep"](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scope_creep). When features are added not because the customer wants them, but because management thinks they can charge for it.
&lt;p>Another thing that can happen is that as carefully designed product is rolled out, which suddenly picks up sales. Now that it's a succes, the design is pulled from the people that had the original idea, and some manager decides to make it &amp;quot;better&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there are the managers that understand to leave things alone. Don't hold your breath, these managers have another trick to ruin things: time pressure. Leaning on people and putting constraints on things effectively makes them no worse than the manager who decided to &amp;quot;make it better&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Becomming a manager may mean getting a better salary and a nice office, but statistically you have a bigger chance of being clueless while telling others how to do their jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of this is happening because there are people on the &amp;quot;workfloor&amp;quot; who think that the way &amp;quot;up&amp;quot; is &amp;quot;management&amp;quot; without realizing that managing is actually a profession you should learn, or like I always like to say, &amp;quot;be&amp;quot;. There is a fine line between learning a trade and intuitively being a craftsman which people almost never get to cross.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good team can perform with a lousy manager, and the other way around. So why is it that the manager is always the guy with the bigger salary?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse there are people who do not fit this whole story, but they're probably typing flames in the box below this article which I will then have to delete with a smile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that a lot of this &amp;quot;you need a career&amp;quot; sillyness will go if we start paying people what they're worth, and stop paying huge amounts of money to those who clearly do not deserve it. You can start today by asking yourself if you want to earn more money, or do you really want to become a manager, even if it pays less?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe finaly the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janitor">janitor&lt;/a> will get payed a proper salary, maybe even more than that lousy boss of his who works 3 hours a day on a desk grunting at his staff. I wouldn't mind if our janitor made more money than I do. He works hard for it, he deserves to make a good living.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Take their money, then take the pain</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/20/take-their-money-then-take-the-pain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/20/take-their-money-then-take-the-pain/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Just to get this out of my system, I'll tell you what I think of the current crisis in the monetary system. It starts off with a fictional story, and explains why we need to get rid of the monetary system, and &lt;a href="http://www.contrarianprofits.com/articles/physical-gold-is-the-only-real-sanctuary-from-inflation/5661">why you should have physical gold&lt;/a> in your safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Suppose I have a nice big bar of gold, sitting in my very safe personal walk-in vault (hey it's my fantasy). I can't do much with a bar of gold so I decide to sell it to you for a thousand dollars. I suppose you don't have a cool walk-in vault, so I offer to keep it in the vault for you. You leave with a certificate.
&lt;p>The money is safely stored together with the gold. Suppose my neighbour also wants to buy a bar of gold. I show him the one in my vault and sell him that same bar of gold. Nobody will know, the bar is in my safe, and both owners can come to see it without knowing they're not the sole owner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything looks okay, but what I've done (except for the plain fraud) is devaluate your dollars, compared to the gold bar which is still in my vault. By now you should probably have noticed that I'm a bank. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because nobody can check what I'm doing in my safe, I can keep this up for quite a while. With all the money, I can loan money to people, and charge interest. Now I'm creating more money from money which wasn't real to begin with. When people loan money for their houses, I effectively own their houses because the money they lent from me is not real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can go on and on, reselling fake dollars on stock markets and so on. Now suppose somebody defaults on his morgage.  By now I am entangled in my own web of money-shoving, so I have to sell that house to be able to pay my debts to other people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, the system collapses and people will partly start seeing what I've done. Because everybody now depends on my created system, it can not be undone without hurting people. So the governement steps in and keeps my little system in place, and even gives me a big bonus for doing god knows what.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looks familiar? I personally think that pumping money in our defective system is not going to help in the long run. The system is not based on real value, it's based on pumping around money, and devaluating it in the process by adding more virtual, non existent money. All people involved in keeping this system alive for their own benefit should be severely punished for knowingly tweaking the system for their personal gain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week, the ING stock dropped 27 points. Our &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; Dutch governement pumped a large sum of money into the bank. Now, the stock is 20 points back up. Guess who profited from that? Exactly, stock brokers who thankfully used the governement-provided tip. While it is illegal to have trading tips, this one actually is provided by the governement itself. Nice huh?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our tax money is going to the wrong people, no matter what we do because we're at the wrong end of the crooked system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a morgage at the ING for our small but way too expensive apartment, and I still think that our governement should not have done this. We should round up the people who actually think this is a good system, and punish them by at least moving them to the wrong end of the stick, where we are. Get their money and use it to undo at least some of the damage they did to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes, it will hurt. We will have to start over. But guess what? If done right, it will be equally hard for everybody. It may look like your house drops in value, but what actually happens is that the true value of your currency goes up. If I'm not mistaken that's what people usually want for their countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes, it will have to be done globally. Although it may have started in America, the concept of the monetary system is a worldwide problem. Look at that bank in Iceland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new monetary system will probably also be based on gold, because we can't come up with somehing better than that. So what you want to do is &lt;a href="http://www.bullionvault.com/">get gold&lt;/a>. But not on paper. Actual, physical gold, preferably not as jewelry, because that's usually impure and harder to sell because it's value is not always measured in weight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what we really need to do the most, is take all (yes, ALL) the money, cars and houses from people who take our money, devaluate our houses, and get a large Christmas bonus for it. Everybody complains about it, but nobody does it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting a high Google Quality Score.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/19/how-to-score-with-google/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 19:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/19/how-to-score-with-google/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="askdave-greenarticle.png">&lt;/a>The past week, I've heard some collegues talking about tweaking websites so that they will show up in Google search results. A lot of people actually try to figure out how to &amp;quot;fool&amp;quot; the Google search engine, and actually make a living writing books about it. The strange thing is, that a lot of people want to be the&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=Tapestry+OGNL+adaptor+for+class"> &amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> link in Google even when the search query hasn't got anything to do with the content they're providing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's actually a funny discussion, because this behaviour which &amp;quot;makes use&amp;quot; of the system, actually breaks it. Suppose a lot of people figure out how to get this done. Now, whenever you use Google, your first page of search results will actually contain stuff you're not looking for. After a few tries, you'll get tired of this and start using a different search engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->It's almost like today's monetary and financial systems, where somebody figures out a way to make money in a dubious way and knowing it. In the end, we know what will happen, but that's a whole different subject (keep posted ;-) ).
&lt;p>For some search terms, this site (yes, rolfje.com) is actually &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=replace+headlights+xsara">on the first page&lt;/a>, and sometimes even the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=lost+oracle+password">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> (I wonder for how long). Why? Well, because the good news is that at Google, there are a lot of smart people working on tweaking the search algorithms each day, to prevent people from succesfully creating &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_bomb">Google bombs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other very important reason is that when Google &amp;quot;crawls&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;spiders&amp;quot; this site, the content it's going to find is real, readable and honest. There are no &amp;quot;hidden fields&amp;quot; in the article which act as spider magnets. When somebody finds this site and likes it, chances are very high that they're going to link to the content. For Google, that's bonus points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do I do that? By doing the following 4 important things:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Do not try to influence Google&lt;/strong>
By adding false content like hidden search terms, malicious &lt;a href="http://www.developer-resource.com/spider-food.htm">spider food&lt;/a>, and paying people to link to your site, you may end up high on any search. The trouble with that is that you are not reaching your intended audience (they were looking for something else). By showing up again and again on the first page, people will develop &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_blindness">&amp;quot;ad blindness&amp;quot;&lt;/a> for your site name. This means they will never, ever click on anything which looks like your URL because you've &amp;quot;betrayed&amp;quot; them before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2) Educate people, educate Google&lt;/strong>
Did you ever have that problem that you were searching for an answer on Google, but all you found were other people with the same question you had? And when you found the answer, did you blog about it? No? Too bad, that was the absolute chance of getting an &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=tomcat+utf8+requestdumpervalve">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3) Put some effort in your posts&lt;/strong>
I can't count the number of times when I found what seemed to be the answer to my question, but the page was hard to read, incomplete or plain wrong. If you want to be the &amp;quot;go-to site&amp;quot; for answers, write them as clear, consise, and complete as possible without using to much &amp;quot;fluff&amp;quot; or intelligent words. People will love you for it, and link to your posts. You can even re-use your own material by pointing to it when somebody asks you a question which you know your blog has the answer to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4) Layout!
The attention span of surfers is short. It's often measured in seconds, or in mouse clicks. To keep somebody on your site, you'd better come up with an easy to read article which contains at least a hint of providing a solution in the first sentence of the post. Having too much blinking ads, colorful layout or a small font will distract from the content, and people will leave early. This is caused by &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.useit.com/alertbox/banner-blindness.html">banner-blindness&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="askdave-greenarticle.png">&lt;img src="askdave-greenarticle.png?w=97" alt="">
&lt;/a>Here's a good example. I've made a screen shot of an &lt;a href="http://www.askdavetaylor.com/">&amp;quot;askdavetaylor&amp;quot;&lt;/a> article. Dave writes nice articles with answers to simple everyday Mac OSX related questions. Every now and then, Dave shows up in my Google searches, but not nearly as much as he could. Why? He violates rule 1 and 4. The page contains all kinds of words and links which have nothing to do with the actual content, and the layout is terrible. On the right, you see a screenshot of Dave's site, where I marked the actual content with a green color. Do you see how hard this must be to read? The article actually squeezes between some unrelated links and a very large Google ad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rolfje-greenarticle.png">&lt;img src="rolfje-greenarticle.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>As a comparison, I did the same with this blog. See the difference? The actual content is much closer to the top of the browser, and most of the time the answer can be found in the first few sentences. There is less distraction and less scrolling. Even if there is some scrolling involved, there are no terrible &amp;quot;next page&amp;quot; links to read further. &amp;quot;next page&amp;quot; links mean the article can not be printed, and it takes an extra amount of time reloading all the ads when I want to continue reading. Half of your audience is gone at the second mouseclick, and will never return (including their first click on the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=java+5+bigdecimal+oracle">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> button).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're still reading at this point, your attention span is longer than the average reader. Congratulations. It also means that you care enough about this stuff to apply to your own site. So I'll stop typing and let you to it. Remember: Focus, and try to be honest and to the point. Less is more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mine are real.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/27/mine-are-real/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 20:15:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/27/mine-are-real/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/08/the-first-law-o.html">Seth Godin pointed out&lt;/a>, &lt;em>&amp;quot;Organizations will work tirelessly to de-personalize every communication medium they encounter.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just to let you know, all my mail is hand typed, including the _&amp;quot;Kind Regards&amp;quot; _and my name at the end. You may find it silly, but I think it shows that you care. I always think about my greetings, and I even try to vary them every now and then. Having a default greeting underneath every mail, wether the content of that mail requires it or not is just plain silly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost just as &lt;a href="http://www.goldmark.org/jeff/stupid-disclaimers/">silly as the disclaimers&lt;/a> people put in the mail, thinking that it has any legal value, or even thinking somebody actually reads those.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next time you receive a mail from me, keep in mind that my greetings are actual, meaningful, honest greetings, personally written from me to you. You may have noticed that I am never &lt;em>&amp;quot;yours&amp;quot;&lt;/em>, because then I would be &lt;em>&amp;quot;truly&amp;quot;&lt;/em> lying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes, it als gives me an opportunity to leave them out, or tone them down. You're allowed to check your mail now. Go and feel special.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anything you say...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/14/anything-you-say/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 06:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/14/anything-you-say/</guid><description>
&lt;p>...can &lt;strong>and will&lt;/strong> be used against you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got an email with a great link to a blog post containing 2 links to great presentations on &lt;a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/07/why_you_should.html">why you should never talk to the police&lt;/a>, even if you're honest, or want to help, or have an alibi, or whatever. Never, ever answer any questions, no matter how trivial. Although this is an American presentation, it definetely applies to a great extend on Dutch and probably a whole lot of other European laws aswel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Pim for sending me this link. I really enjoyed the talk by Professor James Duane, he is a great presenter and a very articulate speaker. I'm jealous of the people in his class, it must be one good teacher.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Censorship: here to stay</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/12/free-information-guess-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 06:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/12/free-information-guess-again/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For those of you who think that media and information are free and uncontroled, guess again. Lately I have been seeing more and more incidents of large corporations hiding information, and even telling other people to hide it for them. I think this is plain wrong, and the guys involved should have been fired or punished otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have information which is of interest to the public, and somebody is making you sign a paper with which he can force you to shut up, you should think twice (and then not do it). Not because of the money, not because of the information itself, but for the sheer principle. Information should not be controled in that way. By anyone. It is dangerous.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Examples:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Blackhat Conference 2005: **Cisco** orders [tearing Michael Lynn's slides](http://cachefly.oreilly.com/make/cisco.mov) on leaks in Cisco's IOS out of the handouts.
* June 2006: **Microsoft** is [censoring Chinese blogs](http://www.wired.com/culture/lifestyle/news/2005/06/67842)
* July 2007: **India** is [censoring certain blogs](http://in.rediff.com/news/2006/jul/17blog.htm)
* Blackhat Conference 2007: Thomas Dullien (known as Halvar Flake), [was denied access](http://addxorrol.blogspot.com/2007/07/ive-been-denied-entry-to-us-essentially.html) to the **US** because he carried his presentation and some slides with him.
* Blackhat Conference 2007: **HID Global** [prevents Chris Paget to do a presentation](http://www.securityfocus.com/news/11444/1) on the [security flaws in RFID](http://www.theregister.co.uk/2008/04/08/e_passports_fingerprinted/)
* Blackhat Conference 2008: **Apple** [prevents Charles Edge](http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1616) from doing a presentation on a zero-day exploit in Apple's filevault by having him sign a non-disclosure agreement.
* 2008: The search results in [China are still censored](http://effortlessenglishclub.blogspot.com/2007/11/microsoft-censorship-lessons.html) by **Microsoft**, **Yahoo** and **Google**.
* 2008: India and China are not the only ones, judging [this wikipedia page](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_censorship)...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>When do these people realize that witholding information is only postponing the inevitable fact that people are going to hear about the stuff they are trying to hide? Are they really thinking that people all over the world, connected in all kinds of different ways, aren't going to notice what you are doing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse, they are doing a pretty darn good job so far, but it will break down eventually. Small are the minds of people who fear free flow of information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No Exclamation Please</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/01/no-exclamation-please/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 21:36:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/01/no-exclamation-please/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;figure class="float_left">&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exclamation_mark">&lt;img src="no-exclamation.png" width="80"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
Some developers nowadays still think that putting an exclamation mark in their log entries adds to the visibility of their entry. When other developers notice this, they will add even more exclamation marks so their log entries are even more visible. I compiled a few examples of bad log entries and some pointers for you to improve your log entries.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>In my current project, I've seen log lines like:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span class="ln">1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Logger&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="na">warn&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">(&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;No null allowed here !!!&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Or the &amp;quot;I really stand out&amp;quot; tricks like:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span class="ln">1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Logger&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="na">debug&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">(&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;-&amp;gt;-&amp;gt;-&amp;gt;-&amp;gt; Reached this line !&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Writing log entries like this really show your inability to use your &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment">IDE&lt;/a> for setting breakpoints and stepping through code,  while also showing your poor comunication skills. If I encounter these kind of log entries, I try to see if I can improve them, and/or adjust their level. Here are some pointers I use for writing log entries:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Be informative.&lt;/strong> Try to include all information in the log entry which could help the reader determine the reason or cause for this log entry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use full sentences.&lt;/strong> Write your log entries like a novel. It will make them easier to read, and will also allow system administrators to litteraly copy/paste the text into a mail when sharing information about problem analysis. They will thank you for it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Refrain from using &amp;quot;search strings&amp;quot;.&lt;/strong> Lots of stars, dashes or quotes do not improve readability of the log file, and it will make it look unprofessional. Searching for a bunch of stars is just as fast as searching for a word, given the right tools.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Don't overdo it.&lt;/strong> Try to have at most 1 log statement per method. Don't spoil it on trivial information, it will devaluate the rest of the entries in the logfile.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Using these guidelines, the log entries I showed you could be rewritten as:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span class="ln">1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Logger&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="na">warn&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">(&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">2&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;The method &amp;#39;storeUser&amp;#39; doesn&amp;#39;t accept &amp;#39;null&amp;#39; as it&amp;#39;s parameter.&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>and&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-java" data-lang="java">&lt;span class="ln">1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Logger&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="na">debug&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">(&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">2&lt;/span> &lt;span class="s">&amp;#34;The user with id &amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">+&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">user&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="na">getId&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">()+&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s">&amp;#34; was stored in the database.&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">);&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Comparing these new versions with the earlier examples, I think you will find that there is much more information in these, and you can now even guess that these entries are from a storage method in a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Access_Object">DAO&lt;/a> for storing users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important thing to think about when writing log entries is the level at which you log. For Log4J log messages, I use the following definitions to choose log levels:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>FATAL&lt;/strong> - The system has encountered such a severe error that it needs to shut down completely. No user can access the system after this log message. &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Core_dump">Core dump&lt;/a>&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crash_%28computing%29">Crash&lt;/a>&amp;quot; come to mind.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ERROR&lt;/strong> - A serious error prevented the action from completing. Although the application is still running, the user session is probably terminated or in an awkward state. Examples of ERROR are temporarily inaccessable databases or remote systems which prevent the current action from completing succesfuly. A few error messages should be enough to call second level support in the middle of the night.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WARN&lt;/strong> - The user session is still usable, and the system encountered an abnormality which should possibly be analyzed by a system administrator or level 1 support guy to see if corrective actions need to be planned.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>INFO&lt;/strong> - Info to the system administrator about interesting events. These events are &amp;quot;The application started up and is now ready for use&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;The application will use server XYZ for database access&amp;quot;. Informative or confirmative messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>DEBUG&lt;/strong> - Everything else. Stuff you don't really need to see in a production environment. In some rare cases, you can set the visibility of the log levels to &amp;quot;debug&amp;quot; in a production environment if you have a really strange problem and are willing to sacrifice some system speed and storage to analyze. System administrators will (should) not want to see this information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The last tip I am going to give you, which does not only apply to coding, but also writing mails and documentation in general:&lt;/p>
&lt;center>&lt;br/>&lt;span style="font-weight: bold; font-size: 1.5rem;">Never, ever use exclamation marks in professional texts!&lt;/span>&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/center>
&lt;p>Exclamation marks are a poor mans way of expressing the inability to indicate the importance of a sentence, while at the same time insulting the reader. Why do you assume that the reader does not get the importance of your words?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you ever wonder why I didn't answer your mail immediately, see if there are exclamation marks in there. And no, adding some will not help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conform Specs is not enough</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/07/12/conform-specs-is-not-enough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 19:13:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/07/12/conform-specs-is-not-enough/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Like any good software company, when a project starts, we sit down with the client, and talk about what we can do to help. The result is usually a more or less complete SRS (Software Requirement Specification). The SRS serves as input to the design fase (we usually already have an architecture sketch when the SRS is made) and those two documents are used to brief the developers and keep everybody posted on what to build. If all done correctly, this should then result in a perfect piece of software right?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Well yes and no. Recently I noticed a funny implementation of a requirement which proved to me that sometimes, people do not care enough to see what they are actually doing.
&lt;p>&lt;img src="conform-specs.png" alt="">
In this particular case, the customer wanted an authorization workflow built into a system so that administrators could aprove of a customer request. In the SRS it was clearly written that the state of the customer request should be easily visible, using traffic light icons. The developer that was responsible for this perfectly implemented the requirement, and created the traffic lights, as you can see on the right. Yes, these are exact copies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far so good right? Functionality implemented and working, no bugs, traffic lights according to specs. This was implemented 11 months ago, and the customer has not complained. He had no reason to. It was according to specs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These traffic lights are viewed by the clients employees and customers in 5 countries, about 4000 times a month. If any of these users are like me, they are probably amazed by the traffic lights. It has no hint of design in it. It was just hacked together. Look at the red traffic ligt. The red lamp is not in the middle of the black box. To me, it shows utter carelesness. The whole traffic light is 8 pixels wide. When hand-pixeling this in 800% zoom mode (which has obviously been done), the creator was so blind that he didn't take care in placing the lights in the middle of the black area. How blind can you be?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mission critical applications are expensive. So why is it that sometimes they don't &amp;quot;look-and-feel&amp;quot; expensive? Because it is all up to the developer to care about these details. Not only do you need perfectionists, you need passionate people wo actually care about what they're building and have a bad nights sleep when something is wrong with the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="good-solution.png" alt="">
I this case, I made an attempt to fix it by replacing the traffic lights with my own versions (shown at your right). To me, it is a huge difference. You may not like the design, but these lights at least show that we care. Because we do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don't just fight the specs. Beat them. &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jh_RGjqkJ04">&amp;quot;Swiftly, and with style.&amp;quot;&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Norton Fixes it's Software</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/06/how-norton-fixes-its-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 20:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/06/how-norton-fixes-its-software/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As you may know, Norton and Symantec were originally rivals in the anti-virus software market. Then, Norton bought Symantec and the two anti-virus products merged into &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_AntiVirus">Norton Anti Virus&lt;/a>. Yes, I know, I'm talking PC here. Bare with me on this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->If you are the "you do something with computers, don't you?" free computer repair guy to a lot of people around you, you have probably uninstalled Norton Anti Virus Trial Edition from more than a few newly bought PC's. And it was painful. Admit it. I know. I've been there. Several times.
&lt;p>A few months ago I discovered that maybe Norton is fixing this. But strangely enough, not in their software. They're using the community to solve it. And no, it's not by open-sourcing it either. It's by buying user opinions. Yes, you've read that right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-1.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-1.png" alt="effectiveness of Norton Propaganda">
&lt;/a>Check out the screenshot. It's an &lt;a href="http://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome">Amazon's Mechanical Turk&lt;/a> &amp;quot;HIT&amp;quot; (Human Intelligence Task). Here, the requester asks people to post positive reviews of the Norton Anti Virus products as part of a French scientific research project. (no, it's not photoshopped)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Norton is not really the requester, and I am probably blowing this out of proportion. But next time you're on a forum, and people start telling you how wonderful Norton Antivirus is, stop and think for a minute. They might be getting payed to tell you this. Doesn't that feel awfully close to a mini-&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Propaganda">propaganda&lt;/a>? Yes, I know, this is not news. But this screenshot reminded me of how easily some people trust information on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Online forums are great for sharing information. I really like the internet, and hey, I wouldn't be blogging if I didn't, now would I? But for all you know, I could be an Apple execitive trying to &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/12/02/hidden-get-a-mac-ads/">get people to &lt;/a>buy an Apple computer. Or a Seagate employee trying to sell you a drive instead of &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/10/24/no-such-thing-harddisk-warranty/">repairing your old one&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/05/21/ichat-saves-the-day/">Bruce&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm &lt;a href="http://fakesteve.blogspot.com/">Steve&lt;/a>. Or maybe I'm just a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCwGDihDkmE">FireStarter&lt;/a> :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BusySync vs Spanning Sync</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/03/busysync-vs-spanning-sync/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2008 19:31:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/03/busysync-vs-spanning-sync/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Google calendar is the new &amp;quot;Cool&amp;quot; in the calendar world. Or at least, the guys at work seem to think so. For me, a 100% online calendar is not always a good solution, because I can't take it with me. Getting Google calendar to sync with iCal would help, because that syncs to my phone and iPod. I tried BusySync and Spanning Sync to do this. One of them succeeded.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I've always been a FiloFax guy. My organizer is a typical one, it's rather big, and contains all business cards, papers, copies and notes I think are important enough to carry around. Every now and then (about every 2 years when I think about it) I try to migrate to a digital version. I've had a [Psion 3c](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psion_3), an [HP iPaq](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipaq), I tried to do the "[Print](http://www.43folders.com/forum/2007/10/10/google-calendar-index-card)-a-[Google](http://www.google.com/support/calendar/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=41067)-[Calendar](http://lifehacker.com/358308/convert-your-google-calendar-to-pdf)" trick, and even briefly used my [Sony Ericsson T610](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony_Ericsson_T610) as my calendar.
&lt;p>Every time, after a while, I find myself switching back to my trusty FiloFax. Usually because something happens to my calendar, or me not being able to access it. Failing backups, failing batteries, unreadable screens, awkward interfaces, and inability to scribble a simple drawing in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last weekend I entered a new cycle of getting it all digital again. I've been digital for a complete week now, and it doesn't feel too awkward. Maybe this time it will work...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Backing up&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before trying anything, I backed up my Google Calendars and iCal calendars. There wasn't much in them, but it's nice to be able to return to a known state. Yes, I have Time Machine but the trick of a backup system is not having to rely on it in your daily work. So here are 2 important links:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/calendar/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=37111">Backing up your Google Calendar&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://leopardtips.blogspot.com/2007/11/back-up-ical-and-address-book.html">Backing up your iCal Calendar&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Problem&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get a usable solution to view and update my calendar online aswell as on the road, without manual actions to get everything synchronized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Solution&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use Google Calendar for online editting, use iCal as central hub for synchronizing to all my devices, use my Nokia 6300 for viewing and editting on the road. My iPod nano is a nice extra for viewing my calendar when my phone dies on the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple has done a great job of synchronizing iCal to all my devices, so that's a no-brainer. iTunes and iSync take care of that flawlessly, even without me asking, for a couple of months already. It's just that I wasn't really using iCal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The challenge is in getting Google Calendar to sync with iCal. There are a &lt;a href="http://www.twistermc.com/blog/2007/06/28/sync-ical-google">couple of solutions&lt;/a> to do this, and I choose to give BusySync and Spanning Sync a try, because these feel most suited to my wishes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BusySync&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first program I tried was &lt;a href="http://www.busymac.com/">BusySync&lt;/a>. It's a bit bloated for what I wanted to do with it, but it's pricing model is nice, $25 for a license. I downloaded the trail and without reading the manual (because I think good software does not really need one) I tried to sync 2 existing calendars, one in iCal and one in Google Calendar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I immediately screwed up all my calendars, 3 times in a row. This did not feel good. BusySync has a way too complex user interface, too many features, and has one very big flaw: It can not sync an existing Google Calendar into an existing iCal calendar (at least, I didn't get how to do that). It is not clear about what it's doing and the whole &amp;quot;publish/subscribe&amp;quot; thing confuses me because I don't want to do either. I want to &lt;em>Synchronize both ways&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BusySync is trying to be the all-in-one solution for sharing calendars with Google, your friends, the neighbours dog, and back. It's more like a &amp;quot;Calendar Server&amp;quot; kind of application which feels like it has to be online, all the time. This may be fun for the tweak-freaks out there, but it sure was not solving my problem in an easy and elegant way. So, BusySync was quickly uninstalled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SpanningSync&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much less bloated, &lt;a href="http://spanningsync.com/">Spanning Sync&lt;/a> is a piece of software that only tries to solve 1 problem, and tries to solve it good. Spannig Sync can only do one thing, and that is synchronize Google Calendars with iCal calendars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Immediately after installing, I entered my Google acount data, and Spanning Sync fetches the Calendar list from Google. It then asks which iCal calendar I want to sync with which Google Calendar. Nice. Within 3 minutes, I had all (existing) Google Calendars synced with my (existing) iCal calendars. Flawlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I tried turning on the &lt;a href="http://www.macobserver.com/tip/2007/01/29.1.shtml">birthday feature of iCal&lt;/a>, and sync that to a new Google calendar. Spanning Sync politely warns me that this Calendar is not editable, and changes in it's Google counter part will not result in changes in iCal. Great, that's the kind of warnings I can live with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After synchronizing, I renamed my Google Birthday calendar to add the words &amp;quot;Read Only&amp;quot;, so I would not make the mistake of adding appointments there. Spanning Sync has no trouble with renamed Google Calendars. It recognizes them by a hidden unique identifier. Rename as you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see who has won the competition for me, hands down. Spanning Sync does a really nice job in synchronizing my calendars. The only downside is it's strange pricing strategy. You can use Spanning Sync for a year for $25. Or, you can buy an unlimited license, which will set you back $65.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because I returned to my FiloFax nearly every time I tried to &amp;quot;go digital&amp;quot;, I think I'll pay for a yearly license en see where it all ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The showdown&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my case Spanning Sync &amp;quot;just works&amp;quot; and in the end, that's what counts. I haven't touched the Spanning Sync preference pane for a few days, and it is still synchronizing nicely. My phone is also &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/04/27/homezone-more-seemless-sync/">synchronizing nicely&lt;/a>, so I really feel that the calendar is there for me, in stead of the &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/03/07/remember-the-milk-review/#more-263">other way around&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the top of my head, here are a few thoughts when comparing BusySync and Spanning Sync next to eachother:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >BusySyncSpanning Sync&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Multi-purpose, all-in-one, lots of bells and whistles
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Single purpose, simple user interface
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Publish/Subscribe model
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Two-way synchronization
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Can not sync existing Calendars
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Can sync existing Calendars
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Cheap, simple license
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Strange yearly license
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >$25
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >$25 a year, or $65 for an unlimited license
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>For now, it's my Nokia 6300, iCal, Google Calendar and Spanning sync for me. But maybe, in a few weeks, you'll read hwo lovely my FiloFax really is. It doesn't need batteries, is crash-proof and allways-on. :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sell a Name or an Image?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/30/sell-a-name-or-an-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 08:45:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/30/sell-a-name-or-an-image/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The new marketing &amp;quot;trick&amp;quot; seems to be to give a product a nice name, which sounds &amp;quot;expensive&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;design&amp;quot; like. So the marketing boys come up with a nice name. Compaq for instance has been using &amp;quot;pressario&amp;quot; for a while now. But when I say that I have a &amp;quot;pressario&amp;quot;, do you really know what kind of computer I have? Do you know which computer to buy when you hear my praise on my great new computer?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Probably not. And that's what amazes me at the current marketing tactics. Let me give you a couple of examples. If I say I have a pressario, I could have any of these computers (and this is ony a small selection of the ones I found):
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images.jpg">&lt;img src="images.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="images-1.jpg">&lt;img src="images-1.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-2.jpg">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-2.jpg">&lt;img src="images-2.jpg?w=135" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-3.jpg">&lt;img src="images-3.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So there's a problem for Compaq, which they have created themselves. &amp;quot;Pressario&amp;quot; does not identify anything. It can be a laptop, a desktop, and AMD processor, an Intel processor, with or without DVD player, small or large amounts of memory, and with or without monitor or keyboard. So what does &amp;quot;Pressario&amp;quot; mean?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem seels to be common for modern marketing. Look at the Renault Mégane for example. When Renault just started with the Mégane series, it was really clear what kind of car you were buying. But now, there are many Méganes on the market. Here's a small selection of Mégane models I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-4.jpg">&lt;img src="images-4.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-5.jpg">&lt;img src="images-5.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-6.jpg">&lt;img src="images-6.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-8.jpg">&lt;img src="images-8.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what kind of car you drive? In the old days, when you had a &amp;quot;Mustang&amp;quot;, people knew what car you had. The name was synonym to an image, and people knew what car to ask for if they wanted to have it. And the sales people knew what car to order for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No matter how hard you try to give a product a name, if you use that same name for a different product, people get confused, and you will never be able to build an image.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stretch pants...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/26/stretch-pants/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 14:13:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/26/stretch-pants/</guid><description>
&lt;p>... invented for people who order size 12 pants for their size 18 butts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The vi religion</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/05/the-vi-religion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 22:22:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/05/the-vi-religion/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Every age has it's tools. Many, many years ago, in 1976 to be exact, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Joy">squinty-eyed nerds&lt;/a> with a social deficiency ruled the computer world. They talked to eachother in a secret code, wore geeky clothes and made sure that everybody thought that computers were magic. To make sure that nobody could ever use a computer to edit a file, they all swore to never ever use another editor than... &lt;scary music> &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vi">vi&lt;/a> &amp;lt;/scary music&amp;gt;.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->To make sure nobody understood how to work with vi, they had the editor behave like 4 different programs. To switch between the modes, you had to ritually punch the right combination of keys while singing the imaginary theme song of [NetHack](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nethack). Backwards. To make it all look as a good thing, they even came up with a techy sounding term for all this: "modal editor"
&lt;p>For good measure, the SONAU (Secret Organization of Nerds Against Usability) even came up with a devious name for the editor. With a reference to the world &amp;quot;visual&amp;quot;, nobody was going to believe you were using an editor even if they were looking at your screen full of green text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vi even has a&amp;quot;camouflage&amp;quot; mode where it starts up showing a column of &amp;quot;~&amp;quot; characters. Ha! Now the mortal user will be really lost! Nobody will be able to edit a file, ever again! &lt;em>MUHAHAHAHAAAAAA&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ok sorry. lost myself a bit there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the SONAU people were in charge,they made sure that every computer shipped with vi. No other editors were allowed. A few brave people at the University of Washington secretly wrote a nice editor called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pico_%28text_editor%29">pico&lt;/a>. They had to come up with a way to get this editor onto many systems without the SONAU people noticing. So they wrapped pico into what probably is the first Trojan Horse on a computer: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pine_%28e-mail_client%29">pine&lt;/a>. Cleverly disquised as a hard to use email client, pine was approved by the SONAU High Concil and before anybody realized, pico was on many computers around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With pico, some people where actually able to edit documents and even programs, and the SONAU lost quite a bit of it's powers. Now, after 30+ years, computers are actually usable, and editors are actually &amp;quot;visual&amp;quot;. Because SONAU still has an active underground organization, the term &amp;quot;visual&amp;quot; is still being avoided, and the strange term &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYG">WYSIWYG&lt;/a>&amp;quot; is used. Actually, the term WYSIWYG also applies to vi in combination with a 9-needle &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot_matrix_printer">dot matrix printer&lt;/a>, but nobody dares to say that out loud. You also didn't read this on this blog, capiche?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many SONAU members became infurtile by the green screen radiation. An even bigger group thought that women were creatures whose only purpose in life is yell (g)EEEK, turn around and run away. Still, some SONAU members managed to avoid getting a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwin_award">Darwin Award&lt;/a> and had children. These children were subtelly brainwashed, and are now scattered over the internet, posting messages about how good their life is with vi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Painfully desoriented and unable to see the big picture, these children would rather count the atoms in the plastic molecules of their red bike helmet than see the big truck that's comming their way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a collegue like this once. At first, he thought I had supernatural powers for being able to refactor multiple files with code within 5 seconds. In weeks of therapeutic talks, healing and training sessions, I finally got him to see that it was &lt;a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse&lt;/a>, not me, who was doing the refactoring he could not get done in vi. Shortly after he realized I was a mere mortal, and not even exceptionally bright, it dawned: All the work he'd done in the past 10 years could have been done in 2 weeks with a better suited tool. He left the company, and nobody saw him since...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://blog.eleutian.com/2008/01/18/VimScreencast1.aspx">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Example of a bad editor">
&lt;/a>Today I found another poor soul. Even while doing a screencast, typing in vi and telling about what he is doing, he can't see that using the letters &amp;quot;h&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;j&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;k&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;l&amp;quot; for navigation is very strange while your keyboard has had arrow keys for the past 20 years, and a mouse for the past 15 years or so. The flashing text in the film like &amp;quot;Esc is bad, Ctrl-[ is good&amp;quot; shows how big the psychiatric problems of vi users is. No sane persion today will press a cryptic 2-key combination while being able to use the much more intuitive &amp;quot;Esc&amp;quot; key to escape from a certain mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="http://blog.eleutian.com/2008/01/18/VimScreencast1.aspx">the screencast&lt;/a> and by your reaction, I will tell if you are a SONAU member.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For people without patience, here are a few absolutely hilarious texts in the screencast which will make you wonder why people are still using vi:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Insert mode: don't use the arrow keys
* Block cursor is &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot;, thin cursor is &amp;quot;insert mode&amp;quot;
* Esc (bad) ^[ (good)
* Visual mode is like holding &amp;quot;Shift&amp;quot; to select stuff
* Arrow keys bad!
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>vi is the editor which in &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot; can not edit text, and uses a seperate &amp;quot;append&amp;quot; mode to add text to the &lt;em>end&lt;/em> of a line, while using &amp;quot;insert&amp;quot; mode to insert text &lt;em>inside&lt;/em> a line. It's users are misguided members of their own &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sect">sect&lt;/a>, firmly helping eachother to keep up vi's name, while ignoring reality and other people's belief or needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's not about tools; it's about people</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/30/its-not-about-tools-its-about-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 16:22:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/30/its-not-about-tools-its-about-people/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week a collegue of mine did an introductory talk about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Rational_Unified_Process">RUP&lt;/a> (Rational Unified Process). It was an interesting talk about how RUP can be applied in projects, what the philosophy is behind RUP, and lessons learned during her first RUP workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the talk, we discussed how RUP looked a lot like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DSDM">DSDM&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development">Agile&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extreme_Programming">XP&lt;/a>. In all these methods, developers are arrogant enough to &amp;quot;demand&amp;quot; customers to conform to their process. Sure there is a lot to be said for consulting the customer often, and having lots of pre-releases, but the customer is still the customer, not your in-house &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_assurance">QA department&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Another funny thing is that all these methods are trying to solve "problems" which were carefully described by [Frederick Brooks in 1975](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mythical_man-month).
&lt;p>The past 33 years, a lot has changed in the computer industry. Computers have become much faster, programming languages much more powerful, offices have airconditioning and good coffee, and you no longer need to have a soldering iron to be a good programmer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, in the past 33 years, people have not changed. Programmers tend to fiddle too long with a cool, simple, fast but wrong solution to a non-existing customer problem. Managers tend to report &amp;quot;on schedule&amp;quot; while actually they are behind schedule. Customers think that the testing phase is there to be removed in case of a time/budget problem. And still, the majority of people think that simply hiring more people will get the job done faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The real problem in a project is not hardware. It's not software. It's not planning. It's not RUP, DSDM, Agile or XP. The real problems in a project are people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckaly, we're not all lost. Some projects actually do get finished on time, on budget, and with all features included. These successes are often attributed to the methodologies used, the brilliant programming language, or the good weather. Do you know what I think? These succeses are nothing more than the result of a good team of people, who actually care for the project to become a success. A team which has enough common sense to know what to do, and when to do it. A team which gets a kick out of having a happy customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing computer programs is a bit like solving a lot of puzzles in a day. It's a creative process, and although you can make rough estimates, you'll never know how much puzzles you are going to solve today. Writing programs in a team is a bit more complicated. You need to know what your team members are up to, and what their strong and weak points are. Deviding the puzzles between the team members needs to be done with great care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a process like RUP or any other (maybe self-made) process will be fine, but will only work if everybody in the team knows why this process was introduced,what it solves and what their role is in that process. If the goal is clear, and the team is a true team, the members will have no problem correcting eachother, and accepting corrections from eachother. It will become a sport.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the real solutions in a project are people. More precisely: people who take their profession seriously, 24x7.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remember The Milk review</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/07/remember-the-milk-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2008 19:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/07/remember-the-milk-review/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This morning I thought I had way too much tasks, way too much paper on my desk, a messy inbox, and a cluttered schedule. Then I made a terrible mistake: try to solve this with more tools. You don't always solve &amp;quot;more X&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;more Y&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I remembererd a discussion about ["remember the milk"](http://www.rememberthemilk.com/), a free online todo list with all kinds of taggin, grouping, mailing and Googletalk features. I registered, and happily set of pouring my life into the thing... or so I thought.
&lt;p>As it turns out, it is extremely hard to grasp the user interface of this thing. After registering I was apperently in the &amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot; mode without knowing it. This prevented me from adding tags to tasks for some strange reason. After I found out that I was in the wrong mode, I went to &amp;quot;Overview&amp;quot;. This gives you the tasks for today, tomorow and next week. If you've added tasks without a date, these will not show up here, which is really annoying. There's also no way to add tasks in this view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add tasks in the other screens or groups, you need to remember keyboard shortcuts to get to the functionality you want. There are some links which can do the trick, but for some reason they are not in a logical place. Combined with a very wierd &amp;quot;mouse over&amp;quot; mode where you can only see details of a task when moving your mousepointer over the task, this userinterface really isn't user friendly in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most irritating, and perhaps even killer &amp;quot;feature&amp;quot;: Marking tasks as &amp;quot;finished&amp;quot; is not done by clicking on a &amp;quot;finished&amp;quot; button on the task, but by tick-marking them, and then pusing a button on the top of the screen. I actually had too look for the button for 5 minutes before I worked out how I could finish the task. On my paper todo list, a tickmark marks it as &amp;quot;done&amp;quot;. In Remember The Milk, a tickmark has a whole different meaning and that really bothers me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all I spent 30 minutes with Remember The Milk, I managed to create 1 extra folder, add 5 tasks in the user interface, and 1 task by mail, and tag 3 of them. Then I decided that a todo list should not have a learning curve at all. In addition, I realized that adding this tool would add to my things to do, namely transferring and constantly synchronizing my work into this tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I returned to my trusty paper throw-away todo list, and my paper filofax, and realized again that these work best. I also found out that there are more people realizing this. Take a look at &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/2007/07/simplifying-david-allens-complicated-gtd-setup/">this interisting article&lt;/a> at zenhabits.net. Sometimes, GTD just adds to yor work, in stead of getting the original work done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus. Don't let the shiny tools distract you from your actual work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If Not HTTPS Then Exit</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/12/19/if-not-https-then-exit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 22:42:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/12/19/if-not-https-then-exit/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hello kids. Yes, if you are writing applications for consumer companies, there's a good chance I'm talking to you. We need to have a talk, urgently. It's about a whole new way of doing things, and it's a new word in your dictionary. The word is &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.m-w.com/dictionary/secure">secure&lt;/a>&amp;quot; (linked to Webster's for your convenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Security is a funny thing. Everybody thinks it's very important, some people think it's a synonym for "complex" and some people avoid it because it's "too much hassle". Most worrying are the people who have online shops and think they can do without, particularly if they think "expensive".
&lt;p>Online shops which started out as simple &amp;quot;sell stuff from the attic&amp;quot; stores, seldom have good data protection in place. The &amp;quot;my expensive server does not need to backup&amp;quot; problem aside, most of the time there's nothing in place preventing hackers from stealing data. If that's the shopkeepers data, that's not a big problem. The problem gets bigger if the shopkeeper stores customer data in his system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most larger shops are often developed by students or hobbyists, who can hack some HTML, or maybe even PHP and MySQL. In a short time, a shop is up and running, the student is payed a small amount and the shopkeeper is happy. The forms in the shop requires customers to register and login before buying, because some twisted minds out there think that having a password is absolutely essential to communicate with customers (I have 82 passwords last time I checked). Those same twisted minds also have the guts to ask you everything from your shoe size to your dog's name, and make those fields &lt;em>required&lt;/em> in the registration proces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now suppose that shop sells &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unobtainium">Unobtanium&lt;/a>, and you really need that for your project. You see that it's in stock, so you enter the registration process to be able to fill your shooping cart. You fill in your dog's name, press &amp;quot;register&amp;quot; and your data is sent to the server... unencrypted! The hacker monitoring the site's traffic sees your personal information and uses it to steal your dog, selling it online through e-Bay the next day with relative ease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I typed and removed a whole rant about shops asking you way too much information because sick marketing minds think they are god and can ask and use your information as they please. But some shops need information to ship the products to you. Aside from offering you Unobtanium for a very attractive price, they also need to earn your trust for you to enter your personal data. Funny thing is that nobody seems to care if that site is passing information around using plain http.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have had email discussions with 3 companies so far who asked me to register online over http connections. When a company sends my personal. private information or password over http, I send them a mail I can not comply because of the simple fact that the password is rendered useless by sending it in plain text over the network. Most companies don't see the problem and think they are doing everything perfectly safe (those are the scariest). Then there are the companies who know it is in fact not safe, but simply state that they don't care, or don't want to pay for an &amp;quot;expensive&amp;quot; secure solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think in most cases, &lt;a href="http://www.kelkoo.co.uk/">these&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.buyonline.nl/">buttugly&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.absoluteword.com/order/">shops&lt;/a> (of which the last can't even display it's own Russian characterset) are developed by you, my dear World-of-Warcraft playing, family kid-genius friend. The world is in the hands of &lt;a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=zitface">zitfaced&lt;/a> 13 year old &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leet">noobs&lt;/a>&amp;quot; to life who think downloading software without paying for it is cool, and have the nerve to tell shopkeepers that their PHP-MySQL-Tomcat solution on an old 386 machine running the obscurest version of default-installed Linux without firewalls over http is perfectly safe to store customer data and VISA card numbers. These kids are probably the very same kids who think that &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.cs.utah.edu/~gk/atwork/">under construction&lt;/a>&amp;quot; is a very normal term to use on your site because they are, in fact, developing software on the live production server and their tiny mind can't think of any other way to hide those parts from the customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, I lost myself there, but you get the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I really don't get, is that with the computing power nowadays, protocols like http still even exist. Why isn't each and every server doing https by default? Even my 3-year old mobile phone can do https, so let's fase out http alltogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the site administrator is anything like the one at my office, chances are that a lot of sites will have random, or self-signed certificates which are expired 2 days after they're made, never to be replaced with new ones. To circumvent this, we should have a public-certificate server like a &lt;a href="http://keyserver.pgp.com/">PGP key server&lt;/a>. When I access a site with an unknown certificate to me, I can check that certificate at some centralized server, where I can find if this certificate is really belonging to that site (yeah yeah I know about certificate chains, but admin's don't). Besides that, the site could also list if the shops is handling it's data carefully, if your email address is sold, or used to spam you. This data can be statistical, and/or based on customer reviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next step is that in stead of your browser showing you a tiny, small lock icon at the bottom of your screen indicating this is &amp;quot;safe&amp;quot; https, the browser should display a big fat red cross accross the whole site indicating that it's &lt;em>not&lt;/em> https.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trouble this will cause, is that site admins will still not protect their data, but hey, I guess there's only so much you can do. Maybe we need a global police department running site-scans to detect unsafe sites, and list them on the public certificate-server we discussed for everybody to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next step would be to make it illegal to store data that's not yours in an unsafe manner. Yes internet is &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; and I think we should try to keep it that way in the original sense of the word in the early internet years. Right now, the word &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; on the internet is used to defend the rights of (internet)criminals. But that's a different story...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For now, make sure your data, any data about you, is transported over https. Spam companies who are still using http or otherwise unsafe methods to transport your data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wordpress.com is a good example...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escape from Alcatraz</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/29/escape-from-alcatraz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/29/escape-from-alcatraz/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Should you be in the position that you are convicted to spending 3 or 4 hours in the Dutch &lt;a href="http://www.alcatraz.nl/politie.html">Alcatraz theatre program&lt;/a>, there are a few things you should know beforehand. The photographs on the site have absolutely nothing to do with the show itself, and should not be used to judge setting or quality. The audience is not only encouraged, but in fact required to play an active part in the &amp;quot;show&amp;quot;. The whole show is based on humiliation of people in front of their friends/collegues. The show is definetely not wheelchair friendly, and toilets are in fact unreachable by wheelchair.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->This is what will happen:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * From the moment you enter the building to the moment you leave, you and your party will be shouted at, insulted, and treated as infants. There will even be some public physical humiliation too for a few chosen ones.
* Depending on the arrangement, you can be called by name to step forward, and are then subject to cheap jokes based on information given to the cast prior to your arrival.
* There is no real break. The show lasts 3 to 4 hours, and during that time there are a few brief moments you can drink or eat in a tiny space cramped with 20 people in a cell, sitting on wooden benches.
* Entertainment will be limited to a few sing-and-dance moments, of which at least 2 will contain singing &amp;quot;Je ne regrette rien&amp;quot;.
* Performances will range from moderate quality to cheap to plain vulgar, generally the stuff you'd expect at cheap backalley theatres.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>These are pointers to survive:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Do not enter the building in the first place, unless you are socially forced or tricked.
* Eat before you enter. Although food is advertized to be served, it is of avarage microwave-meal quality, and there is a big chance you are not allowed to eat all of it.
* Drink before you enter. Getting a drink means you have to communicate with one of the cast. This can result in more humiliating shouting, no matter how polite you ask.
* Mingle and dissapear in the crowd. Try not to be at the edges of a group. The concrete pillars will block a lot of the view of the cast, make use of them to stay out of sight, but be casual about it.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Picking a good moment and route to leave:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. After entering the building, it will be some time before you can leave without alarming anyone. Wait for the right moment.
2. There will be a &amp;quot;trail&amp;quot; where the &amp;quot;judge&amp;quot; will read cheap and uncomfortably personal jokes about you and your party from a piece of paper. Moving our coughing will place you in the center of attention. Hold still.
3. You are sent to walk down an isle while hearing a long, slow and boring story about a made-up Alcatraz inmate and his wife. The cast is around you in uniform, still no chance to leave without a trace.
4. The lights will go out while everbody is standing close to eachother, and a lot of noise will be made with the prison bars around you. Claustrofobic people will definetely not like this. The door behind you is black, closed and barely visible, still no good time to leave.
5. Lights will go on and you are ordered to enter the cells, about 10 to 20 people per cell. The cells have no doors that can be closed. There will be some shouting, ordering you to stand up if you're sitting, and sit down when you're standing. The guards have a strange fascination of ordering people to put their hands in the air.
6. At some point, you will be given soup and bread. Don't bother with it, it will be taken from you as soon as everybody starts to eat.
7. [![Alcatraz escape plan](alcatraz-escape.thumbnail.jpg)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](alcatraz-escape.jpg)As soon as you see a green bus entering the building, that's your queue. It signals a &amp;quot;break&amp;quot; in the program where preople can get drinks.
8. Walk to the bar where wine and soda is served (marked drinks/food in &lt;a href="alcatraz-escape.jpg">the map&lt;/a>).
9. When at the bar, kindly ask where the toilets are. You will be directed (ordered) through a black door, and you'll find yourself in the room where the trail was held, and the toilets and wardrobe are. The white doors can be opened from the inside, try the small door next to the wardrobe first. (Follow the red line in the map).
10. Walk to your car and hope noone misses you before you can start it. After that, enjoy your freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote this plan because I regret leaving earlier. I kept thinking this nonsense could not last 3 hours, but it did. There are people who like this kind of entertainment very much, but I don't. The problem is that if your party has a good time, the social pressure of joining the fun can be tremendous, and can lead you into doing stuff you'll regret later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would strongly advise against going to this show.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scholierenstaking (Dutch)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/27/scholierenstaking-dutch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 20:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/27/scholierenstaking-dutch/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Tijd om auto's in brand te steken van onschuldige mensen die daar jaren voor gespaard hebben want ojee, de scholieren krijgen 1040 lesuren. En dat terwijl ze 960 uur al genoeg les vinden met al dat huiswerk dat ze krijgen. Het is zelfs zo erg dat het komt tot &lt;a href="http://www.rtl.nl//actueel/rtlnieuws/binnenland/articleview//components/actueel/rtlnieuws/2007/11_november/19/binnenland/1119_1519_arrestaties_scholieren_sittard.xml">Aanhoudingen bij scholierenstaking&lt;/a>. Misschien is het tijd om het op een akkoordje te gooien.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Nou kan ik heel makkelijk shermen met statements als _"wees blij dat je les krijgt"_ en _"de kindjes in Afrika..."_ maar dat komt natuurlijk allemaal niet aan en bovendien wordt ik daar zelf ook misselijk van. Om een beetje een beeld te krijgen waarom die 1040 uur nou zo'n probleem is, heb ik even een simpel rekensommetje bedacht. (Nee, dit mag je niet van je studieuren aftrekken).
&lt;p>Straks, in de grote boze wereld werk je 40 uur per week. 40x52 weken = 2080 uur per jaar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Natuurlijk werk je niet iedere week de hele week. Je krijgt meestal tussen de 25 en 30 vrije dagen per jaar. Laten we rekenen met 30 vrije dagen, dat is 30x8 uur = 240 vrije uren per jaar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Daarnaast zijn er natuurlijk feestdagen die niet in het weekend vallen, laten we even zeggen dat we daar een stuk of 10 van hebben (lijkt me aan de ruime kant). 10x8 = 80 uur vrij i.v.m. feestdagen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hoeveel uren werkt een gemiddelde werknemer met een voltijd baan dus ongeveer per jaar?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2080 - 240 - 80 = &lt;strong>1760 uur per jaar&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In vergelijking met een gemiddelde werknemer heb je na de 1040 lesuren dus nog 720 uur over om je huiswerk te maken. Dus stel, je ergste droom wordt werkelijkheid en je krijgt bij alle vakken huiswerk mee. Je kunt dan voor ieder uur dat je op school zit ruim 41 minuten huiswerk maken, en dan ben je nog steeds klaar voordat pa en/of ma thuiskomt van zijn/haar werk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Het lijkt er bijna op dat het aantal uren op school bijna niet meer is dan een goede smoes om wat herrie te trappen. Maar door het lage aantal schooldagen door alle vakanties kan de lengte van de schooldag natuurlijk wel oplopen. Omdat scholieren meer vrije dagen hebben moeten ze de lesuren dus in minder werkdagen verstoken, en dan zou het wel eens op een complete werkdag kunnen gaan lijken, waarna je je huiswerk nog moet doen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik ben geen scholier meer, dus ik kan er niet zomaar een oordeel over vellen. Er is een stemmetje dat zegt dat de meeste ouders misschien wel 3000 lesuren per jaar zouden willen invoeren. Waarom? Dat wat eerst nog &amp;quot;een leuk babietje&amp;quot; leek, blijkt minstens 21 jaar lang 24x7 support nodig te hebben, en een hoop geld te kosten. Zoonlief kan tenslotte ook niet met een tweedehands iPod op school komen, wat moeten de andere ouders daar niet van denken?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omdat Pa en Ma kaalgeplukt worden door een regering die niet met centjes kan omgaan, en toch ook wel gehecht zijn aan de BMW X5 en de grote eensgezinswoning (lees: zelf ook niet met centjes om kunnen gaan) moeten ze alletwee blijven werken. En tsja, dan is het lastig dat je kind vroeg van school komt, als je zelf niet thuis bent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vroeger was naschoolse opvang meer een soort service voor incidentele gevallen waarbij zoonlief even niet thuis terecht kon. Het groeit nu uit naar een &amp;quot;standaardpakket&amp;quot; waartoe scholen verplicht worden. Naschoolse opvang is gegroeid tot een &amp;quot;collectieve kind dump service&amp;quot; voor mensen die niet nagedacht hebben over het opvoeden van een kind. Sommige mensen herinneren zich de reclame &lt;em>&amp;quot;wie is toch die man die zondag het vlees komt snijden&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Dit is voor veel gezinnen tegenwoordig gruwelijke werkelijkheid geworden, zelfs zo erg dat het &lt;em>&amp;quot;wie zijn toch die mensen die me ieder weekend naar de IKEA brengen en denken dat ik dat leuk vind?&amp;quot;&lt;/em> gaat worden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Misschien moeten we dus voor een compromis gaan: Nou vooruit, 1000 lesuren per schooljaar, op voorwaarde dat er ten alle tijde één van beide ouders thuis is om de kinderen op te vangen. Daarmee wordt de kostbare naschoolse opvang overbodig en hebben leraren wat meer lucht. Het lost gelijk nog een probleem op: Kinderen hoeven elkaar niet meer op te voeden. Ouders zijn gewoon thuis en kunnen de kinderen corrigeren (tsja sorry, dat hoort erbij) en normen bijbrengen (alweer sorry). Zoals bijvoorbeeld de norm dat je niet andermans spullen sloopt als je het zelf ergens niet mee eens bent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zullen we met zijn allen eens normaal gaan doen?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stuff to think about</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/05/stuff-to-think-about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 20:36:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/05/stuff-to-think-about/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Normally I try to steer clear of any politics, beliefs, or war on this blog, but I could not resist to link to this &lt;a href="http://video.google.nl/videoplay?docid=1296126090432829344">google video&lt;/a> I found, where Arab-American psychologist Wafa Sultan has some strong words to say to (extremist) Muslims on Al-Jazeera. Although broadcast in February 2006, I just noticed it, and I think she has some good points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personaly I don't believe you should interfere with people's lives if they're more than 10km away from your home (and they shouldn't interfere with yours). Say hello to your neighbour and ask how his/her day went. You'll notice that you can often help or solve your neighbours problems easily. Stop worrying about those people 10.000km away. If their neighbours follow your example, soon the world will be an even better place!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It ain't what you do...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/11/02/it-aint-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 19:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/11/02/it-aint-what-you-do/</guid><description>
&lt;p>...it's the way that you do it. Last week I noticed a funny thing in an application I'm involved in as a developer. For logging in to the application, the term &amp;quot;Log On&amp;quot; was used. However, for logging off, &amp;quot;Log Out&amp;quot; was used. This did not feel right, so I searched a bit on the use of these terms. It looks like more people are having trouble choosing one form or the other, and are also mixing on/off and in/out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.m-w.com/dictionary/log%20in">&lt;!-- more -->Log in&lt;/a> / Log out
This is the Unix variant for logging in and out a user. Note that &amp;quot;Log in&amp;quot; is two words. In modern dictionaries like the Merriam-Webster's Collegiate Dictionary, &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; is written both as &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;log-in&amp;quot;, with a hypen. &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; is a synonym for the main entry, &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot;. Funny detail is that the dictionary has no entry for &amp;quot;log out&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.m-w.com/dictionary/log%20on">Log on&lt;/a> / Log off
This is the Windows variant for logging in and out a user. As with &amp;quot;Log in&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Log on&amp;quot; is always written as two seperate words, optionaly concatinated with a hypen. Merriam also doesn't contain entries for &amp;quot;log off&amp;quot; or alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.m-w.com/dictionary/sign%20in">Sign in&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="http://www.m-w.com/dictionary/sign%20out">Sign out&lt;/a>
This is the Google (and several other websites) variant of &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;log out&amp;quot;. It is arguably the best choice on earth for log in and out actions, because of the following reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. The term &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot; is often used to send people to a URL, without actually logging in. Example (as heard on TV): &amp;quot;Log on to www.nbc.com for more information.&amp;quot;. This use of the term &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot; confuses people as to what the term &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot; means.
2. The term &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; suffers more or less from the same problem as &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot;. Like &amp;quot;log on&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;log in&amp;quot; has no counterpart in Merriam-Webster's dictionary.
3. The term &amp;quot;Sign in&amp;quot; is a clear association with physically entering a building, and in this case, a system.
4. &amp;quot;Sign in&amp;quot; has a clear counterpart in Merriam-Webster, &amp;quot;Sign out&amp;quot;, and is less likely to be intermixed with &amp;quot;log out/off&amp;quot;.
5. For some reason, everybody knows that &amp;quot;Sign in&amp;quot; is written as two seperate words.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Yes I know, it sounds like a lot of trouble for a seemingly little thing. But I like to be consequent when writing code, thereby hoping that other people can actually read, understand and maintain my code as I would like to be able to read, understand and maintain theirs. Programmers often spend (much) more time trying to understand other people's code than writing new code of their own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To come back to the start of all this, I changed &amp;quot;Log in&amp;quot; to read &amp;quot;Log on&amp;quot;, so the application is now a Windows-like &amp;quot;Log on&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Log off&amp;quot; application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sharpening, denoizing, smoothing, enhancing, vandalizing!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/17/sharpening-denoizing-smoothing-enhancing-vandalizing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 15:23:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/17/sharpening-denoizing-smoothing-enhancing-vandalizing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To every photo-editing, image-manipulating, red-eye-reducing software developer on the planet: Sharpening photographs by default is NOT a good idea! If images aren't sharp directly from the camera, there was something wrong with them to begin with. Most camera's nowadays make fine pictures which don't need sharpening.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Reason for this post is that just a few minutes ago, I was wondering why my new (and expensive) Canon 350D still showed noise in blue skies, even at 100 ISO. It turned out not to be noise. It was [Lightroom](http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/lightroom/) (the public Beta application for OSX) tries to "Sharpen" and "Smooth" the images by default, and not by a small amount, I might add. So the little dust particles which were perfectly captured by my excelent camera with that excelent lens, were (cough) "enhanced", after which the very nice flat-blue sky turned in to a freckle disaster. I also heard that [Rawshooter](http://www.pixmantec.com/products/rawshooter.asp) does the exact same thing. It's really a shame, because a good lens, a good camera, some experience and a little effort should produce sharp photo's to begin with.
&lt;p>Sure I like the &amp;quot;digital darkroom&amp;quot; idea of being able to do some post-processing of photographs, but I am convinced of the fact that you should have quality material to begin with (meaning a good photo). I think that for every minute you spend trying to make a great shot with the camera in your hand, you save 15 minutes trying to correct mistakes with a mouse in your hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I am not a star photographer. Yes, I need to tweak some photo's to get the effect I was looking for with the camera. Yes, I am trying to learn to do it directly with aperture and shutter speed, and yes, that takes a lot of time and effort because no, I'm not a natural :-) . Just venting some furstrations here. Sorry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dodenherdenking (2)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/04/dodenherdenking-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 15:52:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/04/dodenherdenking-2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Vorig jaar heb ik mij aardig druk gemaakt over de abnormale manier waarop steeds meer mensen met dodenherdenking omgaan. Dit jaar was mijn ervaring gelukkig een stuk prettiger. Ik heb een klein stukje van de herdenking op de dam gezien, en dat was duidelijk een stuk beter dan vorig jaar. De taptoe werd foutloos en netjes geblazen, zelfs toen er (hoorbaar) iets omviel. Chapeau. Ook het inzetten van het volkslied waarbij mensen spontaan mee begonnen te zingen was erg goed om te horen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Na de herdenking ben ik overgestapt op de uitzending vanaf de &lt;a href="http://www.grebbeberg.nl/">Grebbeberg&lt;/a>. Minder (geen) toespraken, een stuk beter. Van mij mag het commentaar bij de uitzending ook nog weg, dat past beter bij het &amp;quot;geen toespraken&amp;quot; beleid en zorgt ook voor minder gewauwel &amp;quot;kijk er staan veel mensen&amp;quot;... Ja dat zie ik! Geluid uit, en probleem opgelost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nee (nogmaals) ik ben geen herdenkinsfanaat, maar ik vind dat mensen wel weer eens wat meer op hun gedrag, respect en elkaar mogen gaan letten. Bijvoorbeeld: Prachtig als je op je blog schrijft dat je je irriteert aan aggressieve weggebruikers, maar geef je ook het goede voorbeeld als je in je auto zit?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;quot;A people that values its privileges above it's principles soon loses both&amp;quot;&lt;/strong> - Dwight D. Eisenhower&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, genoeg gezeurd. Zennnn.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inventive minds</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/28/inventive-minds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 20:17:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/28/inventive-minds/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Of all inventive minds, the religious mind must be the most inventive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can justify a massacre by refering to a book that essentially says &amp;quot;Thou shall not kill&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pomphouders dupe van 'spookliters'</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/24/pomphouders-dupe-van-spookliters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 20:52:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/24/pomphouders-dupe-van-spookliters/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For those that can read Dutch. &lt;a href="http://www.nos.nl/nos/artikelen/2006/01/art00006006024D.html">This&lt;/a> is a nice example of Dutch gasstation owners wanting to be compensated for the fact that gasoline (or any other fluid you can sell) schrinks when cooled.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->What happens is, that the delivery trucks cary the gasoline at the normal outside temperatures. When pumped into the underground tanks at the station, the number of liters is measured and the gasstation owner gets charged for those liters. Then, the gasoline cools down (and shrinks!) because it is stored underground. So when de car owners put the gas in their car, the cold ("smaller") liters get measured and the gasstation owner is "swindled by nature" because het can only sell say 99 liters of gasoline, while he bought 100 from the oil company!
&lt;p>Now, things get better because the gassstation owner wants to be compensated for this law of nature! It's like wanting to be compensated for the fact that you get wet when you jump in the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let's say this is &lt;em>really&lt;/em> a problem, because in my opinion it isn't, they make enough money and they could have known this upfront if they have had payed attention in first grade. You can basically do two things about this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Insulate the underground tank, and maybe even heat it. You can actually now &amp;quot;swindle&amp;quot; the car owners, because you can sell them &amp;quot;more&amp;quot; petrol than you have bought from the oil company! Woopee!. You might want to check your heating bill at the end of the year though, I doubt it will do you any good.
2. We can start selling petrol/gasoline by *kilograms*, which is actually allready standard in some forms of industry. It's a bit harder to measure, but absolutely independant of the temperature of the product
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Just another fine example of people allways wanting to change the rules and be compensated for anything they &amp;quot;missed out&amp;quot; on. And we find it strange that the world becomes more burocratic. tsss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSM Abonnement: Wisselen of blijven?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/06/gsm-abonnement-wisselen-of-blijven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/06/gsm-abonnement-wisselen-of-blijven/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This article is about selecting a new phone contract. Since this article describes a specific Dutch situation, it will be in Dutch. Sorry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dit jaar lijkt een constant &amp;quot;blijven of wisselen&amp;quot; jaar te zijn. Wil je de nieuwe zorgverlof regeling of blijf je spaarloon houden? Wil je een nieuwe Zorgverzekeraar of wil je bij je oude blijven? En vandaag is was mijn beltegoed voor mijn gevoel te snel op, en rees de vraag &amp;quot;Wil je prepaid blijven bellen, of wil je een abonnement?&amp;quot;. Gelukkig was de vraag bij welke provider ik wil blijven snel beantwoord, ik heb altijd goede ervaringen met Vodafone (als bedrijf) gehad dus het moet Vodafone blijven. Ik ben al lid sinds het nog Libertel heette, en heb ook nog steeds hetzelfde nummer.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Hoewel een abonnement al snel goedkoper lijkt, is dat niet altijd het geval, zelfs niet als je een maandje of twee flink wat meer belt dan normaal. Dat komt omdat GSM providers hun tarieven zo kiezen dat ze moeilijk te vergelijken zijn, en vooral ook antrekkelijk lijken te zijn.
&lt;p>Om een beetje wijs te worden uit de Vodafone tarieven heb ik eerst maar een selectie van candidaten gemaakt. Ik ben een prepaid fan omdat ik dan nooit aan het einde van de maand voor een verassende torenhoge rekening kom te staan doordat mijn telefoon per ongeluk ergens is blijven liggen of ik vergeten ben op &amp;quot;gesprek beeindigen&amp;quot; te drukken. Verder heb ik een prima tweedehands Ericcson T610 gekocht die het prima doet dus een abonnement zou van het &amp;quot;Sim Only&amp;quot; type moeten zijn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vodafone biedt voor deze situaties de volgende abonnementen:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * **Prepaid**, met het nieuwe &amp;quot;60 minuten halen, 3 betalen&amp;quot; tarief waarbij de eerste 3 minuten van het uur 35 cent kosten, en daarna betaal je niets meer (tot het uur voorbij is maar dat lijkt me een uitzondering). Dit tarief is niet voor niets zo gekozen. Vodafone heeft gemerkt dat de meeste gesprekken van prepaid bellers 3 minuten zijn, en dus gaan ze het schip daar niet mee in.
* **Sim-Only - Vodafone 12.50**, dit is een variant op het normale Vodafone 12.50 abonnement. Omdat je geen telefoon bij het abonnement koopt, krijg je korting. Zo is het maandtarief niet 12.50 zoals de naam suggereert, maar 7.50. Ook de tarieven per minuut liggen lager. Hoewel je een &amp;quot;beltegoed&amp;quot; van 50 minuten hebt, is bellen niet gratis. Bellen kost 9 cent per minuut voor elke minuut **binnen** je beltegoed. Bel je meer dan 50 minuten per maand, dan betaal je voor elke minuut **buiten** je beltegoed het standaardtarief van 25 cent per minuut. Vodafone heeft ook een 17.50, 22.50 en duurdere varianten van dit abonnement. Deze heb ik buiten beschouwing gelaten.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Voor diepgaander analyse moet je zelf maar even naar &lt;a href="http://www.vodafone.nl/">www.vodafone.nl&lt;/a> browsen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_vodafone-tarieven-2006.gif">&lt;img src="o_vodafone-tarieven-2006.gif" alt="Vodafone Tarieven 2006">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In bovenstaande grafiek kunnen we een beetje zien hoe de kosten verlopen. Onderaan van links naar rechts is uitgezet hoeveel minuten je per maand belt. Let op, dit is een gemiddelde, dat je dus niet per maand moet meten, maar over een jaar. Als je namelijk de eerste helft van het jaar bijna niet belt, en de laatste helft van het jaar erg intensief, en je hebt een prepaid abonnement, dan kun je toch nog steeds wel eens heel erg goedkoop uit zijn. Omdat prepaid bellers geen inzicht hebben in hun belgedrag is dit moeilijk te bepalen, je zult de gesprekstellers in je telefoon moeten gebruiken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Omdat het Vodafone prepaid tarief zo raar inelkaar zit, heb ik er 3 grafieken voor gemaakt, eentje voor 3 minuten gemiddeld per gesprek of minder (slechtste geval), 5 minuten per gesprek, en 10 minuten per gesprek. Let op, dit zijn gemiddelden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uit de grafiek kunnen we de volgende conclusies trekken:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Mensen die 3 minuten of minder per gesprek bellen, en meer dan 40 minuten per maand bellen, zouden kunnen overstappen op een abonnement. (Dit is meer dan 14 gesprekken per maand van 3 minuten of minder)
2. Mensen die gemiddeld 5 minuten per gesprek bellen, en meer dan 100 minuten per maand bellen, zouden kunnen overstappen op een abonnement.
3. Mensen die gemiddeld 6 minuten of langer per gesprek bellen, moeten absoluut niet overstappen op een abonnement. Hoe langer je gesprek duurt (mits binnen het uur) hoe goedkoper je uit bent.
4. Voor gemiddelde bellers (3 minuten per gesprek) liggen de omslagpunten tussen 40 en 110 minuten bellen per maand. Binnen deze band scheelt overstappen tussen abonnementen ruwweg 20% per maand, uitgezonderd overstappen van prepaid naar abonnement.
5. Los van de kosten zijn de abonnementsvormen ook op andere manieren (on)aantrekkelijk: Als je je provider niet leuk vind kun je een prepaid kaart zo in de hoek smijten; aan een abonnement zit je toch vaak minimaal een jaar aan de maandelijkse kosten vast.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Je kunt de grafiek ook andersom lezen: als je 40 euro per maand beltegoed uitgeeft en je bent een gemiddelde &amp;quot;3 minuten&amp;quot; beller, bel je ongeveer 115 minuten per maand. Je kunt dan het beste overstappen op een sim-only vodafone 22.50 abonement overstappen, mits je zeker weet dat je belgedrag niet minder word. Met het 12.50 abonnement ben je iets duurder uit, maar daarbij lopen de kosten sterker terug als je minder gaat bellen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik hoop dat dit verhaaltje heeft geholpen een betere keuze te maken. Voor mij is het nog steeds niet helemaal duidelijk, omdat mijn belgedrag grillig verloopt over het jaar en ik eigenlijk geen gegevens heb verzameld van afgelopen jaar. Het blijft dus nog even prepaid vrees ik. En ja, ik heb SMS bundels buiten beschouwing gelaten omdat ik een telefoon heb om mee te bellen, en niet om foto's te maken, spelletjes te doen of te SMSen. Telefoons moeten klein, en simpel zijn, zonder teveel toeters en bellen, zonder externe antene en zeker niet uitgerust met schuifjes of uitklapschermen. Alles wat kan bewegen kan ook afbreken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tot slot nog een tip voor prepaid gebruikers van Vodafone: Als je NIET accoord gaat met de nieuwe voorwaarden en je hebt een oude prepaid kaart, bel je dus NIET voor het 60 halen - 3 betalen tarief. Je betaalt dan gewoon 35 cent per minuut voor AL je minuten! Kijk dus even op de Vodafone site hoe je dit kunt veranderen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wikipedia is not the truth!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/12/13/wikipedia-is-not-the-truth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2005 21:18:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/12/13/wikipedia-is-not-the-truth/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.wikipedia.org/">Wikipedia&lt;/a> is not as good as you might think. Things written on Wikipedia are copied &amp;quot;verbatim&amp;quot; by other sites. By the time somebody checks the wikipedia story, he finds the verbatim copies and sees them as confirmation of the wikipedia story. And so the story stays on Wikipedia, spreading wrong ideas to schools, teachers, and you and I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spreading wrong information on the internet can have very big consequences, and &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/news/opinion/editorials/2005-11-29-wikipedia-edit_x.htm">John Seigenthaler knows this by personal experience&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->This is a typical case where the many good people suffer from the few rotten apples out there. Since Wikipedia is usually editted by the same people (although a large group), I think a simple, non-intrusive useraccount system would be the answer to these problems. Anonymous internet access is good, but when you write something about someone, I believe in the "open visor". If you write about a real person (with first and lastname), you should sign with your own real name (or at least be traceable). If you write about an alias, you should sign with your oen alias on that same system (or at least be traceable).
&lt;p>If the person who wrote the wikipedia article had done this, this whole situation could have been stopped soon. Maybe the writer didn't even do this on purpouse, but just got the wrong information. He could be contacted, the article could be corrected, and we all would have learned from it without too much harm done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, to all writers out there, be careful, because these days people still think that &amp;quot;what is printed (on screen) is the truth&amp;quot;. And certainly on the Internet, alas that is not the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yes, even on this blog I can make mistakes. But unlike wikipedia, my posts are traceable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where's North again?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/10/03/wheres-north-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2005 12:57:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/10/03/wheres-north-again/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Lately, I've been collecting race circuit locations using &lt;a href="http://earth.google.com/">Google Earth&lt;/a>. It's really nice to see the sometimes very detailed satelite images of race circuits. You can actually see the seperate kerbstone blocks of silverstone, and see how many cars there were parked at the time the picture was taken. You should try it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What really started to catch my interest is the fact that the maps of circuits as they are used in logo's or (worse) &amp;quot;how to get there&amp;quot;-maps are almost never of the &amp;quot;north pointing up&amp;quot; type. An example:
The circuit &amp;quot;Road America&amp;quot;, which is located a few miles north-east of Atlanta, Georgia, has a &lt;a href="http://www.roadatlanta.com/trackmap.lasso">web-site&lt;/a> which shows you a detailed map of the circuit, as well as pointers to the nearest highways. I have grabbed an image (because they only have these stupid noise making flash movie thingied nobody is interersted in after the second visit). It looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_road-atlanta.gif">&lt;img src="o_road-atlanta.gif" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in my quest to find this circuit using Google Earth, I found the circuit to be along the 53, halfway from the I85 to the I985, just like the directions stated. But, the circuit seemed to be &amp;quot;turned around:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_road-atlanta-google.gif">&lt;img src="o_road-atlanta-google.gif" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have noticed this with a lot of ciruits. I understand the need of turning and simplifying the circuit to make a nice logo, but when the circuit is depicted next to driving directions, I would make the map &amp;quot;north side up&amp;quot; so nobody gets confused. In the first image, the I85 apears to be west of the circuit, while it is actually east of the circuit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Earth location of Road America (so you can check for yourselves):&lt;/p>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
&lt;kml xmlns="http://earth.google.com/kml/2.0">
&lt;Document>
&lt;Style id="khStyle662">
&lt;IconStyle id="khIconStyle664">
&lt;Icon>
&lt;href>root://icons/palette-3.png&lt;/href>
&lt;x>224&lt;/x>
&lt;w>32&lt;/w>
&lt;h>32&lt;/h>
&lt;/Icon>
&lt;/IconStyle>
&lt;/Style>
&lt;Placemark>
&lt;name>Road Atlanta&lt;/name>
&lt;LookAt>
&lt;longitude>-83.81483349103033&lt;/longitude>
&lt;latitude>34.14598906888146&lt;/latitude>
&lt;range>2835.974155514713&lt;/range>
&lt;tilt>-8.888997363646108e-012&lt;/tilt>
&lt;heading>0.3186400317363279&lt;/heading>
&lt;/LookAt>
&lt;styleUrl>#khStyle662&lt;/styleUrl>
&lt;Point>
&lt;coordinates>-83.81483349103033,34.14598906888146,0&lt;/coordinates>
&lt;/Point>
&lt;/Placemark>
&lt;/Document>
&lt;/kml></description></item><item><title>Dodenherdenking</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/05/04/dodenherdenking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2005 13:12:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/05/04/dodenherdenking/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Ben ik nou gek, of word dodenherdenking tegenwoordig een beetje &amp;quot;afgeraffeld&amp;quot;? Iedere Nederlander zou toch moeten weten hoe belangrijk het herdenken van de tweede wereld oorlog is (en zou moeten blijven). Toch lijkt het erop dat er steeds meer gemorreld wordt aan de gedachte, en de uitvoering van de herdenking zelf.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Tegenwoordig word er niet alleen aan de oorlog, maar ook aan allerlei andere zaken gedacht bij de herdenking. Dat vertroebeld volgens mij de echte kern van de herdenking. De tweede wereldorlog is een duidelijk beeld, wat goed uit te leggen is aan onze kinderen, en staat symbool voor alle slechte dingen en ideeen die we nu niet meer willen hebben. Als iets ergens "symbool" voor staat hoef je niet een lijst met bijzaken aan te halen. Als je dat moet doen, moeten misschien scholen en media meer aandacht gaan geven aan het begrip "symbool". Mensen mogen echt zelf ook nog wel denkruimte hebben, we hoeven niet alles voor te kauwen (zoals op TV, zucht).
&lt;p>Door een waslijst bij te gaan houden waar de dodenherdenking allemaal voor staat, word het idee en de uitstraling wat mij betreft een stuk minder krachtig, en een stuk minder makkelijk uit te leggen aan de nieuwe generatie(s).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dat &amp;quot;minder belangrijk&amp;quot; merken we nu al. De muziek die vandaag is gespeeld had af en toe weg van iets wat niet zou misstaan in een vrolijke circusvoorstelling, of een spannende aflevering van StarTrek. Ik vind het jammer dat deze muziek duidelijk niet is getoetsd aan de gepaste stemming die er in mijn ogen zou moeten heersen op een dergelijk moment. Het hele jaar door hebben we tijd zat om allerlei vrolijke dingen te doen. Dat is ook waarom we de doden herdenken, en daarna bevrijdingsdag vieren. Op bevrijdings dag hebben we vrij. Dan vind ik ook dat je 1x per jaar het fatsoen moet kunnen opbrengen om een keertje stil te staan bij de gevallenen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Misschien wel het ergste voorbeeld geven de commerciele (Nederlandse!) omroepen. Zij passen de programmering er niet voor aan, na de herdenking (2 seconden na de stilte ongeveer) word de knop weer teruggezet en vallen we midden in een vrolijke aflevering van &amp;quot;Friends!&amp;quot;. Dat kan toch niet de bedoeling zijn van een herdenking?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gelukkig kon ik op Nederland 2 wel verder kijken. Wat trouwens opviel is dat tijdens de 2 minuten stilte de microfoons open bleven staan, waardoor er allerlei geluiden hoorbaar waren. Kan zo'n regiseur niet even de geluidsknop dichtdraaien om ervoor te zorgen dat het ECHT stil is, en even letten op de monitor waarop hij kan zien dat het Wilhelmus word ingezet om vervolgens de schuif weer open te draaien? Ik vond het erg knullig overkomen, luide geluiden van paardgetrappel (o.i.d.) en het huilen van een mevrouw die dicht bij de microfoon stond.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>En dan wijst de commentator er even fijntjes op dat alleen mensen met de Nederlandse nationaliteit kransen mogen leggen. Vlak daarna zien we 60 kinderen een bloemetje leggen die duidelijk niet van Nederlandse afkomst zijn. Hebben we dan niet weer juist die scheiding gemaakt? Zouden we na de oorlog niet juist geen verschil mogen maken tussen ras, afkomst of nationaliteit? De wereld heeft verdomme 5 jaar oorlog gehad met mensen die zo dachten, het maakt toch niet uit wie er een krans legt, als het maar met de juiste gedachte, bedoelingen en respect gaat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ik hoop dat sommige mensen eens naar een videobandje van wat oudere herdenkingen gaan kijken, daarvan leren en iets meer aandacht gaan spenderen aan de volgende herdenking. Misschien wel net zoveel aandacht als er gegeven word aan de mooie kleurige ragscherpe reclames in dolby surround met perfecte timing. Kom op jongens, het is niet ingewikkeld. Nee het is allemaal niet leuk, en we verdienen er vast geen geld mee, maar het hoort er wel bij. En als je het niet kunt, moet je het iemand laten doen die wel dat respect en geduld kan opbrengen. En nee, ik ben niet ouder dan 80, zelfs niet ouder dan 40. Mijn ouders hebben mij waarschijnlijk iets geleerd wat tegenwoordig niet meer in moderne woordenboeken past, of waarvan de spelling dermate is veranderd dat zelfs de betekenis verloren is gegaan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maargoed, ik zal niet te lang zeuren, want dan verpest ik jullie vrije dag nog, die ongetwijfeld wel in de juiste steming word doorgebracht, nadat je waarschijnlijk met de koffers in de caravan stond te hannesen om 8 uur, of zelfs al onderweg was met de kids luidruchtig en onwetend op de achterbank. Want ja, prioriteiten moeten er zijn natuurlijk he. Trompetles is er denk ik 1 van.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(original post and comments are &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/archive/2005/05/04/37873.aspx">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>