<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lathe on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/lathe/</link><description>Recent content in lathe on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 18:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/lathe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lathe Spindle rebuild, part 1</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/28/lathe-spindle-rebuild-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/28/lathe-spindle-rebuild-part-1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_7615.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7615.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7615.jpg">
&lt;/a>Past few weeks I noticed that the spindle bearings of my lathe were becomming warmer than I liked, particularly when working with higher rpm. Last weekend I decided to take the spindle out, clean the old grease out, and rebuilding it. It turned out to be more work than I expected. The tight fit of the pully made me use the hammer-and-wood trick on the spindle, which I did not like. After a few hours of tapping and fiddling, the pully came of. The spindle gear and the left hand bearing were no fun job either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, the whole thing is apart now, and I cleaned out all the grease. I test-fitted the spindle sundaynight, but I can feel a slight &amp;quot;bump&amp;quot; when turning it, I think the grease must have picked up some dirt, most likely a wood chip from the bench. So I have to take it apart again, it has to be perfectly smooth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I re-fit the spindle, I have to adjust it with my micrometer to have a play of between 0.004 and 0.005 mm, no more, and no less, while being able to turn it by hand. Sounds like an interesting excercise which will take up more than a few minutes :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_7613.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7613.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7613.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7617.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7617.jpg" alt="o_img_7617.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7618.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7618.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7618.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7620.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7620.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7620.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>