<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>applescript on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/applescript/</link><description>Recent content in applescript on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 09:49:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/applescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seemless Bluetooth iSync</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/27/homezone-more-seemless-sync/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 09:49:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/27/homezone-more-seemless-sync/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In my last post, I wrote about how I got &lt;a href="http://metaquark.de/homezone/">HomeZone&lt;/a> to detect my bluetooth phone, and automatically start iSync. While I was playing with it, I noticed how HomeZone opens the Address book application and iSync, and doesn't close them. To make it more seemless, I used a script I found at &lt;a href="http://www.technocrat.ca/?p=44">The Technocrat&lt;/a> to start and stop iSync without interfering with your work. Here's how I did that.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->First, I opened the script editor and typed the following script into it (slightly modified from the one at Technocrat):
&lt;pre>&lt;code>tell application &amp;quot;Finder&amp;quot;
set iSyncRunning to (number of items in
(processes whose name is &amp;quot;iSync&amp;quot;) is greater than 0)
tell application &amp;quot;iSync&amp;quot;
if last sync is less than ((current date) - 120) then
synchronize
end if
end tell
tell application &amp;quot;iSync&amp;quot;
repeat while (syncing is true)
delay 1
end repeat
if iSyncRunning is not true then
quit
end if
end tell
end tell
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Then, I saved this script as an application called &amp;quot;iSyncNow.app&amp;quot; . On the save dialog, make sure that &amp;quot;keep running&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;show on screen&amp;quot; are NOT thicked, like so:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-9.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-9.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, open the HomeZone preferences and configure HomeZone to run this application when your phone is in range. My configuration looks as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-10.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-10.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this simple little trick, my Mac Mini has become a lot cooler. When I approach the computer, I see the iSync logo appear in the dock, it bounces a few times, and then it dissapears. My phone is now always synchronized with my iCal, without popups or manual actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please note that the script prevents iSync to synchronize if the last synchronization was less than 2 minutes (120 seconds) ago. You can adjust this by editting the &amp;quot;120&amp;quot; in the applescript to any number of seconds you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>