<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>stock market on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/stock-market/</link><description>Recent content in stock market on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 10:38:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/stock-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monkeys: How to get rich.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/23/monkeys-how-to-get-rich/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 10:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/23/monkeys-how-to-get-rich/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently got an email with a brilliant little fairytale about how to trick people into happily giving you all their money. I wanted to share with you, but it was in Dutch, and the origin was cleary not the original author.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I was &lt;a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/rummaging">rummaging&lt;/a> around the internet to see if I could find the original author, and I did. I found out that the Dutch story was freely translated from an English source. Here's the original story from that English source, unaltered (and with reference):&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;blockquote>**Monkeys**
&lt;p>Once upon a time in a village, a man appeared and announced to the villagers that he would buy monkeys for $5 each. The villagers seeing that there were many monkeys around, went out to the forest and started catching them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man bought thousands at $5 and as supply started to diminish, the villagers stopped their effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He further announced that he would now buy at $10. This renewed the efforts of the villagers and they started catching monkeys again. Soon the supply diminished even further and people started going back to their farms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The offer increased to $15 each and the supply of monkeys became so little that it was an effort to even see a monkey, let alone catch it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man now announced that he would buy monkeys at $50. However, since he had to go to the city on some business, his assistant would now buy on his behalf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the man’s absence, the assistant told the villagers “Look at all these monkeys in the big cage that the man has collected. I will sell them to you at $45 and when the man returns from the city, you can sell them to him for $50 each.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The villagers rounded up with all their savings and bought all the monkeys. Then they never again saw the man nor his assistant, only monkeys everywhere!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And THAT ladies and gentleman is how the stock market works…&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(by John Sinteur,
as published on October 25th, 2008
on &lt;a href="http://weblog.sinteur.com/2008/10/monkeys-2/">&amp;quot;the Daily Irrelevant&amp;quot;&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>