<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gmail on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/gmail/</link><description>Recent content in gmail on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 21:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/gmail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gmail: Save an email to disk</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/10/18/gmail-save-an-email-to-disk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/10/18/gmail-save-an-email-to-disk/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="gmail-save-to-disk.png" alt="Gmail save to disk">
Want to save a single email from gmail to disk, in a readable format for Outlook, Thunderbird or Apple Mail? Here's how:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Open your browser and log into your gmail account.
2. Open the email you want to save.
3. On the top-right, there is a little triangle next to the &amp;quot;Reply&amp;quot; button. Click that, and select [&amp;quot;Show Original&amp;quot;](gmail-show-original.png).
4. The original, raw email opens in a new window or tab.
5. Right-click on this new window, and select [&amp;quot;Save as...&amp;quot;](gmail-save-as.png).
6. When saving the file, make sure the extension of the filename is &amp;quot;**eml**&amp;quot;. So for example [&amp;quot;MyEmail.eml&amp;quot;](gmail-name-it-eml.png).
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>All done. Now you dan open the file in Thunderbird, Outlook or whatever email viewer you have out there and see the original mail, in all it's marked-up glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If Gmail Had Been Designed by Microsoft?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/22/what-if-gmail-had-been-designed-by-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 20:53:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/22/what-if-gmail-had-been-designed-by-microsoft/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Philipp Lenssen from the Google Blogoscoped blog does some iterations on the Google Mail userinterface while he investigates the question &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://blogoscoped.com/archive/2007-11-20-n35.html">What If Gmail Had Been Designed by Microsoft?&lt;/a>&amp;quot;. He ends up with a userinterface which is very much like the hotmail I knew before I replaced it with my current gmail account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. Did you notice that the gmail space has increased to around 5GB lately? Google continues to amaze (frighten?) me at how much data they can store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>brain down for days</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/10/brain-down-for-days/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 15:27:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/10/brain-down-for-days/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Yup, you've guessed it. User error. There I was in my last post complaining that gmail was down, while actually my ADSL modem needed a good reset. At work, I could access gmail, and when I got home, I had the same problem as yesterday. I cleared the browser cache, still no result. Then I resetted my ADSL modem, and presto: I could log in again. Really strange error...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sorry gmail, my mistake. But yes, I am going to back up my mail now :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>gmail down for days</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/09/gmail-down-for-days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2006 15:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/09/gmail-down-for-days/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Great, gmail is down for days now. I really hope it will return soon, so I can back up that mail to my server. By going down, Google showed me how much I came to rely on them, while they're actually unreachable when something happens, and I don't even have backups of my own mails! I really like gmail and the way it organizes your mail by -ehrm- not organizing it (when it's up, that is).&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Problem with these free online services (gmail, hotmail, yahoo mail...) is that because you do not pay for them, you can't hold them responsible for anything basically. Sure, they have a moral duty to be online because you trust them with your mail, and they can't violate that trust. But still, you don't pay them, and they probably have had lawyers carefully craft the license agreement so that you can't sue them when they go down or -shudder- loose your data.
&lt;p>So, when you're using gmail, make sure you also set up a machine at home to backup your account through POP. I know I'll be doing that when it comes back up. I also tell people to send mail to my email alias. Most people don't even know my gmail address. Another good measure for being able to switch mail providers without having to tell everybody. So... watch it google, you may loose a freeloading customer here! (you can stop giggling now, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/execs.html#larry">Larry&lt;/a>, and you too, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/execs.html#sergey">Sergey&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>