<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>design on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in design on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 22:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join, don't judge</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 22:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ef91za0liTM">
&lt;img src="beautiful-restaurant-websites-550x3221.jpeg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Like many people, I like to dine in a good restaurant, where the mood is mellow, the waiter is a fine host, and the cook is passionate about good food and nice presentation. The courses are perfectly timed with your appetite, and each shiny polished plate of food contains the best looking, smelling and tasting food with the nicest textures. After desert, you get the best fresh mineral water coffee, and just sit there, satisfied, happy, in good company. The waiter discretely places the check on the table, and you happily pay whatever that check tells you to pay, and add a big tip for good measure, to show you had a great evening.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The next morning, you check your bank account and discover there is not much left. Yesterdays meal cost you a bit more than you anticipated. But the memory puts a smile on your face, and you just decide that it's worth it.
&lt;p>At work you tell a colleague about your great meal in the perfect restaurant. He smiles and listens, and asks directions to this perfect restaurant. He drives to the restaurant, looks at the menu and writes down what you had. Then he goes to the supermarket and buys the ingredients for the perfect meal you had. He goes home, and tries is best to cook everything to perfection in his small 1 bedroom apartment while constantly chasing the cat from the kitchen sink. He removes yesterday's dishes from the kitchen table, lights a candle and eats the food. After he finishes his desert he has his Senseo coffee and enjoys the sound of the dryer beeping that it's finished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next morning, he comes in and tells you that you've been screwed. He goes on and on about how he had exactly the same meal, and maybe even more, for about 1/10th the price you payed at the restaurant. Where you had to listen to pre-selected restaurant music, he could choose his own. Where you had to wait for the waiter to bring your courses, he could just pick them from the kitchen sink at will. His meal was so much better than yours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, each time somebody asks about your wonderful dinner, he butts in to say that that restaurant is a ripoff, and how you can have a much better experience with more choice, more freedom, at only 1/10th of the cost. As soon as anybody so much as mentions this restaurant, he starts is rant all over again about how people should not go to that place. What could have been a wonderful exchange of culinary experiences turns into a holy war, where people think they should &amp;quot;win&amp;quot; a discussion, ruining it for everybody,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, in the real world there are very few people so fanatic, going to great lengths to ruin that moment in a conversation where you can tell about the great restaurant you found. Or are there?&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >![Macbook Pro Unibody, Matte screen](macbookpro_15inch_pfop_matte_screen.jpeg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Dell XPS 15](screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-13-10-021.png)
](screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-13-10-021.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >**Macbook Pro 15"**
2GHz Intel Core i7
4GB 1333MHz DDR3
AMD Radeon HD 6490M 256 MB
250GB SSD OCZ Vertex 3
Dual layer DVD writer
Wifi
1GB Ethernet
Webcam
Bluetooth
SD Cardreader
USB 2.0, Firewire 800
**€2499,-**
&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:right;" >**Dell XPS 15**
2.2GHz Intel Core i7
6GB 1333MHz DDR3
NVidia GeForce GT 525M 1GB
500GB HDD
Dual layer DVD writer
Wifi
1GB Ethernet
Webcam
Bluetooth
9-in-1 Cardreader
USB 2.0
**€699,-**
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
Two laptops. Roughly the same specifications. Still, one of these is almost 4 times more expensive than the other. If you'd own one of these laptops you probably enjoy the choice you've made, for whatever reason. You'd want to tell your colleagues about the wonderful new computer you bought, and how you enjoy working on it, how it looks, how it holds all your music, how easily it edits videos and how it plays HD movies. But most colleagues own their own laptops, and will immediately stop you in your tracks, telling you that you bought the wrong laptop because it's too ugly, can't play a 3D movie, is too expensive or doesn't have that essential megatunderpurplebit connector you've never heard of.
&lt;p>Isn't it funny how computer enthusiasts often forget that they're taking the fun out of each other's story by disapproving somebodies choice simply because that decision is not based on the same criterea?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcycle riders are often very different in that respect. When you drive a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofDllsEV6hE">BMW GS80&lt;/a>  and pull up next to a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-7gDVmdiDY">Ducati Panigale&lt;/a>, the rider will most likely smile at you. When you compliment him on his beautiful new bike, he will probably return a compliment on the pristine condition of your classic. You can exchange pleasantries about how you enjoy your bikes, without down talking the other guy's bike. He will happily ride along with you for a few miles down a beautiful road, even though he has to make his 195hp supercomputer wait for your reliable mechanical boxer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcyclists &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/13159991">celebrate riding&lt;/a> regardless of sound, style or skill. Cooks celebrate food regardless of price, place or palette. Computer users could learn to celebrate computing regardless of form, function or fan noise. Smartphone users could celebrate connectivity regardless of color, coverage or cpu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respect is only gained by respecting others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Car Buying Story</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2010 22:50:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-04-om-21-22-13.png" alt="">
Stephen needs a new car. Being dilligent and a car lover, he takes the time to write down all criteria for a great car. When he finishes the list, he notices that the only car matching all his criteria is a Ferrari. Well, he always loved a Ferrari so that makes sense. To make things more realistic he adds another criteria, called &amp;quot;price&amp;quot;, and starts looking for alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The first car he looks at is practical, but hasn't got the speed of a Ferrari. The second car can carry a lot of stuff, but hasn't got the sound of a Ferrari. The third car is really modular, but hasn't got the looks of a Ferrari. The fourth car is very fast, but doesn't handle as a Ferrari. The fifth car is an independant brand, and can be repaired in any shop, but it breaks down much more often than a Ferrari. The sixth car has a cool design-flip-type-clock and integrated MP3 player, but the manual coming with it does not explain how to operate them.
&lt;p>The seventh car looked too good to be true good in the advertisement. The images in the brochure look stunning. It has everything on his list, and also matches the price criteria. Stephen orders it immediately. But when delivered it does not live up to the whole Ferrari design, look and feel. By far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen is not really unhappy and has learned to live with the car's shortcomings. When asked about his new car, Stephen kindly shows it, but the first sentence he regretfuly utters is &lt;em>&amp;quot;but ofcourse, it's not a Ferrari&amp;quot;...&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The moral of this story is: If you don't buy a Ferrari, you'll never own a Ferrari.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: car
replace: mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: Ferrari
replace: iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="the-events-in-this-story-are-fictitious-any-similarity-to-any-person-living-or-dead-is-merely-coincidental-i-cannot-emphasize-enough-how-coincidental-the-fictional-entities-are-to-any-real-life-individual-entity-or-character-for-more-disclaimers-id-like-to-refer-you-to-this-sites-about-pagehttprolfjewordpresscomabout">The events in this story are fictitious. Any similarity to any person living or dead is merely coincidental. I cannot emphasize enough how coincidental the fictional entities are to any real life individual, entity, or character. For more disclaimers I'd like to refer you to this site's &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/about/">about page&lt;/a>.&lt;/h6></description></item><item><title>Design Gripes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dear Akio Morita,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">&lt;img src="2009-04-08-234308.png" alt="Onion News Network on Sony products">
&lt;/a>Lately I have some small issues with a lot of design decisions being made by the company you founded a while ago. If you look at my irritations seperately they're just small gripes of a grumpy old customer. But the increasing number of design mistakes have me worried about your user acceptance testing and quality assurance processes. Given the sheer size of your company, and the fact that the very same people who are sabotaging your overall product quality can silently delete my complaint, I thought I'd share it with you here, on my very private blog.  Nobody else will read this. Honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me start by saying that I love my Playstation 3. No wait, let me rephrase that. I love playing games on my playstation 3. Because the playstation 3 itself is absolutely not intuitive, logical or even pleasant to use. Both hardware and software wise.
&lt;p>I am very fortunate to have a loving wife who bought a PS3 for me. Because she did not expect to have to do in-depth research about the differences between the models, she bought the 80GB PS3 for me. It was the biggest drive in the store, so she thought that was the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was/am really happy with the very nice present. Not having any PS3 games yet, I slapped in a PS2 game, fully expecting that it would play. Not so. As it turns out, only the 60GB model plays &lt;em>some&lt;/em> of the PS2 games, and most of the time not even perfectly. What's with that? Can this 3-Cell processor huge 80GB machine with metric craploads of memory not emulate the outdated PS2? Did nobody at Sony realize that they can capitalize on people upgrading from the PS2? Not even now that the &lt;a href="http://ps3finder.com/">60GB models actually sell for more money than the 80GB&lt;/a> model retail price?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disapointedly leaving the PS2 compatibility issue, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/">I got a DLNA server running&lt;/a> on my Mac. When I want to view media on that server, I have to use your &amp;quot;X media bar&amp;quot; menu. For some reason, some designer came up with the brilliant idea to seperate music, photo's and video's in that menu. This means that before browsing my DLNA server, I have to decide what filetype I'm going to browse. If I have folders containing both video and photo's of the same birthday party, I constantly have to back out of the photo viewing mode, get into the video mode, browse all the way back to the folder, and view the video. It's like having to fill in a form to flip the channel on your TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what's with the forgetting of discovered DLNA servers? The PS3 takes ages to re-discover my DLNA server on the network each time I turn the PS3 on, or return to the menu from a game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it even more cringeworthy, the PS3 scares the crap out of me each time I browse to a folder to see that &amp;quot;There are no files...&amp;quot;. The PS3 is lying ofcourse, what it means is that there are MPG's and AVI's there, but I'm in photo viewing mode. The whole X-media-bar design must have never been usability tested by random customers. It's a very common practice nowadays which I can really recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By now, I had scored some PS3 games (&lt;a href="http://www.ps3home.nl/products/playstation-3-games/alle-games-a-tot-z/moto-gp-2008-ps3.htm">Moto GP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.tombraiderunderworld.com">Tomb Raider: Underworld&lt;/a>). After a nice evening of gaming,  I discover that the controller battery is running low. So I connect it to the PS3, and put the PS3 in standby mode, expecting my controller to be charged the next morning. To my huge disapointment, the controller does not charge when the PS3 is not fully on. That strikes me as really strange. To charge my wireless controller, I have to connect it during gaming. Now how did someone on your design team did not notice that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a big old Phillips Matchline TV which worked fine, but was getting a bit dated. The thought of being able to play games in full HD 1080p resolution was very tempting, so I bought a new model Sony Bravia 40 inch TV, thinking that it would interface nicely with the PS3. To my absolute horror, the PS3 video signal looked horrible on this new TV. As it turned out, you are shipping this full HD 300+ dollar gaming machine with a crappy composite video cable. Oh boy. Now I know why people think the difference between a Wii and a PS3 is not that huge. Another obvious commercial win down the drain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and I discovered that HDMI is the best way to go. I bought an HDMI cable and connected the PS3 to the TV with that. The TV manual said it could use some HDMI protocol to discover HDMI connected devices. Surely enough, my brandnew Sony Bravia does not recognize my Sony PS3. How nice is that? Luckaly, after some manual fiddling with the absolutely horrid X-media bar-like menu's in the TV and the PS3, I got everything to play in full HD. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What strikes me as another design flaw is the size of the screen fonts. On my big TV everything looks nice, but I can imagine that the paperboy who emptied his piggybank to get a PS3, and connects it to his little TV in his room, can not read any of the menu items. I take it that the Sony testing department only has Full HD TV's with HDMI cables, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there's the whole casing design thing. Come on. Rounded top? I can not even place a controller on there, it slides off. The ventilation holes are on the side, which makes it imposible to put the PS3 with it's right side against the cupboard. The USB ports are recessed in such a way that if you place the PS3 low to the ground (which happens most), you can not see the ports without having to lie down on the floor eyeballing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you're down there, you can als see the rediculously thick and sturdy mains cable. It can transport enough current to power my microwave. Does the PS3 really use that much current? Now be honest. You could have selected a thinner, more flexible mains lead, and maybe it would even have been cheaper. The current lead almost pushes the PS3 out from the wall. Good thing the PS3 is so heavy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When waking the PS3 from it's sleep mode, there is another interesting thing that strikes me as odd. There is a green and a blue led next to eachother on the top of the button pannel. Not only are those two colors looking horrible next to eachother, and the fact that I have come to loathe any product with a blue led, there is absolutely no way that colorblind people are going to notice the difference in color, which makes them pointless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said, this is just a selection of the gripes I have with the design. For instance, the fact that game makers are allowed to play sounds and video as soon as a game is inserted, is just terrible. It scares the crap out of me each time I insert &lt;a href="http://www.racedrivergrid.com/">Race Driver:GRID&lt;/a>, and there is no way I can turn it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="photo.jpg">&lt;img src="photo.jpg" alt="Sony Bravia remote button misplacement">
&lt;/a>The nicest example of hardware design failure by Sony is the remote control of the Sony Bravia TV. The buttons you use most are in fact unreachable when holding the remote in your hand. The least used buttons are right there by your thumb. What was this designer thinking? Oh and never mind pressing the buttons, because this TV, which can interpolate frames of a 24fps source into 100fps fluid motion while dynamically adjusting sound and backlight, has a very hard time to display a menu or react to the remote. This is absolutely mind boggling to me. It's like a race car which can go from 0 to 300mph in 2 seconds but takes 5 seconds to react to the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I bought all this Sony stuff. I know, I could have bought something else. But there are reasons for me to put up with all this crap. OTHER manufacturers make such great stuff for Sony devices. The games on the PS3 are absolutely beautiful and brilliant. Watching video on the PSP on an airplane is great. Looking at a bluray at 100Hz 1080p on the Bravia is eye-popping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, dear mr. Morita, please, please make the people at Sony aware of these details. They're important. Solving them will set your product apart from the competition in a large way. People may not be able to tell why, but they will like your product better. This is what good designers do. Make a product have a good &amp;quot;feel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will also rid you of online video's describing your products as... well... you've already seen &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">that video&lt;/a>, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading this rant.
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Irritating "Features": Philips Matchline TV</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/17/irritating-features-phillips-matchline-tv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 20:11:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/17/irritating-features-phillips-matchline-tv/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Okay, I have to get this out of my system. It is something I've been complaining about for months, and it is really an example of the utter dumbness of some product designers. What am I talking about? Simply turning on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have this very nice big heavy 100Hz 4:3 Phillips Matchline TV, which I bought 8 or so years ago. For that time, it was a feature-rich TV which could store all kinds of user settings through on-screen menus, and keep them stored even when the power went out. A few weeks ago I noticed a new TV at a friends house has the same &amp;quot;feature&amp;quot; as my old Matchline. You can't turn it on!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens? Monday evening, you are done watching TV and use the remote to switch it to &amp;quot;Stand By&amp;quot; mode. Before you go to bed, you walk by the TV and hit the power button to completely turn it off. Now on Tuesday, after dinner, you decide to watch TV. You walk to the TV, hit the power button, and what happens? The TV goes from &amp;quot;off&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Standby&amp;quot;. What complete and utter IDIOT designs a TV which goes to &amp;quot;standby&amp;quot; after turning it on with the power button? It wouldn't surprise me that a junior programmer was showing off his l33t skills by remembering the state of the TV before it was turned off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, after 8 years of introducing the wierdest features to TV's, the usability labs in this world have still not found the most obvious feature to a TV: Turning it on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essential Color Design Tool</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/15/essential-color-design-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 19:59:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/15/essential-color-design-tool/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For those people out there designing user interfaces, web frontends or anything else displayed on a screen: About 8% of all males are color blind. This could mean that because of a simple color choice, 8% of your target audience (customers) could have serious difficulty in using your design. 5% of all males can't distinguish green from red, although they are regarded as high contrast to eachother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you want to test how your design looks to colorblind people? Now you can, with &lt;a href="http://colororacle.cartography.ch/">Color Oracle&lt;/a>, a tool for Mac OSX and Windows which transposes the colors of your screen to reflect what it would look like if you were color blind. In fact, it can simulate 3 different kinds of color blindness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the site: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Color Oracle takes the guesswork out of designing for color blindness by showing you in real time what people with common color vision impairments will see. Color Oracle applies a full screen color filter to art you are designing – independently of the software that you are using. Eight percent of all males are affected by color vision impairement – make sure that your graphical work is readable by the widest possible audience.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>