<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 12:00:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1N4148 diode as RF switch</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2018/02/24/1n4148-diode-as-rf-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2018/02/24/1n4148-diode-as-rf-switch/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/hgll-XTqcS4">&lt;img src="1n4148.jpg" alt="1N4148.jpg">
&lt;/a>For a recent experiment I was using &lt;a href="http://www.datasheetarchive.com/BA389-datasheet.html">BA389 PIN diodes&lt;/a> to switch low power RF signals. I was asked why I didn't use an ordinary &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1N4148_signal_diode">1N4148&lt;/a> for that. Since I didn't know what an 1N4148 would do when used like that, and I also didn't really know what a BA389 actually does, I decided to do some measurements.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Aren't diodes rectifiers?&lt;/strong>
Yes and no. The most basic operation of a diode is to pass current in one way, and block it in the other. But when the diode passes DC current, the internal capacitance lowers, and RF resistance will drop to around 1 Ohm. If you can separate the DC and RF currents, you can switch RF with DC. Most, if not all modern transceivers use PIN diodes to switch the antenna between the internal transmitter and receiver components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PIN or PN diode?&lt;/strong>
A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P%E2%80%93n_diode">P/N diode&lt;/a> like the 1N4148 only has P and N doped regions. A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PIN_diode">P/I/N diode&lt;/a> has three semiconductor regions with different doping. The I region in a PIN diode makes it a bad/slow rectifier but it a great RF switch, see the provided wikipedia link for more info.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enough talk. Let's go. In this case I want to know how a PIN diode like the BA389 compares to an 1N4148 when used for switching RF signals on 145 MHz and 435 MHz. I decided to use my &lt;a href="http://miniradiosolutions.com/54-2/">MiniVNA Tiny&lt;/a> and the following circuit to do the measurements:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="screen-shot-2018-02-23-at-17-31-36.png" alt="Screen Shot 2018-02-23 at 17.31.36">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The output of the MiniVNA Tiny is connected to a 10 dB attenuator, reducing the -6 dBm (0.251 mW) output of the VNA to -16 dBm (0.025 mW) hoping to reduce signal leaking around the diode (less signal, less leakage). The output of the attenuator is connected to the AC input on the left side of the schematic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The input of the MiniVNA Tiny is connected to the output of the schematic. Yes, the RF travels through the diode the &amp;quot;wrong way&amp;quot;, against the DC current. This is not an error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DC input of the circuit is connected to a variable resistor, a multimeter and a power supply to be able to vary the current through the diode (DUT) from 0.001 mA to 20 mA.&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Test setup](img_6758.jpg?w=250)
](img_6758.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![test circuit](img_6767.jpg?w=150)
](img_6767.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
The coils are 0.35 mm copper wound 15 turns around a 3 mm drillbit. The capacitors are SMD to keep everything as short as possible. I also added some extra shielding to separate the in and outputs better.
&lt;p>Before measuring diodes I callibrated the whole setup by having vnaJ measure the &amp;quot;OPEN&amp;quot; characteristics with everything connected but with the diode removed. Then, I soldered a wire in place of the diode and had vnaJ measure the &amp;quot;CLOSED&amp;quot; characteristics. I saved this callibration dataset and used it throughout all other measurements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I soldered a 1N4148 in place and measured RF Transmission Loss for a number of currents between 0 and 15 mA. Then I did the same for the BA389. After a bit of fiddling with Excel I produced the following graph of the results:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2018-02-23-at-21-39-15.png" alt="Screen Shot 2018-02-23 at 21.39.15 .png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2018-02-23-at-21-39-15.png)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The verdict:&lt;/strong>
The results are actually not that bad for the 1N4148. It shows behaviour and comparable linearity to the BA389 PIN diode. The attenuation of the 1N4148 leaves to be desired: -25,5 dB attenuation compared to -30.3 dB of the BA389 on 145 MHz. On 435 MHz the difference is a bit bigger: -14.1 dB vs -20.1 dB for the BA389. All in all, the 1N4148 is roughly 6 dB more &amp;quot;leaky&amp;quot; than the BA389.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So a 1N4148 actually works as an RF switch, if you are on lower frequencies and don't mind that it only attenuates -25,5 dB. If you need high performance RF switching with high isolation, particularly at frequencies above 200 MHz or so I think you're better off selecting a proper PIN diode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the 1N4148 and the BA389 graphs from the MiniVNA Tiny. The graph for the 1N4148 is an earlier one where I didn't have the extra shields. The dip in the 200MHz range is caused by the measurement jig itself. Mind the vertical scales, they don't match. Blue line is Transmission Loss:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![VNA_180222_174935.jpg](vna_180222_174935.jpg)
](vna_180222_174935.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![VNA_180223_150657.jpg](vna_180223_150657.jpg)
](vna_180223_150657.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Morse Code is not dead (yet)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2013/04/09/morse-code-is-not-dead-yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 19:40:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2013/04/09/morse-code-is-not-dead-yet/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KaHm1ecBCgw">&lt;img src="international_amateur_radio_symbol.png" alt="International_amateur_radio_symbol">
&lt;/a>Not everybody understands why I am trying to learn &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morse_code">morse code&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="http://lcwo.net/">lcwo.net&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm not even sure myself. But most people seem to think morse code is absolutely dead. I could tell you that's not the case, but it is far better to find out for yourself. To be able to do that you need access to a radio which can receive &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_wave">CW (continuous wave)&lt;/a> signals somewhere between 8MHz and 15MHz. This is the place where &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amateur_radio_license">HAM Radio Operators&lt;/a> hang out and try to talk to eachother. Morse code is still used there, mainly for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DXing">DX-ing&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do you do that? With the power of the internet and a few very enthusiastic people in Dwingeloo, you can now receive radio signals right on your computer using radios all over the world. Lots of links in this article, have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->My father is a HAM radio operator . When I was around 16, he had a CEPT Class II license _(I searched the [www.cept.org](www.cept.org) site but for the life of me I can't find an exact description of the license and its entitlements)_. Because a lot of the theory required to get that license was already covered by my study at that time, I decided to get the same class license as my dad. This allowed me to operate on Amateur Radio bands from 50MHz and up.
&lt;p>To be able to operate on lower bands, we had to pass a morse code exam, both sending and receiving. Together with my dad we started listening to 12 words per minute morse courses on tape, and I even joined some on-the-air courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that time, there was some talk on removing morse from the exams because it was an &amp;quot;artificial barrier&amp;quot; and a skill which was not really required to operate radio equipment. So on the 1st of September in 2003, the morse requirement was dropped, which immediately meant that my license now covered the HF bands, and I did not have to pass the morse exam. I never looked at morse again. I also never worked on the lower HF bands, stayed mainly on 144MHz and up. My interests gradually changed and for the last 12 years or so, I didn't even look at HAM radio at all. Until I came across this video:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i8Ed0TSp0gs]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It made me smile. Morse Code and CW are not dead. I thought it would be fun to see if I could still do that. Well, I couldn't, not even at a much, much lower speed. Which lead me to lcwo.net and here I am, learning morse code again for no other reason than &amp;quot;because I can&amp;quot;. For now I think my goal is to make at least 1 short conversation (called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(amateur_radio)">QSO&lt;/a> by HAMs) , with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telegraph_key">straight key&lt;/a>, to another amateur. If not only just so I can say I did that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=feGwrW2rT1I">&lt;img src="kenwood-ts50.gif" alt="kenwood ts50">
&lt;/a>I thought I'd do everything low profile, low power (called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QRP_operation">QRP&lt;/a> by HAMs), with a small second hand cheap transceiver like the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oT_rJvVi22I">Youkits HB1B&lt;/a>. But my very supportive dad immediately lent me his &lt;a href="http://www.rigpix.com/kenwood/ts50s.htm">Kenwood TS-50&lt;/a>, so I could listen to morse on the bands. According to &amp;quot;general wisdom&amp;quot; this is not smart because you should not learn from sloppy coders or incorrect speeds. But hey, this is just a hobby. My brother heard I got the TS-50 and dug up his 25 Amps power supply so I could put a full 100 Watts on the antenna, and he also had a 32 meter &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dipole_antenna">dipole antenna&lt;/a> for me to use. I can't use that antenna in my apartment building because of practical reasons but that's for another blogpost I think, &amp;quot;How to create a dipole antenna&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days later, my brother mailed me an awesome link to a site where anybody could listen to these bands, even without a receiver. In 2007, the Radio Club at the University of Twente found a way to make the receiver of the 25m radio telescope available to many people online, while giving every individual user the power to choose a different frequency to listen to. The original goal was to listen to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EME_(communications)">EME signals&lt;/a>, which are sent from earth to the moon, bounce back from the moon's surface and received by the telescope. But the technology of having multiple people use the same receiver over the internet led to something awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the schematics and software were made publicly available and today quite a few people have built receivers with it connected to normal dipole antennas, tuned to the Amateur Radio bands. So if you want to listen to Amateur Radio, or check how much morse is still out there, or even listen to your own signal as it is received by a receiver far, far away, go to &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.websdr.org/">http://www.websdr.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and check for yourself. Scroll down for a Google Earth map with all the receivers on there. You do need to have Java enabled for the receivers to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the image below you can see me tuned in on 14.040MHz, on a morse code signal. I usually hear a lot of morse code between 14.000MHz and 14.100MHz. Based on the timing of the dit's and dah's, a lot of people are even still using &amp;quot;straight keys&amp;quot; so I think I can safely connect my old &lt;a href="http://www.mtechnologies.com/junker/">Junker&lt;/a> to the TS50 and get this show on the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="sdr-14mhz.png">&lt;img src="sdr-14mhz.png?w=450" alt="SDR-14mhz">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun playing with your new receivers, kids. See you on air.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join, don't judge</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 22:41:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/03/04/join-dont-judge/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ef91za0liTM">
&lt;img src="beautiful-restaurant-websites-550x3221.jpeg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Like many people, I like to dine in a good restaurant, where the mood is mellow, the waiter is a fine host, and the cook is passionate about good food and nice presentation. The courses are perfectly timed with your appetite, and each shiny polished plate of food contains the best looking, smelling and tasting food with the nicest textures. After desert, you get the best fresh mineral water coffee, and just sit there, satisfied, happy, in good company. The waiter discretely places the check on the table, and you happily pay whatever that check tells you to pay, and add a big tip for good measure, to show you had a great evening.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The next morning, you check your bank account and discover there is not much left. Yesterdays meal cost you a bit more than you anticipated. But the memory puts a smile on your face, and you just decide that it's worth it.
&lt;p>At work you tell a colleague about your great meal in the perfect restaurant. He smiles and listens, and asks directions to this perfect restaurant. He drives to the restaurant, looks at the menu and writes down what you had. Then he goes to the supermarket and buys the ingredients for the perfect meal you had. He goes home, and tries is best to cook everything to perfection in his small 1 bedroom apartment while constantly chasing the cat from the kitchen sink. He removes yesterday's dishes from the kitchen table, lights a candle and eats the food. After he finishes his desert he has his Senseo coffee and enjoys the sound of the dryer beeping that it's finished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next morning, he comes in and tells you that you've been screwed. He goes on and on about how he had exactly the same meal, and maybe even more, for about 1/10th the price you payed at the restaurant. Where you had to listen to pre-selected restaurant music, he could choose his own. Where you had to wait for the waiter to bring your courses, he could just pick them from the kitchen sink at will. His meal was so much better than yours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, each time somebody asks about your wonderful dinner, he butts in to say that that restaurant is a ripoff, and how you can have a much better experience with more choice, more freedom, at only 1/10th of the cost. As soon as anybody so much as mentions this restaurant, he starts is rant all over again about how people should not go to that place. What could have been a wonderful exchange of culinary experiences turns into a holy war, where people think they should &amp;quot;win&amp;quot; a discussion, ruining it for everybody,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, in the real world there are very few people so fanatic, going to great lengths to ruin that moment in a conversation where you can tell about the great restaurant you found. Or are there?&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >![Macbook Pro Unibody, Matte screen](macbookpro_15inch_pfop_matte_screen.jpeg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Dell XPS 15](screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-13-10-021.png)
](screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-13-10-021.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >**Macbook Pro 15"**
2GHz Intel Core i7
4GB 1333MHz DDR3
AMD Radeon HD 6490M 256 MB
250GB SSD OCZ Vertex 3
Dual layer DVD writer
Wifi
1GB Ethernet
Webcam
Bluetooth
SD Cardreader
USB 2.0, Firewire 800
**€2499,-**
&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:right;" >**Dell XPS 15**
2.2GHz Intel Core i7
6GB 1333MHz DDR3
NVidia GeForce GT 525M 1GB
500GB HDD
Dual layer DVD writer
Wifi
1GB Ethernet
Webcam
Bluetooth
9-in-1 Cardreader
USB 2.0
**€699,-**
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
Two laptops. Roughly the same specifications. Still, one of these is almost 4 times more expensive than the other. If you'd own one of these laptops you probably enjoy the choice you've made, for whatever reason. You'd want to tell your colleagues about the wonderful new computer you bought, and how you enjoy working on it, how it looks, how it holds all your music, how easily it edits videos and how it plays HD movies. But most colleagues own their own laptops, and will immediately stop you in your tracks, telling you that you bought the wrong laptop because it's too ugly, can't play a 3D movie, is too expensive or doesn't have that essential megatunderpurplebit connector you've never heard of.
&lt;p>Isn't it funny how computer enthusiasts often forget that they're taking the fun out of each other's story by disapproving somebodies choice simply because that decision is not based on the same criterea?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcycle riders are often very different in that respect. When you drive a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofDllsEV6hE">BMW GS80&lt;/a>  and pull up next to a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z-7gDVmdiDY">Ducati Panigale&lt;/a>, the rider will most likely smile at you. When you compliment him on his beautiful new bike, he will probably return a compliment on the pristine condition of your classic. You can exchange pleasantries about how you enjoy your bikes, without down talking the other guy's bike. He will happily ride along with you for a few miles down a beautiful road, even though he has to make his 195hp supercomputer wait for your reliable mechanical boxer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Motorcyclists &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/13159991">celebrate riding&lt;/a> regardless of sound, style or skill. Cooks celebrate food regardless of price, place or palette. Computer users could learn to celebrate computing regardless of form, function or fan noise. Smartphone users could celebrate connectivity regardless of color, coverage or cpu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Respect is only gained by respecting others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Useless Machine</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/12/18/the-useless-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 09:56:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/12/18/the-useless-machine/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The past year, you may have seen me tweeting some &amp;quot;#secretproject&amp;quot; tweets. Last week, the project was finally revealed, and here is the video, in case you've missed it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7nkebVQL5zc]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what is known on the internet as a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z86V_ICUCD4">&amp;quot;Useless Machine&amp;quot;&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.leavemealonebox.com/">&amp;quot;Leave-me-alone Box&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. In case you want to make one, there are plenty of instructions online. I think you can build a basic version of this in about a weekend, and it will cost you less than ten euros. &lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="1-img_0272.jpg">&lt;img src="1-img_0272.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
The tea box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="2-img_0268.jpg">&lt;img src="2-img_0268.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Servo, dismantled&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3-img_9316.jpg">&lt;img src="3-img_9316.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Servo mounted to switch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-img_0294.jpg">&lt;img src="4-img_0294.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Wooden arm on the sander&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-img_9329.jpg">&lt;img src="4-img_9329.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Aluminum arm offset bushing in the lathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="5-img_9331.jpg">&lt;img src="5-img_9331.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Arm mounted on the servo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="6-img_9337.jpg">&lt;img src="6-img_9337.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Assembly in front of the tea box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="7-img_0314.jpg">&lt;img src="7-img_0314.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Cutting the decorative ventilation holes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="8-img_0381.jpg">&lt;img src="8-img_0381.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Painting sanding painting sanding painting sanding...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="8-img_3259.jpg">&lt;img src="8-img_3259.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Assembly painted black for cool looks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="9-img_3291.jpg">&lt;img src="9-img_3291.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Waiting for glue to set&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3288.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3288.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Last minute hack: on/off switch for transport&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3305.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3305.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
The &amp;quot;Useless Machine&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Leave me alone box&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now go build your own. Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>