<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keynote on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/keynote/</link><description>Recent content in Keynote on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 16:41:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/keynote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mortgage Awareness</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/04/01/mortgage-awareness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 16:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2012/04/01/mortgage-awareness/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This weekend I tinkered around with Apple Keynote. I thought I'd make something useful. In this video I'm trying to show you how much money the bank makes on your mortgage. Banks like you to pay a low monthly fee on your mortgage because it keeps the loan higher for a longer period of time. This way the bank can cash in on the interest rate, and then cash in again at the end of the mortgage contract, when you are still hopelessly in debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;video width=100% controls autoplay>
&lt;source src="Mortgage Awareness with audio.m4v" type="video/mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Financial advisors&amp;quot; working for the bank will throw sand in your eyes, saying that keeping your debt high gives you all kinds of tax breaks. But in the end, it's them who get better of that construction, not you. Don't fall into this trap. Understand your mortgage contract, learn how the model works, and check your model against the bank's model (without that financial advisor or the lady at the helpdesk talking to you). You have more room than you think. Use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having fun at J-Fall 2011</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2973-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2973-small.jpg?w=150" alt="J-Fall 2011">
&lt;/a>This year's Dutch Java Nerd event called &lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/">J-Fall&lt;/a> was held in Nijkerk, in a beautiful location called &lt;a href="http://www.regardz.nl/locaties/event-centers/regardz-hart-van-holland-nijkerk.aspx?gclid=CK7bg8zwmKwCFUMm3godUFpdPQ">&amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;&lt;/a> . With plenty of sessions by speakers from all over the world it promised to be a great day for Java enthusiasts, at a great location for meeting friends and colleagues. I took a day off from work and it was well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00024/">&lt;!-- more -->Opening by Bert Ertman&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Bert starts the day by welcoming the 1000+ attendees in the main presentation room in &amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;. After explaining what the day is going to bring and where to find rooms, food, drinks, and company booths, he goes on to tell how they tried to get better network coverage. All these nerds with their smartphones in one single place is asking for trouble. It turns out it's too expensive to get good data network so they didn't do that. Network connections proved to be spotty at best in the main building, but I had good 3G coverage outside the main building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The organizer of &lt;a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Home">Devoxx&lt;/a> came by to say hi, and also told us that the J-Fall presentations are being professionally captured and the most popular ones are going to be online soon at &lt;a href="http://www.parleys.com/">parleys.com&lt;/a>. He closed off with the hilarious &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b-Cr0EWwaTk">&amp;quot;Java Life&amp;quot; Rap Music Video&lt;/a> . By the way if you liked that, you certainly will like the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2UFc1pr2yUU">&amp;quot;Whole foods Parking Lot&amp;quot; video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00025/">Java 7 Directors Cut&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
After the cool opening and videos the whole room was ready for some kick-ass sessions. Tomas Nilsson said that he would have a hard time topping the Java Life music video. And he did. Opening with a laughable slide containing a full page mandatory disclaimer text, the presentation was a terrible erratic drive through his very personal memory lane, and after 15 minutes he lost about 80% of the audience. I had absolutely no idea what point he was trying to make, and why nobody advised him to revise his presentation after he gave the same talk at JavaOne. The good thing was that because of the spotty network coverage, not all tweets during this presentation reached the twitter servers, and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23jfall">#jfall&lt;/a> was not trending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the small coffee break we gather around to see what sessions each of us want to join. Scanning the company booths in the main lobby learns that the world didn't change: Booths luring you with pens, mints, stickers, iPads and nice ladies in the booth who are almost always never representing the companies' people or culture. I did score some nice ball pens though :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00071/">Building Highly Scalable Java Applications on Windows Azure&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Microsoft being a big sponsor of this year's J-Fall, they have to have a keynote. And so they did. And it was a good one. Certainly after the below par presentation skills of Oracle, Microsoft has a nicely polished slides and a demo of Azure, a good story and good pace. During the demo the DNS switching is a bit slow and prevents some things to be shown. At the end of the talk, the speaker confidently retries and it now works. This results in a well-deserved warm applause from the audience. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/doortje123/status/131721454352998400">Well done Microsoft&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00050/">The Java EE7 Platform: Developing for the Cloud&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
With &amp;quot;Cloud&amp;quot; being the new buzzword nowadays, &lt;a href="http://www.java.net/blogs/arungupta/">Arun Gupta&lt;/a> did a keynote on where Java 7 is going, and how applications would fit in this cloud structure. I never heard the term &amp;quot;tenants&amp;quot; being used in this respect, which was interesting. The whole talk was a bit erratic, and after Java EE 6 fixing all the EJB gripes of EJB 3, I couldn't help but feeling that all these &amp;quot;enterprisey&amp;quot; terms are re-introduced in Java 7. The whole idea that you build an application but other people configure the actual building blocks that your application will be instantiated with, is a proven failure to me. Administrators don't have developer knowledge. Changing configuration of key components in your application will severely break it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I came out of this session not feeling to hot about Java 7 and the whole components-in-the cloud and people renting instances idea. Too many roles, academic, over engineered, very Sun Enterprise EJB 2 feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00066/">Don't call us - we'll push&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
A colleague advised be to go see &lt;a href="http://technology.amis.nl/blog/author/lucas">Lucas Jellema&lt;/a>. Lucas was the first speaker of the day who actually seemed to know what he was doing on stage. Although his slides were a bit crowded, he had a good story with many demos. It was a welcome change after Tomas and Arun, although Lucas didn't have any real new stuff. Polling, long-polls, asynchronus AJAX calls and the old request/response problem in http, and database triggers firing Java programs. Except for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket">Web Sockets&lt;/a> there was nothing new but nice to be reminded how these things actually work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Lucas' talk we went to get our complimentary lunch. Because we were relatively early, we had no problems getting the lunch package, and enjoyed our tasty sandwiches, milk, apples and Mars. Another free coffee and we're recharged and ready for the afternoon sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00053/">Migrating Spring to Java EE 6&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/paulb01">Paul Bakker&lt;/a> &lt;a href="img_2974-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2974-small.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>had clearly prepared his slides well, and insisted in giving his talk in English because it would be recorded. I thought this was a nice touch (in case you haven't noticed, I have this idea that everything you want to share with technical people should be in English). Paul explained the tactics to use when converting a Spring application to Java EE 6. Where to start, and how to keep your code compiling while doing the conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have worked on some large projects and although Paul mentions that some parts of the conversion will take a bit more time than others, I am not looking forward to convert my current 250+ thousand lines of code to Java EE 6 just yet. A plain Spring application may be easy, but as soon as you have Spring AOP, interesting Proxy beans and Custom Factory beans, you'd have to rewrite that code in Java EE6, which could take quite some time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I predict converting to Java EE 6 will be much more expensive than upgrading to the next version of Spring for most serious enterprise level applications. I have a home project I'd try to convert first, maybe more on that later on this blog, who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00056/">Extreme performance with the Disruptor&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Although the title and the talk description in the schedule didn't hint too much about it, this talk was 100% about Queues. After some high level talk about Producers, Consumers and Queues, &lt;a href="http://blog.dutchworks.nl/author/allard/">Allard Buijze&lt;/a> drops a bomb and introduces some circle and the name &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot;, without introduction. After a few slides everybody understands that this is some kind of &amp;quot;Circular Queue&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a bit of a laugh when Allard uses 4 slides to explain about dirty cache line reads at CPU level and how the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/">Disruptor&lt;/a> prevents all that, which he then dismisses with &amp;quot;but that doesn't help much&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The talk was entertaining and what I got from it is that the main reason why the &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot; works faster than regular Queues, is that Producers and Consumers can inform each other about their position in the queue, which prevents Queue polling. I can't help but think that this can be done with regular Queue implementations as well, so maybe I missed something here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00058/">Java Tuning Puzzlers&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
For the final session for today most of us decided to go to &amp;quot;Java Tuning Puzzlers&amp;quot;, because it looked like fun. And it was. The presentation by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/kjkoster">Kees Jan Koster&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/jpinpointcom">Jeroen Borgers&lt;/a> was fast, funny, interactive, hands-on and very refreshing. They showed some real-life performance problems they encountered in their work, and asked the audience to solve them. All Java nerds lit up and started shouting answers and funny remarks. Jeroen and particularly Kees Jan were very good in answering questions and snarky comments from the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the talk went into overtime and the organization was trying to cut it short, Jeroen and Kees Jan asked the audience &amp;quot;are we going to get beer, or are we going to finish this?&amp;quot;. The whole audience shouted &amp;quot;Finish it!&amp;quot; and we finished the last Puzzler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No fancy new frameworks, no buzzword bingo, just plain old dry-coding and a plug for one of my favorite tools, findbugs &lt;a href="http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/">http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a> . It was the best session I had all day, and I actually went back to Kees Jan and Jeroen to compliment them with their awesome talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
I might sound a bit critical here and there, but I had a great day. Being amongst fellow-nerds, talking tech talk, sharing funny stories, listening to interesting new developments and hearing other people's views on things was really refreshing. Next thing on my list: Try to get Kees Jan Koster to do at least one big main-track keynote at J-Spring or J-Fall next year, about any subject. Because he will at least keep the audience awake.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks Bert and all of the NLJug people and sponsors who made this possible. See you all at J-Spring!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2978-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2978-small.jpg" alt="Oracle J-Fall flowers">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bill Gates works at Apple</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 23:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.jpg?w=150" alt="Steve Jobs">
&lt;/a>I was happy to see Steve return on the Apple keynote of 9 September, because boy does Apple need somebody with clear vision. The introductions on the new iPod line are all over the place. Let me tell you why I think Steve has not been running the operation for the past few months:&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * **Ringtones.** The price of a ringtone in the iTunes store is (still) higher than that of a song. You can make a ring tone out of a song [for free](http://www.wired.com/software/coolapps/news/2007/09/ringtone_hacks) already, so why put the effort into selling ringtones at a way too high price? The phone companies must have influenced some &amp;quot;less sturdy&amp;quot; people at Apple for this.
* **The Nano Camera.** 2 mistakes on this one. First is the device. Why put a camera on the Nano of all iPods? Wouldn't we expect that on the iPod touch? Or perhaps both? Second is the location. Anybody holding a nano must notice that the camera is in a place where your hand is when holding the nano. Maybe it makes a bit more sense in landscape mode, right after you smudged it with your hand. Maybe I'd have to hold one for good testing. I heard that the camera is not nearly as good as the one on the iPhone 3Gs.
* **iTunes 9's Column Browser.** When I installed iTunes 9, my trusty 3-pane music browser was gone. I had a list of artists on the left, and next to that all my music as a long list of unsorted tracks. Gee thanks. After some fiddling I got the 3-paned browser back (see my [earlier blogpost](http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/)) but the fiddling in the menus got me that &amp;quot;Windows&amp;quot; feeling of tweaking a crappy UI into something I can sort of use.
* **Genius Mixes.** After seeing the keynote, I was eager to try out the &amp;quot;Genius Mixes&amp;quot; feature. In the keynote, these mixes are available under the Genius item on the left. When I looked, there was nothing there. I searched preferences and menus to turn them on, but found nothing. It turns out that you need to upload Genius data to Apple before the Genius Mixes appear. The mixes themselves are working fine, but when a Genius Mix is playing, you can do nothing. No coverflow. No Track details. I can not even rate the currently playing song. This cripples it's potential of finding and rating great songs in a large library.
* **Syncing knobs and levers.** Where syncing used to be simple, it is now 9 tabs with a slew of boxes and sliders you can drag suff between. I know a lot of customers asked for it, but that has never stopped Apple coming up with a totally brilliant solution to a problem, instead of just implementing the user's crappy first thought. I will get used to it, and it will probably work fine, but it just adds to a scary feeling I had of an Apple without Steve.
* **Twitter integration.** Come on Apple, you are not serious now, are you? There are hundreds of Twitter and IM integration apps that will do something like this. Apple did not even add that &amp;quot;innovative cool juice&amp;quot; to it. They just messed up iTunes codebase with this quick hack, making it even harder to port iTunes to 64 bit Cocoa.
* &amp;quot;**Richer&amp;quot; LP content.** I hate the iTunes appstore pages where developers are using way more CSS and markup than you would like to. It's like the walls of the grocery store change each time you look at a different product. It's confusing and ugly. Now, with the LP stuff added, Apple now is going one step further, and starts selling this for a price. Just like the ringtones.
* **Incoherent iPod touch line.** The 8GB iPod touch is sold at $199, which is great, but it was not &amp;quot;revved&amp;quot;, meaning that the 16+GB iPod touches have a different chipset. How do you explain the customer that a game is running slower on one touch, and faster on the other? Sure it's done to get to the $199 price point, but Apple didn't work like this in the old days. They used to introduce a new (revved) model at the same pricepoint.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The whole talk feels a bit &amp;quot;all over the place&amp;quot;, and a way of charging customers for something they do not really need. I know, usually keynotes get the &amp;quot;woos&amp;quot; from the cround every 15 seconds and it's hard to do that time and time again. And Steve just returned, having to sell the stuff he may not have wanted to put out there in the first place. So I'll forgive them this time. But this fan boy will be watching Apple and hope it will be a bit more consistent next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-4.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.jpg" alt="Jeff? Or Bill?">
&lt;/a>So Steve, get those guys back on track will you? And you might want to do an extra surprise round in the office, because I smell &amp;quot;feature creep&amp;quot;. And is it me, or does Jeff Robin's profile  look like a younger Bill Gates?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm. I hope he doesn't try that silly &lt;a href="http://www.pencomputing.com/frames/tablet_pc.html">tablet-thing&lt;/a> again...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macworld 2008 thin as air</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/17/macworld-2008-thin-as-air/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 20:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/17/macworld-2008-thin-as-air/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hi, I've read the writeups on Steve's keynote this year, and listened to some podcasts of people who were in the audience. Personally I'm a bit dissapointed by the features introduced at this Macworld. Surely it's hard to live up to the ever rising expectations every year, but I do have some comments to make on the introduced products.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**TimeCapsule**
&lt;p>This is the worst product Apple has introduced in years. Not that it's crappy hardware or a lousy idea, but the way they are artificially forcing you to buy their $299 500GB harddrive (0r $499 for the 1TB version) in stead of the 100's of readily available, $150 to $200 cheap ethernet connected harddrives out there which would perfectly perform this task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Quick tip: Should you have an Ethernet connected FAT32 drive on which you want timemachine to run, create a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_disk_image">sparse disk image&lt;/a> on that disk (no need to commandline, can also be done with the disk utility). A sparse disk image is effectively a DMG file in 8MB chunks. You can mount that DMG file and have a network connected (strong encrypted if you like), HFS+ journalled drive. After the &lt;a href="http://andreas.louca.org/2007/11/10/time-machine-and-network-drives/">Timemachine network trick&lt;/a>, you're probably good to go at no cost at all. The only difference is that you can't connect your printer to that drive. Well I have my Airport extreme for that, which also streams audio to my stereo.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Macbook air&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Very cool looking laptop with lots of potential for journalists and the occasional &lt;a href="http://www.ijustine.tv/">life blogger&lt;/a>, but I have some doubts about the intended audience. The most obvious is the lack of a CD/DVD drive. This is not a big problem for most users, and with the added tools to connect to any DVD drive on a remote Windows or Apple machine it will not be as big as a problem as one would think. For my wife this is a no-go, she watches DVD's on her laptop, so she's not getting this Macbook air anytime soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My next problem is the configuration options. The cheap model is a 1.3GHz machine, 2GB memory and 80GB Harddrive. It is priced at $1799, which is pretty steep compared to a normal Macbook. For $700 less, you can get a 2.0GHz macbook with a combo drive, which is much nicer in my opinion. Should you want the Macbook air and have a heftier processor, you're in for a surprise. The 1.8GHz model (still not as fast as the cheapest macbook) is priced at a staggering $3098! This is not because of the processor, but it contains a 64GB flash-based harddrive. Less storage space, but more battery life and crash-resistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with the 1.8GHz model of the Macbook air is that you effectively get a smaller harddrive, a marginally better processor, for $3098. Compared to that, for $2799, you can get the 17&amp;quot; Macbook pro at 2.4 GHz, with a superdrive. I know what I would get. Additionaly, the 64GB flash-based drive has a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid_state_disk#Disadvantages">limited amount of write-cycles&lt;/a>. This means that the solid state drive will probably wear out faster than any cheap traditional HD in the market. Based on the write cycles, a normal HD will likely last 5 times longer than a flash-based disk under the same circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need a really thin laptop with good battery life for simple word processing, or simply something to match your gucci wardrobe and your &lt;a href="http://www.owensworld.com/funnyimages/files/I_beat_anorexia_big.jpg">perfect figure&lt;/a>, get the Macbook air. If you need anything marginally better, go for the normal macbook, which is still in my opinion the best value for money and a darn cool, acceptably thin and very portable laptop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me, the Macbook air is a no-go even if it was priced at $1000. Why? **IT HAS NO ETHERNET!**What were they thinking? Many companies have wired-only policies because of security and troughput reasons. This means you can't take your Macbook air to the office for the occasional showing off. It's helpless in a wired-only environment. No DVD, and no means of connecting to the network?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Macbook air becomes a succes, Apple is clearly into some voodoo-market-magic because I don't get it. It also doesn't have Audio in, to put off the mobile podcasters or radio journalists out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apple TV&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;quot;all new&amp;quot; software for the Apple TV is very cool for people who already own an Apple TV. It looks like a big improvement, and not needing a PC or Mac is a step in the right direction. No need to explain &amp;quot;syncing&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;connecting&amp;quot; to newcommers, just plug and play. Nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The missing thing here is that they could have chosen to make the Apple TV the TimeCapsule. It has a harddrive, USB ports, and wifi. Why do I need another machine with anothe power brick if I have a harddisk onderneath my TV which is doing nothing 80% of it's time? Selling a 1TB Apple TV with a smart disk usage policy would make much more sense to me. As an added benefit, people who are looking for a backup solution get sucked into the &amp;quot;Movie Rentals&amp;quot; scheme on the go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One missing thing:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The iPhone. It was mentioned, but still I was expecting 2 major announcements. The first, and most obvious announcement would be a 16 or 32 GB model. This was anticipated to happen for over a year now, but it didn't. I think it's not that big of a deal because I have a 8GB nano and it stores more than enough music to listen to in between syncs. Just use &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/">really smart playlists&lt;/a> and iTunes will take care of it for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second thing I missed was the introduction of the iPhone in more European countries. Hello Apple, Europe doesn't consist of Great Brittain, France and Germany alone! Over here in the Netherlands, a lot of people have hacked grey import iPhones because they are dying to buy one, but can't get it legally. Maybe Apple thinks it's done beccause they reached their targets, but I think they are missing out on a big market of wealthy (west-) European consumers easily wanting to pay for the legal version of the iPhone, no matter which provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To top that, the free software update for the iPhone will cost $20 dollars for iPod touch owners, while new iPod touch's will have that included for free. I wonder what &amp;quot;marketing genius&amp;quot; is behind that. It almost looks like Steve has been on a year's vacation, leaving business to somebody else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just noticed that the complete video of the keynote is online at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/qtv/keynote/">http://www.apple.com/quicktime/qtv/keynote/&lt;/a>. Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edit:  I see that there is an USB Ethernet adapter and an external DVD drive available as options to the Macbook air. But still, I think the ethernet port should be in there, I don't want to have to carry all kinds of adapters with my Macbook.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple WWDC 2006 Keynote Address problems?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/08/10/apple-wwdc-2006-keynote-address-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 15:08:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/08/10/apple-wwdc-2006-keynote-address-problems/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Trying to view his Steveness in the Apple WWDC 2006 Keynote addres? Me too, and haven't been lucky for 3 days in a row. I actually managed to view 3 minutes of distorted, half-audio presentation, but then it died, and has given me an error 400 ever since. It's not nice to see Apple not being able to cope with the demand. A bittorrent would be nice I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my first edit of this post I thought I'd found a mirror, but it was an old keynote. Searching on, I found a terrific tip which solved the problem of not being able to view the keynote. It actually turns out it's the default Quicktime settings are causing the problems. Quicktime fetches the stream over UDP, which makes no guarantee over lost packets. You can set Quicktime to fetch the stream through http, which has a few advantages, such as losless transfer of data, and ability for proxy server to cache data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To set Quicktime to fetch the video accros http:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Go to System Preferences
* Open Quicktime preferences from the system preferences screen
* Click on the &amp;quot;advanced&amp;quot; tab
* Choose &amp;quot;Custom&amp;quot; for transport setup
* In the window that pops up, choose the HTTP transport protocol
* Close the system preferences
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now go to the &lt;a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/aug_2006/event/index.html">WWDC 2006 Keynote address page&lt;/a> and view the video. I just did, it worked fine, no dropped frames or audio.
Enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. Tiger shipped for 80 euro's when it was released. If Leopard is anywhere close to that same price, it will be hard to find an operating system which gives you all this, with this quality, for this price. Professional grade OS, for the price of a SuSe distribution! I love Tiger, I know I'm going to love Leopard. Since I have my Mac, my Windows laptop (which was an expensive one I might add) is sitting in a corner of my desk, covered under a layer of dust. It's simply not good enough anymore. My Mac mini will beat it any day.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>