<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>google on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/google/</link><description>Recent content in google on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 22:41:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>There's life without Google. Or iCloud. Or Facebook.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/08/theres-life-without-google-or-icloud-or-facebook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 22:41:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/08/theres-life-without-google-or-icloud-or-facebook/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://threema.ch/en/">&lt;img src="appicon128.png" alt="Threema, the secure Whatsapp alternative">
&lt;/a>Regular readers of this blog already know that I am &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2011/07/03/1355/">not using dropbox&lt;/a>, and I was an Evernote user, but recently decided it became to dangerous and &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/?s=evernote">replaced it with my own scripts&lt;/a>. I had an interesting discussion on Twitter which made me decide to show you how I run my digital life without the help of Google, Facebook, Dropbox, Whatsapp or iCloud, and still be able to have all the functionality these services offer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The search was hard and sometimes I need to reconsider some of the choices, but the last few years the selection of products was very stable and the setup has worked flawlessly. Searching for a secure replacement for Whatsapp or Google? It's in here.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
Original
The Safer Alternative:
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Whatsapp
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[**Threema**](https://threema.ch/en/). Hands-down the best safe messaging service. Easy to use, group chats, image and video transfers. Under the hood it always uses true end-to-end encryption, and does not store any data about you or contacts your addressbook while still being able to find your friends. Threema costs a mere €1,70 for the iPhone and €1,60 for Android, and is very clear about their revenue model. Sending a message is free of charge. No I don't use Telegram.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Mail
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >**[Hushmail](https://www.hushmail.com/services/hushmail/)**. A Canadian email provider which at least claims it respects your privacy and is not bound to American legislation. I use their [Premium service](https://www.hushmail.com/premium/) which costs $35 a year. A bargain.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Google Search
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >**[DuckDuckGo](https://duckduckgo.com)**. Although there are some sceptics out there who argue that there is no way to verify how duckduckgo is any different than Google's search engine, I still think it is a better alternative. One of the most important ones is that they don't ["bubble"](http://dontbubble.us) you. Image searching is not possible yet. so I do fall back to Google for that every now and than, but only in a separate, private browser session with cleared cookies.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Google Maps
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >The Apple [**Maps**](http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/06/26/new-maps-app-in-os-x-mavericks-extends-tools-for-reporting-fixing-errors) app, or if you don't have a Mac or need to search online: [Mapquest](http://www.mapquest.com) provides a good alternative to Google maps. Not the prettiest interface, but any product other than a Google product gives them less data to harvest on me. Always remember: If you're not paying for the product, you're the product.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Calendar, Contacts
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[**Owncloud**](http://owncloud.org). In my case, I have bought a $40 Raspberry Pi which is beautifully running Owncloud to sync Calendars over SSL between my iPhone and all my Macs. It requires a bit of Linux skills and isn't really safe "out of the box", but can be made pretty airtight. **Remember to close all ports and only access Owncloud over**** SSL** (most tutorials wrongly teach you otherwise), and don't expect high performance from the Raspberry when it comes to rendering browser pages. I've added a little script that sends backups to my file server via SMB.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >File synching (Dropbox)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[**SpiderOak**](https://spideroak.com/signup/referral/4b01a22f64d398afbd846637080bd2b4/). A true zero-knowledge encrypted file storage. With the new ["Hive" feature](https://spideroak.com/hive/) it behaves exactly like Dropbox, but has additional features like a backup service. Choose a safe password and store it somewhere secure, because Spideroak can not recover your password or your files if you loose it. I started with the 2GB free for life account, but it soon grew to a 50GB account. Great stuff, very reliable, safe.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Evernote
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >**[SpiderNote](http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2014/03/02/replace-evernote-with-spidernote/)**. It may be a bit cobbled together, but as an old Evernote fan I needed a good alternative and it should be able to sync between all my Macs. So I save my notes in a SpiderOak folder and search them with Spotlight. Not as fancy as Evernote, but the price (risk) of storing my data unencrypted on an American server became too high. **
**
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Facebook
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[**Twitter**](https://twitter.com/rolfje#). I hate to dissapoint you, but Facebook is free of charge and they store your entire digital life. What do you think is Facebook's product precisely? Also, I see that you have 86.355 "friends" on Facebook. I hate to disappoint you but those are called "random strangers". Even if your account is *cough* private (except for Mark $uckeberg). I like to talk to people too, that's why I have this blog, and for the smaller chit-chat I use Twitter. My real friends are on Threema, or, if need be, I talk to them. It's very old-fashioned. I drive over and meet them in person. And sometimes they even come to my house. I know, crazy right? Old school.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >LinkedIn
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >None. I could hold the same rant for Facebook and LinkedIn alike. They're not there for you. You're there for them. I did make the mistake of creating a LinkedIn account a long time ago because people said "you need this". After quite a few mails from LinkedIn requesting me to endorse people, update my profile or water their plants, I realized that I was working for them, not the other way around. I cancelled and deleted my account. Guess what? I'm still alive and well. If you're a developer, you're better off by gaining community based reputation on sites like **[Stackoverflow](https://stackoverflow.com/users/21134/rolf)**.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr valign="top" >
&lt;td >Local Backups
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >**[Encrypted TimeMachine](http://support.apple.com/kb/PH11102)** and Time Capsule volumes. My local drives are also full-disk encrypted using Apple's built-in [FileVault 2](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4790?viewlocale=en_US&amp;locale=en_US). There is a Mac Mini file server in the house which holds all familiy photos  so that we can view them on the TV for example. The photos are on a read-only fileshare and are backed up using Time Machine locally.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Remote/Offsite Backups
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[**Crashplan Free**](https://www.code42.com/store/), sending the data on the TimeMachine drive on the fileserver to another fileserver at my parents' house. His fileserver backs up on my machine and vice-versa. One house can completely burn down and we still have all data, without it ever being uploaded to some unencrypted company server.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
**Why not Telegram?**
A few words of advice on using Telegram: Whatever they tell you, the data is *not* (properly) encrypted and it is easy to tell: The data is [stored in their "cloud"](http://unhandledexpression.com/2013/12/17/telegram-stand-back-we-know-maths/) and provided to you on all your devices. Even worse: They are [showing your data to "potential friends"](http://mcleaver.blogspot.nl/2014/02/telegram-verses-whatsapp.html?m=1) who [do not have you in their contact](https://twitter.com/GVerbaan/status/436909531625697280) lists or may have never heard of you. They upload your complete address book to their servers. They also know the [geolocation of your phone](http://blog.hackapp.com/2013/12/telegram-secret-chat-geolocation-leak.html). Unencrypted. They have your data, and show it by leaking it. They can fix the leaks and tell you it's safe, but they still have your data. It's also fishy that they clearly [have money to pimp their server farm](https://twitter.com/telegram/status/437745646007631872), even when the app and the messages are free of charge. Who do you think is the product here?
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.netmess.org/only-threema-rated-uncritical-telegram-rated-critical-for-privacy/">&lt;img src="telegram.png" alt=""Come in to the dark side. We have privacy"">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How big is 5 Zettabyte?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.spyvsspyhq.com/images.html">&lt;img src="3050431703_spyblack_answer_2_xlarge.jpeg" alt="Spy vs Spy">
&lt;/a>Since the interview of &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/jun/09/nsa-whistleblower-edward-snowden-interview-video">Edward Snowden with the Guardian&lt;/a>, the discussion about privacy and companies storing and sharing unencrypted private data is picking up. Particularly Americans are worried about what it does for their National security and their private data. But that's actually a naive thought, given the NSA stores worldwide data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">recent coverage on theblaze.com&lt;/a> (a rather tabloid-looking news station in the U.S.), the interviewers are shocked to see that the NSA spies on &amp;quot;every American&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a limited view of the world and failing to see the importance of spying on people &lt;em>outside&lt;/em> the U.S., but lets start with technical side of things first. What data are they storing and how big is their hard-disk?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->As you may know, the internet is a [packet switching network](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing). Although people try to mess with the routing and sometimes even [disconnect whole countries](http://www.bgpmon.net/syria-shuts-down-the-internet/), it is hard to make a packet travel a certain route or prevent it from traveling through a certain country. Much of the internet traffic passes through the U.S. regardless of it's source and destination. But even if it didn't, the NSA has that covered. Many companies, Like Facebook, [Google](http://highscalability.com/google-architecture) has [servers all over the world](http://serverfault.com/questions/370385/location-of-google-servers). Since Google and Facebook are companies registered in the U.S. the [NSA could technically indirectly tap into](http://www.breitbart.com/Big-Government/2013/06/09/NSA-Obtains-Data-From-50-Companies) one of their servers in a foreign country which contains data which never travelled through the US in the first place.
&lt;p>According to the &lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/stats.htm">worldwide distribution of internet users&lt;/a>, if the NSA wanted to store data just about Americans, they could have built a much smaller, simpler facility. But they didn't, which make you think. So how big is this facility exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://img.pr0gramm.com/2009/04/funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg">&lt;img src="funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg" alt="Holy Crepe">
&lt;/a>5 Zettabyte**
If you've watched the &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">coverage&lt;/a>, you'll hear James Bamford say that the facility that the NSA is building can hold enough physical machines to store around 5 Zettabyte of data, given current technology standards. It sounds like a lot, but how big is a Zettabyte really?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettabyte">wikipedia&lt;/a>, 5 Zettabyte is 5,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 bytes. If, like me, you can not get your head around a number with 21 zeroes in it, I'll give you some of the calculations I made to understand just how big this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with the Internet Archive. Currently, the Internet Archive and it's &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/59207751">Wayback machine holds 10 Petabytes&lt;/a> of data (10,000,000,000,000,000 bytes). The servers at the Internet Archive crawl the Internet and store all public data they can find in a searchable manner. They provide the public with that data, so you can do cool things like &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.rolfje.com">see how my blog looked 10 years ago&lt;/a>. The Internet Archive is pretty big you might think. With 5ZB, the NSA could store the complete Internet Archive &lt;em>500,000 times&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to world population&lt;/strong>
Ok so maybe the size of the internet, or the size of a Petabyte are not very imaginable. Let's take it to the individual level. At the time of this writing, there are &lt;a href="http://www.worldometers.info">roughly 7.124.855.134 people on the world&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the NSA would wanted to store information on every person in the world, regardless if they were a president or a newborn African child, they would have 701,768,654,374 bytes per person to do so:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperperson.png" alt="5ZB per person">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, they can store 701GB for each person in the world. My personal email archive is around 5GB right now, and I have a 1TB hard-disk containing every (digital or digitized) photo I have ever made. If I would be the standard (which I am probably not), the NSA could very easily store everybody's personal data, worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to the people connected to the internet&lt;/strong>
Not everybody is connected to the internet (in fact that's not entirely true but we'll come to that later). As you have probably already seen on the &lt;a href="http://worldmeters.info">worldmeters.info&lt;/a> site, there are roughly 2,552,435,328 active internet users (at the time of writing). So let's see what the NSA can store if they &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; target the internet users:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperuser.png" alt="5ZB per Internet User">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah that's better. Almost &lt;strong>2TB per Internet user&lt;/strong>. The NSA can now not only store my private data, photo's and videos, but now there is room to spare so I can put a couple of blockbuster movies in there, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the NSA probably does some smart data reduction, like storing an email I send to you just once instead of a copy for each of us, I'm guessing the practical space per user will be more like 4TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YozC8yFrZKI">&lt;img src="p.png" alt="Homer">
&lt;/a>Am I connected to the internet?**
In short: Yes. We are all connected in some way to the internet. Particularly if you are living in a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_world">&amp;quot;Western Country&amp;quot;&lt;/a> you can be sure that in some way you, or at least data about your existance, is online somewhere. Cities store data about their inhabitants and share them with other departments and services to do their work. By default, this data travels accross the internet and we all know how good governements are at protecting and encrypting their data, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's do an interesting thought experiment to see how far this goes. Suppose I have never connected to the internet, and neither have you. I own an old &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota_Corolla_(E70)">Toyota Corolla E70&lt;/a> and you and I stayed with our trusty &lt;a href="http://nokiamuseum.info/nokia-p-30/">Nokia P-30&lt;/a>'s. Now let's say I lend you my car. The NSA would know about that, instantly. How? My car is registered to me. The roads are covered with cameras to detect traffic violations, but in fact, the most governments like to store data about which car is going where. Our cellphones are connected to cell towers, which reveals &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_phone_tracking">pretty accurate data&lt;/a> about where they are. So the NSA can map the time and place of my car to the time and place of my cell phone and all cell phones I've called. They would quickly and easily discover that my car is moving with your cellphone in it. The fact that their data shows that my cellphone is at home means that you are probably driving my car. Based on our cellphone data, it would even be pretty easy to see our daily commutes, see where you and I work and when and where we met in person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conspiracy? &lt;em>Maybe.&lt;/em> Possibility? &lt;em>Yes.&lt;/em> Privacy breach? &lt;em>Absolutely.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different countries have different meanings of the word &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy">&amp;quot;Privacy&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. By definition, gathering of data which is considered to be private (secret or confidential) in the country of origin, is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espionage">Espionage&lt;/a>. This is not surprising, as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_War">old habbits die hard&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I don't care, I have nothing to hide.&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5VAgSdGnSQ">&lt;img src="gollum.jpg" alt="Gollum has something to hide">
&lt;/a>Not so fast grasshopper. You do. In fact, the NSA just introduced the very need to keep your data private and store it locally, indefinitely. In the example above, suppose you used my car to take pictures as a hobby photographer of a crime scene that was in the news. With the data they gathered, the NSA could frame either you or me at that scene, at their peril. Because you and I have no access to the data they are storing about us, it will be very hard for you or me to prove that we weren't, because the NSA will not provide you or the court with data that will prove otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for mail and other communications. Tabloid journalists can explain how to use one email, or once sentence from an email out of context to start a nasty gossip. The NSA could do that too. Suppose you are sharing role-playing stories with a friend over email. Those emails could suddenly look very interesting when placed out of context. Don't think they will not do that. &lt;a href="http://www.whereisthemoney.org/1.1trillion.htm">Power corrupts.&lt;/a> They will, and very likely already have done so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_Make_Me_Think">Don't make me think&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
I've always said that the failure to make stuff user friendly is the single most important reason for brilliant ideas to &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/06/14/nsa-proof-encryption-exists-why-doesnt-anyone-use-it/">fail miserably&lt;/a>. In the light of current events and the power of modern computers, can we at least try to make strong encryption like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy">PGP&lt;/a> stupid-easy to use, and add &amp;quot;coolness&amp;quot; so people will &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to use it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Because much like openness, responsibility and privacy is now more important than ever.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Related material I found while writing this blog post:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la Prison](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discipline_and_Punish) is a 1975 book by the French philosopher Michel Foucault. If he was still alive, Foucault would probably see that after a period of individualism and consumer-centric change, the NSA is the re-introduction the [Panopticon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panopticon), a prison (or society) where the prisoners can not see the guards.
* This Dutch program [&amp;quot;Dare to Think&amp;quot;](http://www.uitzendinggemist.nl/afleveringen/1304898) discusses how Foucault thought, and places it in the modern time. It discusses how modern individualism and a market driven society needs new mechanisms to steer the individual. The theory is in essence that people need to learn to steer themselves and check the self-set boundaries with others from time to time.
* In the source of Windows NT 4 Service Pack 5 a [variable with the name _NSAKEY](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NSAKEY) was discovered which led to speculation that Windows computers could leak private data to the NSA.
* Because few people do, When you decide to use PGP to encrypt your mail, you are likely to gain some attention, particularly from American &amp;quot;authorities&amp;quot;. Because you stand out. If you decide to stand out and encrypt stuff, you better do it right. Gather some information about [Uncrackable Email](http://www.ncmilitia.org/spycounterspy/fs006.html) (yes it's possible). Please note that all your encrypted mails will be stored, so when somebody does find reason to detain you and get your passphrase, deleting your drive will be useless.
* Estimations in the linked articles say that the NSA facility cost $2B to build, has it's own 65MW power station, 60,000 tons of cooling equipment, and an electricity bill of $40M per year (unclear if that includes running their own power station). If you looked closely at the WorldMeters link, you could have noticed that there are almost 4 million Cancer related deaths per year and 35 million HIV related deaths, versus [less than 8,000 terrorism related deaths in 2010](http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/09/global-terrorism-deaths). If the NSA is here to pretect us from dying, they'd better use their budget and intelligence to start investigating other stuff.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Gmail: Save an email to disk</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/10/18/gmail-save-an-email-to-disk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/10/18/gmail-save-an-email-to-disk/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="gmail-save-to-disk.png" alt="Gmail save to disk">
Want to save a single email from gmail to disk, in a readable format for Outlook, Thunderbird or Apple Mail? Here's how:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Open your browser and log into your gmail account.
2. Open the email you want to save.
3. On the top-right, there is a little triangle next to the &amp;quot;Reply&amp;quot; button. Click that, and select [&amp;quot;Show Original&amp;quot;](gmail-show-original.png).
4. The original, raw email opens in a new window or tab.
5. Right-click on this new window, and select [&amp;quot;Save as...&amp;quot;](gmail-save-as.png).
6. When saving the file, make sure the extension of the filename is &amp;quot;**eml**&amp;quot;. So for example [&amp;quot;MyEmail.eml&amp;quot;](gmail-name-it-eml.png).
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>All done. Now you dan open the file in Thunderbird, Outlook or whatever email viewer you have out there and see the original mail, in all it's marked-up glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting a high Google Quality Score.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/19/how-to-score-with-google/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 19:56:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/19/how-to-score-with-google/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="askdave-greenarticle.png">&lt;/a>The past week, I've heard some collegues talking about tweaking websites so that they will show up in Google search results. A lot of people actually try to figure out how to &amp;quot;fool&amp;quot; the Google search engine, and actually make a living writing books about it. The strange thing is, that a lot of people want to be the&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=Tapestry+OGNL+adaptor+for+class"> &amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> link in Google even when the search query hasn't got anything to do with the content they're providing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's actually a funny discussion, because this behaviour which &amp;quot;makes use&amp;quot; of the system, actually breaks it. Suppose a lot of people figure out how to get this done. Now, whenever you use Google, your first page of search results will actually contain stuff you're not looking for. After a few tries, you'll get tired of this and start using a different search engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->It's almost like today's monetary and financial systems, where somebody figures out a way to make money in a dubious way and knowing it. In the end, we know what will happen, but that's a whole different subject (keep posted ;-) ).
&lt;p>For some search terms, this site (yes, rolfje.com) is actually &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=replace+headlights+xsara">on the first page&lt;/a>, and sometimes even the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=lost+oracle+password">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> (I wonder for how long). Why? Well, because the good news is that at Google, there are a lot of smart people working on tweaking the search algorithms each day, to prevent people from succesfully creating &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_bomb">Google bombs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other very important reason is that when Google &amp;quot;crawls&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;spiders&amp;quot; this site, the content it's going to find is real, readable and honest. There are no &amp;quot;hidden fields&amp;quot; in the article which act as spider magnets. When somebody finds this site and likes it, chances are very high that they're going to link to the content. For Google, that's bonus points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do I do that? By doing the following 4 important things:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1) Do not try to influence Google&lt;/strong>
By adding false content like hidden search terms, malicious &lt;a href="http://www.developer-resource.com/spider-food.htm">spider food&lt;/a>, and paying people to link to your site, you may end up high on any search. The trouble with that is that you are not reaching your intended audience (they were looking for something else). By showing up again and again on the first page, people will develop &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_blindness">&amp;quot;ad blindness&amp;quot;&lt;/a> for your site name. This means they will never, ever click on anything which looks like your URL because you've &amp;quot;betrayed&amp;quot; them before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2) Educate people, educate Google&lt;/strong>
Did you ever have that problem that you were searching for an answer on Google, but all you found were other people with the same question you had? And when you found the answer, did you blog about it? No? Too bad, that was the absolute chance of getting an &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=tomcat+utf8+requestdumpervalve">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3) Put some effort in your posts&lt;/strong>
I can't count the number of times when I found what seemed to be the answer to my question, but the page was hard to read, incomplete or plain wrong. If you want to be the &amp;quot;go-to site&amp;quot; for answers, write them as clear, consise, and complete as possible without using to much &amp;quot;fluff&amp;quot; or intelligent words. People will love you for it, and link to your posts. You can even re-use your own material by pointing to it when somebody asks you a question which you know your blog has the answer to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4) Layout!
The attention span of surfers is short. It's often measured in seconds, or in mouse clicks. To keep somebody on your site, you'd better come up with an easy to read article which contains at least a hint of providing a solution in the first sentence of the post. Having too much blinking ads, colorful layout or a small font will distract from the content, and people will leave early. This is caused by &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.useit.com/alertbox/banner-blindness.html">banner-blindness&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="askdave-greenarticle.png">&lt;img src="askdave-greenarticle.png?w=97" alt="">
&lt;/a>Here's a good example. I've made a screen shot of an &lt;a href="http://www.askdavetaylor.com/">&amp;quot;askdavetaylor&amp;quot;&lt;/a> article. Dave writes nice articles with answers to simple everyday Mac OSX related questions. Every now and then, Dave shows up in my Google searches, but not nearly as much as he could. Why? He violates rule 1 and 4. The page contains all kinds of words and links which have nothing to do with the actual content, and the layout is terrible. On the right, you see a screenshot of Dave's site, where I marked the actual content with a green color. Do you see how hard this must be to read? The article actually squeezes between some unrelated links and a very large Google ad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rolfje-greenarticle.png">&lt;img src="rolfje-greenarticle.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>As a comparison, I did the same with this blog. See the difference? The actual content is much closer to the top of the browser, and most of the time the answer can be found in the first few sentences. There is less distraction and less scrolling. Even if there is some scrolling involved, there are no terrible &amp;quot;next page&amp;quot; links to read further. &amp;quot;next page&amp;quot; links mean the article can not be printed, and it takes an extra amount of time reloading all the ads when I want to continue reading. Half of your audience is gone at the second mouseclick, and will never return (including their first click on the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=java+5+bigdecimal+oracle">&amp;quot;I feel lucky&amp;quot;&lt;/a> button).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're still reading at this point, your attention span is longer than the average reader. Congratulations. It also means that you care enough about this stuff to apply to your own site. So I'll stop typing and let you to it. Remember: Focus, and try to be honest and to the point. Less is more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Maps Improved?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/29/google-maps-improved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 22:10:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/29/google-maps-improved/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Just noticed a funny Google Maps parody video. Enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fPgV6-gnQaE">[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fPgV6-gnQaE&amp;amp;rel=1]&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Talk with your browser!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/08/google-talk-with-your-browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 20:39:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/08/google-talk-with-your-browser/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_googletalk-in-browser.gif">&lt;img src="o_googletalk-in-browser.thumbnail.gif" alt="Google talk in the browser">
&lt;/a>For some reason I've been selected my the google company to have the new interface of gmail, where you can use google talk without even installing it! Yes you've read that right. When I log in to Google, I immediately see a quick contacts list of people who are online (on googletalk), and I can chat with them as if I was using the actual application! Only voice is missing, but I don't use that anyway (Skype fan), so I am really happy.Now I can google-talk with my friends on &lt;em>any&lt;/em> computer without having to install plugins, upgrading MSN otherwise contaminating the host's computer. I am really impressed and amazed (for the past 3 hours or so). Go Google! I feel like buying a t-shirt now :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yeah, and it works in both FireFox and Microsoft Internet Explorer. And I am not kidding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Auch, and I just missed the &lt;a href="http://slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=06/02/07/1327248">scoop on Slashdot...&lt;/a> I could have been a succesful submitter. so close, so close.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>