<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 18:14:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Steve Jobs' yacht launched, named "Venus"</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/10/28/steve-jobs-yacht-called-venus-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 18:14:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/10/28/steve-jobs-yacht-called-venus-launched/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZh4aSszD5k">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZh4aSszD5k&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Steve Job's yacht was launched from a dock a few miles from my house. I went there with some friends and we shot some awesome footage of this incredible ship. Through the glass, we could see the 7 iMacs which are used to control the ship. There are also large doors on the side and the back, I suspect these will be used to launch boats or jetskis into a nice warm Mediterranean water.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->We were able to catch a glimpse of it's name on the stern: "Venus". Too bad Steve didn't get to enjoy this. I hope is family and friends have a great time aboard this ship.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="20121028_113907.jpg">&lt;img src="20121028_113907.jpg" alt="Steve Jobs' yacht, side">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="20121028_114233.jpg">&lt;img src="20121028_114233.jpg" alt="Steve Jobs' yacht, stern">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="imacs-cropped.jpg">&lt;img src="imacs-cropped.jpg" alt="iMacs on bridge of Venus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kihsnQjgFg8">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kihsnQjgFg8&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Having fun at J-Fall 2011</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2973-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2973-small.jpg?w=150" alt="J-Fall 2011">
&lt;/a>This year's Dutch Java Nerd event called &lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/">J-Fall&lt;/a> was held in Nijkerk, in a beautiful location called &lt;a href="http://www.regardz.nl/locaties/event-centers/regardz-hart-van-holland-nijkerk.aspx?gclid=CK7bg8zwmKwCFUMm3godUFpdPQ">&amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;&lt;/a> . With plenty of sessions by speakers from all over the world it promised to be a great day for Java enthusiasts, at a great location for meeting friends and colleagues. I took a day off from work and it was well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00024/">&lt;!-- more -->Opening by Bert Ertman&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Bert starts the day by welcoming the 1000+ attendees in the main presentation room in &amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;. After explaining what the day is going to bring and where to find rooms, food, drinks, and company booths, he goes on to tell how they tried to get better network coverage. All these nerds with their smartphones in one single place is asking for trouble. It turns out it's too expensive to get good data network so they didn't do that. Network connections proved to be spotty at best in the main building, but I had good 3G coverage outside the main building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The organizer of &lt;a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Home">Devoxx&lt;/a> came by to say hi, and also told us that the J-Fall presentations are being professionally captured and the most popular ones are going to be online soon at &lt;a href="http://www.parleys.com/">parleys.com&lt;/a>. He closed off with the hilarious &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b-Cr0EWwaTk">&amp;quot;Java Life&amp;quot; Rap Music Video&lt;/a> . By the way if you liked that, you certainly will like the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2UFc1pr2yUU">&amp;quot;Whole foods Parking Lot&amp;quot; video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00025/">Java 7 Directors Cut&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
After the cool opening and videos the whole room was ready for some kick-ass sessions. Tomas Nilsson said that he would have a hard time topping the Java Life music video. And he did. Opening with a laughable slide containing a full page mandatory disclaimer text, the presentation was a terrible erratic drive through his very personal memory lane, and after 15 minutes he lost about 80% of the audience. I had absolutely no idea what point he was trying to make, and why nobody advised him to revise his presentation after he gave the same talk at JavaOne. The good thing was that because of the spotty network coverage, not all tweets during this presentation reached the twitter servers, and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23jfall">#jfall&lt;/a> was not trending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the small coffee break we gather around to see what sessions each of us want to join. Scanning the company booths in the main lobby learns that the world didn't change: Booths luring you with pens, mints, stickers, iPads and nice ladies in the booth who are almost always never representing the companies' people or culture. I did score some nice ball pens though :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00071/">Building Highly Scalable Java Applications on Windows Azure&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Microsoft being a big sponsor of this year's J-Fall, they have to have a keynote. And so they did. And it was a good one. Certainly after the below par presentation skills of Oracle, Microsoft has a nicely polished slides and a demo of Azure, a good story and good pace. During the demo the DNS switching is a bit slow and prevents some things to be shown. At the end of the talk, the speaker confidently retries and it now works. This results in a well-deserved warm applause from the audience. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/doortje123/status/131721454352998400">Well done Microsoft&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00050/">The Java EE7 Platform: Developing for the Cloud&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
With &amp;quot;Cloud&amp;quot; being the new buzzword nowadays, &lt;a href="http://www.java.net/blogs/arungupta/">Arun Gupta&lt;/a> did a keynote on where Java 7 is going, and how applications would fit in this cloud structure. I never heard the term &amp;quot;tenants&amp;quot; being used in this respect, which was interesting. The whole talk was a bit erratic, and after Java EE 6 fixing all the EJB gripes of EJB 3, I couldn't help but feeling that all these &amp;quot;enterprisey&amp;quot; terms are re-introduced in Java 7. The whole idea that you build an application but other people configure the actual building blocks that your application will be instantiated with, is a proven failure to me. Administrators don't have developer knowledge. Changing configuration of key components in your application will severely break it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I came out of this session not feeling to hot about Java 7 and the whole components-in-the cloud and people renting instances idea. Too many roles, academic, over engineered, very Sun Enterprise EJB 2 feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00066/">Don't call us - we'll push&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
A colleague advised be to go see &lt;a href="http://technology.amis.nl/blog/author/lucas">Lucas Jellema&lt;/a>. Lucas was the first speaker of the day who actually seemed to know what he was doing on stage. Although his slides were a bit crowded, he had a good story with many demos. It was a welcome change after Tomas and Arun, although Lucas didn't have any real new stuff. Polling, long-polls, asynchronus AJAX calls and the old request/response problem in http, and database triggers firing Java programs. Except for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket">Web Sockets&lt;/a> there was nothing new but nice to be reminded how these things actually work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Lucas' talk we went to get our complimentary lunch. Because we were relatively early, we had no problems getting the lunch package, and enjoyed our tasty sandwiches, milk, apples and Mars. Another free coffee and we're recharged and ready for the afternoon sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00053/">Migrating Spring to Java EE 6&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/paulb01">Paul Bakker&lt;/a> &lt;a href="img_2974-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2974-small.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>had clearly prepared his slides well, and insisted in giving his talk in English because it would be recorded. I thought this was a nice touch (in case you haven't noticed, I have this idea that everything you want to share with technical people should be in English). Paul explained the tactics to use when converting a Spring application to Java EE 6. Where to start, and how to keep your code compiling while doing the conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have worked on some large projects and although Paul mentions that some parts of the conversion will take a bit more time than others, I am not looking forward to convert my current 250+ thousand lines of code to Java EE 6 just yet. A plain Spring application may be easy, but as soon as you have Spring AOP, interesting Proxy beans and Custom Factory beans, you'd have to rewrite that code in Java EE6, which could take quite some time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I predict converting to Java EE 6 will be much more expensive than upgrading to the next version of Spring for most serious enterprise level applications. I have a home project I'd try to convert first, maybe more on that later on this blog, who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00056/">Extreme performance with the Disruptor&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Although the title and the talk description in the schedule didn't hint too much about it, this talk was 100% about Queues. After some high level talk about Producers, Consumers and Queues, &lt;a href="http://blog.dutchworks.nl/author/allard/">Allard Buijze&lt;/a> drops a bomb and introduces some circle and the name &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot;, without introduction. After a few slides everybody understands that this is some kind of &amp;quot;Circular Queue&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a bit of a laugh when Allard uses 4 slides to explain about dirty cache line reads at CPU level and how the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/">Disruptor&lt;/a> prevents all that, which he then dismisses with &amp;quot;but that doesn't help much&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The talk was entertaining and what I got from it is that the main reason why the &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot; works faster than regular Queues, is that Producers and Consumers can inform each other about their position in the queue, which prevents Queue polling. I can't help but think that this can be done with regular Queue implementations as well, so maybe I missed something here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00058/">Java Tuning Puzzlers&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
For the final session for today most of us decided to go to &amp;quot;Java Tuning Puzzlers&amp;quot;, because it looked like fun. And it was. The presentation by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/kjkoster">Kees Jan Koster&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/jpinpointcom">Jeroen Borgers&lt;/a> was fast, funny, interactive, hands-on and very refreshing. They showed some real-life performance problems they encountered in their work, and asked the audience to solve them. All Java nerds lit up and started shouting answers and funny remarks. Jeroen and particularly Kees Jan were very good in answering questions and snarky comments from the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the talk went into overtime and the organization was trying to cut it short, Jeroen and Kees Jan asked the audience &amp;quot;are we going to get beer, or are we going to finish this?&amp;quot;. The whole audience shouted &amp;quot;Finish it!&amp;quot; and we finished the last Puzzler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No fancy new frameworks, no buzzword bingo, just plain old dry-coding and a plug for one of my favorite tools, findbugs &lt;a href="http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/">http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a> . It was the best session I had all day, and I actually went back to Kees Jan and Jeroen to compliment them with their awesome talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
I might sound a bit critical here and there, but I had a great day. Being amongst fellow-nerds, talking tech talk, sharing funny stories, listening to interesting new developments and hearing other people's views on things was really refreshing. Next thing on my list: Try to get Kees Jan Koster to do at least one big main-track keynote at J-Spring or J-Fall next year, about any subject. Because he will at least keep the audience awake.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks Bert and all of the NLJug people and sponsors who made this possible. See you all at J-Spring!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2978-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2978-small.jpg" alt="Oracle J-Fall flowers">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The rumors can stop now. iPad is here.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png?w=119" alt="">
&lt;/a>So the word is finally out, it's going to be the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/">iPad&lt;/a>. I was kind of worried about this, and my worries are not completely taken away by the news currently oozing out of the Apple keynote. I see some problems with this device, although they are well hidden under Steve's reality distortion field, the Apple secret sauce and the &amp;quot;gee why didn't we think of that&amp;quot; features.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * The dock for the iPad is has me worried about mechanical failure. A large device resting on a small connector.
* Most people I know have a macbook and/or an iPhone. The iPad overlaps both the macbook and the iPhone in functionality, and it requires an extra data subscription. So they will probably hold out for a bit.
* Although the rest of the pad looks beautiful, the &amp;quot;home&amp;quot; button makes it into a big iPhone which I personally think is not a plus.
* The carriers will try to sell you the 3G models, subsidized. Don't go for that, buy the wifi instead, or try to get the wifi+3G sim-lock free. I'm glad Apple did not go for the carrier lock in construction on this one.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I admit, the video looks stunning. The UI is very polished (look at the pinch to peek in a stack of photo's), the device is nice and thin. Notice how the screen does not go all the way to the edge, so that you can put your thumb somewhere to hold it. And although it lacks a camera, it has all other iPhone features (yes, including GPS) so almost all iPhone apps will work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The additional $130 for the 3G option may be a bit steep, but the overall pricing is pretty good, almost competing with the netbooks, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/pricing/">starting at $499&lt;/a> at the 16GB wifi only model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judging from the very young information right now, I understand that I may not be target audience for this advice. I need a keyboard and a large screen. But if you're in the (American) market for a netbook or something to browse a bit on the couch, have a look at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/ipad-video/#medium">the video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tweet Week</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/rolfje">&lt;img src="twitter-logo.png" alt="Twitter">
&lt;/a>About a week ago, I was a bit bored and decided to see what Twitter is all about. I created an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje">account&lt;/a>, and I Tweeted for a week. I tried to keep to the original idea, where a Tweet should answer the question &amp;quot;What are you doing&amp;quot;? Looking back, my tweets include &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1198486833">Coffee&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1199748992">Podcasts&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1200610213">Global frustration&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1203692363">Small joys&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1206502512">Small irritations&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209317512">Re-tweets&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209634779">Replies&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Twitter is a service were you can send short texts of 140 characters or less, called "tweets". These texts end up on a webpage, resulting in a micro-blog for all to read. Think of it as SMS-ing to your blog. One of the fun parts of Twitter is that people find really creative ways to express themselves in 140 characters or less. This allows you to follow an amazing amount of people, getting short messages about what they're doing, such as ["is relaxing with the wife and kids..... at home"](https://twitter.com/richard_hammond/statuses/1209417438)  or   ["Great meal at Michael Minna with my best gal"](https://twitter.com/ev/statuses/1211691640).
&lt;table border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["at"](afbeelding-1.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Should you find a "Tweet" you think is interesting, you can reply to that person (not to the tweet directly) by starting your tweet with an "@" and the username of the person you want to reply to. 
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["hash"](afbeelding-2.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >You can even "tag" your Tweets by using a "#" and a word. So for instance "#rolfje" would add the tag "rolfje" to my Tweet. You can then easily [search tweets with this tag](http://hashtags.org/tag/rolfje). Tags are sometimes used to create something of a "communications channel". For instance, the [#followfriday](http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday) tag is used to tweet about people you think are worth following.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
Starting in the US, Twitter is becoming increasingly popular all over the world, now taking over Europe. [BBC had an item](http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/7287536.stm) on English television about twitter, massively increasing the number of English twitterers. 
&lt;p>And ofcourse, where there are people, there are money-sharks to spoil the fun. Some companies are showing up, and are clearly not understanding what Twitter is about. They start a twitter account and twitter promotional messages, product releases, etc. The problem with this (for the company) is that for this to be succesful, people must follow you. If there's nothing interesting to read, people will not follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This same problem occurs with people who have their staff update their twitter accounts. This makes for really uninteresting, unpersonal tweets, and replying to them will almost never result in a nice conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com">&lt;img src="http://laikaspoetnik.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/twitter-addicts.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**What I used:
**During my Tweetweek, I tried different OSX and iPhone clients. There are a lot of clients out there, but none of them are good enough to be your &amp;quot;single client of choice&amp;quot;. Here's what I think of them, in short:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl&lt;/a>: Done in Adobe AIR, multi-platform and consistent accross OS's. Good for a Windows app, terrible for an OSX app. Settings are in strange places, not clear what the &amp;quot;narrow&amp;quot; column mode is for. Ugly but probably the best twitter client out there, with twitpic and tinyurl integration all out of the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetdeck.com/beta/">Tweetdeck&lt;/a>: Also done in Adobe AIR, mutli-platform and consistent. Works fine, has multiple columns for monitoring your tweets, search results and profiles. Feels a bit funny, for instance the same icon is used for &amp;quot;show input window&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;send tweet&amp;quot;. It works, but it doesn't fit the &amp;quot;clean and simple&amp;quot; design I think a twitter client needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific">Twitterific&lt;/a>: Nice design, clean. Not much features, too overpriced. If Twitterific had tinyURL and twitpic integration, and sold for about $5, it would be a huge hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=296415944&amp;amp;mt=8">Tweetie (iPhone)&lt;/a>: The funny thing is that &amp;quot;Tweetie&amp;quot;, the iPhone twitter client is way better than any of the clients I tried on a normal computer. Tweetie wins hands down. The best twitter client for the iPhone, simple and clean, camera integration, GPS integration. This also fits way better in the twitter philosophy, Tweeting whatever you are doing, wherever you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I learned:&lt;/strong>
Twitter is for everyday people, like you and me, and feels like a mix between &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens'_Band_Radio">CB radio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texting">texting&lt;/a>. Twitter is all about you and who you follow. It's definetely not about your followers. Ofcourse you can try to get as much followers as possible, but I think that does not guarantee a nice twitter experience. Some people think it's rude not to follow back if they're followed, and will tweet to let somebody know that they're being &amp;quot;un-followed&amp;quot;. I think that's not how the system is supposed to work. There's also no real relationship. Follow or unfollow, it's not like you're devorcing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just Tweet, and see what happens. There's no currency, only small text messages from people around the world for you to read and reply to. Or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bill's Mosquitoes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.png" alt="Bill Gates Releases Musquitoes">
&lt;/a>Bill Gates found a very good way to get the news reporters to pay attention to the malaria problem. In his talk at the TED conference, he released a few mosquitoes, stating that malaria should not be just for poor people to experience. People who did not see the whole performance may react shocked, because when placed out of context it sounds like an outrageous thing to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that's the case, you should maybe &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">have a look at his talk&lt;/a>, available (for free, without registering) at TED.com. You'll see that the audience is actually laughing when he releases the mosquitoes, and at the end of the talk Bill gets a standing ovation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the malaria problem, Bill also makes a very good case about how important good teachers are, and what we can do to help teachers become just that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Noisy feeds and bad news</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/16/noisy-feeds-and-bad-news/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 14:15:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/16/noisy-feeds-and-bad-news/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Since the comming of rss feeds, the world is a better place for online people like me. I can select interesting newsfeeds I'd like to read, and compose my own newspaper. For newssites, this requires a new skill. For them to keep me as a reader, they need to keep the rss feed up to date, and with items I'd like to see. Because I can do research on the spot, the news items better be balanced, verified and unbiased (unless it's funny ;-). Recently I dumped the &lt;a href="http://www.nu.nl/">nu.nl&lt;/a> rss feed because of the constant re-posting of only slightly modified articles.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->At this time, I am monitoring about 30 newsfeeds, which are mostly centered around programming and technology. I don't care much for journalism in general, because I think nowadays it's biased, often unverified, and very much geared to "get the most viewers". This results in over-the-top dramatic and emotional articles, generally only covering death, hunger, war and preferably contains "shocking images". Good news just doesn't sell.
&lt;p>Up until now, I only had 1 rss feed covering local daily news, which was the nu.nl feed. A few weeks ago, I noticed that nu.nl had become more active. The rss feed kept popping up as having new items, but when I checked them, they looked familiar. At the time I thought it was a date-bug in either the reader or at the feedserver. Today, I checked more thourougly and found out that this is probably deliberate. 33% of the items in the nu.nl rss feed are re-posts or only slightly modified articles. Very irritating, and almost makes you think that the nu.nl journalists are freelancers which are payed per article. It gave me the feeling of a little kid who is telling you over-and-over again that it found a penny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="nu-rss-done-right.png">&lt;img src="nu-rss-done-right.png" alt="nu rss feed done right">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took a screenshot of the nu.nl feed in the &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com/">Google Reader&lt;/a>, and highlighted the double entries. Then I removed the articles which could have been prevented from showing up in the rss feed. The result is shown at the right. From the 33 articles in the original feed, only 22 contained new information. That means that 33% of the feed-alerts for the nu.nl feed makes me waste time to look at news I've allready seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If somebody tells me that people are dying somewere, it ruins my day. I can't stand people hurting eachother. Since journalists are having the tendency to report people dying every 6 seconds (because it sells), and nu.nl also finds it necesary to make sure I read it by re-posting 33% of their content, I've dropped the feed. And actually it feels nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've already almost stopped watching TV, because of the repetiteveness, and constant display of dead, dismembered people 24x7, regardless of viewer age or interest. Now, I've unsubscribed the last &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; newsfeed and I think my world will get brighter because of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe someday the word &amp;quot;reality&amp;quot; is no longer related to 5000 top-payed reporters pointing their camera's at a dying child without helping it. And I hope that that same day, the word &amp;quot;reality-TV&amp;quot; is no longer related to locking people inside a house, pointing camera's at them while they fight eachother for a moneyprice. And maybe, just maybe, the word &amp;quot;news&amp;quot; could also include the &lt;a href="http://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/">good news&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="http://www.explodingcigar.com/article2042.html">wierd news&lt;/a>, and every other kind of news to balance things out. And if that day is &lt;a href="http://www.yarr.org.uk/">19 September&lt;/a>, we'd be in for a lot of fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pomphouders dupe van 'spookliters'</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/24/pomphouders-dupe-van-spookliters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 20:52:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/01/24/pomphouders-dupe-van-spookliters/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For those that can read Dutch. &lt;a href="http://www.nos.nl/nos/artikelen/2006/01/art00006006024D.html">This&lt;/a> is a nice example of Dutch gasstation owners wanting to be compensated for the fact that gasoline (or any other fluid you can sell) schrinks when cooled.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->What happens is, that the delivery trucks cary the gasoline at the normal outside temperatures. When pumped into the underground tanks at the station, the number of liters is measured and the gasstation owner gets charged for those liters. Then, the gasoline cools down (and shrinks!) because it is stored underground. So when de car owners put the gas in their car, the cold ("smaller") liters get measured and the gasstation owner is "swindled by nature" because het can only sell say 99 liters of gasoline, while he bought 100 from the oil company!
&lt;p>Now, things get better because the gassstation owner wants to be compensated for this law of nature! It's like wanting to be compensated for the fact that you get wet when you jump in the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let's say this is &lt;em>really&lt;/em> a problem, because in my opinion it isn't, they make enough money and they could have known this upfront if they have had payed attention in first grade. You can basically do two things about this:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Insulate the underground tank, and maybe even heat it. You can actually now &amp;quot;swindle&amp;quot; the car owners, because you can sell them &amp;quot;more&amp;quot; petrol than you have bought from the oil company! Woopee!. You might want to check your heating bill at the end of the year though, I doubt it will do you any good.
2. We can start selling petrol/gasoline by *kilograms*, which is actually allready standard in some forms of industry. It's a bit harder to measure, but absolutely independant of the temperature of the product
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Just another fine example of people allways wanting to change the rules and be compensated for anything they &amp;quot;missed out&amp;quot; on. And we find it strange that the world becomes more burocratic. tsss.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>