<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>update on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in update on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 22:03:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OSX 10.5.1 Update, still SMB problems</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/16/osx-1051-update-still-smb-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 22:03:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/16/osx-1051-update-still-smb-problems/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week, I hapily installed OSX 10.5 (Leopard) on my trusty Mac Mini. The upgrade from Tiger went without a hitch, and the system even got a bit &amp;quot;snappier&amp;quot;. For a week, I had no major issues with Leopard. The Dock dissapeared once, and I had a non-reacting keyboard once when waking from sleep mode. Other than that I am a happy Leopard user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up until a few das ago, when I tried to access my newly acquired 500GB &lt;a href="http://www.iomega.com/direct/products/detail.jsp?PRODUCT%3C%3Eprd_id=51400371&amp;amp;FOLDER%3C%3Efolder_id=31699021&amp;amp;ASSORTMENT%3C%3East_id=26890319&amp;amp;bmUID=1195162566206">Iomega Network Storage&lt;/a>. The Iomega drive is a network connected drive, formatted as FAT32, and accessible through the samba (SMB://) protocol. With Leopard, I could see the drive in the network, and I could double click on it's shares, but when (if) the share connected, I could not drag files onto it, or see what is on the disk. Unmounting takes ages, and sometimes requires me to &amp;quot;killall -9 Finder&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I browsed the net and found quite a few people on forums discussing the same problem. Luckaly, Apple also had payed attention, and put out an update, which I installed just a few minutes ago. Sad thing is, that this update does not solve my problem (yes, that's Dutch you're reading):
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upload to Samba Share problem">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I tried all tips I could find in the forums:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Connect using the IP address, rather than the network name
* Change the group of the device (WORKGROUP changed to NOTIT)
* Remove any non-alphabetical characters from paswords
* Remove passwords alltogether
* Connect using CIFS:// in stead of SMB://
* Any combination of the above
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>After previous experience with Apple products I seriously began doubting the samba implementation of the Iomega drive. So I tried some things on the Iomega drive, amongst which were:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * installing a (wrong) firmware update, which almost bricked it.
* Resetting to factory defaults
* Erasing Mac sidecar or meta files (the .DS ones)
* Formatting the drive completely
* Unsetting and setting passwords
* Changing share names to lowercase
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>But still, nothing. Leopard will not properly access this drive. Funny thing is, that when I try to connect to the Iomega drive from my other Mac, which runs Tiger, it works flawlessly. And I can also connect to that same drive from a Windows machine. This makes it clearly a Leopard problem to me, and one that still needs to be fixed, despite the speedy update issued by Apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can we have another fix please, Apple? I can't reach my remote rsynced backups until you do...&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>