<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zundapp on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/zundapp/</link><description>Recent content in zundapp on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2004 21:03:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/zundapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mopeds are cool</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/10/31/mopeds-are-cool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2004 21:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/10/31/mopeds-are-cool/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_2662.jpg">&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4030/t_IMG_2662.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> Today I picked up my old moped at my parents house. Yes, that's right, I'm 33 and I still have my very first moped. It's a real special one. I belonged to my grandfather, who passed it on to my nephew, who passed it on to me when I turned 15. When I got it it needed a lot of work. I spent some months taking it completely apart with my dad. We didn't have a workshop back then, so we took it apart in the kitchen, of my parent's apartment on the 7th floor :-)When I turned 16 it was ready and better than new. It was really cool to have a classic Zundapp CS50. At that time, it looked like a motorbike next to my friend's puchs and peugeots. It really was a dream to ride, you could sit for hours on it without getting tired. I drove it for a good 6 years before it went in to &amp;quot;hibernation&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4015/t_IMG_2371.JPG" alt="">
So, having my own home and my own workshop right now, I decided it was a good time to pick it up and make it run once again. These German mopeds are made to last, I can tell you. When I get it running again I am sure it will be able to run for at least another 20 years or so, provided it gets reasonable maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Browse through the &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/gallery/4030.aspx">&amp;quot;Zundapp&amp;quot; gallery&lt;/a> to see more pictures.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>