<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 20:31:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iTunes 9: "Genre-Artist-Album" panes restored</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-5.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-5.png" alt="iTunes 9 with 3 panes">
&lt;/a>What I loved about iTunes is the three pane &amp;quot;Genre-Artist-Album&amp;quot; on top of my music list. It allowed me to quickly go through my music and find that great Anouk album I was looking for. After installing iTunes 9, it was gone. And I was sad. But I found a way to get it back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png?w=150" alt="Settings to get the panes back">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look at this screenshot (sorry, it's in Dutch). In iTunes, select &amp;quot;View&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Show Column Browser&amp;quot;. Now, put it on top by selecting &amp;quot;View&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Column Browser&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Top&amp;quot;. Voila, your trusted browser is at the top. You may need to add &amp;quot;Genre&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Album&amp;quot; there, but you've already seen the options for that now, have you? ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rip and Convert FLAC, M4A, MP3, AAC files</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&lt;img src="afbeelding-8.png" alt="Max Audio Transcoder">
&lt;/a>I recently found an old harddisk which used to be in one of my old PC's. I discovered some &lt;a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">FLAC&lt;/a> files on there, which were rips of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOU8GIRUd_g">old CD's&lt;/a> I used to have. iTunes is not too happy with importing them into my library, and the original CD's are in a box in a deep dark corner of my garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I searched for a converter and found this wonderful converter which can just about convert any audio format out there. It's called &lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&amp;quot;Max&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, it's Open Source, free to use, and available as bundled OSX application. Brilliant! It does have a bunch of options, but as long as you go for the &amp;quot;MP4 Audio&amp;quot; output format, high quiality, 256 bits and VBR, you can't go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to their website &lt;em>&amp;quot;Max can generate audio in over 20 compressed and uncompressed formats including MP3, Ogg Vorbis, FLAC, AAC, Apple Lossless, Monkey's Audio, WavPack, Speex, AIFF, and WAVE&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy transcoding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DLNA on OSX, done right</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3">&lt;img src="200x150_playstation3_logo1.jpg" alt="Sony PS3 Logo">
&lt;/a>My wife bought me a playstation 3 last year, and I've enjoyed many hours of gaming on it, finishing Tomb Raider underworld, and now making decent progress in Ratchet and Clank: Tools of Destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dlna.org/home">&lt;img src="afbeelding-22.png" alt="DLNA logo">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a bit sceptical about the DLNA capabilities of the PS3, because I read a lot of bad news on this fairly new  &amp;quot;Interoperability Guidelines&amp;quot; concept. It sounded like a lot of trouble to go through to simply watch the photos and home videos on a TV. For weeks, I was not able to find a single site telling me how to install a DLNA server on my Mac, or where to find a decent one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Altgough they're hard to find, there are a few OSX DLNA servers out there. One of them is actually very good. Here's what I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**CyberMediaGate**
&lt;p>I found a DLNA server implemented in Java, and didn't get it to work. It misses a Xerces library and I can not seem to get the right version added to the classpath. I decided this was not very &amp;quot;Mac like&amp;quot; and dumped it. Not being able to install software &amp;quot;out of the box&amp;quot; may be normal on Linux, but is unaccepatble on a Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TwonkyMedia&lt;/strong>
Then, I came across TwonkyMedia. This was the first DLNA server I actually got to work on my Mac, and had it serving video to my PS3. It is a strange (wonky?) piece of software, had no native GUI and only lives on your machine as a webapplication. The installer copies &amp;quot;TwonkyMediaServer.app&amp;quot; in your application folder, starts it, and then opens a browser which points to the local URL of it's configuration screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that moment, it already is serving clients, but when you try to access it with the PS3, you will get a protocol error. This is because TwonkyMedia does not come with a default server name. The PS3 aparently can not handle an empty server name. After filling it in and restarting Twonky, I could access it with the PS3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TwonkyMedia does not look very Mac-like, and I don't like the looks of the webpage it is serving. The installer leaves two webloc files on your desktop which point to the configuration screens. It's a bit strange but it gets the job done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Potentially Twonky can do a bit more than CyberMediaGate. Twonky can do some transcoding and other streaming stuff, but I did not try that because I simply wanted to see my photo's and home video's on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trial version of Twonkymedia last for 30 days, but on the first day it already started acting up on me, and I had to restart it a few times while watching video. The look and feel, and the crashes didn't feel like it was worth the $40 to me, so I uninstalled it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uninstalling TwonkyMedia requires you to kill the process from the Terminal, and then drag TwonkyMediaServer.app to your trashcan. Another way is dragging the app to the trashcan and then restarting your Mac (not mac-like but it works).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>MediaLink&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink">&lt;img src="printablelogo.png" alt="Nullriver Logo">
&lt;/a>The nullriver homepage looked very elegant, and promising. A simple page explains what it is, what it does, and what it costs. Nullriver also allows you to send requests and reports on their site without registering (in contract with TwonkyMedia, to which you have to &amp;quot;sell your soul&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nullriver Medialink comes as a preference pane application, and has a beautifuly simple interface, with not many options. It integrates with your mac applications like iTunes, iPhoto and now even Aperture. It does not have all the fancy configuration options of TwonkyMedia. One of my small complaints is that your content is shared to all DLNA clients on your local network, which may not be what you want if you have more than one DLNA client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me MediaLink is a perfect fit. I control my own network, my PS3 is my only DLNA client so I don't need the fancy stuff. Most people will be perfectly happy with Medialink. It's simple, transparent, drag-and-drop, has a &amp;quot;stop&amp;quot; button and is cheap. It does not have all the fancy features, but all the features that are in there work flawlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played with it for more than a week now, and so far it hasn't crashed on me. I did need to buy a registration key, because the trial version only lasts you for about 30 minutes of watching content (which should be plenty to try it out, and it's not like the 20 bucks are going to kill you).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
Once again, all DLNA servers I tried put together:&lt;/p>
&lt;table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="1" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[CyberMediaGate](http://www.cybergarage.org/net/cmgate/java/index.html)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Free
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Terrible, unable to install.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[TwonkyMedia](http://www.twonkyvision.de/)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$40
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Works, lots of features, no GUI, buggy/ Crashed on me more than once.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[MediaLink](http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$20
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Simple, stable, nice GUI, best value for money. Just works.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
So if you have a PS3 and a Mac, it's a no-brainer. Buy Medialink!</description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real guitar game: Guitar Wizzard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:35:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>No, I'm not a guitar player, but I noticed this cool post on TUAW where the &amp;quot;Guitar Hero&amp;quot; game has been taken a notch up. &lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/09/guitar-wizard-coming-for-mac/">TUAW reports&lt;/a> that the guys at &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com">www.musicwizard.com&lt;/a> have built &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com/guitar_wizard/updates.php">&amp;quot;Guitar Wizzard&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, a game with which you can learn to play popular songs on a &lt;em>real guitar&lt;/em>. From what I can see in the video, this looks way less frustrating than doing the same excersizes over and over to learn to play the guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, you might not turn in to Mark Knopfler in a week, but isn't it a much better feeling to hold a real guitar in your hand, in stead of that plasticky, toy-like mini quitar with the bright colored buttons? And the price is about right for a game including hardware aswell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Headphone search</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week I've been complaining about the capped volume on the iPod nano and the inability to circumvent it. At the end of that very week, the iPod earbuds solved the problem for me by breaking down. The rubber rings started comming off, and the right speaker produced only 10% of the sound the left speaker was producing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided that this was enough reason to go looking for a nice set of in-ear headphones (earbuds) which would sound nice, and also improve on produced volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8110.jpg">&lt;!-- more -->&lt;img src="img_8110.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Apple ear-buds">
&lt;/a>After reading some reviews on in-ear headphones ranging from €40,- to €140,- I decided on the Apple in-ear headphones. Judging from reviews, these should compare to Sony Fontopia's, seal of surrounding noise and produce more sound. I payed the €40,- (that's $58,- at the current Dollar-to-Euro rate) and plugged them into the ipod, and my ears. Although I have pretty standard ears,  I couldn't get the Apple earbuds to fit comfortably. Apple provides 3 different size caps, of which the middle size was the least uncomfortable, and sealed off my ear properly. You can tell this by the pressure you feel in your ear when inserting the buds. The pressure will slowly go away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I noticed is that by sealing off your earcanal, you can hear everything going on with the cords to the earbuds. Move your head, and you hear the cord move accross your clothes at a pretty uncomfortable volume. When playing music, don't move. The cord movement sounds will sometimes be louder than the music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sitting perfectly still and trying to judge the sound quality, I found that the Apple ear-buds are actually not good at all. Yes they provide lots of bass (which is a measure of quality nowadays I guess) but everything else is lacking. They sound flat, and miss the sharpness I expect from expensive earbuds. They are absolutely sounding worse than the standard earbuds that came with the iPod. If I had too choose between the two, I'd go for the standard iPod earphones in stead of the more expensive ear-buds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with headphones in general and in-ear headphones in particular, is that you can't return them, because they can't be sold as new after you've jammed them in your ears. For that same reason I'm probably not going to sell them second hand, making these buds one of the more expensive pieces of trash in my bin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8111.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8111.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Sony earphones">
&lt;/a> Last weekend I passed through a hardware store to buy a new harddrive for my fileserver. Next to the cash register I found a pair of &lt;a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/headphones-headsets/sony-mdr-e818lp/4505-6468_7-6900020.html">Sony MDR-E818LP&lt;/a> earphones for about €10,-. I bought them so that I could at least listen to music until I found a set of decent earphones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And guess what? These sound great! They've got too much bass (probably a fashion thing), but that can be cured with the &amp;quot;less bass&amp;quot; setting on the iPod. By doing that, these earphones are the right thing for your iPod, at the right price. The sound is clear and crisp, and these buds produce a LOT more sound than the Apple ones. They don't seal off your ear, which I've come to beleive is a good thing, because of the cord-sound I described above. They come with a set of soft cushions which make for a comfortable fit, and I can wear them for hours at an end without getting sore ears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get some of the €40,- spent on the Apple ear-buds back, I am using the Apple ear-bud carying case to store the Sony earphones in. The Sony's are worth it. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse this isn't the best set of earphones I've ever had. The old Sony fontopids that came with the first walkmans were absolutely the best in-ear headphones I've ever had. Comfortable fit, supple silicone cords, with red and blue stripes on the earpieces to mark right and left, but other than that perfectly symmetrical. Too bad they don't make those anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8113.jpg" alt="Sony MDR-CD770">
&lt;/a>The absolute best set of earphones I've ever had, and in fact still own after some odd 20 years, is a set of &lt;a href="http://www.epinions.com/content_6730518148">Sony MDR-CD770 Digital Reference&lt;/a> earphones. They (still) sound amazing, you feel like you can point out the location of every instrument in the band you're listening too, like they were in the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem with these are that they are big, expensive, and fragile. You won't be taking these with you when you're on vacation. They wouldn't survive the suitcase, and they're impossible when you are trying to lay your head down to sleep while listening to good music. Even if you did, you'd never wake up again, being strangled by the many meters of audio cable dangling off of your left ear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you're sitting at home on the couch, these will beat the * out of any soundsystem anyday, without annoying the neighbours. You'll be amazed at how good a high-bitrate AAC track sounds comming out of your iPod.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monokai</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/14/monokai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 21:24:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/14/monokai/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I just checked out the new &lt;a href="http://www.creativecommons.nl/dvd/">Dutch CC CD/DVD&lt;/a> released under the Creative Commons license. While I was there I found a great &lt;a href="http://www.creativecommons.nl/dvd/tracks/Monokai/Monokai-Mier.mp3">piece of music done by Monokai&lt;/a>. It's kind of old C64 game like music, you like it or hate it. I went to check out &lt;a href="http://www.monokai.nl/">Monokai's website&lt;/a> and I've spent a good 30 minutes playing with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website is filled with music, photo's and electronic games, and is fun to play with. Go check it out! Nice quality!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iTunes alternative</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/09/itunes-alternative/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2006 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/09/itunes-alternative/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I really like iTunes. When you have 1 computer (an apple, that is ;-), and 1 place to store your music, it's all you'll ever need. It is easy to manage your music with, it puts your files in reasonably understandably locations (artist/album/track), has nice smart playlists and there are a lot of plugins available.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I also like to store my precious media at a different machine than my desktop. Since a desktop is more prone to "crashes", nearly allways caused by user error, it is not the place to keep your important or irreplacable files, like your family photo's. So I have a network. On this network, I have a server which contains my digital media (foto's and mp3's, mainly). The server is only used as storage location, does not run strange software, automatically backs up all files to a seperate harddisk, defragments drives and mails me when something goes wrong. Access to shares is restricted properly, guests can only read files, and there is one "incomming" share where people can read and write. Important files get moved to the read-only shares by an administrator user (me). This server has been up and running for over 4 years now, without a hickup, and with backups of at most 2 days old.
&lt;p>Being all organized, my iTunes library is also on this server. As long as I use 1 computer, with 1 instance of iTunes, all is well. But when I start up a different computer (the one in the living room) to listen to my music, things get ugly. The iTunes library is really designed to be managed by 1 iTunes instance. Changes made to my music library on one computer, can not be seen on the other. Even worse: it handles it terribly (music not found, warning messages all over, etc.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One solution would be to leave the &amp;quot;main&amp;quot; iTunes computer running and share the library. Then I can connect to that share in the living room. But when I do this, I have 3 computers eating electricity, and the added trouble of not being able to put files on my mp3 player from the living room machine. And there I am, thinking that my music was mine. Apperently not, iTunes decides to &amp;quot;protect&amp;quot; the music from being listened to by it's rightful owner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and again, I turn to Google to see if anybody has found a cure for this problem. But all Google comes up with, is more people having the same problem, hopelessly crude and complex rsync procedures, or way inferior music player alternatives. Today, I stubled upon &lt;a href="http://www.songbirdnest.com/home">Songbird&lt;/a>, a multi platform music player looking like iTunes. I haven't tried it out yet (I'm not that bold), it's version 0.2, and according to the makers merely a preview of what's to come. So not something I'll be managing my music library with for some time, but I'll be watching that space, because it sure looks like these guys pay attention to what they're doing!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm hoping to see a way to access my music from more than 1 computer in the near future, be it iTunes or SongBird. And I think many more people are hoping this to!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MP3 Gain for OSX</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/06/21/mp3-gain-for-osx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 15:44:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/06/21/mp3-gain-for-osx/</guid><description>
&lt;p>So here I am using iTunes on my Apple. So far so good. The downside is that I have an iBead as an mp3 player, so there are a few problems with that. First of all, iTunes only plays nice with the iPods (and a few other oddballs ;-). For me to put mp3's on my iBead, I can drag them over from iTunes onto the USB drive, but when things' don't fit, it just doesn't copy at all. Also, automatic random playlists aren't that automatic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, I can live with all these little problems. I can create a playlist limited to a particular size, empty my iBead and drag the mp3's over. But when I play them on my iBead, the volume levels are far apart. In the old days I used mp3Gain on my PC to level out all volumes, which worked great. But iTunes has it's own take on that: It stores a relative volume in the file, and iPods know how to handle this properly, adjusting the volume. My iBead however, doesn't.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tonight I went out to look for a tool which could adjust the volumes of my mp3's on my Mac mini. And guess what? I found it! &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/beryrinaldo/AudioTron/MacMP3Gain/">MacMP3Gain&lt;/a> does it all, and it is currently processing my complete library, adjusting all volumes. It has a &amp;quot;nice&amp;quot; option so it won't hog all processing power. I think it will be finished somewhere tommorow afternoon. It claims to be lossless, so I guess I can run it on my complete library every once in a while without having to worry about which files are new or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding double entries in iTunes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/23/finding-double-entries-in-itunes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 16:03:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/23/finding-double-entries-in-itunes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Mac has been on for the past few days, even with the Maxtor FAT32 250GB drive connected, without problems. I hope it doesn't break down again, because I'd have to bring it to a different Mac store and explain the whole thing again... Anyway, I was playing with iTunes and found a simple trick to find double entries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open a Terminal, go to the root of your iTunes music collection folder and type
find . -name &amp;quot;*1.mp3&amp;quot; -type f&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will give you a list of all tracks ending with &amp;quot;1.mp3&amp;quot;, which is how iTunes renames double-entries. Do not look at the filenames, but rather select the artist in iTunes with the double tracks, and use the &amp;quot;show double entries&amp;quot; in iTunes to do the rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It isn't much, but it saves you the trouble of finding double tracks in your 8 zillion tracks ;-) .
Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Want those CD boxes back?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/04/23/want-those-cd-boxes-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 16:11:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/04/23/want-those-cd-boxes-back/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When I used iTunes on XP, I was jealous of the terrific plugins for iTunes running on OS X. Now that I have a Mac Mini, I was looking for a plugin to update the album art automatically. &lt;a href="http://www.zwet.com/">Pim&lt;/a> showed me an even better alternative: &lt;a href="http://www.sprote.com/clutter/">Clutter&lt;/a>! Not only can it search and update album art automatically for you, it also gives you the option to put your albums on your desktop. This is the best virtual alternative to having CD's lying on your desk. A must have for iTunes users I think. Very nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidebar: My file server still runs Windows, and it has been working flawlessly for the past 5 years, being constantly &amp;quot;on&amp;quot; and storing family pictures and music. My laptop is an XP machine and works quite nicely too. So maybe it's because I don't need to, but for now I don't want to &lt;a href="http://zwet.com/2006/04/20/apple-switch-complete-but-the-demon-is-still-here/">install XP on my Mac&lt;/a>. It feels like a step back, it adds a sour taste to your strawberry icecream :-). XP is nice, but not as a desktop. Too much bloatware.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>