<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xs4all on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/xs4all/</link><description>Recent content in xs4all on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 09:17:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/xs4all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/07/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 09:17:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/07/welcome/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hello reader,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to the new location of my weblog. The old data is not completely transferred yet, I'll be doing that from newest to oldest post by hand, because there is no way to do that in the old blog software. This is one of the reasons I am moving away from that blog. I may be running into all kinds of problems, and it may take a while, so if you are looking for existing information, bare with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can't find the content and tips you are looking for, please check out the location of my old blog at &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje">http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phrack still in ASCII</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/04/phrack-still-in-ascii/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/04/phrack-still-in-ascii/</guid><description>
&lt;p>It is a long time since I read this stuff, but I &lt;a href="http://www.phrack.org/issues.html?issue=64&amp;amp;id=11#article">stumbled upon a paper &lt;/a>discussing the non-executable stack on OSX (a trick to prevent buffer/stack overflow exploits). Ah, the good old days. And with all this markup, it's good to see that Phrack magazine stuck to their format. It's still the same as over 20 years ago... Well written articles, focussed on correctness and content, for the coders out there who are not afraid experimenting with some assembly. The amount of (nightly) hours that go into the research and proof of these articles are unbelievable, and it shows.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm afraid the years of Java have eroded my assembly knowledge, it's hard to keep up with the paper. But I loved to skim through the mov's, jne and jnz's, and the great comments. New young developers don't even learn how to write assembly anymore, the spoiled brats... :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more trips down memory lane, also check the Dutch &lt;a href="http://www.hacktic.nl/">Hack-Tic magazine&lt;/a>. Someone actually scanned all the pages every written in Hacktic. See if you can find the first XS4ALL machine in there... Too bad that they didn't have photo's of te &amp;quot;Hacking at the end of the Universe&amp;quot; in 1993, I really liked that one. I did found the &lt;a href="http://www.well.com:70/0/hacking/hack-tic/galac.hac">invitation&lt;/a> online, and Fransisco wrote a &lt;a href="http://www.xs4all.nl/~fvjole/archief/artikelen/Volkskrant/1993/heu.html">nice article&lt;/a> for the Volkskrant. There are more links at the bottom of Fransisco's article if you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now where did I leave my &lt;a href="http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jolt_Cola">Jolt&lt;/a>? Twice the energy, half the taste...&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>