<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technology on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 12:00:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1N4148 diode as RF switch</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/24/1n4148-diode-as-rf-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/24/1n4148-diode-as-rf-switch/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;figure class="float_left">&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/hgll-XTqcS4">&lt;img src="1n4148.jpg" width="50"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
For a recent experiment I was using &lt;a href="http://www.datasheetarchive.com/BA389-datasheet.html">BA389 PIN diodes&lt;/a> to switch low power RF signals. I was asked why I didn't use an ordinary &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1N4148_signal_diode">1N4148&lt;/a> for that. Since I didn't know what an 1N4148 would do when used like that, and I also didn't really know what a BA389 actually does, I decided to do some measurements.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Aren't diodes rectifiers?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Yes and no. The most basic operation of a diode is to pass current in one way, and block it in the other. But when the diode passes DC current, the internal capacitance lowers, and RF resistance will drop to around 1 Ohm. If you can separate the DC and RF currents, you can switch RF with DC. Most, if not all modern transceivers use PIN diodes to switch the antenna between the internal transmitter and receiver components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>PIN or PN diode?&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P%E2%80%93n_diode">P/N diode&lt;/a> like the 1N4148 only has P and N doped regions. A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PIN_diode">P/I/N diode&lt;/a> has three semiconductor regions with different doping. The I region in a PIN diode makes it a bad/slow rectifier but it a great RF switch, see the provided wikipedia link for more info.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enough talk. Let's go. In this case I want to know how a PIN diode like the BA389 compares to an 1N4148 when used for switching RF signals on 145 MHz and 435 MHz. I decided to use my &lt;a href="http://miniradiosolutions.com/54-2/">MiniVNA Tiny&lt;/a> and the following circuit to do the measurements:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="screen-shot-2018-02-23-at-17-31-36.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The output of the MiniVNA Tiny is connected to a 10 dB attenuator, reducing the -6 dBm (0.251 mW) output of the VNA to -16 dBm (0.025 mW) hoping to reduce signal leaking around the diode (less signal, less leakage). The output of the attenuator is connected to the AC input on the left side of the schematic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The input of the MiniVNA Tiny is connected to the output of the schematic. Yes, the RF travels through the diode the &amp;quot;wrong way&amp;quot;, against the DC current. This is not an error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DC input of the circuit is connected to a variable resistor, a multimeter and a power supply to be able to vary the current through the diode (DUT) from 0.001 mA to 20 mA.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;img src="img_6758.jpg"/>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;img src="img_6767.jpg"/>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
The coils are 0.35 mm copper wound 15 turns around a 3 mm drillbit. The capacitors are SMD to keep everything as short as possible. I also added some extra shielding to separate the in and outputs better.
&lt;p>Before measuring diodes I callibrated the whole setup by having vnaJ measure the &amp;quot;OPEN&amp;quot; characteristics with everything connected but with the diode removed. Then, I soldered a wire in place of the diode and had vnaJ measure the &amp;quot;CLOSED&amp;quot; characteristics. I saved this callibration dataset and used it throughout all other measurements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I soldered a 1N4148 in place and measured RF Transmission Loss for a number of currents between 0 and 15 mA. Then I did the same for the BA389. After a bit of fiddling with Excel I produced the following graph of the results:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="screen-shot-2018-02-23-at-21-39-15.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The verdict:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The results are actually not that bad for the 1N4148. It shows behaviour and comparable linearity to the BA389 PIN diode. The attenuation of the 1N4148 leaves to be desired: -25,5 dB attenuation compared to -30.3 dB of the BA389 on 145 MHz. On 435 MHz the difference is a bit bigger: -14.1 dB vs -20.1 dB for the BA389. All in all, the 1N4148 is roughly 6 dB more &amp;quot;leaky&amp;quot; than the BA389.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So a 1N4148 actually works as an RF switch, if you are on lower frequencies and don't mind that it only attenuates -25,5 dB. If you need high performance RF switching with high isolation, particularly at frequencies above 200 MHz or so I think you're better off selecting a proper PIN diode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the 1N4148 and the BA389 graphs from the MiniVNA Tiny. The graph for the 1N4148 is an earlier one where I didn't have the extra shields. The dip in the 200MHz range is caused by the measurement jig itself. Mind the vertical scales, they don't match. Blue line is Transmission Loss:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td>&lt;img src="VNA_180222_174935.jpg"/>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;img src="VNA_180223_150657.jpg"/>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Designing a Fox-hunt antenna</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2016/06/19/designing-a-fox-hunt-antenna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 21:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2016/06/19/designing-a-fox-hunt-antenna/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3d-radiation-pattern.png">&lt;img src="3d-radiation-pattern.png" alt="3d radiation pattern">
&lt;/a>Many years ago, I used to do some &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rrNXyv134bE">radio fox hunting with cars&lt;/a>. Usually these hunts are at night to make it more exciting, and can be great fun. As I got older I lost interest and moved on to other things. But last year, I decided to have a go at a &lt;a href="http://www.ballonvossenjacht.nl">popular balloon fox hunt&lt;/a> on 144MHz. This is quite a large scale &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_QrDOEXb_ss">and professionally organized fox hunt&lt;/a> by Dutch Radio Amateurs.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the totally different setup and frequency I decided to join a few recreational 144MHz (2 meter) fox hunts to get the hang of it. If you like to play with radios and walk in the woods, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KDN8w7awAkQ">this is your thing&lt;/a>. Lots of small transmitters hidden in the bushes on random frequencies for you to find.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year I used a borrowed receiver and antenna, and this year I decided to build a &lt;a href="http://www.peildoos.nl/?page_id=128">Foxbox receiver kit&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After building the receiver, the age-old discussion among radio amateurs began: What antenna to use? I had a discussion with Remco who just designed his own &lt;a href="http://remco.org/index.php/2015/02/26/145-mhz-2m-moxon-pt-2/">Moxon antenna&lt;/a> using the &lt;a href="http://www.qsl.net/4nec2/">4nec2 antenna modeler and optimizer&lt;/a>. He convinced me to use this software in order to prevent building a lot of failing antennas and not being sure why they fail. So that's what I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 4nec2 software comes with a bunch of example antennas for you to play around with. The antenna I borrowed last year was a 2 element antenna based on a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log-periodic_antenna">Log Periodic Dipole Array antenna&lt;/a>. It worked fine and I had fun with it so I decided to model an antenna like that. (Also because I'm hard-headed and just copying Remco's Moxon would not lead to interesting discussions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Getting basic dimensions of an LPDA&lt;/strong>
The first thing I needed is a basic, ballpark approximation of a working LPDA antenna for 144MHz so I could get used to the 4nec2 modeling software. I used &lt;a href="http://hamwaves.com/lpda/en/">ON4AA's Log-Periodic Dipole Array calculator&lt;/a> to get an idea of the basic dimensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I noticed that the length of the first and largest element of the antenna is always 1041 mm, no matter what taper or relative spacing I chose as input. Good news, because that means that the antenna only has a few parameters to change when optimizing in 4nec2, see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 2: Getting the design into 4nec2&lt;/strong>
So here is where the struggle starts. As I am a Mac user and the 4nec2 software is Windows only, I installed it on a Linux Mint virtual machine running under Wine without problems. The terminal window will log errors but you have to put your OCD aside for a moment and ignore those.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the LPDA antenna itself the struggle was not that bad, as I found an example file and was able to change that around to learn how 4nec2 works. I'll spare you the details. Just remember that you want to use the new NEC editor (Main Window, Settings → NEC Editor (new)).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="1-editor.png">&lt;img src="1-editor.png" alt="4nec2 Editor">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here you see the two wires of my LPDA antenna. As you can see, each line has a start (X1,Y1,Z1) and end point (X2,Y2,Z2) in 3D space. Ignore the funny formulas in the screenshot for now. A counter intuitive thing for me was that lines are made out of &amp;quot;segments&amp;quot;. 4nec2 cryptically complains about too few and too much segments, and you have to choose a number accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important thing to learn about 4nec2 is that you don't &amp;quot;connect&amp;quot; a source to your antenna. Rather, you choose a segment of a line which will then act as a current or voltage source (current source is the recommended default). This is why if you want to have your feed point in the middle of a wire, you need to choose an odd number of segments. In my design, both wires are 61 segments, and the feed point on both wires is on segment 31 (the middle segment of each wire).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting the two wires of the antenna is done using a transmission line, with a twist (literally). We connect segment 31 of both wires with a transmission line, and chose a &lt;em>negative impedance&lt;/em>. This causes the transmission line to &amp;quot;twist&amp;quot; in your geometry window, and you should see something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="2-geometry.png">&lt;img src="2-geometry.png" alt="LPDA Geometry">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 3: Changing the NEC file for optimization&lt;/strong>
4nec2 contains an optimizer which can optimize certain characteristics of your antenna by iterating values. If you hard-coded the X,Y and Z values of the lines, the optimizer can not change the design. To be able to use the optimizer, I chose to have variables for the length of the boom (L), length of the driving/smallest element (D), length of the reflecting/longest element (R) and impedance of the transmission line (TRI). This explains the funny values for the X,Y,Z coordinates in my file. The variables can be found on the &amp;quot;Symbols&amp;quot; tab of the NEC editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 4: Optimize!&lt;/strong>
Close the Editor window, and in the main window, select Calculate -&amp;gt; Start Optimizer. The optimizer parameters can be a bit confusing. Choose the &amp;quot;Optimize&amp;quot; function in the drop-down top left, and leave the Option set to &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;. Below the text &amp;quot;Weighting factors in %&amp;quot; you'll see 7 text fields. Set them all to 0, except for &amp;quot;F/B&amp;quot;, the Front-to-back ratio. That should be set to 100, As we are only interested in maximum directivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3-optimizer.png">&lt;img src="3-optimizer.png?w=450" alt="Optimizer">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we have told 4nec2 what we want (max F/B), we need to tell the optimizer which variables it can play with. In this simple design, you could select all variables by clicking on them, which moves them to the &amp;quot;selected&amp;quot; column. I tried, this does not lead to practical results and takes a bit of time depending on the speed of the computer. All open geometry or 3D view windows will live-update with the calculations. This looks really cool but things go faster if you close them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3a-optimized-radiation.png">&lt;img src="3a-optimized-radiation.png" alt="Optimized radiation">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a bit of playing with the optimizer, I got to the following radiation pattern:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-radiation-pattern.png">&lt;img src="4-radiation-pattern.png" alt="4. radiation pattern">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 5. Build and field test.&lt;/strong>
At this point, the software will have tried tens, if not hundreds of different antenna variations you didn't have to physically build. But now that we are &amp;quot;certain&amp;quot;, we can build the antenna. The boom is aluminum profile, the radials are made of measuring tape so they can be folded, and the handle is a broomstick:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="5-antenne.jpg">&lt;img src="5-antenne.jpg" alt="Antenna">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've spent extra effort to make sure the dimensions are as close to the simulation as possible, to maximize the chance that it actually works as designed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did a field test together with my dad, where we used a Baofeng handheld (yes &lt;a href="https://rolfje.wordpress.com/2015/05/10/better-modulation-for-the-baofeng-uv-5ra/">that one&lt;/a>) as a &amp;quot;fox&amp;quot;, taking turns in hiding it for the each other. The tests went &amp;quot;sort of okay&amp;quot;, but I noticed that it sometimes felt as if there was not one peak straight in front of the antenna, but rather two peaks left and right. This got me worrying about the accuracy of the build or the simulation. I even started doubting impact of impedance mismatch and cable length. When we got home however, I checked and saw that the 4nec2 software actually predicted this in a different diagram:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="6-vertical-radiation.png">&lt;img src="6-vertical-radiation.png" alt="Vertical radiation">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out, that if the antenna is held horizontally, and the transmitter antenna is a vertical, the whole system behaves exactly as simulated, with the antenna being almost &amp;quot;deaf&amp;quot; right in front of the boom. Solution: Turn the antenna vertical or horizontal while hunting to find the maximum signal. We noticed that without being able to see the radio, I could exactly match the angle of the vertical antenna. My dad hid the fox in a tree at 45 degrees, and without seeing or knowing it I matched the angle of the antenna perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 6. Game on!&lt;/strong>
Just today I tried the whole setup in an actual fox hunt with 24 foxes (yes that many). I was very pleased with the performance of the antenna, and I found 14 of the foxes. With a bit of practice and experience, I'm sure I can improve to find more foxes next time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And last but not least, here is the 4nec2 file for you to play around with:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; padlinenumbers=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
CM Log Periodic Dipole Array for 2m fox hunting
CE
SY L=180 'Boom length
SY D=963 'Driver length
SY R=1041 'Reflector length
SY TRI=70 'Transmission line impedance
GW 1 61 0 -R/2 0 0 R/2 0 10
GW 2 61 L -D/2 0 L D/2 0 10
GS 0 0 0.001
GE 0
GN -1
EK
EX 6 2 31 0 1 0 0
TL 1 31 2 31 -TRI 0 0 0 0 0
FR 0 20 0 0 144 0.1
EN
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replace Evernote with Spidernote</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/02/replace-evernote-with-spidernote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/03/02/replace-evernote-with-spidernote/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/07/28/AR2010072806141.html">&lt;img src="evernotensa.png" alt="Resistance is futile">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past I have used Evernote extensively, it really helped me in my research for this blog and keeping track of meeting notes, todo lists and even making pictures of whiteboards at work searchable. As a product, there is no note taking app that can beat Evernote. But there is a little problem that has become a deal breaker for me, and that is basically the NSA and the way Americans, and particularly the American government seems to think about people's privacy and online security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evernote is an American company, which sadly has to comply with whatever ridiculous request by the U.S. government to turn over data of innocent people all over the world (yes, even outside the U.S. border, I know, it’s amazing). This, combined with the fact that Evernote clearly can not use zero-knowledge encryption because of the services it provides, makes that all the data you and I put into Evernote are at NSA’s fingertips at all times. If you find that as scary as I do, and you have a Mac, there is a way to solve this.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you use Evernote to sync notes between multiple Macs, you have to solve the syncing problem first. Ofcourse Dropbox is a no-go, because that is an American company storing unencrypted data too. I’m &lt;a href="https://rolfje.wordpress.com/2011/07/03/1355/">using SpiderOak  since 2011&lt;/a>, and it is much better than Dropbox in many ways. Check it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re using Evernote on your iPhone I do not have a solution for you yet. But as for me, that is not a big deal, I thought the iPhone is not the ideal note taking platform anyway as this old man is not very fast on the touch keyboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="spidy_5407spx_02.jpg">&lt;img src="spidy_5407spx_02.jpg" alt="Spidernote Icon">
&lt;/a>With all that out of the way, let’s migrate away from Evernote and replace it with a smart script and some synced Spideroak folders. I like to call it ”SpiderNote”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Create a folder structure&lt;/strong>
Inside your Spideroak shared folder or Hive, create a ”Spidernote” folder, and in that folder, create a ”notes” folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2: Export all Evernote Notes&lt;/strong>
Start up your trusty Evernote client and select all your notes. From the ”File” menu, select ”Export Notes…” and store them in a folder called ”Evernote”, inside the ”notes” folder you just created. You should now have a folder called Spidernote/notes/Evernote somewhere inside your Spideroak folder, or somewhere locally on your Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3: Getting Spotlight and Finder to work for you&lt;/strong>
Open the Finder and press Cmd-, or select ”Preferences…” On the ”Advanced” tab, under ”When performing a Search” select ”Search the current Folder”. After you do this, you will find that when you open the notes folder in Finder, you can type some text and your old Evernote notes will popup. Look ma, no hands! And no Evernote!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="finder-search-settings.png">&lt;img src="finder-search-settings.png?w=450" alt="Finder Search Settings">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4: Create a new template note&lt;/strong>
OSX comes with a decent richtext editor, named ”TextEdit” which we are going to use for our note taking.Open TextEdit and save an empty file inside the notes folder which is called ”empty.rtf”. This will be your note template, the start of every new note. Remember you can set preferences that are stored with this file, like the default font and colors and tabs if you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5: Script to create a new note&lt;/strong>
Create a file called ”newnote.command” in the Spidernote folder and copy/paste the following contents into it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;bash&amp;quot;]
#!/bin/bash
date=&lt;code>date +%Y%m%d-%H%M%S&lt;/code>
BASEDIR=$(dirname $0)
cd $BASEDIR&lt;/p>
&lt;p>notesdirectory=&amp;quot;notes/${date}&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>clear
echo &amp;quot;Note will be stored in ${BASEDIR}/${notesdirectory}.&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Type title/filename for note (without extension):&amp;quot;
read filename&lt;/p>
&lt;p>if [[ X&amp;quot;&amp;quot; = X&amp;quot;$filename&amp;quot; ]]; then
filename=&amp;quot;note.rtf&amp;quot;;
fi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>mkdir &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}&amp;quot;
cp notes/empty.rtf &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot;
rm -f lastnote.rtf
ln -s &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot; latestnote.rtf
open -a TextEdit &amp;quot;${notesdirectory}/${filename}.rtf&amp;quot;
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should now have a folder structure which looks something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="folder-structure-1.png">&lt;img src="folder-structure-1.png" alt="Spidernote Folder Structure">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6: Add Spidernote to your Dock&lt;/strong>
Drag the Spidernote folder next to your Trashcan in the doc (not IN your Trashcan, of course). Change the settings to have it’s icon show as a folder, and it’s context as a list. All set!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7: Create your first note&lt;/strong>
From the Dock, click on the Spidernote folder and click on ”newnote.command”. A Terminal window will pop up, asking you for the (optional) title of your note (this will be the filename of the *.rtf file, so that it is easier to scan your search results later). After you press ”enter”, TextEdit will come up and you can type away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are done and close the editor, you can easily find your note by searching, or by the ”latest note” link which the script creates for you in the Spidernote folder, so that you always can return to what you were doing when you accidentally close that note.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s it for now. I know it does not OCR scan your images, and it is really a poor-man’s Evernote, but these days your private has become a valuable asset to scrupules people and it has to be protected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that there are a lot of note taking apps out there but frankly none of them work for me. If you have any tips on how to solve the OCR and tagging/organizing stuff please let me know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh and don't forget to &lt;a href="https://evernote.com/contact/support/kb/#!/article/23403793">deactivate your Evernote account and remove all its data&lt;/a>. After all, that's what started all this sad stuff.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How big is 5 Zettabyte?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 19:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/06/23/how-big-is-5-zettabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.spyvsspyhq.com/images.html">&lt;img src="3050431703_spyblack_answer_2_xlarge.jpeg" alt="Spy vs Spy">
&lt;/a>Since the interview of &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/jun/09/nsa-whistleblower-edward-snowden-interview-video">Edward Snowden with the Guardian&lt;/a>, the discussion about privacy and companies storing and sharing unencrypted private data is picking up. Particularly Americans are worried about what it does for their National security and their private data. But that's actually a naive thought, given the NSA stores worldwide data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">recent coverage on theblaze.com&lt;/a> (a rather tabloid-looking news station in the U.S.), the interviewers are shocked to see that the NSA spies on &amp;quot;every American&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a limited view of the world and failing to see the importance of spying on people &lt;em>outside&lt;/em> the U.S., but lets start with technical side of things first. What data are they storing and how big is their hard-disk?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->As you may know, the internet is a [packet switching network](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Routing). Although people try to mess with the routing and sometimes even [disconnect whole countries](http://www.bgpmon.net/syria-shuts-down-the-internet/), it is hard to make a packet travel a certain route or prevent it from traveling through a certain country. Much of the internet traffic passes through the U.S. regardless of it's source and destination. But even if it didn't, the NSA has that covered. Many companies, Like Facebook, [Google](http://highscalability.com/google-architecture) has [servers all over the world](http://serverfault.com/questions/370385/location-of-google-servers). Since Google and Facebook are companies registered in the U.S. the [NSA could technically indirectly tap into](http://www.breitbart.com/Big-Government/2013/06/09/NSA-Obtains-Data-From-50-Companies) one of their servers in a foreign country which contains data which never travelled through the US in the first place.
&lt;p>According to the &lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/stats.htm">worldwide distribution of internet users&lt;/a>, if the NSA wanted to store data just about Americans, they could have built a much smaller, simpler facility. But they didn't, which make you think. So how big is this facility exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://img.pr0gramm.com/2009/04/funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg">&lt;img src="funny-pictures-cat-looks-at-a-huge-stack-of-crepes.jpg" alt="Holy Crepe">
&lt;/a>5 Zettabyte**
If you've watched the &lt;a href="https://unspy.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/top-secret-nsa-5-zettabyte-spy-building-perfect-surveillence-state-near-completion/">coverage&lt;/a>, you'll hear James Bamford say that the facility that the NSA is building can hold enough physical machines to store around 5 Zettabyte of data, given current technology standards. It sounds like a lot, but how big is a Zettabyte really?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettabyte">wikipedia&lt;/a>, 5 Zettabyte is 5,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 bytes. If, like me, you can not get your head around a number with 21 zeroes in it, I'll give you some of the calculations I made to understand just how big this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with the Internet Archive. Currently, the Internet Archive and it's &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/59207751">Wayback machine holds 10 Petabytes&lt;/a> of data (10,000,000,000,000,000 bytes). The servers at the Internet Archive crawl the Internet and store all public data they can find in a searchable manner. They provide the public with that data, so you can do cool things like &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.rolfje.com">see how my blog looked 10 years ago&lt;/a>. The Internet Archive is pretty big you might think. With 5ZB, the NSA could store the complete Internet Archive &lt;em>500,000 times&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to world population&lt;/strong>
Ok so maybe the size of the internet, or the size of a Petabyte are not very imaginable. Let's take it to the individual level. At the time of this writing, there are &lt;a href="http://www.worldometers.info">roughly 7.124.855.134 people on the world&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the NSA would wanted to store information on every person in the world, regardless if they were a president or a newborn African child, they would have 701,768,654,374 bytes per person to do so:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperperson.png" alt="5ZB per person">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, they can store 701GB for each person in the world. My personal email archive is around 5GB right now, and I have a 1TB hard-disk containing every (digital or digitized) photo I have ever made. If I would be the standard (which I am probably not), the NSA could very easily store everybody's personal data, worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Relative to the people connected to the internet&lt;/strong>
Not everybody is connected to the internet (in fact that's not entirely true but we'll come to that later). As you have probably already seen on the &lt;a href="http://worldmeters.info">worldmeters.info&lt;/a> site, there are roughly 2,552,435,328 active internet users (at the time of writing). So let's see what the NSA can store if they &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; target the internet users:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="5zbperuser.png" alt="5ZB per Internet User">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah that's better. Almost &lt;strong>2TB per Internet user&lt;/strong>. The NSA can now not only store my private data, photo's and videos, but now there is room to spare so I can put a couple of blockbuster movies in there, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the NSA probably does some smart data reduction, like storing an email I send to you just once instead of a copy for each of us, I'm guessing the practical space per user will be more like 4TB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YozC8yFrZKI">&lt;img src="p.png" alt="Homer">
&lt;/a>Am I connected to the internet?**
In short: Yes. We are all connected in some way to the internet. Particularly if you are living in a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_world">&amp;quot;Western Country&amp;quot;&lt;/a> you can be sure that in some way you, or at least data about your existance, is online somewhere. Cities store data about their inhabitants and share them with other departments and services to do their work. By default, this data travels accross the internet and we all know how good governements are at protecting and encrypting their data, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's do an interesting thought experiment to see how far this goes. Suppose I have never connected to the internet, and neither have you. I own an old &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toyota_Corolla_(E70)">Toyota Corolla E70&lt;/a> and you and I stayed with our trusty &lt;a href="http://nokiamuseum.info/nokia-p-30/">Nokia P-30&lt;/a>'s. Now let's say I lend you my car. The NSA would know about that, instantly. How? My car is registered to me. The roads are covered with cameras to detect traffic violations, but in fact, the most governments like to store data about which car is going where. Our cellphones are connected to cell towers, which reveals &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_phone_tracking">pretty accurate data&lt;/a> about where they are. So the NSA can map the time and place of my car to the time and place of my cell phone and all cell phones I've called. They would quickly and easily discover that my car is moving with your cellphone in it. The fact that their data shows that my cellphone is at home means that you are probably driving my car. Based on our cellphone data, it would even be pretty easy to see our daily commutes, see where you and I work and when and where we met in person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conspiracy? &lt;em>Maybe.&lt;/em> Possibility? &lt;em>Yes.&lt;/em> Privacy breach? &lt;em>Absolutely.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different countries have different meanings of the word &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy">&amp;quot;Privacy&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. By definition, gathering of data which is considered to be private (secret or confidential) in the country of origin, is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espionage">Espionage&lt;/a>. This is not surprising, as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_War">old habbits die hard&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I don't care, I have nothing to hide.&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5VAgSdGnSQ">&lt;img src="gollum.jpg" alt="Gollum has something to hide">
&lt;/a>Not so fast grasshopper. You do. In fact, the NSA just introduced the very need to keep your data private and store it locally, indefinitely. In the example above, suppose you used my car to take pictures as a hobby photographer of a crime scene that was in the news. With the data they gathered, the NSA could frame either you or me at that scene, at their peril. Because you and I have no access to the data they are storing about us, it will be very hard for you or me to prove that we weren't, because the NSA will not provide you or the court with data that will prove otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for mail and other communications. Tabloid journalists can explain how to use one email, or once sentence from an email out of context to start a nasty gossip. The NSA could do that too. Suppose you are sharing role-playing stories with a friend over email. Those emails could suddenly look very interesting when placed out of context. Don't think they will not do that. &lt;a href="http://www.whereisthemoney.org/1.1trillion.htm">Power corrupts.&lt;/a> They will, and very likely already have done so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_Make_Me_Think">Don't make me think&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
I've always said that the failure to make stuff user friendly is the single most important reason for brilliant ideas to &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/06/14/nsa-proof-encryption-exists-why-doesnt-anyone-use-it/">fail miserably&lt;/a>. In the light of current events and the power of modern computers, can we at least try to make strong encryption like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy">PGP&lt;/a> stupid-easy to use, and add &amp;quot;coolness&amp;quot; so people will &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to use it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Because much like openness, responsibility and privacy is now more important than ever.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Related material I found while writing this blog post:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Surveiller et punir: Naissance de la Prison](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discipline_and_Punish) is a 1975 book by the French philosopher Michel Foucault. If he was still alive, Foucault would probably see that after a period of individualism and consumer-centric change, the NSA is the re-introduction the [Panopticon](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panopticon), a prison (or society) where the prisoners can not see the guards.
* This Dutch program [&amp;quot;Dare to Think&amp;quot;](http://www.uitzendinggemist.nl/afleveringen/1304898) discusses how Foucault thought, and places it in the modern time. It discusses how modern individualism and a market driven society needs new mechanisms to steer the individual. The theory is in essence that people need to learn to steer themselves and check the self-set boundaries with others from time to time.
* In the source of Windows NT 4 Service Pack 5 a [variable with the name _NSAKEY](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NSAKEY) was discovered which led to speculation that Windows computers could leak private data to the NSA.
* Because few people do, When you decide to use PGP to encrypt your mail, you are likely to gain some attention, particularly from American &amp;quot;authorities&amp;quot;. Because you stand out. If you decide to stand out and encrypt stuff, you better do it right. Gather some information about [Uncrackable Email](http://www.ncmilitia.org/spycounterspy/fs006.html) (yes it's possible). Please note that all your encrypted mails will be stored, so when somebody does find reason to detain you and get your passphrase, deleting your drive will be useless.
* Estimations in the linked articles say that the NSA facility cost $2B to build, has it's own 65MW power station, 60,000 tons of cooling equipment, and an electricity bill of $40M per year (unclear if that includes running their own power station). If you looked closely at the WorldMeters link, you could have noticed that there are almost 4 million Cancer related deaths per year and 35 million HIV related deaths, versus [less than 8,000 terrorism related deaths in 2010](http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/09/global-terrorism-deaths). If the NSA is here to pretect us from dying, they'd better use their budget and intelligence to start investigating other stuff.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Morse Code is not dead (yet)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/04/09/morse-code-is-not-dead-yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 19:40:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/04/09/morse-code-is-not-dead-yet/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KaHm1ecBCgw">&lt;img src="international_amateur_radio_symbol.png" alt="International_amateur_radio_symbol">
&lt;/a>Not everybody understands why I am trying to learn &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morse_code">morse code&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="http://lcwo.net/">lcwo.net&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm not even sure myself. But most people seem to think morse code is absolutely dead. I could tell you that's not the case, but it is far better to find out for yourself. To be able to do that you need access to a radio which can receive &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_wave">CW (continuous wave)&lt;/a> signals somewhere between 8MHz and 15MHz. This is the place where &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amateur_radio_license">HAM Radio Operators&lt;/a> hang out and try to talk to eachother. Morse code is still used there, mainly for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DXing">DX-ing&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do you do that? With the power of the internet and a few very enthusiastic people in Dwingeloo, you can now receive radio signals right on your computer using radios all over the world. Lots of links in this article, have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->My father is a HAM radio operator . When I was around 16, he had a CEPT Class II license _(I searched the [www.cept.org](www.cept.org) site but for the life of me I can't find an exact description of the license and its entitlements)_. Because a lot of the theory required to get that license was already covered by my study at that time, I decided to get the same class license as my dad. This allowed me to operate on Amateur Radio bands from 50MHz and up.
&lt;p>To be able to operate on lower bands, we had to pass a morse code exam, both sending and receiving. Together with my dad we started listening to 12 words per minute morse courses on tape, and I even joined some on-the-air courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that time, there was some talk on removing morse from the exams because it was an &amp;quot;artificial barrier&amp;quot; and a skill which was not really required to operate radio equipment. So on the 1st of September in 2003, the morse requirement was dropped, which immediately meant that my license now covered the HF bands, and I did not have to pass the morse exam. I never looked at morse again. I also never worked on the lower HF bands, stayed mainly on 144MHz and up. My interests gradually changed and for the last 12 years or so, I didn't even look at HAM radio at all. Until I came across this video:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i8Ed0TSp0gs]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It made me smile. Morse Code and CW are not dead. I thought it would be fun to see if I could still do that. Well, I couldn't, not even at a much, much lower speed. Which lead me to lcwo.net and here I am, learning morse code again for no other reason than &amp;quot;because I can&amp;quot;. For now I think my goal is to make at least 1 short conversation (called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contact_(amateur_radio)">QSO&lt;/a> by HAMs) , with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telegraph_key">straight key&lt;/a>, to another amateur. If not only just so I can say I did that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=feGwrW2rT1I">&lt;img src="kenwood-ts50.gif" alt="kenwood ts50">
&lt;/a>I thought I'd do everything low profile, low power (called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QRP_operation">QRP&lt;/a> by HAMs), with a small second hand cheap transceiver like the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oT_rJvVi22I">Youkits HB1B&lt;/a>. But my very supportive dad immediately lent me his &lt;a href="http://www.rigpix.com/kenwood/ts50s.htm">Kenwood TS-50&lt;/a>, so I could listen to morse on the bands. According to &amp;quot;general wisdom&amp;quot; this is not smart because you should not learn from sloppy coders or incorrect speeds. But hey, this is just a hobby. My brother heard I got the TS-50 and dug up his 25 Amps power supply so I could put a full 100 Watts on the antenna, and he also had a 32 meter &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dipole_antenna">dipole antenna&lt;/a> for me to use. I can't use that antenna in my apartment building because of practical reasons but that's for another blogpost I think, &amp;quot;How to create a dipole antenna&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few days later, my brother mailed me an awesome link to a site where anybody could listen to these bands, even without a receiver. In 2007, the Radio Club at the University of Twente found a way to make the receiver of the 25m radio telescope available to many people online, while giving every individual user the power to choose a different frequency to listen to. The original goal was to listen to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EME_(communications)">EME signals&lt;/a>, which are sent from earth to the moon, bounce back from the moon's surface and received by the telescope. But the technology of having multiple people use the same receiver over the internet led to something awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the schematics and software were made publicly available and today quite a few people have built receivers with it connected to normal dipole antennas, tuned to the Amateur Radio bands. So if you want to listen to Amateur Radio, or check how much morse is still out there, or even listen to your own signal as it is received by a receiver far, far away, go to &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.websdr.org/">http://www.websdr.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and check for yourself. Scroll down for a Google Earth map with all the receivers on there. You do need to have Java enabled for the receivers to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the image below you can see me tuned in on 14.040MHz, on a morse code signal. I usually hear a lot of morse code between 14.000MHz and 14.100MHz. Based on the timing of the dit's and dah's, a lot of people are even still using &amp;quot;straight keys&amp;quot; so I think I can safely connect my old &lt;a href="http://www.mtechnologies.com/junker/">Junker&lt;/a> to the TS50 and get this show on the road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="sdr-14mhz.png">&lt;img src="sdr-14mhz.png?w=450" alt="SDR-14mhz">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun playing with your new receivers, kids. See you on air.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Steve Jobs' yacht launched, named "Venus"</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/10/28/steve-jobs-yacht-called-venus-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 18:14:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/10/28/steve-jobs-yacht-called-venus-launched/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZh4aSszD5k">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZh4aSszD5k&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Steve Job's yacht was launched from a dock a few miles from my house. I went there with some friends and we shot some awesome footage of this incredible ship. Through the glass, we could see the 7 iMacs which are used to control the ship. There are also large doors on the side and the back, I suspect these will be used to launch boats or jetskis into a nice warm Mediterranean water.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->We were able to catch a glimpse of it's name on the stern: "Venus". Too bad Steve didn't get to enjoy this. I hope is family and friends have a great time aboard this ship.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="20121028_113907.jpg">&lt;img src="20121028_113907.jpg" alt="Steve Jobs' yacht, side">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="20121028_114233.jpg">&lt;img src="20121028_114233.jpg" alt="Steve Jobs' yacht, stern">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="imacs-cropped.jpg">&lt;img src="imacs-cropped.jpg" alt="iMacs on bridge of Venus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kihsnQjgFg8">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kihsnQjgFg8&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pan Rant</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 13:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQu5Unc_TNY">&lt;img src="de-buyer-26cm-carbon-steel-mineral-frying-pan-11546-0-1315069074000.jpeg" alt="">
&lt;/a>You may have seen recent tweets from me ranting about my frying pans. I've ruined a few (very expensive) pans and replaced them with dirt-cheap pans which are actually much better. I would like to share my experiences and solutions with you, so that you can buy the right (cheap) pan without having to go through the same thing. Links to all the pans are in the article below.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->In my household, I try to avoid PTFE (Teflon) coated pans as much as I can. In normal consumer stores, it is almost impossible to find good PTFE-free pans. A few years ago I found two [Calphalon pans](http://www.calphalon.com/pages/home.aspx), a small 20cm frying pan of around €90,- (yes you've read that correctly) and a 30cm frying pan of €140,- (yes, you've read that correctly too). I convinced the store owner that this was rather expensive for two pans so he "let me have them" for "just" €200,- These pans are made of hard anodized aluminum, are scratch resistant and have have pretty good non-stick properties.
&lt;p>After a few years, the large Calphalon pan started to show some black stains on the rim, and I wanted to clean those. I regularly clean the pans with abrasive sponges, but this black stuff wouldn't come off. In a strange (and stupid) last effort to clean it, I sprayed the large pan with oven cleaner. The aluminum started oxidizing, and the pan was ruined. I was pretty upset, but luckily I did it with just one pan (albeit the most expensive one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3113.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Off to the store I went, but this time with a smaller budget. I bought a nice and shiny polished aluminum BK frying pan for €30,- . I used it for a few days and very quickly the pan had some brown spots on the rim of the pan. Being polished aluminum, I could not use abrasive sponges here. So I tried all kinds of tricks from this &lt;a href="http://www.omaweetraad.com/">&amp;quot;grandma's advice&amp;quot; website&lt;/a> without the desired results. The last tip I tried was to kook some washing detergent in it, which should dissolve the brown grease. It did not. Instead, it &lt;a href="img_3135.jpg">ruined the pan completely&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frustrated by the fact that nobody in the world (or at least on &amp;quot;the internets&amp;quot;) seemed to have pan cleaning problems or answers, I started looking for different alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some googling shows that most professional restaurants use rolled steel pans, without any coating. Just plain steel. This is actually pretty funny, when you think about the expensive Teflon and Ceramic coated pans in the stores for well over €30,- while professional cooks use steel pans of around €20,- which survive many years of heavy use and actually become better and better over time. Professional cooks mostly use gas as heat source, but steel pans can be used on &lt;em>any&lt;/em> heat source, even on induction stoves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I already have a rolled steel wok, and am very happy with that, so I decided to get a rolled steel &amp;quot;De Buyer&amp;quot; frying pan at &lt;a href="http://www.kookman.nl/nl/pannen/plaatstaal.html?page=shop.product_details&amp;amp;flypage=flypage.tpl&amp;amp;product_id=991&amp;amp;category_id=28">kookman.nl&lt;/a>. I ordered it on a Saturday, and on Sunday they mailed me that didn't have the 26cm pan and offered to send me the 30cm for the same price. That sounded like a good deal so that's what I received on my doorstep on Tuesday. Very good service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before doing any cooking, you have to prepare the pan in order to keep the meat from sticking to the steel. This is called &amp;quot;seasoning the pan&amp;quot; and is really easy to do: Heat the pan, then add oil, and fry some salt in it. There are different methods but salt blackens the pan quicker, I like that. The good thing about a steel pan is that if you screw it up, you can practically sand it down with your abrasive sponge and try again. and again. and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3347.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3347.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Here you see my de Buyer pan after seasoning and a few evenings of cooking. This is how your clean pan should look. Washing a non-coated steel pan is generally done without detergent, under extremely hot water with a brush. This keeps the dark &amp;quot;nonstick coating&amp;quot; in the pan. The pans will become darker upon use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you leave the pan dirty overnight, the grease will sometimes come off, or it will start to rust. Don't worry, scrub it and re-season it and you have a new pan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My new steel frying pan will probably outlast me and my kids. And if I can keep the small Calphalon pan away from the oven cleaner, it may do the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="imgres-1.jpeg" alt="">
So that's the pan story. But I hear you ask &amp;quot;Why all this trouble? Why not buy a Teflon pan?&amp;quot; Here's why: I don't trust it to be healthy. Teflon is one of the scariest polymers out there, and anybody knows how Teflon coating degrades, leaving little pieces of Teflon in your food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you search around for the chemical properties of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polytetrafluoroethylene">Teflon&lt;/a>, you will find some interesting facts. Meat is usually fried between 200 and 230 °C. The thermochemical decomposition of PTFE (Teflon) is detectable at 200 °C. If you ever wondered why your canary died early, the degradation by-products can be &lt;a href="http://www.bartcop.com/dead-canary.gif">lethal to birds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfluorooctanoic_acid">PFOA&lt;/a> is used in the production process of PTFE coated pans to reduce surface tension. Tests with PFOA on laboratory animals showed increased risk of cancer. Recently higher serum levels of PFOA were found to be associated with increased risk of chronic kidney disease in the general United States population. This is consistent with earlier animal studies. It is also recently &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/07/13/us-teflon-component-linked-to-arthritis-idUSTRE76C3WR20110713">linked to Arthritis&lt;/a>. PFOA is a carcinogen, liver toxicant, a developmental toxicant, an immune system toxicant, and also exerts hormonal effects including alteration of thyroid hormone levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, several manufacturers have started selling pans with ceramic coatings and put &amp;quot;PTFE Free&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;PFOA Free&amp;quot; labels on these pans. Why do you think they did that? Maybe it's because PTFE and PFOA aren't all that healthy after all. And apart from the coating in your pan, the production process of PTFE and PFOA is very, very bad for the environment. &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/manufacturing/2005-07-19-teflon_x.htm">Ask Dupont&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it turns out, if you know how to treat a pan, &lt;strong>the best coating is no coating at all&lt;/strong>. It's not only healthier and better for the environment, but top chefs will tell you it actually makes your food taste better. Next time you are in an expensive restaurant, ask what pans they use. You'd be surprised.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Tim Cook</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/20/open-letter-to-tim-cook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 20:04:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/20/open-letter-to-tim-cook/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.thewareaglereader.com/2011/08/portrait-of-new-apple-ceo-tim-cook-as-a-young-auburn-student/">&lt;img src="timcook.png" alt="Our new old friend, Tim Cook">
&lt;/a>Dear Tim,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am certainly not the first, nor the last to congratulate you with your new position at Apple. I'm sure there will be many great things to come for Apple and it's customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple has become the doctor that doesn't fix the pain, but cures the illness and improves our daily digital lives. Please make sure Apple keeps it's focus, perseverance and good taste in the endless search for true quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tell Steve and Jony I said hi, and keep up the good work. If there's anything I can help you with, you know how to reach me ;-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers,
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why phone companies will fail</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 19:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/phone">&lt;img src="wet-cell-phone.jpeg" alt="cell phone under water">
&lt;/a>I recently had a very unpleasant experience with my mobile phone. Actually, it wasn't so much my mobile phone itself, as it was the sharing of my private mobile phone number between colleagues. Seemingly harmless, but with great consequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my colleagues, in his innocence and with nothing but good intentions, shared my phone number with another colleague. As I was sitting in the hospital, the second colleague called me with questions about estimates I made for a project, which at that time &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rolfje/status/545010403512320">intensely frustrated me&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I had the whole weekend to cool down, I was still pretty pissed the following monday. Some unpleasant conversations followed. I think everything is solved now but I can only hope somebody actually deletes my number when he says he does. Which got me to think about the old fashioned and spectacularly broken addressing model phone companies are still using.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->When I was little, there were no mobile phones (yes, I'm that old). People had a single line into their house, with a single number. This situation lead to some "number sharing etiquette": If person A asks for the phone number of person B, instead of giving it, you asked for A's phone number instead, and passed that to B. This way, both parties have control over sharing their number, without you compromising anybody's number without their consent.
&lt;p>Nowadays, it seems that only my &amp;quot;smarter&amp;quot; friends find this etiquette normal to be used in sharing email addresses and other address information. Sadly, this is not the case for the younger generations. Sharing email addresses and phone numbers without asking is common practice. With modern communication methods this is not a problem, because the receiver is in control of the inbound traffic. Messages can be blocked, filtered or re-routed. Mails can be routed to different folders or straight into the trash with a simple mail rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much unlike unlike messaging, routing incoming calls is not possible on your phone. Why? Because the phone companies have created a problem when they introduced caller-ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of protecting the receiver of the call, they chose to protect the caller by hiding his number if he wishes to do so. This simple oversight results in the receiver not being able to route calls based on caller-ID. I can not block anonymous incoming calls without knowing if I am missing important calls, say from the hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to fix this, I propose we do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. We still keep (or re-introduce) the sharing etiquette described above, because I think it is good courtesy to handle other people's data with respect. It's also a workaround for the inbound routing problem.
2. We create a system where a phone can have multiple numbers, of which the owner can route traffic. Google voice is already doing this, but european phone companies are not allowing that to happen over here (guess why).
3. We loose the whole &amp;quot;anonymous calling&amp;quot; idea after implementing 2. As with MSN and Google Talk, I get to see who is calling me, and I can choose to block future calls or add you to my &amp;quot;buddy list&amp;quot;.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Having said all this, I think phone companies are dying. Sure they're doing okay now, but they keep holding on to old landline business models and apply them to new technology. It will fail like it is failing for the music and film industry right now. Unless phone companies act up and start behaving more like reasonable &amp;quot;data/Internet providers&amp;quot; they will be replaced by internet providers putting up cell towers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until then, we need to put up with (but protest against) ridiculous data plans, absurd roaming charges, single-provider GSM towers with coverage problems and the recent &amp;quot;round up to nearest minute&amp;quot; method of over-billing customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I expect all this to happen not earlier than world peace, let's be careful about sharing each others numbers, shall we?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The rumors can stop now. iPad is here.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png?w=119" alt="">
&lt;/a>So the word is finally out, it's going to be the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/">iPad&lt;/a>. I was kind of worried about this, and my worries are not completely taken away by the news currently oozing out of the Apple keynote. I see some problems with this device, although they are well hidden under Steve's reality distortion field, the Apple secret sauce and the &amp;quot;gee why didn't we think of that&amp;quot; features.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * The dock for the iPad is has me worried about mechanical failure. A large device resting on a small connector.
* Most people I know have a macbook and/or an iPhone. The iPad overlaps both the macbook and the iPhone in functionality, and it requires an extra data subscription. So they will probably hold out for a bit.
* Although the rest of the pad looks beautiful, the &amp;quot;home&amp;quot; button makes it into a big iPhone which I personally think is not a plus.
* The carriers will try to sell you the 3G models, subsidized. Don't go for that, buy the wifi instead, or try to get the wifi+3G sim-lock free. I'm glad Apple did not go for the carrier lock in construction on this one.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I admit, the video looks stunning. The UI is very polished (look at the pinch to peek in a stack of photo's), the device is nice and thin. Notice how the screen does not go all the way to the edge, so that you can put your thumb somewhere to hold it. And although it lacks a camera, it has all other iPhone features (yes, including GPS) so almost all iPhone apps will work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The additional $130 for the 3G option may be a bit steep, but the overall pricing is pretty good, almost competing with the netbooks, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/pricing/">starting at $499&lt;/a> at the 16GB wifi only model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judging from the very young information right now, I understand that I may not be target audience for this advice. I need a keyboard and a large screen. But if you're in the (American) market for a netbook or something to browse a bit on the couch, have a look at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/ipad-video/#medium">the video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flow</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/22/flow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 21:34:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/22/flow/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="left-right.jpg">&lt;img src="left-right.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Being &amp;quot;in the flow&amp;quot;. The nicest state of mind known to mankind. You act without thinking, and everyone of your actions is the perfect response to the situation. Riding a motorcycle on a beautiful road without a destination can easily get you into this state. With an empty mind, you see the next 2 corners, feel your bike as your brakes hit the disc, smell the forest, and hear the wind as you start accelerating out of the first corner while naturally placing the bike into position for the next.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Software developers also know "flow", and mentally it does not differ that much from riding a motorcycle. Coders call this "being in the zone". It's you, the code, and the next 2 unittests. You effortlesly write the perfect conditions for your loop, while noticing the log of the buildserver, and thinking about the solution you already have for the next problem.
&lt;p>In order to get into the flow, conditions need to be perfect. You have to be in the right mood. There should be no distractions. There needs to be rythm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coding and biking is done by &amp;quot;enjoy the ride&amp;quot; people. They enjoy the thrill of that perfect corner, or that perfect try/catch block, without worrying to much about the destination. Destination is usually the worry of the &amp;quot;a-to-b&amp;quot; people. These are to people that need to get to their destination. Usually car drivers, they will talk about destinations, the bluetooth and stereo in their cars, but rarely enjoy the ride itself. When they get to &amp;quot;B&amp;quot;, a new destination is chosen and the race is on again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;A-to-b&amp;quot; people often don't understand &amp;quot;flow&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;being in the zone&amp;quot;. They also don't understand that it's hard to get &amp;quot;in the flow&amp;quot; and very easy to get out. Changing the end goal of a long project is not all that troublesome. But changing the next 2 corners will get your &amp;quot;enjoy the ride&amp;quot; team members out of the flow for sure. Do it too often, and your team will not even try to get into the flow, because there is nothing more frustrating than being yanked out of your flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Programming seems dull and nerdy. But being &amp;quot;in the zone&amp;quot; or having &amp;quot;flow&amp;quot; can give you quite a rush, with some similarities to riding a bike on a sunny, twisty mountain road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T(w)inkering</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/06/07/twinkering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 21:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/06/07/twinkering/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Now that the twitter hype is cooling down, and companies tart to realize that it is, in fact, just CB radio in a new asynchronous form, only the &amp;quot;true tweeps&amp;quot; still hang around. And now, it's time to t(w)inker with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_942&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Early 2002, in my dad's old &amp;quot;shack&amp;quot;, we measured the accuracy of a delayed solonoid triggering device I made.&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="02020905.jpg">&lt;img src="02020905.jpg?w=150" alt="Early 2002, in my dad's old "shack", we measured the accuracy of a delayed solonoid triggering device I made.">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some years ago, I did some playing around with CB radio. With my dad being an electronics engineer and a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amateur_radio">HAM radio&lt;/a> operator, it didn't take long before I got my HAM radio license, and start taking apart and putting together all kinds of electronics to play with this medium. We had quite some fun doing this, and I got a lot of great stories out of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the coming of Twitter as the &amp;quot;new CB radio&amp;quot;, a new kind of tinkering came along. Not so much with electronics, but more with the data of twitter itself. Here are some of the funny and/or interesting services I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>WARNING:&lt;/strong> Some of these services show you a very &amp;quot;Twitter like&amp;quot; login form, and ask you to sign in with your Twitter userid and password. Please think very careful about this. Giving somebody your twitter password can render your account useless, and exposes you to possible forms of identity theft. Except for twitpic, none of these services have ever seen my password.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitoaster.com/rolfje">Twitoaster&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
One of the problems with Twitter is that you don't always see your conversations. People might only see one half of it, or because of it's asynchronous character, miss essential tweets in a conversation. To solve this, Twitoaster searches your tweets, finds replies, and groups them together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The downside is that you need to follow @twitoaster, which can ruin your &amp;quot;tweet stream&amp;quot;. Having said that, there are not much tweets coming from that account so maybe it won't bother you that much. Although twitoaster.com shows you a login form, you are not required to log in for this service to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://xefer.com/twitter/rolfje">Xefer&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
If you like cool pictures made from your tweeting habbits, Xefer can do that for you. It will display an activity graph which shows you which days of the week and which hours of those days you are most active on Twitter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitterank.com/?u=rolfje">Twitterank&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Some mysterious algorithm places people in a list in a certain order, and calls it a &amp;quot;rank&amp;quot;. Now all of a sudden, people want to be on top. Isn't that funny? The developer of this site had hacked some stuff together, and was soon overwhelmed by people wanting to know their &amp;quot;rank&amp;quot;. This is ofcourse just as silly as measuring your success by the number of followers you have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time of this writing, my twitterrank is 14.26. According to twitterank, this score is higher than 37.68 of the other ranked twitterers. Not knowing what the algorithm is, and not knowing how to influence it, means this number is totally useless and silly. But hey, we like numbers... Yay twitterank!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.twitteranalyzer.com/ms.aspx?userId=rolfje">Twitteranalyzer&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Just another graphing thing to show you when you tweet the most, what words or hashtags you most commonly use, and what kind of clients you use. Nicely done, but not really compelling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetstats.com/status/rolfje">Tweetstats&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
One of my favourites, displays your usage info in nice simple colorful layout. While you are waiting, funny texts as &amp;quot;magic happening&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;there be feries&amp;quot; are shown on the progess bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/status.php?search=rolfje">Twanalyst&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/suggest.php">&lt;img src="hatter.png" alt="Twanalyst logo">
&lt;/a>Always fun to read and always changing (if you keep tweeting), this service reads all your tweets and takes a shot at estimating your personality from their contents. At the time of this writing, it thinks of me as &amp;quot;likeable sociable fair&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;garrulous coherent&amp;quot;. It sums it up as &amp;quot;Poet&amp;quot;. Ahem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I you're not tweeting enough, or there is something else this service thinks is wrong, it will give you some tweeting tips. Very funny. Don't forget to check out the &lt;a href="http://twanalyst.com/rolfje/suggest">&amp;quot;suggest&amp;quot;&lt;/a> feature, which will try to find people with a similar writing style youmight like following.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://hashtags.org/">Hashtags&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Tracks hashtags in the global timeline. With this service you can see people's tweets grouped by tags. Very handy if you want to keep up with a particular subject. I personally use it to check &lt;a href="http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday/messages">followfriday&lt;/a> tags every now and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://twitterposter.com/nl">Twitterposter&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Shows you a cloud of twitter icons. The bigger the icon, the more followers this account has. The bad news is that it sometimes does not load all icons or avatars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Final thoughts&lt;/strong>
There are many, many, many more twitter services out there, but you want to be careful with sharing your password. For example, &lt;em>Tweetmondo.com&lt;/em> needs your twitter account password, just to tell you if there are &amp;quot;tweeps&amp;quot; close to your location? No thank you, Tweetie on my iPhone already does that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same goes for &lt;em>Localtweeps.com&lt;/em>, which tries to match you and other local tweeps through your ZIP code. I never was even tempted to give them my password, because it's developers seem to think that the world only consists of US, Canada and UK. Nothing to see here, move along...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a twitter account which has enough data to make these services work, you are one of the luck few. An &lt;a href="http://tech.yahoo.com/blogs/patterson/50591/study-top-10-of-twitter-users-do-90-of-the-tweeting/">article on tech.yahoo.com&lt;/a> shows that the top 10% of twitter users do 90% of the twittering. I hope they didn't count those dumb automated tweets, because there are a lot of those...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's funny how companies still seem to think that they can just &amp;quot;connect to a network&amp;quot;, send us spam, and them expect we'll like them. These companies are either loaded, or doomed, because in a few months, they might have to connect to a different network. Like Scoble said: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Networks don't have people. People have networks.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design Gripes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dear Akio Morita,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">&lt;img src="2009-04-08-234308.png" alt="Onion News Network on Sony products">
&lt;/a>Lately I have some small issues with a lot of design decisions being made by the company you founded a while ago. If you look at my irritations seperately they're just small gripes of a grumpy old customer. But the increasing number of design mistakes have me worried about your user acceptance testing and quality assurance processes. Given the sheer size of your company, and the fact that the very same people who are sabotaging your overall product quality can silently delete my complaint, I thought I'd share it with you here, on my very private blog.  Nobody else will read this. Honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me start by saying that I love my Playstation 3. No wait, let me rephrase that. I love playing games on my playstation 3. Because the playstation 3 itself is absolutely not intuitive, logical or even pleasant to use. Both hardware and software wise.
&lt;p>I am very fortunate to have a loving wife who bought a PS3 for me. Because she did not expect to have to do in-depth research about the differences between the models, she bought the 80GB PS3 for me. It was the biggest drive in the store, so she thought that was the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was/am really happy with the very nice present. Not having any PS3 games yet, I slapped in a PS2 game, fully expecting that it would play. Not so. As it turns out, only the 60GB model plays &lt;em>some&lt;/em> of the PS2 games, and most of the time not even perfectly. What's with that? Can this 3-Cell processor huge 80GB machine with metric craploads of memory not emulate the outdated PS2? Did nobody at Sony realize that they can capitalize on people upgrading from the PS2? Not even now that the &lt;a href="http://ps3finder.com/">60GB models actually sell for more money than the 80GB&lt;/a> model retail price?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disapointedly leaving the PS2 compatibility issue, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/">I got a DLNA server running&lt;/a> on my Mac. When I want to view media on that server, I have to use your &amp;quot;X media bar&amp;quot; menu. For some reason, some designer came up with the brilliant idea to seperate music, photo's and video's in that menu. This means that before browsing my DLNA server, I have to decide what filetype I'm going to browse. If I have folders containing both video and photo's of the same birthday party, I constantly have to back out of the photo viewing mode, get into the video mode, browse all the way back to the folder, and view the video. It's like having to fill in a form to flip the channel on your TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what's with the forgetting of discovered DLNA servers? The PS3 takes ages to re-discover my DLNA server on the network each time I turn the PS3 on, or return to the menu from a game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it even more cringeworthy, the PS3 scares the crap out of me each time I browse to a folder to see that &amp;quot;There are no files...&amp;quot;. The PS3 is lying ofcourse, what it means is that there are MPG's and AVI's there, but I'm in photo viewing mode. The whole X-media-bar design must have never been usability tested by random customers. It's a very common practice nowadays which I can really recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By now, I had scored some PS3 games (&lt;a href="http://www.ps3home.nl/products/playstation-3-games/alle-games-a-tot-z/moto-gp-2008-ps3.htm">Moto GP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.tombraiderunderworld.com">Tomb Raider: Underworld&lt;/a>). After a nice evening of gaming,  I discover that the controller battery is running low. So I connect it to the PS3, and put the PS3 in standby mode, expecting my controller to be charged the next morning. To my huge disapointment, the controller does not charge when the PS3 is not fully on. That strikes me as really strange. To charge my wireless controller, I have to connect it during gaming. Now how did someone on your design team did not notice that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a big old Phillips Matchline TV which worked fine, but was getting a bit dated. The thought of being able to play games in full HD 1080p resolution was very tempting, so I bought a new model Sony Bravia 40 inch TV, thinking that it would interface nicely with the PS3. To my absolute horror, the PS3 video signal looked horrible on this new TV. As it turned out, you are shipping this full HD 300+ dollar gaming machine with a crappy composite video cable. Oh boy. Now I know why people think the difference between a Wii and a PS3 is not that huge. Another obvious commercial win down the drain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and I discovered that HDMI is the best way to go. I bought an HDMI cable and connected the PS3 to the TV with that. The TV manual said it could use some HDMI protocol to discover HDMI connected devices. Surely enough, my brandnew Sony Bravia does not recognize my Sony PS3. How nice is that? Luckaly, after some manual fiddling with the absolutely horrid X-media bar-like menu's in the TV and the PS3, I got everything to play in full HD. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What strikes me as another design flaw is the size of the screen fonts. On my big TV everything looks nice, but I can imagine that the paperboy who emptied his piggybank to get a PS3, and connects it to his little TV in his room, can not read any of the menu items. I take it that the Sony testing department only has Full HD TV's with HDMI cables, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there's the whole casing design thing. Come on. Rounded top? I can not even place a controller on there, it slides off. The ventilation holes are on the side, which makes it imposible to put the PS3 with it's right side against the cupboard. The USB ports are recessed in such a way that if you place the PS3 low to the ground (which happens most), you can not see the ports without having to lie down on the floor eyeballing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you're down there, you can als see the rediculously thick and sturdy mains cable. It can transport enough current to power my microwave. Does the PS3 really use that much current? Now be honest. You could have selected a thinner, more flexible mains lead, and maybe it would even have been cheaper. The current lead almost pushes the PS3 out from the wall. Good thing the PS3 is so heavy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When waking the PS3 from it's sleep mode, there is another interesting thing that strikes me as odd. There is a green and a blue led next to eachother on the top of the button pannel. Not only are those two colors looking horrible next to eachother, and the fact that I have come to loathe any product with a blue led, there is absolutely no way that colorblind people are going to notice the difference in color, which makes them pointless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said, this is just a selection of the gripes I have with the design. For instance, the fact that game makers are allowed to play sounds and video as soon as a game is inserted, is just terrible. It scares the crap out of me each time I insert &lt;a href="http://www.racedrivergrid.com/">Race Driver:GRID&lt;/a>, and there is no way I can turn it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="photo.jpg">&lt;img src="photo.jpg" alt="Sony Bravia remote button misplacement">
&lt;/a>The nicest example of hardware design failure by Sony is the remote control of the Sony Bravia TV. The buttons you use most are in fact unreachable when holding the remote in your hand. The least used buttons are right there by your thumb. What was this designer thinking? Oh and never mind pressing the buttons, because this TV, which can interpolate frames of a 24fps source into 100fps fluid motion while dynamically adjusting sound and backlight, has a very hard time to display a menu or react to the remote. This is absolutely mind boggling to me. It's like a race car which can go from 0 to 300mph in 2 seconds but takes 5 seconds to react to the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I bought all this Sony stuff. I know, I could have bought something else. But there are reasons for me to put up with all this crap. OTHER manufacturers make such great stuff for Sony devices. The games on the PS3 are absolutely beautiful and brilliant. Watching video on the PSP on an airplane is great. Looking at a bluray at 100Hz 1080p on the Bravia is eye-popping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, dear mr. Morita, please, please make the people at Sony aware of these details. They're important. Solving them will set your product apart from the competition in a large way. People may not be able to tell why, but they will like your product better. This is what good designers do. Make a product have a good &amp;quot;feel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will also rid you of online video's describing your products as... well... you've already seen &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">that video&lt;/a>, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading this rant.
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LED's in your livingroom?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/03/08/leds-in-your-livingroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 21:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/03/08/leds-in-your-livingroom/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In some countries, there is some talk on &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase_out_of_incandescent_light_bulbs">banishing the classic (incandescant) lightbulb&lt;/a>. I think this whole discussion is needless. The only reason why it exists, is that the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluorescent_light">fluorescent&lt;/a> bulbs are often of mediocre quality, and certain people are here to enforce their bad tastes upon us &amp;quot;for a greater purpose&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don't get me wrong, I really like trees and birds around my house, and I would be more than happy to install &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/">energy-efficient appliances&lt;/a> in my home, even if they cost me slightly more. But especially if I'm paying more, I expect to get a certain level of quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the inefficiency of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incandescent_light_bulb">incandescent&lt;/a> bulbs, and the number of bulbs in my household, I decided to look around for energy efficient solutions. Particulary LED lighting caught my interest, because it is not only energy efficient, it's also dimmable with normal (cheap) floor dimmers. They even stay cold enough so that children touching them do not burn their fingers.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**The Search
&lt;p>**I went online, and looked around for LED bulbs which would fit in a normal E14 (small) socket. It was a long and hard search, because information on LED lighting is sparse, as if manufacturers don't want to sell them. I found this &amp;quot;Parlat&amp;quot; lamp at &lt;a href="http://www.ledgloeilamp.nl/LED-Gloeilampen-E27-E14/LED-lamp-E14-kaarsvorm/productdetails.tpl.htm">ledgloeilamp.nl&lt;/a> which promised to be &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot;, with a color temperature of 3000 Kelvin. Some Googling learned that a 2 Watt LED lamp is considered to be roughly equal to 30 Watts of incandescent light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**The Test Results
**&lt;a href="img_1203_text1.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1203_text1.jpg?w=72" alt="LED lighting, side-by-side comparison">
&lt;/a>In the picture on the right, you can see the result. The topmost bulb is a normal Phillips 25Watt &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot; lamp, which produces the expected &amp;quot;Incandescent&amp;quot; lighting. The wall behind is yellow by the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bottom bulb is a 25Watt &amp;quot;Terracotta&amp;quot; lamp, also from Phillips. This is the warmest color you can buy, and it's even slightly to yellow for my taste, but better than the normal white bulb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The middle bulb is the Parlat &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot; 2Watt LED lamp. As you can see it is nowhere near &amp;quot;warm&amp;quot;. It produces an ugly green-blue-ish color which has a colder color temperature than the incandescent &amp;quot;Warm White&amp;quot;. The 2 Watts is not nearly enough to even maka the wall behind it light up in the photo. Because of the plastic LED housing in the bottom of the bulb, it is unable to produce an even light pattern, and results in ugly shades in my lamp cover.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Additional Field Work
**&lt;a href="img_0384.jpg">&lt;img src="img_0384.jpg?w=117" alt="LED lighting on display">
&lt;/a>Last weekend I got a tip from my dad, a local shop had some LED bulbs on display. To rule out the possibility of having bought a faulty lamp, I drove to the shop to take a look for myself. The result: I didn't even buy a lamp, I snapped a picture with my iPhone instead. The dark banding is caused by interference between the camera and the light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the left are fluorescent bulbs, which look quite ok. On the right: LED lighting, again in the ugliest of all colors, even more blue than the one I ordered online. The lamps in the middle are also LED lights, but have more LED's in them and produce more light, and are slightly less &amp;quot;blue/gray&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**How to Improve
**I think the lighting industry needs someone with authority who can think, has authority, and some taste. LED lighting would be(come) a lot better if it did:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Laboritory employee, proudly showing LED lamp: _"Look boss, we made this beautiful lamp. Here, let me turn it on for you"_
&lt;p>&lt;em>-plink-&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Ehm. right. What kind of color did you say this was?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Employee, looks at the lamp and tries to lie at his boss the same way he is planning to lie to the customers: &lt;em>&amp;quot;Warm white ofcourse. We measured it at 3000K&amp;quot;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;It's not &amp;quot;Warm&amp;quot;, it's not &amp;quot;White&amp;quot;, it's not &amp;quot;3000K&amp;quot; and it's not beautiful. Do you know what this is?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Employee, feeling like he has been caught: &lt;em>&amp;quot;No, what boss?&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boss: &lt;em>&amp;quot;The reason you are fired.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/blockquote>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Final Thoughts
I think LED lighting is the future, and I really hope that it becomes a lot better. But until then, you have been warned. Don't buy LED (or any other) bulbs &amp;quot;unseen&amp;quot;. Don't go by the temperature or &amp;quot;equivalent watts&amp;quot; crap. Use your eyes and your brain.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For now, I'm holding on to my beautiful incandescent lamps, and I will buy boatloads of them if the Dutch governement is stupid enough to think about banishing incandescent lamps without accurate, usable, affordable alternatives.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tweet Week</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/rolfje">&lt;img src="twitter-logo.png" alt="Twitter">
&lt;/a>About a week ago, I was a bit bored and decided to see what Twitter is all about. I created an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje">account&lt;/a>, and I Tweeted for a week. I tried to keep to the original idea, where a Tweet should answer the question &amp;quot;What are you doing&amp;quot;? Looking back, my tweets include &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1198486833">Coffee&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1199748992">Podcasts&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1200610213">Global frustration&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1203692363">Small joys&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1206502512">Small irritations&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209317512">Re-tweets&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209634779">Replies&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Twitter is a service were you can send short texts of 140 characters or less, called "tweets". These texts end up on a webpage, resulting in a micro-blog for all to read. Think of it as SMS-ing to your blog. One of the fun parts of Twitter is that people find really creative ways to express themselves in 140 characters or less. This allows you to follow an amazing amount of people, getting short messages about what they're doing, such as ["is relaxing with the wife and kids..... at home"](https://twitter.com/richard_hammond/statuses/1209417438)  or   ["Great meal at Michael Minna with my best gal"](https://twitter.com/ev/statuses/1211691640).
&lt;table border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["at"](afbeelding-1.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Should you find a "Tweet" you think is interesting, you can reply to that person (not to the tweet directly) by starting your tweet with an "@" and the username of the person you want to reply to. 
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["hash"](afbeelding-2.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >You can even "tag" your Tweets by using a "#" and a word. So for instance "#rolfje" would add the tag "rolfje" to my Tweet. You can then easily [search tweets with this tag](http://hashtags.org/tag/rolfje). Tags are sometimes used to create something of a "communications channel". For instance, the [#followfriday](http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday) tag is used to tweet about people you think are worth following.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
Starting in the US, Twitter is becoming increasingly popular all over the world, now taking over Europe. [BBC had an item](http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/7287536.stm) on English television about twitter, massively increasing the number of English twitterers. 
&lt;p>And ofcourse, where there are people, there are money-sharks to spoil the fun. Some companies are showing up, and are clearly not understanding what Twitter is about. They start a twitter account and twitter promotional messages, product releases, etc. The problem with this (for the company) is that for this to be succesful, people must follow you. If there's nothing interesting to read, people will not follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This same problem occurs with people who have their staff update their twitter accounts. This makes for really uninteresting, unpersonal tweets, and replying to them will almost never result in a nice conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com">&lt;img src="http://laikaspoetnik.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/twitter-addicts.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**What I used:
**During my Tweetweek, I tried different OSX and iPhone clients. There are a lot of clients out there, but none of them are good enough to be your &amp;quot;single client of choice&amp;quot;. Here's what I think of them, in short:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl&lt;/a>: Done in Adobe AIR, multi-platform and consistent accross OS's. Good for a Windows app, terrible for an OSX app. Settings are in strange places, not clear what the &amp;quot;narrow&amp;quot; column mode is for. Ugly but probably the best twitter client out there, with twitpic and tinyurl integration all out of the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetdeck.com/beta/">Tweetdeck&lt;/a>: Also done in Adobe AIR, mutli-platform and consistent. Works fine, has multiple columns for monitoring your tweets, search results and profiles. Feels a bit funny, for instance the same icon is used for &amp;quot;show input window&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;send tweet&amp;quot;. It works, but it doesn't fit the &amp;quot;clean and simple&amp;quot; design I think a twitter client needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific">Twitterific&lt;/a>: Nice design, clean. Not much features, too overpriced. If Twitterific had tinyURL and twitpic integration, and sold for about $5, it would be a huge hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=296415944&amp;amp;mt=8">Tweetie (iPhone)&lt;/a>: The funny thing is that &amp;quot;Tweetie&amp;quot;, the iPhone twitter client is way better than any of the clients I tried on a normal computer. Tweetie wins hands down. The best twitter client for the iPhone, simple and clean, camera integration, GPS integration. This also fits way better in the twitter philosophy, Tweeting whatever you are doing, wherever you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I learned:&lt;/strong>
Twitter is for everyday people, like you and me, and feels like a mix between &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens'_Band_Radio">CB radio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texting">texting&lt;/a>. Twitter is all about you and who you follow. It's definetely not about your followers. Ofcourse you can try to get as much followers as possible, but I think that does not guarantee a nice twitter experience. Some people think it's rude not to follow back if they're followed, and will tweet to let somebody know that they're being &amp;quot;un-followed&amp;quot;. I think that's not how the system is supposed to work. There's also no real relationship. Follow or unfollow, it's not like you're devorcing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just Tweet, and see what happens. There's no currency, only small text messages from people around the world for you to read and reply to. Or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DLNA on OSX, done right</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3">&lt;img src="200x150_playstation3_logo1.jpg" alt="Sony PS3 Logo">
&lt;/a>My wife bought me a playstation 3 last year, and I've enjoyed many hours of gaming on it, finishing Tomb Raider underworld, and now making decent progress in Ratchet and Clank: Tools of Destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dlna.org/home">&lt;img src="afbeelding-22.png" alt="DLNA logo">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a bit sceptical about the DLNA capabilities of the PS3, because I read a lot of bad news on this fairly new  &amp;quot;Interoperability Guidelines&amp;quot; concept. It sounded like a lot of trouble to go through to simply watch the photos and home videos on a TV. For weeks, I was not able to find a single site telling me how to install a DLNA server on my Mac, or where to find a decent one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Altgough they're hard to find, there are a few OSX DLNA servers out there. One of them is actually very good. Here's what I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**CyberMediaGate**
&lt;p>I found a DLNA server implemented in Java, and didn't get it to work. It misses a Xerces library and I can not seem to get the right version added to the classpath. I decided this was not very &amp;quot;Mac like&amp;quot; and dumped it. Not being able to install software &amp;quot;out of the box&amp;quot; may be normal on Linux, but is unaccepatble on a Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TwonkyMedia&lt;/strong>
Then, I came across TwonkyMedia. This was the first DLNA server I actually got to work on my Mac, and had it serving video to my PS3. It is a strange (wonky?) piece of software, had no native GUI and only lives on your machine as a webapplication. The installer copies &amp;quot;TwonkyMediaServer.app&amp;quot; in your application folder, starts it, and then opens a browser which points to the local URL of it's configuration screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that moment, it already is serving clients, but when you try to access it with the PS3, you will get a protocol error. This is because TwonkyMedia does not come with a default server name. The PS3 aparently can not handle an empty server name. After filling it in and restarting Twonky, I could access it with the PS3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TwonkyMedia does not look very Mac-like, and I don't like the looks of the webpage it is serving. The installer leaves two webloc files on your desktop which point to the configuration screens. It's a bit strange but it gets the job done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Potentially Twonky can do a bit more than CyberMediaGate. Twonky can do some transcoding and other streaming stuff, but I did not try that because I simply wanted to see my photo's and home video's on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trial version of Twonkymedia last for 30 days, but on the first day it already started acting up on me, and I had to restart it a few times while watching video. The look and feel, and the crashes didn't feel like it was worth the $40 to me, so I uninstalled it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uninstalling TwonkyMedia requires you to kill the process from the Terminal, and then drag TwonkyMediaServer.app to your trashcan. Another way is dragging the app to the trashcan and then restarting your Mac (not mac-like but it works).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>MediaLink&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink">&lt;img src="printablelogo.png" alt="Nullriver Logo">
&lt;/a>The nullriver homepage looked very elegant, and promising. A simple page explains what it is, what it does, and what it costs. Nullriver also allows you to send requests and reports on their site without registering (in contract with TwonkyMedia, to which you have to &amp;quot;sell your soul&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nullriver Medialink comes as a preference pane application, and has a beautifuly simple interface, with not many options. It integrates with your mac applications like iTunes, iPhoto and now even Aperture. It does not have all the fancy configuration options of TwonkyMedia. One of my small complaints is that your content is shared to all DLNA clients on your local network, which may not be what you want if you have more than one DLNA client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me MediaLink is a perfect fit. I control my own network, my PS3 is my only DLNA client so I don't need the fancy stuff. Most people will be perfectly happy with Medialink. It's simple, transparent, drag-and-drop, has a &amp;quot;stop&amp;quot; button and is cheap. It does not have all the fancy features, but all the features that are in there work flawlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played with it for more than a week now, and so far it hasn't crashed on me. I did need to buy a registration key, because the trial version only lasts you for about 30 minutes of watching content (which should be plenty to try it out, and it's not like the 20 bucks are going to kill you).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
Once again, all DLNA servers I tried put together:&lt;/p>
&lt;table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="1" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[CyberMediaGate](http://www.cybergarage.org/net/cmgate/java/index.html)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Free
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Terrible, unable to install.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[TwonkyMedia](http://www.twonkyvision.de/)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$40
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Works, lots of features, no GUI, buggy/ Crashed on me more than once.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[MediaLink](http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$20
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Simple, stable, nice GUI, best value for money. Just works.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
So if you have a PS3 and a Mac, it's a no-brainer. Buy Medialink!</description></item><item><title>Technology does not sell</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/09/technology-does-not-sell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 20:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/09/technology-does-not-sell/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/">Seth Godin&lt;/a> did a talk at Google campus in Februari last year. I recently stumbled upon &lt;a href="http://video.google.nl/videoplay?docid=-6909078385965257294">this video of his talk&lt;/a>, in which he explains to the Google people why Google sells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He is very clear in explaining to technology people that &lt;strong>technology does not sell&lt;/strong>. It's technology that gives you a shot at marketing, nothing more. He makes some very good points which I'll try to summarize, because the video takes 48 minutes to watch :-)&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * People don't care about cool technology, they care about their problem being solved.
* When buying a product, people actually are buying a feeling or experience. Apple and Google are good examples of &amp;quot;solve the problem&amp;quot; products, which gives more &amp;quot;feeling&amp;quot; than &amp;quot;product&amp;quot;.
* People who buy &amp;quot;feeling&amp;quot; and are happy with that, will market the product for you. You just plant a seed, and if the product is good enough for the right people, it will sel itself
* You can only sell answers to people who have questions. The classic &amp;quot;tv show interruption commercial&amp;quot; is way less efficient than the [Add-Sense](https://www.google.com/adsense) commercials which presents relevant products to people who are searching.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>When reading back this list, I think it is clear that Seth should speak to you, and not me ;-). My summary is lousy compared to the talk, maybe you're better of watching it. But the main conclusion for me still is that technology does not sell, nor does a product. It's the (happy) feeling people get from buying the product, making them want to tell other people about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He brings up a nice example still true today: If you wanted to search for something on the web, and go to &lt;a href="http://www.yahoo.com/">Yahoo!&lt;/a>, you'll see a page with 100 links, and somewhere on the page (you have to look for it) is a search query entry field and a search button. When you go too &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/">Google&lt;/a>, it's very clear that you can search there. Almost no links, and the search functionality is in the middle of the page and everybody knows how to use it. This will make you come back at that page, and even better: If your friends wanted to search for something, you'd send them to Google, because you know they will know how to use that page, and not come bother you with questions about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google's page is becomming slightly more cluttered with links, I just hope they paid attention to Seth and will remove some soon. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Edit:&lt;/strong> This is also a nice addition of Seth. Only 10 minutes, about &lt;a href="http://video.google.nl/videoplay?docid=-4101280286098310645">stuff that's &amp;quot;broken&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. I whish people would not only watch it and laugh, but actually use it while designing/building/doing things! You can also visit his website on &lt;a href="http://broken.typepad.com/">Stuff that's broken&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Widgets, Gadgets, Screenlets</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/11/thoughts-on-widgets-gadgets-screenlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 21:14:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/11/thoughts-on-widgets-gadgets-screenlets/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Just now, I was listening to the &lt;a href="http://javaposse.com/">Java Posse podcast&lt;/a> about the ab5k screenlet framework for Java, and I am finally convinced that software developers are a bunch of crazy, unrealistic, memory-hungry, cpu cycle stealers and by lack of normal people telling them otherwise are proud of it, too. The problem? Look at this list (no particular order):&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Linux screenlets or applets](http://kde.org/screenshots/images/3.5/35-superkaramba.png)
* [Windows Sidebar Gadgets](http://www.microsoft.com/windows/products/windowsvista/features/details/sidebargadgets.mspx)
* [Apple Dashboard Widgets](http://developer.apple.com/macosx/dashboard.html)
* [Google Desktop Gadgets](http://desktop.google.com/nl/?utm_campaign=nl&amp;amp;utm_source=nl-ha-emea-nl-google&amp;amp;utm_medium=ha&amp;amp;utm_term=google%20widgets)
* [Yahoo Widgets](http://widgets.yahoo.com/)
* and recently added: [ab5k.org java screenlets](http://www.ab5k.org/)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- more -->As you can see, this list shows what modern OS's are offering to the user as an extra desktop with little applications on them like clocks, calculators, rss readers or whatever small tool you can think of. Aside from having a polished look and feel, looking good in screenshots, and -in the case of OSX- animations, all these share the same problems:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Usage of CPU cycles while not visible/used (and I don't care how few, there are some!)
* Usage of wired memory (memory which is not swapped out to disk for windows users), even while being inactive
* Slow loading times when restoring swapped-out widgets (memory swapped to disk which needs to be loaded back into memory)
* While resembling in name (screenlets, widgets, gadgets) not really portable between systems (although ab5k is about to solve that one)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I was triggered by the &lt;a href="http://javaposse.com/index.php?post_id=201631">Java Posse podcast on ab5k&lt;/a>, where one of the developers said that when the screenlet container was swapped out, it &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; used 24 megs of memory. That 24 megs could be just that 24 meg which makes windows swap out Photoshop to disk. 24 megs is a considerable amount of memory, for something which does absolutely nothing. An argument for *lets is probably the fast load time, but if all of them get swapped out, it would be just as fast just to start them, wouldn't it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On my Mac, the dashboard looks great, and the widgets do what they promise. But apart from using it simply because it was new, I really don't use it that much nowadays. Once the coolfactor wears off, you just want it to work, and I think I like it better to have my utilities on the desktop, where I am working, rather than on a seperate cool looking transparent overlay from which I can not drag and drop easily into an application on the desktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that I realized while listening is that a lot of the functionality of these widgets are developer driven, not end user driven. I think half of the widgets are build by tech-nerds, but only 10% of the widgets actually end up being used by normal end-users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My point is: Can we please stop using the dashboard containers and just build these utilities so they are normal, small, self-contained, fast loading applications which just do what they are designed for, and exit (as in: die and free up memory) when closed? I think this will free up a lot of memory on a lot of systems, and puts CPU cycles to a better use, giving the user more control of what the computer is doing for him, and what he doesn't want the computer to do for him. And if these utilities are in a self-contained package like Apple applications, people can actually uninstall them without leaving a lot of crap behind on the system. Say no to setup.exe!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess the faster computers we buy, the greedier developers get.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soybean racer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The big car manufacturers could have done &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2006/02/17/eveningnews/main1329941.shtml">this&lt;/a>, but they didn't, because they are sponsored by the big oil companies. And your local governement is swimming in taxmoney that's added to your oil price. And no, they don't want to get rid of the cars, despite of what they say. The nicest thing for governements would be the complete population sitting in single-seated, gas guzzling cars in a traffic jam accross the country!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that a few school kids have proven that you don't need oil to race, and several American race series run on methanol (no that's not an oil product), can we please stop making cars that run on gasoline? And by the way, also stop pumping money into the super-dangerous liquid nitrogen cars? All that is purely to keep the oil companies in the same place: monopoly. Do you really think they do it for the environment? What if I told you that your current petrol car can run on bio-degradable methanol, with almost no changes? If you have a very modern car, the fuel system will even auto-adapt! But noooo, they won't tell you that, because the oil companies and governements want to keep the monopoly intact!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not that you can really do anything about it though. Except maybe not buying liquid-nitrogen or hybrid cars. There are better technical alternatives, although not on the market yet. Boycot the &amp;quot;environmentally friendly&amp;quot; car, force them into making a &lt;em>real&lt;/em> environmentally friendly car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I'm driving a diesel, and a motorbike. And no, I'm not worried about oil-shortage. It's all bullshit from the oil companies, who could have come up with alternatives a long while ago, but chose not to. If there really was an oil shortage, we all would have been driving on methanol for quite some time now. And co2 emmisions would have been reduced to absolutely 0.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>