<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fun on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/fun/</link><description>Recent content in Fun on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 21:19:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to share Garmin routes with your friends</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/06/30/how-to-share-garmin-routes-with-your-friends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 21:19:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/06/30/how-to-share-garmin-routes-with-your-friends/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png" alt="Recalculated route (green) does not match the original (pink)">
I've been struggling to get routes into my Garmin Zūmo® in such a way that it matches the plans of the original author, while at the same time setting the Garmin to &amp;quot;recalculate&amp;quot; so that when I take a wrong turn, it will send me back to the track. After reading a lot on the Garmin forums, and experimenting with this on my two recent road trips (one to Eifel and one to Sauerland in Germany) I can say I have found a way to do this. It's a bit of work, but it will make your trip a lot more trouble-free. Here's the recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Needed:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nice motorcycle route in a GPX or GDB file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www8.garmin.com/support/download_details.jsp?id=4435">Garmin BaseCamp&lt;/a> (BaseCamp 3.0.1.0 for OSX at time of writing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://buy.garmin.com/shop/shop.do?cID=135&amp;amp;pID=15000">Garmin Zūmo®&lt;/a> (model 660 at time of writing)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- more -->**Before you begin:**
&lt;p>Open &amp;quot;Preferences...&amp;quot; in Garmin BaseCamp on the Mac and make sure you selected &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Dinstance&amp;quot;&lt;/em> on the routing tab. This is to prevent routing errors because of changed maximum speeds on different maps. Speeds may differ, but distances are always the same.
On the Zūmo, make sure you matched the BaseCamp routing settings as well as you can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Import the route&lt;/strong>
You friend sends you a file with a great motorcycle route, in this case &lt;em>&amp;quot;Demo.GPX&amp;quot;&lt;/em>
You import the file into BaseCamp by clicking on &lt;em>&amp;quot;File&amp;quot; -&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Import...&amp;quot;&lt;/em> and selecting the file. Basecamp loads the route and it shows up as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-26-19.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-26-19.png?w=450" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Copy the route&lt;/strong>
In order to make sure your Zūmo will re-calculate the route as your friend intended it, you may need to correct for mismatches in maps, software versions or settings influencing the calculation. To correct the route, we copy it. Select the imported route (it will highlight on the map), right click it and select &lt;em>&amp;quot;Duplicate&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. You should now have 2 routes in the List on the left side of the screen:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-33-11.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-33-11.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, right click the copied route (in this case &lt;em>&amp;quot;Demo Route 1&amp;quot;&lt;/em>) and choose &lt;em>&amp;quot;Get Info&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. On the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Summary&amp;quot;&lt;/em> tab, choose a different color for the copied route, so we know what we are editing. In this case, I choose green.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Recalculate and fix the copy&lt;/strong>
Close the info screen and right-click the copied route again, this time choosing &lt;em>&amp;quot;Recalculate&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. To demonstrate what happens when settings differ, I exported the route with the (wrong) &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Time&amp;quot;&lt;/em> setting, and imported/recalculated it with the (correct) &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Distance&amp;quot;&lt;/em> setting. We see that the copied route is now recalculated and does not match the original:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png" alt="Recalculated route (green) does not match the original (pink)">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because your friend will likely be riding the pink route, you want to correct your copy of the route so that both BaseCamp and the Zūmo will send you down the roads you intended to ride. You can do this by selecting the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Selector Tool&amp;quot;&lt;/em> and dragging the green route towards the purple one. Each time you do this, it will create a new waypoint in your copied route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-42-51.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-42-51.png" alt="Selector tool">
&lt;/a>When placing a new waypoint, try to avoid placing waypoints on intersections. This will give both BaseCamp and the Zūmo more room to choose different routes, which you don't want. Think of it this way: You want to be driving on a certain road, not on a certain intersection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you think you are ready, zoom in to about 300m level, and carefully scan the route so that you can correct the final details of the route. Because we selected different colors, the differences are easy to spot, and it's easy to see how to correct them. This is what it looks like when making corrections, note that I'm dragging the new waypoint to the middle of the road, as mentioned earlier:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-49-20.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-49-20.png" alt="Dragging waypoint to correct route">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Fine-tune the waypoints&lt;/strong>
After the route looks as intented, you need to make sure that the waypoints are placed perfectly on the road. This is particularly important on 2-way highways, where a misplaced waypoint can make your Zūmo think you want to be riding in the other direction on this highway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right-click the copied route and select &lt;em>&amp;quot;Get Info&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. If not already selected, choose the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Via Points&amp;quot;&lt;/em> tab and place a checkmark on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Center on Selected&amp;quot;&lt;/em> option. Now click on the first waypoint, and see if it is placed exactly where you want it to be. If it is not, press the &lt;em>&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;&lt;/em> (also called &lt;em>&amp;quot;option&amp;quot;)&lt;/em> key on your keyboard and use the Selector Tool to drag the waypoint to the correct location. Below you can see a misplaced waypoint that needs to be corrected:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-52-51.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-52-51.png?w=450" alt="Misaligned waypoint">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Export the route&lt;/strong>
If you placed the copied route in the same List as the original route (like in this example), you might want to delete the original route from the list (or from your Collection if you choose), and save the resulting list into a GPX file. This is an extra safety measure, giving you a backup of the route to take along on your trip on an SD card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have 2 options in BaseCamp for transporting the route to the Zūmo. Either you send it directly to the device, or you save the exported GPX file onto the SD card in the &lt;em>/Garmin/GPX&lt;/em> folder. Doing the latter will enable you to recover from a crashing Zūmo, because you can re-import the route from the SD card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6. Check the imported route in the Zūmo&lt;/strong>
Whether you exported it directly to the Zūmo, or you put it onto the SD card, a few seconds after booting the Zūmo will tell you that it found new user data. You choose &amp;quot;import&amp;quot; and select the route(s) you want to import. I did notice that selecting &amp;quot;&lt;em>Import all&amp;quot;&lt;/em> for larger routes, the Zūmo tells you after 5 routes or so that it failed. This is probably a memory problem. Importing them one-by-one nearly always works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the route is imported and you're still behind your Mac, you might want to compare the route in the Zūmo with the one on your screen. In some cases the Zūmo is still stubborn enough to select a different route. Most of the time this is because of incorrect settings in the Zūmo, causing it to avoid ferries or take the faster route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Have fun!&lt;/strong>
The most important thing of all this work is to have fun. No matter where Garmin sends you, remember that you're on your bike to have fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tweet Week</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 10:55:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/15/tweet-week/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/rolfje">&lt;img src="twitter-logo.png" alt="Twitter">
&lt;/a>About a week ago, I was a bit bored and decided to see what Twitter is all about. I created an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje">account&lt;/a>, and I Tweeted for a week. I tried to keep to the original idea, where a Tweet should answer the question &amp;quot;What are you doing&amp;quot;? Looking back, my tweets include &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1198486833">Coffee&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1199748992">Podcasts&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1200610213">Global frustration&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1203692363">Small joys&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1206502512">Small irritations&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209317512">Re-tweets&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rolfje/statuses/1209634779">Replies&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Twitter is a service were you can send short texts of 140 characters or less, called "tweets". These texts end up on a webpage, resulting in a micro-blog for all to read. Think of it as SMS-ing to your blog. One of the fun parts of Twitter is that people find really creative ways to express themselves in 140 characters or less. This allows you to follow an amazing amount of people, getting short messages about what they're doing, such as ["is relaxing with the wife and kids..... at home"](https://twitter.com/richard_hammond/statuses/1209417438)  or   ["Great meal at Michael Minna with my best gal"](https://twitter.com/ev/statuses/1211691640).
&lt;table border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["at"](afbeelding-1.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Should you find a "Tweet" you think is interesting, you can reply to that person (not to the tweet directly) by starting your tweet with an "@" and the username of the person you want to reply to. 
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >!["hash"](afbeelding-2.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >You can even "tag" your Tweets by using a "#" and a word. So for instance "#rolfje" would add the tag "rolfje" to my Tweet. You can then easily [search tweets with this tag](http://hashtags.org/tag/rolfje). Tags are sometimes used to create something of a "communications channel". For instance, the [#followfriday](http://hashtags.org/tag/followfriday) tag is used to tweet about people you think are worth following.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
Starting in the US, Twitter is becoming increasingly popular all over the world, now taking over Europe. [BBC had an item](http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/7287536.stm) on English television about twitter, massively increasing the number of English twitterers. 
&lt;p>And ofcourse, where there are people, there are money-sharks to spoil the fun. Some companies are showing up, and are clearly not understanding what Twitter is about. They start a twitter account and twitter promotional messages, product releases, etc. The problem with this (for the company) is that for this to be succesful, people must follow you. If there's nothing interesting to read, people will not follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This same problem occurs with people who have their staff update their twitter accounts. This makes for really uninteresting, unpersonal tweets, and replying to them will almost never result in a nice conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com">&lt;img src="http://laikaspoetnik.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/twitter-addicts.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**What I used:
**During my Tweetweek, I tried different OSX and iPhone clients. There are a lot of clients out there, but none of them are good enough to be your &amp;quot;single client of choice&amp;quot;. Here's what I think of them, in short:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl&lt;/a>: Done in Adobe AIR, multi-platform and consistent accross OS's. Good for a Windows app, terrible for an OSX app. Settings are in strange places, not clear what the &amp;quot;narrow&amp;quot; column mode is for. Ugly but probably the best twitter client out there, with twitpic and tinyurl integration all out of the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.tweetdeck.com/beta/">Tweetdeck&lt;/a>: Also done in Adobe AIR, mutli-platform and consistent. Works fine, has multiple columns for monitoring your tweets, search results and profiles. Feels a bit funny, for instance the same icon is used for &amp;quot;show input window&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;send tweet&amp;quot;. It works, but it doesn't fit the &amp;quot;clean and simple&amp;quot; design I think a twitter client needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific">Twitterific&lt;/a>: Nice design, clean. Not much features, too overpriced. If Twitterific had tinyURL and twitpic integration, and sold for about $5, it would be a huge hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=296415944&amp;amp;mt=8">Tweetie (iPhone)&lt;/a>: The funny thing is that &amp;quot;Tweetie&amp;quot;, the iPhone twitter client is way better than any of the clients I tried on a normal computer. Tweetie wins hands down. The best twitter client for the iPhone, simple and clean, camera integration, GPS integration. This also fits way better in the twitter philosophy, Tweeting whatever you are doing, wherever you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I learned:&lt;/strong>
Twitter is for everyday people, like you and me, and feels like a mix between &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens'_Band_Radio">CB radio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texting">texting&lt;/a>. Twitter is all about you and who you follow. It's definetely not about your followers. Ofcourse you can try to get as much followers as possible, but I think that does not guarantee a nice twitter experience. Some people think it's rude not to follow back if they're followed, and will tweet to let somebody know that they're being &amp;quot;un-followed&amp;quot;. I think that's not how the system is supposed to work. There's also no real relationship. Follow or unfollow, it's not like you're devorcing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just Tweet, and see what happens. There's no currency, only small text messages from people around the world for you to read and reply to. Or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmer Quotes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/12/19/programmer-quotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 19:45:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/12/19/programmer-quotes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>On StackOverflow, there is a question asking for the &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/58640?sort=votes#sort-top">greatest programmer quotes&lt;/a> you know. In the top 3 quotes are the following two quotes which I think hold much truth:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>_**"Always code as if the guy who ends up maintaining your code will be a violent psychopath who knows where you live."**_ - Rick Osborne&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>**_"Debugging is twice as hard as writing the code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it."_** - Brian Kernighan&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These two quotes are briliantly summing up the usual rant I always use. &amp;quot;if my phone rings at 3 a.m. for a prio 1 production issue, I want to be able to easily read the code. And I'm not going to be awake or cheerful at that time of night.&amp;quot; I guess at that time of night, it's easy to awaken the violent psychopath in me, and so it better not be &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; code. &lt;a href="http://stuvel.eu/archive/42/blame-support-in-eclipse">CVS blame support&lt;/a> anybody?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Helicopter to Master</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 20:41:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3362481">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3362481_59575b58bcabdbf0ca1207bdb4756665_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>A friend of mine and me ordered 2 Walkera 4#3B electric model helicopters 3 weeks ago. Last frinday, they finally arrived, and this weekend we had some good fun flying them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think flying a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/12/06/helicopter-fun/">PicooZ&lt;/a> is hard, don't even start thinking about one of these. It looks easier on the &lt;a href="http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=VbvD4OYOqt8">youtube video's&lt;/a> than it seems. I have some experience with RC models (mainly cars and boats), but flying this helicopter is really hard. I can not get it to hover steadily, I need some serious practice to tame this baby. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just took my camera out to shoot make some action shots of the heli's in the air, when one of them crashed so hard that the tail boom broke. We ordered some spare parts for both 'copters, they'll arrive somewhere next week. In the meantime you can check out some of the &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/album/3362467">photographs I made&lt;/a> of my Walkera on my desk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Norton Fixes it's Software</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/05/06/how-norton-fixes-its-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 20:30:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/05/06/how-norton-fixes-its-software/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As you may know, Norton and Symantec were originally rivals in the anti-virus software market. Then, Norton bought Symantec and the two anti-virus products merged into &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norton_AntiVirus">Norton Anti Virus&lt;/a>. Yes, I know, I'm talking PC here. Bare with me on this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->If you are the "you do something with computers, don't you?" free computer repair guy to a lot of people around you, you have probably uninstalled Norton Anti Virus Trial Edition from more than a few newly bought PC's. And it was painful. Admit it. I know. I've been there. Several times.
&lt;p>A few months ago I discovered that maybe Norton is fixing this. But strangely enough, not in their software. They're using the community to solve it. And no, it's not by open-sourcing it either. It's by buying user opinions. Yes, you've read that right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-1.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-1.png" alt="effectiveness of Norton Propaganda">
&lt;/a>Check out the screenshot. It's an &lt;a href="http://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome">Amazon's Mechanical Turk&lt;/a> &amp;quot;HIT&amp;quot; (Human Intelligence Task). Here, the requester asks people to post positive reviews of the Norton Anti Virus products as part of a French scientific research project. (no, it's not photoshopped)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Norton is not really the requester, and I am probably blowing this out of proportion. But next time you're on a forum, and people start telling you how wonderful Norton Antivirus is, stop and think for a minute. They might be getting payed to tell you this. Doesn't that feel awfully close to a mini-&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Propaganda">propaganda&lt;/a>? Yes, I know, this is not news. But this screenshot reminded me of how easily some people trust information on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Online forums are great for sharing information. I really like the internet, and hey, I wouldn't be blogging if I didn't, now would I? But for all you know, I could be an Apple execitive trying to &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/12/02/hidden-get-a-mac-ads/">get people to &lt;/a>buy an Apple computer. Or a Seagate employee trying to sell you a drive instead of &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/10/24/no-such-thing-harddisk-warranty/">repairing your old one&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/05/21/ichat-saves-the-day/">Bruce&lt;/a>. Maybe I'm &lt;a href="http://fakesteve.blogspot.com/">Steve&lt;/a>. Or maybe I'm just a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCwGDihDkmE">FireStarter&lt;/a> :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reboot...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/29/reboot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 21:05:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/29/reboot/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today the Mac OS Software update popped up, and warned that these updates would require a reboot (about 80% of the updates do not require a reboot). I have gotten so used to not having reboot and hangup troubles that I almost was surprised to see that I needed to reboot. I use my Mac mini for editting foto's, video, recording TV programs, streaming music, programming, mail, and the usual webbrowsing. It is so quiet and uses so little power that I only power off the screen, and leave the Mac on. I noticed that I have not turned it off for the past 20 days:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;rolf$ uptime
20:17 up 20 days, 23:37, 3 users, load averages: 0.20 0.26 0.20
&amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Not bad for a workstation eh? Glad I bought a Mac, it was worth every penny. The other Mac mini I bought to replace my fileserver is also still worth every penny.Just thought I'd share some of my newly acquired Zen with you...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where's North again?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2005/10/03/wheres-north-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2005 12:57:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2005/10/03/wheres-north-again/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Lately, I've been collecting race circuit locations using &lt;a href="http://earth.google.com/">Google Earth&lt;/a>. It's really nice to see the sometimes very detailed satelite images of race circuits. You can actually see the seperate kerbstone blocks of silverstone, and see how many cars there were parked at the time the picture was taken. You should try it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What really started to catch my interest is the fact that the maps of circuits as they are used in logo's or (worse) &amp;quot;how to get there&amp;quot;-maps are almost never of the &amp;quot;north pointing up&amp;quot; type. An example:
The circuit &amp;quot;Road America&amp;quot;, which is located a few miles north-east of Atlanta, Georgia, has a &lt;a href="http://www.roadatlanta.com/trackmap.lasso">web-site&lt;/a> which shows you a detailed map of the circuit, as well as pointers to the nearest highways. I have grabbed an image (because they only have these stupid noise making flash movie thingied nobody is interersted in after the second visit). It looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_road-atlanta.gif">&lt;img src="o_road-atlanta.gif" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in my quest to find this circuit using Google Earth, I found the circuit to be along the 53, halfway from the I85 to the I985, just like the directions stated. But, the circuit seemed to be &amp;quot;turned around:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_road-atlanta-google.gif">&lt;img src="o_road-atlanta-google.gif" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have noticed this with a lot of ciruits. I understand the need of turning and simplifying the circuit to make a nice logo, but when the circuit is depicted next to driving directions, I would make the map &amp;quot;north side up&amp;quot; so nobody gets confused. In the first image, the I85 apears to be west of the circuit, while it is actually east of the circuit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Earth location of Road America (so you can check for yourselves):&lt;/p>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
&lt;kml xmlns="http://earth.google.com/kml/2.0">
&lt;Document>
&lt;Style id="khStyle662">
&lt;IconStyle id="khIconStyle664">
&lt;Icon>
&lt;href>root://icons/palette-3.png&lt;/href>
&lt;x>224&lt;/x>
&lt;w>32&lt;/w>
&lt;h>32&lt;/h>
&lt;/Icon>
&lt;/IconStyle>
&lt;/Style>
&lt;Placemark>
&lt;name>Road Atlanta&lt;/name>
&lt;LookAt>
&lt;longitude>-83.81483349103033&lt;/longitude>
&lt;latitude>34.14598906888146&lt;/latitude>
&lt;range>2835.974155514713&lt;/range>
&lt;tilt>-8.888997363646108e-012&lt;/tilt>
&lt;heading>0.3186400317363279&lt;/heading>
&lt;/LookAt>
&lt;styleUrl>#khStyle662&lt;/styleUrl>
&lt;Point>
&lt;coordinates>-83.81483349103033,34.14598906888146,0&lt;/coordinates>
&lt;/Point>
&lt;/Placemark>
&lt;/Document>
&lt;/kml></description></item></channel></rss>