<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>environment on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/environment/</link><description>Recent content in environment on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading an ISKRA AM550 P1 Port with a Pi</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/01/18/reading-an-iskra-am550-p1-port-with-a-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/01/18/reading-an-iskra-am550-p1-port-with-a-pi/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;figure class="float_right">&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_meter">&lt;img src="iskra-am550-gprs-meter.jpg" width="120"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
Although I am the guy with a soldering iron and a bit of software development experience, I am not a fan of the &amp;quot;internet of things&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;smart meters&amp;quot; or smart anything really. Not because I don't like technology, but because of the potential security and privacy problems it brings with it. That said, because of some unfortunate events I now have a smart meter my home. So when life gives you lemons, you make Pi!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've got an &lt;a href="http://www.iskraemeco.com/en/portfolio/electricity-meters/residential-smart-meters/am550/">AM550 Smart meter&lt;/a> with a P1 port. Seeing all the online content and suggestions about reading your smart meter, I decided to have an hour of fun trying to read the P1 data. Here's how I did it:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>The P1 port on the AM550 sends serial data, but the signal is inverted. It is possible to invert that in software, but it is a kludge that requires some &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bit_banging">bit banging&lt;/a>. Bringing the data in the right polarity and connecting it to the Rx serial input on the GPIO port is the cheapest and fastest way to go if you happen to have an RJ11 connenctor, a PNP transistor and a few resistors lying around. Here are my notes on how I wired the P1 to the Raspberry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schematic-am550.jpg">&lt;img src="schematic-am550.jpg?w=450" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that was left is reading the data from the serial port. Pin 10 maps to GPIO15 and happens to also be the Rx pin on the Raspberry Pi's internal Serial adapter, which is available as a device at /dev/ttyAMA0 (I did not choose this pin by accident ;-). I wrote a simple Python script to read the serial port so I could change it to produce munin graphs later:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span class="ln"> 1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="kn">import&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nn">serial&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 2&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">ser&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">(&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 3&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">port&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s1">&amp;#39;/dev/ttyAMA0&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 4&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">baudrate&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="mi">115200&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 5&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">parity&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">PARITY_NONE&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 6&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">stopbits&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">STOPBITS_ONE&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 7&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">bytesize&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">EIGHTBITS&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 8&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">timeout&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="mi">1&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 9&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">)&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">10&lt;/span>&lt;span class="k">while&lt;/span> &lt;span class="kc">True&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">11&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nb">print&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">ser&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">readline&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">()&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>When running this program, you should see a whole blob of text scroll by about every second or so. It is readable ASCII and can be parsed by many libraries out there. I tried a few but they were sometimes buggy, or sometimes overengineered and requiring a lot of external resources. So I wrote my own, very crude, parsing. It is not like the meter will be updated every week with new software and ssl certificates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are actually only a few lines in the output that interest me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.7&lt;/strong> contain the current power usage in Watts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.8.1&lt;/strong> are the T1 (low tariff) meter reading in Watt-hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.8.2&lt;/strong> are the T2 (high tariff) meter reading in Watt-hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A few lines of additional python gave me three separate munin plugins to produce the graphs I wanted. Here is a nice one showing the power usage of last week, split between high and low tariff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="smartmeter_totals_am550-week.png">&lt;img src="smartmeter_totals_am550-week.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This nice graph also shows one of the problems with smart meters: Given enough resolution, you can see at which times devices and lights are switched on. This can provide some interesting patterns, and enables anybody with access to your meter data to determine when you are home or on vacation. Of course there are some tricks to create constant or confusing usage patterns, I'm sure you'll come up with something smart now that you can see the graphs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find all three munin plugins in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/realrolfje/munin-plugins">munin-plugin repository&lt;/a>, in the &amp;quot;plugin&amp;quot; folder. There may also be other interesting stuff there for you munin enthausiasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pan Rant</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 13:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQu5Unc_TNY">&lt;img src="de-buyer-26cm-carbon-steel-mineral-frying-pan-11546-0-1315069074000.jpeg" alt="">
&lt;/a>You may have seen recent tweets from me ranting about my frying pans. I've ruined a few (very expensive) pans and replaced them with dirt-cheap pans which are actually much better. I would like to share my experiences and solutions with you, so that you can buy the right (cheap) pan without having to go through the same thing. Links to all the pans are in the article below.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->In my household, I try to avoid PTFE (Teflon) coated pans as much as I can. In normal consumer stores, it is almost impossible to find good PTFE-free pans. A few years ago I found two [Calphalon pans](http://www.calphalon.com/pages/home.aspx), a small 20cm frying pan of around €90,- (yes you've read that correctly) and a 30cm frying pan of €140,- (yes, you've read that correctly too). I convinced the store owner that this was rather expensive for two pans so he "let me have them" for "just" €200,- These pans are made of hard anodized aluminum, are scratch resistant and have have pretty good non-stick properties.
&lt;p>After a few years, the large Calphalon pan started to show some black stains on the rim, and I wanted to clean those. I regularly clean the pans with abrasive sponges, but this black stuff wouldn't come off. In a strange (and stupid) last effort to clean it, I sprayed the large pan with oven cleaner. The aluminum started oxidizing, and the pan was ruined. I was pretty upset, but luckily I did it with just one pan (albeit the most expensive one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3113.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Off to the store I went, but this time with a smaller budget. I bought a nice and shiny polished aluminum BK frying pan for €30,- . I used it for a few days and very quickly the pan had some brown spots on the rim of the pan. Being polished aluminum, I could not use abrasive sponges here. So I tried all kinds of tricks from this &lt;a href="http://www.omaweetraad.com/">&amp;quot;grandma's advice&amp;quot; website&lt;/a> without the desired results. The last tip I tried was to kook some washing detergent in it, which should dissolve the brown grease. It did not. Instead, it &lt;a href="img_3135.jpg">ruined the pan completely&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frustrated by the fact that nobody in the world (or at least on &amp;quot;the internets&amp;quot;) seemed to have pan cleaning problems or answers, I started looking for different alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some googling shows that most professional restaurants use rolled steel pans, without any coating. Just plain steel. This is actually pretty funny, when you think about the expensive Teflon and Ceramic coated pans in the stores for well over €30,- while professional cooks use steel pans of around €20,- which survive many years of heavy use and actually become better and better over time. Professional cooks mostly use gas as heat source, but steel pans can be used on &lt;em>any&lt;/em> heat source, even on induction stoves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I already have a rolled steel wok, and am very happy with that, so I decided to get a rolled steel &amp;quot;De Buyer&amp;quot; frying pan at &lt;a href="http://www.kookman.nl/nl/pannen/plaatstaal.html?page=shop.product_details&amp;amp;flypage=flypage.tpl&amp;amp;product_id=991&amp;amp;category_id=28">kookman.nl&lt;/a>. I ordered it on a Saturday, and on Sunday they mailed me that didn't have the 26cm pan and offered to send me the 30cm for the same price. That sounded like a good deal so that's what I received on my doorstep on Tuesday. Very good service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before doing any cooking, you have to prepare the pan in order to keep the meat from sticking to the steel. This is called &amp;quot;seasoning the pan&amp;quot; and is really easy to do: Heat the pan, then add oil, and fry some salt in it. There are different methods but salt blackens the pan quicker, I like that. The good thing about a steel pan is that if you screw it up, you can practically sand it down with your abrasive sponge and try again. and again. and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3347.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3347.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Here you see my de Buyer pan after seasoning and a few evenings of cooking. This is how your clean pan should look. Washing a non-coated steel pan is generally done without detergent, under extremely hot water with a brush. This keeps the dark &amp;quot;nonstick coating&amp;quot; in the pan. The pans will become darker upon use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you leave the pan dirty overnight, the grease will sometimes come off, or it will start to rust. Don't worry, scrub it and re-season it and you have a new pan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My new steel frying pan will probably outlast me and my kids. And if I can keep the small Calphalon pan away from the oven cleaner, it may do the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="imgres-1.jpeg" alt="">
So that's the pan story. But I hear you ask &amp;quot;Why all this trouble? Why not buy a Teflon pan?&amp;quot; Here's why: I don't trust it to be healthy. Teflon is one of the scariest polymers out there, and anybody knows how Teflon coating degrades, leaving little pieces of Teflon in your food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you search around for the chemical properties of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polytetrafluoroethylene">Teflon&lt;/a>, you will find some interesting facts. Meat is usually fried between 200 and 230 °C. The thermochemical decomposition of PTFE (Teflon) is detectable at 200 °C. If you ever wondered why your canary died early, the degradation by-products can be &lt;a href="http://www.bartcop.com/dead-canary.gif">lethal to birds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfluorooctanoic_acid">PFOA&lt;/a> is used in the production process of PTFE coated pans to reduce surface tension. Tests with PFOA on laboratory animals showed increased risk of cancer. Recently higher serum levels of PFOA were found to be associated with increased risk of chronic kidney disease in the general United States population. This is consistent with earlier animal studies. It is also recently &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/07/13/us-teflon-component-linked-to-arthritis-idUSTRE76C3WR20110713">linked to Arthritis&lt;/a>. PFOA is a carcinogen, liver toxicant, a developmental toxicant, an immune system toxicant, and also exerts hormonal effects including alteration of thyroid hormone levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, several manufacturers have started selling pans with ceramic coatings and put &amp;quot;PTFE Free&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;PFOA Free&amp;quot; labels on these pans. Why do you think they did that? Maybe it's because PTFE and PFOA aren't all that healthy after all. And apart from the coating in your pan, the production process of PTFE and PFOA is very, very bad for the environment. &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/manufacturing/2005-07-19-teflon_x.htm">Ask Dupont&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it turns out, if you know how to treat a pan, &lt;strong>the best coating is no coating at all&lt;/strong>. It's not only healthier and better for the environment, but top chefs will tell you it actually makes your food taste better. Next time you are in an expensive restaurant, ask what pans they use. You'd be surprised.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catnip Watering System</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/04/catnip-watering-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 20:04:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/04/catnip-watering-system/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Here's a one minute how-to on growing catnip without having to water your plants every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6jyqNzNeQeE]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem Solving for Dummies</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/07/15/problem-solving-for-dummies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 20:12:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/07/15/problem-solving-for-dummies/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Some people can not seperate cause and effect when solving problems, and every now and then you run into a great example.&lt;/p>
&lt;table align="center" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >If this is your problem...
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >this is not your solution
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Some people are still trying here...](img_8018.jpg?w=200)
](img_8018.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[!["It is not allowed to throw paper towels into the toilet."](img_7048.jpg)
](img_7048.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
The towel bin is next to the sink. Why would anyone walk all the way back to the toilet to throw their paper towel in there? Well maybe it's because they have nowhere to put it? There is a simple solution to solving problems with other people's behavior, without having to put up signs and making up silly rules:
&lt;h2 id="make-the-right-thing-to-do">Make the right thing to do&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="the-easy-thing-to-do">the easy thing to do.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>spacing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Growth is a bad thing. Bad.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/05/17/why-growth-is-a-bad-thing-bad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/05/17/why-growth-is-a-bad-thing-bad/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="petri-dish.jpg" alt="">
Quite often I am amazed at people's ability to miss what looks obvious to me. Not only the small things like cleaning up when you spill coffee over the floor, or washing your hands when you get off the toilet, but also bigger things. Like the silly &amp;quot;solutions&amp;quot; to the world's pollution problem for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking to solve our pollution problem by changing people's behavior is one of the things which to me is obvious to fail. Although some behavior may speed up pollution, in the end we all pollute, wether we like it or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the risk of writing a very unpopular blogpost, I'd like to share some thoughts on the ongoing and ever increasing pollution problem. In my eyes, there are 2 real causes of pollution, and ultimately these causes are even self-repairing although you may not like how that works out for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->Growth&lt;/strong>
If you've watched &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_Way_Round">&amp;quot;The Long Way Round&amp;quot;&lt;/a> you've noticed that farmers in Mongolia have nothing but their animals and the land they live on. To them, there is a natural balance between people and nature. Having more of one thing (regardless which) disturbs the balance of things and renders pretty immediate problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the &amp;quot;modern world&amp;quot; this balance is less obvious, and the urge to &amp;quot;want&amp;quot; something is not naturally stopped. People always to want have more. Bigger house, bigger car, more money, more kids. It is the constant urge for a &amp;quot;better life&amp;quot;. This urge, combined with the unimaginable stupidity of people in large groups have lead to a system which is based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot;. If you don't believe me, stare at the &lt;a href="http://www.worldometers.info/">worldometers web site&lt;/a> for a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any rational thinking person must see that endless growth results in an infinitely large system. Since the earth has a fixed size, any system based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; is bound to hit the limits of what is physically possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Waste production&lt;/strong>
Every living thing on this planet produces waste. This can be in the form of breathing out co2, or taking a dump behind a tree. Nature has a way to deal with this. Waste is decomposed, and therefore part of the system. In fact, everything on this earth is part of &amp;quot;the system&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to Merriam-Webster's online dictionary, &amp;quot;pollution&amp;quot; is &lt;em>&amp;quot;the action of polluting especially by environmental contamination with man-made waste&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Oversimplified and on a (very) large scale, we can not produce stuff that's not here. Everything is synthesized in some way from existing materials. In my mind, &amp;quot;pollution&amp;quot; is just &amp;quot;waste with a longer recycle time&amp;quot;. Even &lt;a href="http://www.mnn.com/technology/research-innovations/blogs/boy-discovers-microbe-that-eats-plastic">plastic eventually breaks down&lt;/a> and re-enters the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oil">Wikipedia&lt;/a>, oils are &lt;em>&amp;quot;classified as mineral oils because they do not have an organic origin on human timescales&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. So what it says is that Oil is in fact a natural product, but because it took so freakin' long to become oil, we don't recognize it as a natural product. What it says to me is, if we are able to find the balance, we may be able to keep using oil, as long as it's in the same rate as it is reproduced. Mind you, that's an incredibly slow rate, to &amp;quot;human timescales&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to keep the earth as &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot; as it is now, we can introduce the following rule of thumb:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>n x p = r&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>where:
n = number of people on the planet
p = pollution per person per month
r = Earth's natural pollution recycle rate, per month (constant)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>So, if you want to have twice the people, you need to pollute half as much, on average, because the earth's natural recycle rate is fixed. I'm sure this formula is nowhere near a realistic model, but it shows that both increasing consumption and increasing the world's population is not going to work out in the long run. Even if  everybody &amp;quot;sees the light&amp;quot;, becomes an environmentalist, stops driving cars, and cuts down on consumption in general, we can't continue to endlessly grow our population.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Spot the Similarities&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Extrapolated_world_population_history.png">&lt;img src="extrapolated_world_population_history1.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>So now we understand that this &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; system is resulting/has resulted in too many people on this planet, producing too much long lasting waste at a high rate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, it get's scarier. Let's look at the growth rate of the human population on this planet. Several graphs, including this one from wikipedia, will show relatively slow population growth until the 1920's. Between 1920 and 2000 we see exponential growth. After that, it is expected that the growth will decline into a more &amp;quot;stationary&amp;quot; phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm now where did we see that before? Remember biology class, particularly the lessons about bacterial growth ? In this next graph, you can see the different phases of bacterial growth, resulting in certain death of the complete population, due to the depletion of resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://onlinebiologybook.blogspot.com/2009/01/microorganism-exam-1.html">&lt;img src="06-14_bacteriagrowth_11.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Guess what we're doing? By getting more and more kids, our population &amp;quot;eats&amp;quot; all the natural resources at a rate at which the earth can not match. It can not produce enough new resources to maintain the population, effectively resulting in a petri dish which also doesn't &amp;quot;replenish&amp;quot; it's resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Again, this painfully demonstrates that any system based on &amp;quot;Growth&amp;quot; is a system doomed to fail. Having kids to support your pension might seem like a good idea, but essentially you're sacrificing the life of your kids (or theirs) for your comfortable retirement days. In my (unpopular) opinion, the only (and I mean &lt;em>only&lt;/em>) way to reduce the whole pollution and economic problems is to have less people on this world. Much, much less. In fact, we would see quicker results if particularly modern &amp;quot;western&amp;quot; people shrunk in numbers first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Unpopular measures are... unpopular
As mentioned before, people are loosing the ability to stop giving in to any urge they get. One of these urges (albeit strongly driven by nature itself) is having kids.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please understand that I have nothing against kids, in fact I'm a grandfather myself. It's just that I think it's funny that we actively encourage having kids, while at the same time recognizing that people are the very cause of all these environmental problems in the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We continue to stick our heads in the sand and talk about &lt;em>&lt;em>cough&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Co2 neutral flying&amp;quot;, &lt;em>&lt;em>rhrmhhhrrm&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Bio degradable rubber&amp;quot; and last but not least, the hilarious &lt;em>&lt;em>COUGHcoughcough&lt;/em>&lt;/em> &amp;quot;Renewable energy&amp;quot;. What we should really think about is how to at least stop the world population from growing. This may result in imposing all kinds of unpopular/impossible worldwide measures I don't care to get into right now, but killing is of course not one of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since no politician is going to win voters by saying that he wants the whole country to be celibate (or worse), I realize that this will probably never happen, at least not in my lifetime.  The good thing is that our weak minds aren't forced to make these choices, because the system will make the choice for us. Just like the petri dish does for bacteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I'm not the most environmental friendly freak you'd encounter, maybe even far from that with my motorcycle, car, computers, and airconditioner. My point is actually that we probably can keep enjoying a lot, if not all of these things, if we just stop putting more and more people on this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe I can best put it like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;If you love kids, stop having them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Please note that nothing in this post is meant to be personal or offensive to anybody in any way. It's just a silly blogpost in which I think aloud. Use it as food for thought, or discard it, but don't let it spoil your day. Don't worry, I don't have the power to control my kids, or even my cat, let alone the world. I have no intentions to becoming a politician.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Give me spots on my Apples</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 20:43:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_ilove-apple-green.jpg">&lt;img src="o_ilove-apple-green.thumbnail.jpg" alt="I love my Apple">
&lt;/a>Lately Greenpeace has started a &lt;a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/apple/">campaign&lt;/a> against the usage of hazardous materials by Apple. The campain setup is friendly, nicely designed and urges Apple to choose materials which are less hazadous to the environment.As a spinoff of the Greenpeace campain all kinds of so called &amp;quot;journalists&amp;quot; have begun to put Apple on the &amp;quot;wrong end of the scale&amp;quot; of their &amp;quot;environment-o-meter&amp;quot;, and are happily writing doom articles about what will happen to your Karma if you buy any Apple product. But how environmentally unfriedly are Apple's computers really?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let's say you believe the hype, and avoid Apple like the plague because of it's [environmentally unfriendly plastics](http://www.apple.com/hotnews/agreenerapple/), it's [huge pricetag](http://kurafire.net/log/archive/2006/04/25/debunking-the-price-myth-apple-vs-dell) and the risk of becomming a brainwashed [cult member](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cult_%28religious_practice%29) worshipping Apple for te rest of your life.
&lt;p>So you buy a &lt;a href="http://www.shivaranjan.com/shivaupload/trashcanpc/musor_02.jpg">shiny new $800 PC&lt;/a> to run Vista, with that new 8 zillion transistor processor, dual &amp;quot;Energy Star&amp;quot; power supply and an &amp;quot;Energy Star&amp;quot; screen. When you turn the computer on, it starts to warm up your room with the 80 Watts it's consuming. When you really put it through it's paces, it consumes up to 150 Watts, or more if you bought that superduper video card which is more of an &amp;quot;audio card&amp;quot; when the fan starts blowing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a year of happy computing, your computer bogs down under the weight of all the &amp;quot;uninstalled&amp;quot; programs still on your drive. Vista 2 is released, and requires this all new Chipset to run, so you decide to buy a new PC. You give your old PC to your nephew, who totally turns it into an expensive $100 paper weight in 5 months, and it ends up in the trash because it can not be sold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously your new PC is way cooler than your old one, so it runs way hotter and uses more enery than ever. So there you are. Lot's of money spent, lot's of energy wasted, and lots of plastic in the environment, all in under a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your mother is also in the market for a new computer to read your emails and watch your photographs. You try to push her into buying a &lt;a href="http://www.theage.com.au/articles/2003/08/25/1061663718447.html">&amp;quot;man's computer&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, but before you know it she falls for the slick designs and smoothtalk sales at the Apple store. She buys an &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/imac/">iMac&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She installs the heidonous toxic pastic bomb in her living room because &amp;quot;it looks lovely&amp;quot;. You put on your ear protection to turn it on, but your mother warns you that is already up and running. Yes that's right, you can't hear an Apple when it's on (and that goes for the fruit aswell). You don't believe her, and measure the &lt;a href="http://www.eworld.com/environment/energyefficiency/">power consumption&lt;/a>, which is less than half of the power of your PC, at comparabe system load. And the iMac has a built in screen to that, as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your mother uses the iMac for a year, and you stop by for your yearly 15 minute &amp;quot;tea-and-bisquits-with-mom&amp;quot; session only to discover that the iMac is still running as fast as last year, and is looking just as good as it did when it came out of the box. In fact, the next 2 yearly visits are the same. The iMac does not deteriorate, and judging by eBay, it holds it's value much longer than the average PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each next version of the operating system hapilly runs on the &amp;quot;old hardware&amp;quot;, so your mother does not need to upgrade her hardware each time a new OS is released, apart from not needing to switch to the new OS anyway because it just works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having read all this, let's see how PCs and Macs compare:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;p>PC
Mac&lt;/p>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Life expectancy:
&lt;td valign="top" >1 year.
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >2 to 3 years.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
End of life:
&lt;td valign="top" >Ends up as worthless trash or power-gulping server.
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Gets sold to a happy new user for a good price.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Power usage:
&lt;td valign="top" >More than 100 Watts (Pentium 4 PC without screen).
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Less than 50 Watts (Intel Core Duo Mac Mini without screen).
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
So which one is environmentally unfriendly I ask you? There are way more environmentally unfriendly PCs in the world, which use more energy and end up in the trash more often. I still remember how my electricity bill changed when I switched from PC to Mac, and how it is still running smoothly today.
&lt;p>Just a thought...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soybean racer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The big car manufacturers could have done &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2006/02/17/eveningnews/main1329941.shtml">this&lt;/a>, but they didn't, because they are sponsored by the big oil companies. And your local governement is swimming in taxmoney that's added to your oil price. And no, they don't want to get rid of the cars, despite of what they say. The nicest thing for governements would be the complete population sitting in single-seated, gas guzzling cars in a traffic jam accross the country!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that a few school kids have proven that you don't need oil to race, and several American race series run on methanol (no that's not an oil product), can we please stop making cars that run on gasoline? And by the way, also stop pumping money into the super-dangerous liquid nitrogen cars? All that is purely to keep the oil companies in the same place: monopoly. Do you really think they do it for the environment? What if I told you that your current petrol car can run on bio-degradable methanol, with almost no changes? If you have a very modern car, the fuel system will even auto-adapt! But noooo, they won't tell you that, because the oil companies and governements want to keep the monopoly intact!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not that you can really do anything about it though. Except maybe not buying liquid-nitrogen or hybrid cars. There are better technical alternatives, although not on the market yet. Boycot the &amp;quot;environmentally friendly&amp;quot; car, force them into making a &lt;em>real&lt;/em> environmentally friendly car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I'm driving a diesel, and a motorbike. And no, I'm not worried about oil-shortage. It's all bullshit from the oil companies, who could have come up with alternatives a long while ago, but chose not to. If there really was an oil shortage, we all would have been driving on methanol for quite some time now. And co2 emmisions would have been reduced to absolutely 0.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>