<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dakar on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/dakar/</link><description>Recent content in Dakar on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 20:45:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/dakar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dakar, 369 days to go...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/05/dakar-369-days-to-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 20:45:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/05/dakar-369-days-to-go/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The organization of the Dakar rally has cancelled the rally because some idiots are planning terrorist attacks. Instead of doing a partial rally, or a couple of stages around Lissabon, the complete rally is cancelled. I really think this is unacceptable for all riders, sponsors and TV stations depending on this rally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the time and money people have put into making it to Dakar is wasted. Next year it will be harder to get sponsors for the rally, because the sponsors will not risk investing large amounts of money in a rally which &amp;quot;may or may not&amp;quot; start. All those private riders which loaned money from the bank will have a hard time returning next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although not nearly as bad as for the competitors, this means a lousy start of 2008 for me and a lot of Dakar fans eagerly waiting the start of the rally, which was scheduled tommorow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dakar 2008, 4 days to go.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/01/dakar-2008-4-days-to-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 01:50:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/01/dakar-2008-4-days-to-go/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Only 4 days until the biggest and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dakar_Rally">toughest rally in the world&lt;/a> starts in Lisboa. After 2 weeks, on the 20th of Januari, the bikes will finish their trip in Dakar (oh yes, and there will be some cars too, and some uninteresting truckers). The number to keep an eye on (again) this year is bike 041. It's &lt;a href="http://www.dakarsport.com/index.php?quicklink=teams&amp;amp;teamID=11">Miriam Pol&lt;/a>, who is planning on finishing high in the bikes classification.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![Dakar 2008 Schedule, thanks to DakarSport.com](route2008schema.thumbnail.jpg)
&lt;p>](route2008schema.jpg)People who think that trucks are the best, you probably want to stop reading here. Still reading? I will explain why I think bikes are the absolute real rally competitors (yes, your opinion may differ. Start your own blog. Bye).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Trucks&lt;/strong> are the fastest brute-force machines on the track, and the drivers will push other competitors aside. Inside the trucks, 5 people are &lt;a href="http://gallery.zoom.nl/image/714390/mister-dakar.html">smoking cigarettes&lt;/a> and sipping coffee while bumping cars off the road at 200km/h on a small sandy road. They arrive at the stops first, have a beer and a good night's sleep, and leave the next morning to shove some more dust in the eyes of other competitors. When interviewed,these &amp;quot;men&amp;quot; will complain about branches, sand, other competirors, the food, the tires, and their &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_underwear">longjohns&lt;/a> being too tight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cars&lt;/strong>, the largest group of competitors, are second-fastest on the track, and often have nice fights for position. There are always &lt;a href="http://gallery.zoom.nl/image/579212/masuoka-san-ii.html">2 people in a car&lt;/a>, one navigator and one driver. They work together when digging out their car out of the sand dunes, and solve technical problems. High speeds and great driving skills make cars nice to look at for about 5 minutes, I really enjoyed &lt;a href="http://gallery.zoom.nl/image/642034/robby-gordon---dakar-2007.html">Robbie Gordon&lt;/a>'s &lt;a href="http://gallery.zoom.nl/image/642035/html/">Hummer&lt;/a> last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.thumbnail.png" alt="Mirjam Pol During Shamrock Rally 2007, Marokko">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>Bikes&lt;/strong> are probably the smallest group of competitors. These are in my eyes the only real competitors. They ride their bikes 800km a day through the &lt;a href="dsc_1649.jpg">desert&lt;/a>, 15 hours straight at a time. All roadbook preperations, &lt;a href="http://gallery.zoom.nl/image/667416/html/">riding&lt;/a>, navigating and repairs during the tests are done by themselves. When they arrive late at night, they have to prepare the roadbook for the next day, and catch a few hours of sleep. The next morning, they are the earliest starters, returning to the desert with nothing more than their bikes, water, and candybars to eat. During the day, the bikes are passed by cars, and dumbass maniac truckdrivers often making the bikes tip over and leaving them in a ditch besides the road (if not worse).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bike on the right is this year's outfit of Mirjam. Purple bike, and the ever Orange Helmet. Go Mirjam!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>