<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ipod on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/ipod/</link><description>Recent content in ipod on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 23:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/ipod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bill Gates works at Apple</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 23:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.jpg?w=150" alt="Steve Jobs">
&lt;/a>I was happy to see Steve return on the Apple keynote of 9 September, because boy does Apple need somebody with clear vision. The introductions on the new iPod line are all over the place. Let me tell you why I think Steve has not been running the operation for the past few months:&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * **Ringtones.** The price of a ringtone in the iTunes store is (still) higher than that of a song. You can make a ring tone out of a song [for free](http://www.wired.com/software/coolapps/news/2007/09/ringtone_hacks) already, so why put the effort into selling ringtones at a way too high price? The phone companies must have influenced some &amp;quot;less sturdy&amp;quot; people at Apple for this.
* **The Nano Camera.** 2 mistakes on this one. First is the device. Why put a camera on the Nano of all iPods? Wouldn't we expect that on the iPod touch? Or perhaps both? Second is the location. Anybody holding a nano must notice that the camera is in a place where your hand is when holding the nano. Maybe it makes a bit more sense in landscape mode, right after you smudged it with your hand. Maybe I'd have to hold one for good testing. I heard that the camera is not nearly as good as the one on the iPhone 3Gs.
* **iTunes 9's Column Browser.** When I installed iTunes 9, my trusty 3-pane music browser was gone. I had a list of artists on the left, and next to that all my music as a long list of unsorted tracks. Gee thanks. After some fiddling I got the 3-paned browser back (see my [earlier blogpost](http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/)) but the fiddling in the menus got me that &amp;quot;Windows&amp;quot; feeling of tweaking a crappy UI into something I can sort of use.
* **Genius Mixes.** After seeing the keynote, I was eager to try out the &amp;quot;Genius Mixes&amp;quot; feature. In the keynote, these mixes are available under the Genius item on the left. When I looked, there was nothing there. I searched preferences and menus to turn them on, but found nothing. It turns out that you need to upload Genius data to Apple before the Genius Mixes appear. The mixes themselves are working fine, but when a Genius Mix is playing, you can do nothing. No coverflow. No Track details. I can not even rate the currently playing song. This cripples it's potential of finding and rating great songs in a large library.
* **Syncing knobs and levers.** Where syncing used to be simple, it is now 9 tabs with a slew of boxes and sliders you can drag suff between. I know a lot of customers asked for it, but that has never stopped Apple coming up with a totally brilliant solution to a problem, instead of just implementing the user's crappy first thought. I will get used to it, and it will probably work fine, but it just adds to a scary feeling I had of an Apple without Steve.
* **Twitter integration.** Come on Apple, you are not serious now, are you? There are hundreds of Twitter and IM integration apps that will do something like this. Apple did not even add that &amp;quot;innovative cool juice&amp;quot; to it. They just messed up iTunes codebase with this quick hack, making it even harder to port iTunes to 64 bit Cocoa.
* &amp;quot;**Richer&amp;quot; LP content.** I hate the iTunes appstore pages where developers are using way more CSS and markup than you would like to. It's like the walls of the grocery store change each time you look at a different product. It's confusing and ugly. Now, with the LP stuff added, Apple now is going one step further, and starts selling this for a price. Just like the ringtones.
* **Incoherent iPod touch line.** The 8GB iPod touch is sold at $199, which is great, but it was not &amp;quot;revved&amp;quot;, meaning that the 16+GB iPod touches have a different chipset. How do you explain the customer that a game is running slower on one touch, and faster on the other? Sure it's done to get to the $199 price point, but Apple didn't work like this in the old days. They used to introduce a new (revved) model at the same pricepoint.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The whole talk feels a bit &amp;quot;all over the place&amp;quot;, and a way of charging customers for something they do not really need. I know, usually keynotes get the &amp;quot;woos&amp;quot; from the cround every 15 seconds and it's hard to do that time and time again. And Steve just returned, having to sell the stuff he may not have wanted to put out there in the first place. So I'll forgive them this time. But this fan boy will be watching Apple and hope it will be a bit more consistent next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-4.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.jpg" alt="Jeff? Or Bill?">
&lt;/a>So Steve, get those guys back on track will you? And you might want to do an extra surprise round in the office, because I smell &amp;quot;feature creep&amp;quot;. And is it me, or does Jeff Robin's profile  look like a younger Bill Gates?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm. I hope he doesn't try that silly &lt;a href="http://www.pencomputing.com/frames/tablet_pc.html">tablet-thing&lt;/a> again...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rip and Convert FLAC, M4A, MP3, AAC files</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&lt;img src="afbeelding-8.png" alt="Max Audio Transcoder">
&lt;/a>I recently found an old harddisk which used to be in one of my old PC's. I discovered some &lt;a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">FLAC&lt;/a> files on there, which were rips of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOU8GIRUd_g">old CD's&lt;/a> I used to have. iTunes is not too happy with importing them into my library, and the original CD's are in a box in a deep dark corner of my garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I searched for a converter and found this wonderful converter which can just about convert any audio format out there. It's called &lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&amp;quot;Max&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, it's Open Source, free to use, and available as bundled OSX application. Brilliant! It does have a bunch of options, but as long as you go for the &amp;quot;MP4 Audio&amp;quot; output format, high quiality, 256 bits and VBR, you can't go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to their website &lt;em>&amp;quot;Max can generate audio in over 20 compressed and uncompressed formats including MP3, Ogg Vorbis, FLAC, AAC, Apple Lossless, Monkey's Audio, WavPack, Speex, AIFF, and WAVE&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy transcoding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't buy: Belkin TuneCast II</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/05/23/dont-buy-belkin-tunecast-ii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/05/23/dont-buy-belkin-tunecast-ii/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="341843_rb_00_fbeps.jpg">&lt;img src="341843_rb_00_fbeps.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>I am in the market for a new car. That means I'm in the market for a new car stereo. I decided that the iPod is a far better way to listen to my music in stead of keeping CD's in the car or listening to the 10.000 crappy FM stations in the Netherlands. Since &lt;a href="http://www.dension.com/icelinkgateway500.php">Dension&lt;/a> does not make a cable for my new car, I decided to go for an FM transmitter. Buying the cheap Belkin TuneCast II FM transmitter, I got even less then what I payed for.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->It looks promising from the package, but it was really a big waste of money. When operated using the included AAA batteries, I get no reception at all. Only when using the 12V car adapter the power output slightly increased and I was able to get the car radio to pick up the TuneCast signal, but only with very much static noise.
&lt;p>I took it out of the car to make sure the problem was not my car radio. At home, I put the TuneCast on top of the home stereo (only 4 cm away from the antenna). It was still very hard to get a signal at all, and I have never got it working without any static noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to the manual, the iPod should be set to a moderate volume, and once connected the TuneCast will automatically switch on. In my case, I had to turn the volume of the iPod all the way to 100% before the TuneCast switched on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I spent 20 minutes of fiddling and finding a free frequency (the Netherlands is crowded with radio signals), I noticed that the output volume of the TuneCast is also very low. In the car, I need to crank up the volume to 100% on my car radio to get a normal listening level. This means that if I switch stations by accident, I can possibly blow up my speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My conclusion is: the TuneCast II does not do what it promises. It's output power is way too low, even on 12V car power, it needs high volume input and produces low volume output with a lot of static noise, even when being VERY close to the reciever antenna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DO NOT BUY THE BELKIN TUNECAST II&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Edit:&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_9511.jpg">&lt;img src="img_9511.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>After typing this post I decided to try to get more signal out of the Tunecast. It did not work, but I did find out which terminals to use when trying to get signal from the tunecast. Maybe you can wire it straight into your radio or something. I'm not planning on doing that, but here are some pictures of the mods I tried to do. It might get you started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Opening the TuneCast II is really simple, there is 1 screw underneath the &amp;quot;QC&amp;quot; sticker in the battery compartment. Take it out. Pry the two halves of the tunecast loose they are interlocked with small plastic pins, nothing you can break easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_9512.jpg">&lt;img src="img_9512.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Once opened, you can remove another screw to take out the printed circuit board. On the front side of the circuit boart you'll notice the wires going to the earphone plug. The antenna of the Tunecast is incorprated in the (rather short) earphone cable. In my case this was the blue wire (also marked with &amp;quot;ANT&amp;quot;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_9513.jpg">&lt;img src="img_9513.jpg?w=114" alt="">
&lt;/a>If you flip over the PCB, you can see a few testing points. Two of these can be used to attach a small dipole antenna. TP9 is ground, and TP8 is the antenna output. I tried making a &lt;a href="http://www.electronics-radio.com/articles/radio/antennas/dipole/fm-dipole-antenna.php">small dipole&lt;/a>, but transmision power was not increased enough to get a clear signal to my radio (still 4cm away from the radio). I think the output power can be routed into an FM amplifier so the whole neighbourhood can listen to your station, but for me that's not an option since I was looking for a simple and small device to listen to my iPod in the car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_9518.jpg">&lt;img src="img_9518.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Another interesting tip: I noticed that the &amp;quot;backlight&amp;quot; is really not a backlight, but 2 green leds mounted somewhere near the LCD. If you'd like to get slightly more light onto the LCD, you can try to paint the inside of the casing using white matt paint (like shown).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok that's it, I'm throwing mine in the garbage can and will start looking for something else. I hope you enjoyed this €25,- blog post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Headphone search</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week I've been complaining about the capped volume on the iPod nano and the inability to circumvent it. At the end of that very week, the iPod earbuds solved the problem for me by breaking down. The rubber rings started comming off, and the right speaker produced only 10% of the sound the left speaker was producing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided that this was enough reason to go looking for a nice set of in-ear headphones (earbuds) which would sound nice, and also improve on produced volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8110.jpg">&lt;!-- more -->&lt;img src="img_8110.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Apple ear-buds">
&lt;/a>After reading some reviews on in-ear headphones ranging from €40,- to €140,- I decided on the Apple in-ear headphones. Judging from reviews, these should compare to Sony Fontopia's, seal of surrounding noise and produce more sound. I payed the €40,- (that's $58,- at the current Dollar-to-Euro rate) and plugged them into the ipod, and my ears. Although I have pretty standard ears,  I couldn't get the Apple earbuds to fit comfortably. Apple provides 3 different size caps, of which the middle size was the least uncomfortable, and sealed off my ear properly. You can tell this by the pressure you feel in your ear when inserting the buds. The pressure will slowly go away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I noticed is that by sealing off your earcanal, you can hear everything going on with the cords to the earbuds. Move your head, and you hear the cord move accross your clothes at a pretty uncomfortable volume. When playing music, don't move. The cord movement sounds will sometimes be louder than the music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sitting perfectly still and trying to judge the sound quality, I found that the Apple ear-buds are actually not good at all. Yes they provide lots of bass (which is a measure of quality nowadays I guess) but everything else is lacking. They sound flat, and miss the sharpness I expect from expensive earbuds. They are absolutely sounding worse than the standard earbuds that came with the iPod. If I had too choose between the two, I'd go for the standard iPod earphones in stead of the more expensive ear-buds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with headphones in general and in-ear headphones in particular, is that you can't return them, because they can't be sold as new after you've jammed them in your ears. For that same reason I'm probably not going to sell them second hand, making these buds one of the more expensive pieces of trash in my bin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8111.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8111.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Sony earphones">
&lt;/a> Last weekend I passed through a hardware store to buy a new harddrive for my fileserver. Next to the cash register I found a pair of &lt;a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/headphones-headsets/sony-mdr-e818lp/4505-6468_7-6900020.html">Sony MDR-E818LP&lt;/a> earphones for about €10,-. I bought them so that I could at least listen to music until I found a set of decent earphones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And guess what? These sound great! They've got too much bass (probably a fashion thing), but that can be cured with the &amp;quot;less bass&amp;quot; setting on the iPod. By doing that, these earphones are the right thing for your iPod, at the right price. The sound is clear and crisp, and these buds produce a LOT more sound than the Apple ones. They don't seal off your ear, which I've come to beleive is a good thing, because of the cord-sound I described above. They come with a set of soft cushions which make for a comfortable fit, and I can wear them for hours at an end without getting sore ears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get some of the €40,- spent on the Apple ear-buds back, I am using the Apple ear-bud carying case to store the Sony earphones in. The Sony's are worth it. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse this isn't the best set of earphones I've ever had. The old Sony fontopids that came with the first walkmans were absolutely the best in-ear headphones I've ever had. Comfortable fit, supple silicone cords, with red and blue stripes on the earpieces to mark right and left, but other than that perfectly symmetrical. Too bad they don't make those anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8113.jpg" alt="Sony MDR-CD770">
&lt;/a>The absolute best set of earphones I've ever had, and in fact still own after some odd 20 years, is a set of &lt;a href="http://www.epinions.com/content_6730518148">Sony MDR-CD770 Digital Reference&lt;/a> earphones. They (still) sound amazing, you feel like you can point out the location of every instrument in the band you're listening too, like they were in the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem with these are that they are big, expensive, and fragile. You won't be taking these with you when you're on vacation. They wouldn't survive the suitcase, and they're impossible when you are trying to lay your head down to sleep while listening to good music. Even if you did, you'd never wake up again, being strangled by the many meters of audio cable dangling off of your left ear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you're sitting at home on the couch, these will beat the * out of any soundsystem anyday, without annoying the neighbours. You'll be amazed at how good a high-bitrate AAC track sounds comming out of your iPod.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Birthday!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 20:36:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I know you've been playing with your ultra-cool iPhones, but did you realize that it only is 6 years ago that Apple showed is the first iPod? It's amazing how fast technology advances nowadays. Today I read that 128GB flashdrives are not far away, so how about an 128GB iPhone, or even a MacBook with a solid state disk? We've got a nice future ahead...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Meanwhile, you can watch Steve announce the first ever iPod, and notice the difference with the existing devices at that time. It's not strange that the iPod changed the way people listen to music.
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kN0SVBCJqLs&amp;amp;rel=1]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GoPod tries to crack 2nd gen iPod nano</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/23/gopod-tries-to-crack-2nd-gen-ipod-nano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 21:28:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/23/gopod-tries-to-crack-2nd-gen-ipod-nano/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Since Sony invented the walkman, the trains, trams and busses have been flooding with people wearing earphones. At first, they irritated everybody with the &amp;quot;ts...ts...ts...ts...ts...ts...ts...&amp;quot; sound comming out of their ears, and now, many early walkman owners are starting to show hearing problems. The European Union has stepped in to protect our ears, and have set some limits to how much sound a personal music device can produce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In theory this is a terrific idea, but in practice, it doesn't work. Most manufacturers, like Apple are simply limiting the absolute maximum the device can use by measuring how loud a very loud mp3 plays at max volume. Then, they apply a software cap on the volume slider and that's that. As a side effect, people who like to listen to inheritly low-volume music (classical music or some talkshow podcasts) are very limited in where they can use this device.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I have an 8GB iPod nano myself (a.k.a. the "second generation"), and I am having trouble hearing the voices of a podcast when walking on the street. Most music has a sort-of-okay volume level, but this particular podcast I'm listening is very low on volume. Because it is a news podcast, I don't have the time, or patience, to manually manipulate the audio level of this podcast every single day before synchronizing it to my nano.
&lt;p>Today I found &lt;a href="http://gopod.free-go.net/">GoPod&lt;/a>, a tool which can remove the volume limit on many iPod models. This process is called &amp;quot;uncapping&amp;quot; the volume. I'm on an Intel mac, and even found someone who has compiled it &lt;a href="http://forum.insanelymac.com/index.php?showtopic=29548">for Intel Macs&lt;/a> (not available on the original site). After some fiddling with it, I found that it didn't work with my iPod nano. In a search on the internet, I found that the 2nd generation nanos were not supported by GoPod because the developers had not figured out how to do this for the 2nd generation. Aperantly it is not that simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When entering &lt;a href="http://www.ipodhacks.com/forums/showpost.php?p=47438&amp;amp;postcount=172">diagnostic mode&lt;/a>, you can make the iPod produce a really loud 1KHz tone, which shows that the nano is capable of much more than Apple is showing you. The writers of the GoPod software also found the regional strings interesting, and everybody started posting:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
Reginal code
Purchase location
Capped
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >0x0001 0x0002
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >US
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >no
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x0022 0x0001
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >France, Italy, UK
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >yes
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x0020 0x0001
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Swiss, Austria
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >yes
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x0024 0x0001
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >UK
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >yes
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x0021 0x0001
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Finland, Sweden
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >yes
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x000a 0x0002
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Canada
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >no
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >0x001f 0x0001
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Slovenia, Hungary, Israel, Mauritius
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >yes
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
So far, the regional codes have not helped solving the problem. The GoPod people are still working on a hack, meanwhile the only options you have are the following:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Sell your European (capped) iPod and buy a new one from the US, make sure it is a US version. Maybe this is the moment to upgrade to that nice new generation nano :-)
2. Buy isolating in-ear headphones like the [Sony Fontopia](http://www.amazon.com/Sony-MDR-EX51LP-Fontopia-Headphones/dp/B000095SB6), or the  [Sennheiser cx300,](http://www.sennheiser.nl/nl/icm_nl.nsf/root/500830) or the  [Shure E2c](http://www.shure.com/PersonalAudio/Products/Earphones/ESeries/us_pa_E2c_content). Isolating in-ear phones will cost you anywhere between 30 and 100 euros.
3. Buy a set of [earjams](http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/earjams) to turn your iPod earphones into in-ear earphones. The cheapest, but maybe also clumsiest solution.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Please note that the first option is the most expensive, but actually solves the output voltage problem some people are experiencing when connecting the iPod to other hardware like amplifiers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPhone opens up to developers</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/18/iphone-opens-up-to-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2007 20:40:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/18/iphone-opens-up-to-developers/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Finally, the word is out. Apple (Steve) has announced at the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/">&amp;quot;hot news feed&amp;quot;&lt;/a> that the iPhone (and iPod touch) will be opened up to developers in February 2008. I think this is a wise decision. In stead of fighting developers, bricking phones and constantly being at the defense, the effort of Apple is much better put to use by working together with the (free, unpayed, expert-level, hours-on-end-concentrating, 24/7) programmers out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>Steve wrote an open letter, which I'll quote here because you can not direct-link to posts in the &amp;quot;hot news&amp;quot; feed of Apple. On 17 October 2007 Steve wrote:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>&amp;quot;Third Party Applications on the iPhone&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Let me just say it: We want native third party applications on the iPhone, and we plan to have an SDK in developers’ hands in February. We are excited about creating a vibrant third party developer community around the iPhone and enabling hundreds of new applications for our users. With our revolutionary multi-touch interface, powerful hardware and advanced software architecture, we believe we have created the best mobile platform ever for developers.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It will take until February to release an SDK because we’re trying to do two diametrically opposed things at once—provide an advanced and open platform to developers while at the same time protect iPhone users from viruses, malware, privacy attacks, etc. This is no easy task. Some claim that viruses and malware are not a problem on mobile phones—this is simply not true. There have been serious viruses on other mobile phones already, including some that silently spread from phone to phone over the cell network. As our phones become more powerful, these malicious programs will become more dangerous. And since the iPhone is the most advanced phone ever, it will be a highly visible target.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Some companies are already taking action. Nokia, for example, is not allowing any applications to be loaded onto some of their newest phones unless they have a digital signature that can be traced back to a known developer. While this makes such a phone less than “totally open,” we believe it is a step in the right direction. We are working on an advanced system which will offer developers broad access to natively program the iPhone’s amazing software platform while at the same time protecting users from malicious programs.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We think a few months of patience now will be rewarded by many years of great third party applications running on safe and reliable iPhones.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Steve&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>P.S.: The SDK will also allow developers to create applications for iPod touch. [Oct 17, 2007]&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that Apple will also open up the iPod cables again, for a minute out there Apple seemed to be forgotten what their initial market strategy was (and should be): Compete by designing the best product.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've found Microsoft products to be restrictive, as opposed to Apple's products being liberating. Microsoft makes me want to pirate stuff, Apple makes me want to pay for the great solution they have. Microsoft tries to charge you bigtime, and in return give you long serialnumbers, &amp;quot;authenticity checks&amp;quot;, and a lot of problems and bugs along with a piece of software that does not solve your problem or works like advertised (Vista, anyone?). Apple simply offers the best solution you could possibly imagine, (almost) without (noticable) copy restrictions, at a fair price. It will feel like money well spent, and almost always actually works &lt;em>better&lt;/em> than advertised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why all of a sudden Apple wants to be in the restrictive game is a complete mistery to me, and I hope they'll see the error of their ways soon...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPod Synchronization techniques</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Wherever I go, my iPod nano goes. With a &amp;quot;smaller&amp;quot; disk like on the nano, it's sort of important to make sure you are carrying the tracks you'll want to hear. I have a couple of smart playlists, and leave the rest to iTunes. Syncing takes less than a minute, is fully automatic and I'm very happy with the results every time.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_ipod-smart-playlists.jpg" alt="Smart Playlists">
Some people may be interested in how I organized this, so they can use some of these ideas themselves. On the left, you can see the smart playlists I use to fill my 8GB nano. I have placed these in a seperate folder to seperate them from all the other playlists I use to manage my iTunes collection with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there is the smart naming of the lists. Try to name your smart playlists so you can tell how they're built and what they contain. Looking at my lists, you can tell I only have 3 star rated songs and up on my iPod, unread books, and a seperate list containing tracks I haven't played or rated yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see my playlists are based on ratings. This is a personal choice, and only works on a good rating convention. To be able to build reliable lists based on ratings, try to conform yourself to rules. Mine are:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * **1 Star rating**: Never,ever play this track again. It sucks bigtime, or can't even be qualified as music. By doing this trick, you I effectively &amp;quot;delete&amp;quot; tracks right from the rating screen while playing a track. In iTunes I can later easily delete them when diskspace becomes a problem, but for how I keep them to keep my albums complete.
* **2 Star rating**: Not too good, don't play these too often. 2 star songs are currently not even transferred to my iPod.
* **3 Star rating**: This song is okay, I could listen to a radio station all day if it played songs with 3 star ratings
* **4 Star rating**: This is a good enough song to sit down to listen to. I can play it 2 times in a row without getting bored
* **5 Star rating**: If I had a single-song-ipod this track would be on it, and I would wear out the battery before putting another song on there. Effectively a &amp;quot;must have&amp;quot; song wherever I go.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_smart-3-star-radio-playlist.jpg">&lt;img src="o_smart-3-star-radio-playlist.jpg" alt="3 Star Radio playlist">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Translated: Rating is larger than 2 stars, limit to 2GB in size, select least recently played.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Above, you can see the 3 star radio trick. I found this idea on the web somewhere, and I liked it so I copied it, and added the size limitation. The playlist contains all 3 and more Stars rated songs, and is limited to 2 GB. Songs I played are swapped out during synchronization for ones I haven't heard for a while. The nice thing is that 4 Star rated songs in this list will also be in the 4 Star Radio list, but will only physically be on the iPod once. iTunes will never, ever physically put 2 instances of the same song on your iPod.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also the reason I can have 4 playlists of 2GB in size, plus some audiobooks and some other stuff (photo's) on my 8GB iPod. The 3, 4 and 5 star playlists don't add up 6 GB together, but far less because of the double tracks in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_smart-never-played-or-rated-playlist.jpg">&lt;img src="o_smart-never-played-or-rated-playlist.jpg" alt="Never played or rated">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Translated: Playcount is 0, and rating is less than 1 star, limit to 2GB in size, randomly selected.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be able to listen to new songs in your library and rate them, you'll need a playlist like this one. It's called &amp;quot;Never played (2GB)&amp;quot; and contains songs I have never heard and never rated. I rate most songs on my iPod, because it's within reach when listening to music. I use iTunes to stream music to the living room, and I'm not at the screen then so it's harder to rate songs that way. Nice thing about this list and the rating scheme I use is that 1 or 2 star songs are efectively deleted from my iPod. They don't show up in the playlists, and during synchronisation they are physically removed from the iPod to never return again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_smart-audiobook-playlist.jpg">&lt;img src="o_smart-audiobook-playlist.jpg" alt="Audiobook playlist">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Translated: Genre is Audiobook, Playcount is 0, limit to 5 items, select least recently added.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there are the audiobooks. I only actually have 1 I think, but this playlist makes sure I listen to my audiobooks in order of purchase. It puts the oldest 5 un&amp;quot;read&amp;quot; books on my iPod. Small disadvantage is that audiobooks need to have their genre set to &amp;quot;Audiobook&amp;quot; for this to work. I haven't found a trick to select audiobooks based on their extension (m4b) yet. Encoding type could work, but I also have AAC music tracks I bought in the iTunes store so the playlist would contain those aswell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next to the playlists above I have an important (dumb) playlist called &amp;quot;iPod musthaves&amp;quot;. This is a normal playlist, and any track I want on my iPod no matter what, I drag in there. I also have some lists called &amp;quot;blues&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;easy listening&amp;quot; but I don't use them that much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only thing which is not really perfect is the way I handle genres. Hardrock is next to classical music rightnow. I tried to get the genres right, but found that the whole &amp;quot;genre&amp;quot; idea does not apply to modern music. &amp;quot;Bluesy Rock&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Rocky Blues&amp;quot; are overlapping genres, and are not usable to select tracks based on tempo or feeling. I have used &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/archive/2006/10/22/137730.aspx">Tangerine&lt;/a> to analyse the BPM of my tracks, but that still did not help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_no-more-genres.jpg">&lt;img src="o_no-more-genres.jpg" alt="No more Genres">
&lt;/a>To clean things up, I totally removed all crappy genre information from my library. Only a few very clear to identify songs with wierd genres I left to be able to find quicly. Proof is on the left. The information was indeed so crappy that I don't mis it a single day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I do mis is the ability to find music grouped by &amp;quot;mood&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;energy&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;tempo&amp;quot;. In comes &lt;a href="http://www.crayonroom.com/moody.php">Moody (currently OSX only, Windows version in the making)&lt;/a>, a free iTunes plugin which allows to tag your tracks based on &amp;quot;Tempo&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Energy&amp;quot;. You can then build smart playlists based on tempo and mood ranges. I've tried this on 30 or so tracks and it looks very promising. I hope I can find the time to mood tag a larger portion of my iTunes library. Trouble is that I can't do that on my iPod.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To end this rather lengthy post, I can only encourage you to find your own &amp;quot;plan&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;system&amp;quot;, and translate that into smart playlists. This way iTunes &amp;quot;knows&amp;quot; what you want, and you'll be surprised about the great music you have in your library without knowing it. And if that's not enough, you can listen to your free podcasts for the daily news, music mixes or themed radio station.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recommended podcasts:
&lt;a href="http://javaposse.com/">The Java Posse. Java Programming news.&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://www.twit.tv/mbw">macBreak Weekly, Mac news and roundtable discussion&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://download.caz.nl/downloads/weekendmixpodcaz/rss.xml">CAZ Weekend mix podcaz, 1 hour dance hits mix&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://www.photoshoptvnl.nl/">Photoshop TV (DUTCH, VIDEO)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>