<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>car on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/car/</link><description>Recent content in car on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 19:42:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/car/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Soybean racer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The big car manufacturers could have done &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2006/02/17/eveningnews/main1329941.shtml">this&lt;/a>, but they didn't, because they are sponsored by the big oil companies. And your local governement is swimming in taxmoney that's added to your oil price. And no, they don't want to get rid of the cars, despite of what they say. The nicest thing for governements would be the complete population sitting in single-seated, gas guzzling cars in a traffic jam accross the country!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that a few school kids have proven that you don't need oil to race, and several American race series run on methanol (no that's not an oil product), can we please stop making cars that run on gasoline? And by the way, also stop pumping money into the super-dangerous liquid nitrogen cars? All that is purely to keep the oil companies in the same place: monopoly. Do you really think they do it for the environment? What if I told you that your current petrol car can run on bio-degradable methanol, with almost no changes? If you have a very modern car, the fuel system will even auto-adapt! But noooo, they won't tell you that, because the oil companies and governements want to keep the monopoly intact!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not that you can really do anything about it though. Except maybe not buying liquid-nitrogen or hybrid cars. There are better technical alternatives, although not on the market yet. Boycot the &amp;quot;environmentally friendly&amp;quot; car, force them into making a &lt;em>real&lt;/em> environmentally friendly car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I'm driving a diesel, and a motorbike. And no, I'm not worried about oil-shortage. It's all bullshit from the oil companies, who could have come up with alternatives a long while ago, but chose not to. If there really was an oil shortage, we all would have been driving on methanol for quite some time now. And co2 emmisions would have been reduced to absolutely 0.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>