<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design Gripes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dear Akio Morita,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">&lt;img src="2009-04-08-234308.png" alt="Onion News Network on Sony products">
&lt;/a>Lately I have some small issues with a lot of design decisions being made by the company you founded a while ago. If you look at my irritations seperately they're just small gripes of a grumpy old customer. But the increasing number of design mistakes have me worried about your user acceptance testing and quality assurance processes. Given the sheer size of your company, and the fact that the very same people who are sabotaging your overall product quality can silently delete my complaint, I thought I'd share it with you here, on my very private blog.  Nobody else will read this. Honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me start by saying that I love my Playstation 3. No wait, let me rephrase that. I love playing games on my playstation 3. Because the playstation 3 itself is absolutely not intuitive, logical or even pleasant to use. Both hardware and software wise.
&lt;p>I am very fortunate to have a loving wife who bought a PS3 for me. Because she did not expect to have to do in-depth research about the differences between the models, she bought the 80GB PS3 for me. It was the biggest drive in the store, so she thought that was the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was/am really happy with the very nice present. Not having any PS3 games yet, I slapped in a PS2 game, fully expecting that it would play. Not so. As it turns out, only the 60GB model plays &lt;em>some&lt;/em> of the PS2 games, and most of the time not even perfectly. What's with that? Can this 3-Cell processor huge 80GB machine with metric craploads of memory not emulate the outdated PS2? Did nobody at Sony realize that they can capitalize on people upgrading from the PS2? Not even now that the &lt;a href="http://ps3finder.com/">60GB models actually sell for more money than the 80GB&lt;/a> model retail price?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disapointedly leaving the PS2 compatibility issue, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/">I got a DLNA server running&lt;/a> on my Mac. When I want to view media on that server, I have to use your &amp;quot;X media bar&amp;quot; menu. For some reason, some designer came up with the brilliant idea to seperate music, photo's and video's in that menu. This means that before browsing my DLNA server, I have to decide what filetype I'm going to browse. If I have folders containing both video and photo's of the same birthday party, I constantly have to back out of the photo viewing mode, get into the video mode, browse all the way back to the folder, and view the video. It's like having to fill in a form to flip the channel on your TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what's with the forgetting of discovered DLNA servers? The PS3 takes ages to re-discover my DLNA server on the network each time I turn the PS3 on, or return to the menu from a game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it even more cringeworthy, the PS3 scares the crap out of me each time I browse to a folder to see that &amp;quot;There are no files...&amp;quot;. The PS3 is lying ofcourse, what it means is that there are MPG's and AVI's there, but I'm in photo viewing mode. The whole X-media-bar design must have never been usability tested by random customers. It's a very common practice nowadays which I can really recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By now, I had scored some PS3 games (&lt;a href="http://www.ps3home.nl/products/playstation-3-games/alle-games-a-tot-z/moto-gp-2008-ps3.htm">Moto GP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.tombraiderunderworld.com">Tomb Raider: Underworld&lt;/a>). After a nice evening of gaming,  I discover that the controller battery is running low. So I connect it to the PS3, and put the PS3 in standby mode, expecting my controller to be charged the next morning. To my huge disapointment, the controller does not charge when the PS3 is not fully on. That strikes me as really strange. To charge my wireless controller, I have to connect it during gaming. Now how did someone on your design team did not notice that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a big old Phillips Matchline TV which worked fine, but was getting a bit dated. The thought of being able to play games in full HD 1080p resolution was very tempting, so I bought a new model Sony Bravia 40 inch TV, thinking that it would interface nicely with the PS3. To my absolute horror, the PS3 video signal looked horrible on this new TV. As it turned out, you are shipping this full HD 300+ dollar gaming machine with a crappy composite video cable. Oh boy. Now I know why people think the difference between a Wii and a PS3 is not that huge. Another obvious commercial win down the drain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and I discovered that HDMI is the best way to go. I bought an HDMI cable and connected the PS3 to the TV with that. The TV manual said it could use some HDMI protocol to discover HDMI connected devices. Surely enough, my brandnew Sony Bravia does not recognize my Sony PS3. How nice is that? Luckaly, after some manual fiddling with the absolutely horrid X-media bar-like menu's in the TV and the PS3, I got everything to play in full HD. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What strikes me as another design flaw is the size of the screen fonts. On my big TV everything looks nice, but I can imagine that the paperboy who emptied his piggybank to get a PS3, and connects it to his little TV in his room, can not read any of the menu items. I take it that the Sony testing department only has Full HD TV's with HDMI cables, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there's the whole casing design thing. Come on. Rounded top? I can not even place a controller on there, it slides off. The ventilation holes are on the side, which makes it imposible to put the PS3 with it's right side against the cupboard. The USB ports are recessed in such a way that if you place the PS3 low to the ground (which happens most), you can not see the ports without having to lie down on the floor eyeballing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you're down there, you can als see the rediculously thick and sturdy mains cable. It can transport enough current to power my microwave. Does the PS3 really use that much current? Now be honest. You could have selected a thinner, more flexible mains lead, and maybe it would even have been cheaper. The current lead almost pushes the PS3 out from the wall. Good thing the PS3 is so heavy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When waking the PS3 from it's sleep mode, there is another interesting thing that strikes me as odd. There is a green and a blue led next to eachother on the top of the button pannel. Not only are those two colors looking horrible next to eachother, and the fact that I have come to loathe any product with a blue led, there is absolutely no way that colorblind people are going to notice the difference in color, which makes them pointless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said, this is just a selection of the gripes I have with the design. For instance, the fact that game makers are allowed to play sounds and video as soon as a game is inserted, is just terrible. It scares the crap out of me each time I insert &lt;a href="http://www.racedrivergrid.com/">Race Driver:GRID&lt;/a>, and there is no way I can turn it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="photo.jpg">&lt;img src="photo.jpg" alt="Sony Bravia remote button misplacement">
&lt;/a>The nicest example of hardware design failure by Sony is the remote control of the Sony Bravia TV. The buttons you use most are in fact unreachable when holding the remote in your hand. The least used buttons are right there by your thumb. What was this designer thinking? Oh and never mind pressing the buttons, because this TV, which can interpolate frames of a 24fps source into 100fps fluid motion while dynamically adjusting sound and backlight, has a very hard time to display a menu or react to the remote. This is absolutely mind boggling to me. It's like a race car which can go from 0 to 300mph in 2 seconds but takes 5 seconds to react to the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I bought all this Sony stuff. I know, I could have bought something else. But there are reasons for me to put up with all this crap. OTHER manufacturers make such great stuff for Sony devices. The games on the PS3 are absolutely beautiful and brilliant. Watching video on the PSP on an airplane is great. Looking at a bluray at 100Hz 1080p on the Bravia is eye-popping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, dear mr. Morita, please, please make the people at Sony aware of these details. They're important. Solving them will set your product apart from the competition in a large way. People may not be able to tell why, but they will like your product better. This is what good designers do. Make a product have a good &amp;quot;feel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will also rid you of online video's describing your products as... well... you've already seen &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">that video&lt;/a>, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading this rant.
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DLNA on OSX, done right</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3">&lt;img src="200x150_playstation3_logo1.jpg" alt="Sony PS3 Logo">
&lt;/a>My wife bought me a playstation 3 last year, and I've enjoyed many hours of gaming on it, finishing Tomb Raider underworld, and now making decent progress in Ratchet and Clank: Tools of Destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dlna.org/home">&lt;img src="afbeelding-22.png" alt="DLNA logo">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a bit sceptical about the DLNA capabilities of the PS3, because I read a lot of bad news on this fairly new  &amp;quot;Interoperability Guidelines&amp;quot; concept. It sounded like a lot of trouble to go through to simply watch the photos and home videos on a TV. For weeks, I was not able to find a single site telling me how to install a DLNA server on my Mac, or where to find a decent one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Altgough they're hard to find, there are a few OSX DLNA servers out there. One of them is actually very good. Here's what I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**CyberMediaGate**
&lt;p>I found a DLNA server implemented in Java, and didn't get it to work. It misses a Xerces library and I can not seem to get the right version added to the classpath. I decided this was not very &amp;quot;Mac like&amp;quot; and dumped it. Not being able to install software &amp;quot;out of the box&amp;quot; may be normal on Linux, but is unaccepatble on a Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TwonkyMedia&lt;/strong>
Then, I came across TwonkyMedia. This was the first DLNA server I actually got to work on my Mac, and had it serving video to my PS3. It is a strange (wonky?) piece of software, had no native GUI and only lives on your machine as a webapplication. The installer copies &amp;quot;TwonkyMediaServer.app&amp;quot; in your application folder, starts it, and then opens a browser which points to the local URL of it's configuration screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that moment, it already is serving clients, but when you try to access it with the PS3, you will get a protocol error. This is because TwonkyMedia does not come with a default server name. The PS3 aparently can not handle an empty server name. After filling it in and restarting Twonky, I could access it with the PS3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TwonkyMedia does not look very Mac-like, and I don't like the looks of the webpage it is serving. The installer leaves two webloc files on your desktop which point to the configuration screens. It's a bit strange but it gets the job done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Potentially Twonky can do a bit more than CyberMediaGate. Twonky can do some transcoding and other streaming stuff, but I did not try that because I simply wanted to see my photo's and home video's on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trial version of Twonkymedia last for 30 days, but on the first day it already started acting up on me, and I had to restart it a few times while watching video. The look and feel, and the crashes didn't feel like it was worth the $40 to me, so I uninstalled it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uninstalling TwonkyMedia requires you to kill the process from the Terminal, and then drag TwonkyMediaServer.app to your trashcan. Another way is dragging the app to the trashcan and then restarting your Mac (not mac-like but it works).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>MediaLink&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink">&lt;img src="printablelogo.png" alt="Nullriver Logo">
&lt;/a>The nullriver homepage looked very elegant, and promising. A simple page explains what it is, what it does, and what it costs. Nullriver also allows you to send requests and reports on their site without registering (in contract with TwonkyMedia, to which you have to &amp;quot;sell your soul&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nullriver Medialink comes as a preference pane application, and has a beautifuly simple interface, with not many options. It integrates with your mac applications like iTunes, iPhoto and now even Aperture. It does not have all the fancy configuration options of TwonkyMedia. One of my small complaints is that your content is shared to all DLNA clients on your local network, which may not be what you want if you have more than one DLNA client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me MediaLink is a perfect fit. I control my own network, my PS3 is my only DLNA client so I don't need the fancy stuff. Most people will be perfectly happy with Medialink. It's simple, transparent, drag-and-drop, has a &amp;quot;stop&amp;quot; button and is cheap. It does not have all the fancy features, but all the features that are in there work flawlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played with it for more than a week now, and so far it hasn't crashed on me. I did need to buy a registration key, because the trial version only lasts you for about 30 minutes of watching content (which should be plenty to try it out, and it's not like the 20 bucks are going to kill you).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
Once again, all DLNA servers I tried put together:&lt;/p>
&lt;table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="1" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[CyberMediaGate](http://www.cybergarage.org/net/cmgate/java/index.html)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Free
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Terrible, unable to install.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[TwonkyMedia](http://www.twonkyvision.de/)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$40
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Works, lots of features, no GUI, buggy/ Crashed on me more than once.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[MediaLink](http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$20
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Simple, stable, nice GUI, best value for money. Just works.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
So if you have a PS3 and a Mac, it's a no-brainer. Buy Medialink!</description></item></channel></rss>