<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/categories/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 13:37:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why some App Store apps won't install</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/01/09/why-some-app-store-apps-wont-install/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 13:37:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/01/09/why-some-app-store-apps-wont-install/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com/tag/mac-app-store-comics/">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-28-53.png" alt="App Store Icon">
&lt;/a>I was happily playing around with the appstore, and came across this funny free game called &amp;quot;Hedgewars&amp;quot;. Originally a free Linux game, it apparently got ported to the Mac and put in the App Store, just as a slew of Flash-based games (yes, Steve has some 'splainin' to do).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried to install Hedgewars on my trusty Mac Mini and got this message saying &amp;quot;This Application can not be installed on this machine&amp;quot;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2011-01-08-om-16-45-40.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-08-om-16-45-40.png?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->There was no additional information on what was causing this. So the first thing I did was check out my computer information and the requirements for running this game, which seemed to check out fine:
&lt;table width="100%" class="aligncenter" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-00-40-38.png?w=122)
](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-00-40-38.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-15-55.png)
](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-15-55.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
I was running the correct version of OSX, so what was the problem here? My neighbor came over and I showed him this funny problem. He found out that Hedgewars could be downloaded from the developers site, and so we did. After opening the DMG, we were greeted with the funny Application Icon decoration show on the right:
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-18-25.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-18-25.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Usually this means that the application is compiled for a different system than you're trying to run it on. This can happen when you have an older generation PowerPC processor and try to run a non-universal-binary Intel application. So we checked the properties on the application, and it looked like OSX had it wrong. It's an Intel app, and we're running an Intel Mac. So what gives?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next step was to open the Terminal so we could dissect this app on the command line, showing it's inner guts. Apps have all kinds of interesting XML and plist files telling the operating system what to do and how to start it up. Here's what we found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1,2,8&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ cd Hedgewars.app/Contents/MacOS/
rolf@Mac-mini$ ls -l
total 21344
-rwxr-xr-x 1 rolf admin 2627208 27 dec 21:39 hedgewars
-rwxr-xr-x@ 1 rolf admin 5913164 27 dec 21:37 hedgewars-server
-rwxr-xr-x@ 1 rolf admin 2381240 27 dec 21:37 hwengine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rolf@Mac-mini$ file *
hedgewars: Mach-O 64-bit executable x86_64
hedgewars-server: Mach-O executable i386
hwengine: Mach-O universal binary with 1 architecture
hwengine (for architecture x86_64): Mach-O 64-bit executable x86_64
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hedgewars package has 3 executables, one 64-bit x86, one i386, and one universal binary which only contains an executable for 64-bit x86. We guess the developers made a bit of a mess of this. As expected, we could start the i386 executable just fine:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hedgewars-server
Listening on port 46631
^C
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the x86_64 executable and the universal binary would not start:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1,4&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hedgewars
-bash: ./hedgewars: Bad CPU type in executable&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hwengine
-bash: ./hwengine: Bad CPU type in executable
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because this Mac Mini runs a Core Duo, we figured the x86 was okay, but we weren't sure about the 64-bit architecture. A quick peek at &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_Core">Wikipedia&lt;/a> confirmed our suspicion: The Intel Core Duo is not a 64 bit processor. In fact, 64-bit is the major difference between &amp;quot;Core Duo&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Core 2 Duo&amp;quot;. Additional &amp;quot;Googling&amp;quot; showes that &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht3696">Apple Support knows that&lt;/a>, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So there you have it. The Mac App Store does not tell you what the problem really is, but chances are that if you get the &amp;quot;Could not install this Application on this machine&amp;quot; error, you have 32-bit architecture (the Core Duo) and the developer compiled the application for 64-bit architecture (the Core 2 Duo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why in god's name hedgewars has to be a 64-bit application beats me, but that's something I'm not going to change I'm afraid. It turns out that this as been &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hedgewars/issues/detail?id=147&amp;amp;q=core%20duo">reported as a bug&lt;/a> to the Hedgewars team, which hasn't been picked up yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good news for older model Intel Mac Mini Core Duo owners out there: You can replace your CPU with a Core 2 Duo processor. You'll need one of these:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7200 (2.00Ghz)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7400 (2.16Ghz)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7600 (2.33Ghz).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The processors are quite pricey, our quick check showed that they're all above the $200 price mark, which may be a bit steep for a processor upgrade. We expected about half that, so that was a bummer. Should you want to upgrade your CPU, buy thermal paste, and follow a good howto. To get a feeling of what you're getting into, check out the &lt;a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/Mac-mini-Model-A1283-Teardown/659/1">iFixit teardown of the Mac Mini&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other option would be to trade in your Core Duo Mac Mini for a Core 2 Duo Mac mini. It's safer and probably about as costly as buying one of the strangely priced Core 2 Duo processors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Manualist</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/07/25/the-manualist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 21:31:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/07/25/the-manualist/</guid><description>
&lt;p>There's a funny comercial on Dutch television which says that you should be paying too much for all the rubbish you download on the internet. Here's a nice example of stuff you don't want to pay too much for :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v0bKq3x74UE]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It may look silly, but this guy actually had to be practicing a lot to get to this (Mario) level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real guitar game: Guitar Wizzard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:35:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>No, I'm not a guitar player, but I noticed this cool post on TUAW where the &amp;quot;Guitar Hero&amp;quot; game has been taken a notch up. &lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/09/guitar-wizard-coming-for-mac/">TUAW reports&lt;/a> that the guys at &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com">www.musicwizard.com&lt;/a> have built &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com/guitar_wizard/updates.php">&amp;quot;Guitar Wizzard&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, a game with which you can learn to play popular songs on a &lt;em>real guitar&lt;/em>. From what I can see in the video, this looks way less frustrating than doing the same excersizes over and over to learn to play the guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, you might not turn in to Mark Knopfler in a week, but isn't it a much better feeling to hold a real guitar in your hand, in stead of that plasticky, toy-like mini quitar with the bright colored buttons? And the price is about right for a game including hardware aswell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monokai</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/14/monokai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 21:24:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/01/14/monokai/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I just checked out the new &lt;a href="http://www.creativecommons.nl/dvd/">Dutch CC CD/DVD&lt;/a> released under the Creative Commons license. While I was there I found a great &lt;a href="http://www.creativecommons.nl/dvd/tracks/Monokai/Monokai-Mier.mp3">piece of music done by Monokai&lt;/a>. It's kind of old C64 game like music, you like it or hate it. I went to check out &lt;a href="http://www.monokai.nl/">Monokai's website&lt;/a> and I've spent a good 30 minutes playing with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The website is filled with music, photo's and electronic games, and is fun to play with. Go check it out! Nice quality!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The real bike simulator</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/05/the-real-bike-simulator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 16:14:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/05/the-real-bike-simulator/</guid><description>
&lt;p>From the makers of Gran Turismo:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://us.playstation.com/Content/OGS/SCUS-97502/Site/">&lt;img src="banner2.jpg" alt="Tourist Trophy banner">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is this great or what? It clearly is built on the Gran Turismo 4 rendering engine, and supports everything we've come to expect from Digital Polyphony. Arcade and Trophy mode, Photoshoot mode, a bucketload of (real life) tracks, and a truck load of different bikes to choose from!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looks like my next addition to my PS2 game collection...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Airbus 330 Entertainent system</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/03/31/airbus-330-entertainent-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2006 19:36:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/03/31/airbus-330-entertainent-system/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently went to Vegas, which is a very long trip (about 20 hours including stopover). I don't like flying that much, my ears hurt and it is very boring to be crammed in a chair for 10 hours, with a headrest that makes your chin touch your chest no matter how you adjust it. However, on this flight (and the one back) there was a nice personal entertainment system installed in each chair.Below are some images of the personal entertainment system which is installed on the Airbus 330's of Northwest Airlines. These are a real treat on long distance flights. There is a fair selection of on-demand movies, music, some simple games and flight information. It lets you choose a movie, and you can pause and skip as much as you like. You can use your own 3.5mm jacked headphones, no more of that adapter-buying-if-you-are-lucky-you'll-get-stereo crap you see in the older planes. The menu even contained an item called &amp;quot;email&amp;quot;, but it was not functioning at the time I tried it. Besides you had to swipe your credit card for it, which I didn't find worth trying even if it would work.&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Bejeweled](r_img_3683.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3683.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Controller](r_img_3686.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3686.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Flight information](r_img_3692.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3692.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Movies](r_img_3688.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3688.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Nice little game, Bejeweled
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >The controller (has to be turned 90 degrees sometimes, confusing!)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Guess where we are? Travelling at 950km/h there :-)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Watched Chicken Little. It does not live up to it's commercial by a long shot.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
Funny thing is, that my wife's entertainent system actually crashed during flight. It got stuck for about 5 minutes, after which it automatically rebooted, and guess what? I saw a Tux! It is actually a Linux system. A bit of googling revealed that a few people even have seen the system crash on [all monitors at the same time](http://www.flickr.com/photos/milliped/116393699/). Good thing they aren't using this system for the flight controls yet. ;-)
&lt;p>But it does make sense. It doesn't cost anything, and being open source, Panasonic (the manufacturer of the system) has full controll on getting all the glitches out. Now they actually do need to do that still, but I bet they got a nice (remote?) update procedure for that. After all, they also need to upload new movies every now and then. Maybe they use the same connection as they use for email? 100% remote update would be nice. No &amp;quot;downtime&amp;quot; for the planes!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I for one liked the system very much. It actually has games which let you compete with other passengers, but that didn't seem to be popular on my flights to Las Vegas. I didn't even had to get my PSP out of my bag :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if they only could make those stupid headrests removable so I can put my head back when I want to sleep (like most normal people), flying wouldn't be all that bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DTM2 on PS2 uses Gamespy!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2004/10/30/dtm2-on-ps2-uses-gamespy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2004 07:49:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2004/10/30/dtm2-on-ps2-uses-gamespy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>History, Sony Online Drama&lt;/strong>
I bought a Sony PS2 a few years ago, when it just got out. I beleive it belongs to the first or second batch of Playstation 2 consoles arriving in the Netherlands. It costed a small fortune. About a year later, I purchased the Linux kit for my PS2. The Linux kit came with a network adapter and a harddisk. It worked like a charm. Sony had not started the online game service back then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Sony finally announced their network gaming plans, the Linux for Playstation group very kindly sent me a &amp;quot;Network Access Disc&amp;quot;. This is the disc you normally get when purchasing your network adapter for the PS2. However, being an early version and all, I never got it working properly. I spent hours (no, literally!) trying to register my handle and username. I never got it working properly. Friends of mine who bought the official adapter had newer versions of the software, which seemed to work better but still not good enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The beautiful world of non-Sony developers&lt;/strong>
I had given up on online gaming on the PS2 by now. A few months ago I played an online demo of DTM race driver 2 on my PC, and had great fun. I registered with GameSpy and was online and gaming with my friends in less than 5 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last weekend, I found a copy of DTM2 for the PS2. Since I liked the fysics engine of DTM2 for the PS2, I decided to give it a try. Not even thinking about the cruddy PS2 online gaming option. When I got home and started the game, I was pleasantly surprised to see that DTM2 for PS2 actually uses the GameSpy system in stead ot the stupid Sony stuff. Again, I was playing online in within 5 minutes (had to look up my old GameSpy Id). I even hooked up an USB keyboard, which made logging in even simpler! Terrific!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My compliments to Codemasters and Gamespy, who have restored my hope and ability to play online games with my PS2.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>