<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iTunes on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/itunes/</link><description>Recent content in iTunes on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 23:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/itunes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bill Gates works at Apple</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 23:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/13/bill-gates-works-at-apple/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.jpg?w=150" alt="Steve Jobs">
&lt;/a>I was happy to see Steve return on the Apple keynote of 9 September, because boy does Apple need somebody with clear vision. The introductions on the new iPod line are all over the place. Let me tell you why I think Steve has not been running the operation for the past few months:&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * **Ringtones.** The price of a ringtone in the iTunes store is (still) higher than that of a song. You can make a ring tone out of a song [for free](http://www.wired.com/software/coolapps/news/2007/09/ringtone_hacks) already, so why put the effort into selling ringtones at a way too high price? The phone companies must have influenced some &amp;quot;less sturdy&amp;quot; people at Apple for this.
* **The Nano Camera.** 2 mistakes on this one. First is the device. Why put a camera on the Nano of all iPods? Wouldn't we expect that on the iPod touch? Or perhaps both? Second is the location. Anybody holding a nano must notice that the camera is in a place where your hand is when holding the nano. Maybe it makes a bit more sense in landscape mode, right after you smudged it with your hand. Maybe I'd have to hold one for good testing. I heard that the camera is not nearly as good as the one on the iPhone 3Gs.
* **iTunes 9's Column Browser.** When I installed iTunes 9, my trusty 3-pane music browser was gone. I had a list of artists on the left, and next to that all my music as a long list of unsorted tracks. Gee thanks. After some fiddling I got the 3-paned browser back (see my [earlier blogpost](http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/)) but the fiddling in the menus got me that &amp;quot;Windows&amp;quot; feeling of tweaking a crappy UI into something I can sort of use.
* **Genius Mixes.** After seeing the keynote, I was eager to try out the &amp;quot;Genius Mixes&amp;quot; feature. In the keynote, these mixes are available under the Genius item on the left. When I looked, there was nothing there. I searched preferences and menus to turn them on, but found nothing. It turns out that you need to upload Genius data to Apple before the Genius Mixes appear. The mixes themselves are working fine, but when a Genius Mix is playing, you can do nothing. No coverflow. No Track details. I can not even rate the currently playing song. This cripples it's potential of finding and rating great songs in a large library.
* **Syncing knobs and levers.** Where syncing used to be simple, it is now 9 tabs with a slew of boxes and sliders you can drag suff between. I know a lot of customers asked for it, but that has never stopped Apple coming up with a totally brilliant solution to a problem, instead of just implementing the user's crappy first thought. I will get used to it, and it will probably work fine, but it just adds to a scary feeling I had of an Apple without Steve.
* **Twitter integration.** Come on Apple, you are not serious now, are you? There are hundreds of Twitter and IM integration apps that will do something like this. Apple did not even add that &amp;quot;innovative cool juice&amp;quot; to it. They just messed up iTunes codebase with this quick hack, making it even harder to port iTunes to 64 bit Cocoa.
* &amp;quot;**Richer&amp;quot; LP content.** I hate the iTunes appstore pages where developers are using way more CSS and markup than you would like to. It's like the walls of the grocery store change each time you look at a different product. It's confusing and ugly. Now, with the LP stuff added, Apple now is going one step further, and starts selling this for a price. Just like the ringtones.
* **Incoherent iPod touch line.** The 8GB iPod touch is sold at $199, which is great, but it was not &amp;quot;revved&amp;quot;, meaning that the 16+GB iPod touches have a different chipset. How do you explain the customer that a game is running slower on one touch, and faster on the other? Sure it's done to get to the $199 price point, but Apple didn't work like this in the old days. They used to introduce a new (revved) model at the same pricepoint.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The whole talk feels a bit &amp;quot;all over the place&amp;quot;, and a way of charging customers for something they do not really need. I know, usually keynotes get the &amp;quot;woos&amp;quot; from the cround every 15 seconds and it's hard to do that time and time again. And Steve just returned, having to sell the stuff he may not have wanted to put out there in the first place. So I'll forgive them this time. But this fan boy will be watching Apple and hope it will be a bit more consistent next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-4.jpg">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.jpg" alt="Jeff? Or Bill?">
&lt;/a>So Steve, get those guys back on track will you? And you might want to do an extra surprise round in the office, because I smell &amp;quot;feature creep&amp;quot;. And is it me, or does Jeff Robin's profile  look like a younger Bill Gates?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm. I hope he doesn't try that silly &lt;a href="http://www.pencomputing.com/frames/tablet_pc.html">tablet-thing&lt;/a> again...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iTunes 9: "Genre-Artist-Album" panes restored</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/09/11/itunes-9-genre-artist-album-panes-restored/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-5.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-5.png" alt="iTunes 9 with 3 panes">
&lt;/a>What I loved about iTunes is the three pane &amp;quot;Genre-Artist-Album&amp;quot; on top of my music list. It allowed me to quickly go through my music and find that great Anouk album I was looking for. After installing iTunes 9, it was gone. And I was sad. But I found a way to get it back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png?w=150" alt="Settings to get the panes back">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look at this screenshot (sorry, it's in Dutch). In iTunes, select &amp;quot;View&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Show Column Browser&amp;quot;. Now, put it on top by selecting &amp;quot;View&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Column Browser&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Top&amp;quot;. Voila, your trusted browser is at the top. You may need to add &amp;quot;Genre&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Album&amp;quot; there, but you've already seen the options for that now, have you? ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to put DVD's on your iPhone (for free)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:19:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/28/how-to-put-dvds-on-your-iphone-for-free/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-13a1.png" alt="For A Few Dollars More">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of companies like to sell you applications to put DVD's on your iPhone. Usually these apps are just wrappers around existing tools, and are pretty expensive if you consider you can do it for free. And you don't need to be a computer wizard either! The steps are simple:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Use [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) to rip the DVD to iPhone format
2. Drag the generated mp4 file into iTunes
3. Sync it to your iPhone like all other content
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>To show you exactly how this is done, I've  written up this &amp;quot;babystep-by-babystep&amp;quot; tutorial. Let me show you how I ripped &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Few-Dollars-More-Clint-Eastwood/dp/0792839056">&amp;quot;For A Few Dollars More&amp;quot;&lt;/a> and put it on my iPhone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Disclaimer: **The DVD I ripped is bought and payed for. This article does not relief you of your responsibility to obey the law, so please be careful. And be nice, don't pirate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->What You Need&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [Handbrake](http://handbrake.fr/?article=download) for ripping the DVD
* [VLC](http://www.videolan.org/vlc/), which is used by handbrake for DVD's with encodings not supported by Handbrake. You don't always need it, but download and install it anyway, just to be sure.
* Some patience.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Rip the DVD to an MP4&lt;/strong>
Put a DVD in your Mac, and stop the DVD player application if it opens automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-6.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-6.png?w=128" alt="Select VIDEO_TS folder">
&lt;/a>Start Handbrake. A selection window will open, use it to browse to the DVD, and select the VIDEO_TS folder (just select it, no need to go into it) and then press &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-7.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-7.png" alt="Select Title and Chapters">
&lt;/a>Handbrake will briefly scan the DVD for titles. In the &amp;quot;Source:&amp;quot; section of the screen, select a title and the chapters you want to rip. Usually Handbrake guesses that it's the longest title, with the most chapters you want to rip. Let's go with those defaults.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-81.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-81.png?w=44" alt="Presets Selection Drawer">
&lt;/a>Press the &amp;quot;Toggle Presets&amp;quot; button on the top right, and select &amp;quot;iPhone&amp;quot; from the list that pops out on the right side of the Handbrake window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-10.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-10.png?w=120" alt="Select Audio and Subtitles">
&lt;/a>Next, click the &amp;quot;Audio and Subtitles&amp;quot; tab and select the audio and subtitles you want to listen and read in the ripped video. You can NOT change audio and subtitles later on your iPhone, so choose wisely. This is usually the step I forget, which requires me to wait for the whole ripping process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-12.png" alt="afbeelding-12">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure the destination file is where you want it, and press the green &amp;quot;Start&amp;quot; icon. Handbrake will start reading the DVD and create an MP4 file. This can take a while, so you might want to get a cocktail. Handbrake will show a progress bar in the icon in the dock.
 
&lt;strong>Step 2: Import into iTunes&lt;/strong>
After the ripping is done, you can add your mp4 file to the iTunes library by simply dragging the video file into iTunes. There you can set the title, year, genre and illustration exactly as you did with your music files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-14.png" alt="iTunes showing ripped DVD">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 3: Putting it on your iPhone&lt;/strong>
Plug in you iPhone. Go to the iPhone configuration and click on the &amp;quot;Video&amp;quot; tab. Scroll down, and select the video you just imported:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-15.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-15.png" alt="Sync the movie to the phone">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you press &amp;quot;Apply&amp;quot;, iTunes will immediately start copying the movie over to the iPhone, where you can find it in your iPhone in your iTunes library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Advanced Tips:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [![Few Dollars More on iPhone](img_0005.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](img_0005.png)The DVD I just converted (For A Few Dollars More) averaged out to about 3,5MB per minute. That's about 5 hours of video per GB, but your mileage may vary. On average you should be able to take at least one or to movies with you on your iPhone. If your music is in the way, you can &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/">use these tips&lt;/a> to make iTunes organize your music for you.
* Handbrake has an &amp;quot;Add To Queue&amp;quot; button which lets you convert multiple movies in a row. In order for that to work you need to copy the VIDEO_TS folders of multiple DVD's onto a harddrive. Now you can convert multiple DVD's overnight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rip and Convert FLAC, M4A, MP3, AAC files</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&lt;img src="afbeelding-8.png" alt="Max Audio Transcoder">
&lt;/a>I recently found an old harddisk which used to be in one of my old PC's. I discovered some &lt;a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">FLAC&lt;/a> files on there, which were rips of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOU8GIRUd_g">old CD's&lt;/a> I used to have. iTunes is not too happy with importing them into my library, and the original CD's are in a box in a deep dark corner of my garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I searched for a converter and found this wonderful converter which can just about convert any audio format out there. It's called &lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&amp;quot;Max&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, it's Open Source, free to use, and available as bundled OSX application. Brilliant! It does have a bunch of options, but as long as you go for the &amp;quot;MP4 Audio&amp;quot; output format, high quiality, 256 bits and VBR, you can't go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to their website &lt;em>&amp;quot;Max can generate audio in over 20 compressed and uncompressed formats including MP3, Ogg Vorbis, FLAC, AAC, Apple Lossless, Monkey's Audio, WavPack, Speex, AIFF, and WAVE&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy transcoding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attention to Detail</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/14/attention-to-detail/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 08:54:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/14/attention-to-detail/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As I explained earlier, I think it is really important to &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/07/12/conform-specs-is-not-enough/">go beyond the specs&lt;/a>. It's really important to put care and attention in your product. The new version of iTunes has a great (little) example of what I mean. I use Itunes to play music through both the computer speakers and a stereo in the livingroom, connected to an Airport Express.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In iTunes 7, when I added the Airport Express to the set of outputs while playing a song, the music stopped, and after a while resumed playing through all the selected outputs. I never minded the short silence, and was amazed at how Apple got all the outputs to play perfectly in sync.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In iTunes 8 things changed a tiny bit. When I select the Airport Express, the music keeps on playing on my computer, and after a few seconds the music also starts playing from the speakers in the living room. An still, the music is in sync.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It's these little things, the amazing attention to detail, that give Apple products a tremendous &amp;quot;perceived value&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That, and the Genius button ofcourse. :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Birthday!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 20:36:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I know you've been playing with your ultra-cool iPhones, but did you realize that it only is 6 years ago that Apple showed is the first iPod? It's amazing how fast technology advances nowadays. Today I read that 128GB flashdrives are not far away, so how about an 128GB iPhone, or even a MacBook with a solid state disk? We've got a nice future ahead...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Meanwhile, you can watch Steve announce the first ever iPod, and notice the difference with the existing devices at that time. It's not strange that the iPod changed the way people listen to music.
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kN0SVBCJqLs&amp;amp;rel=1]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use iTunes with *ANY* mp3 player</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/01/use-itunes-with-any-mp3-player/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 21:29:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/01/use-itunes-with-any-mp3-player/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Many years ago, I bought an &lt;a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/Jens_of_Sweden_MP_100_256MB/4514-6490_7-30420028.html">iBead Jens of Sweden MP-100&lt;/a>. At the time I was a Windows/Linux user and everything was fine. Now that I'm a Mac user, syncing tracks to my trusty USB mp3 player is a bit harder. I had to copy tracks by hand, and when two tracks had the same title the copy would fail. THis was all very irritating. I am saving for an iPod nano, but until I get one I'm stuck with the USB copy tricks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But not anymore, 5 minutes ago I discovered &lt;a href="http://www.nesfield.co.uk/synctunes/">SyncTunes&lt;/a>, a free Mac OSX application which can sync iTunes playlists to &lt;strong>any&lt;/strong> drive as long as it's available on your desktop. This means that any drive that mounts as a removable drive (USB memory sticks, PDA's, Sony PSP's...) can be used to sync the playlist to. The only catch is that you have to make the playlist fit onto the drive (in size). This can be easily done by creating a smart playlist in iTunes which is limited in size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tested syncing some of my playlists (through a size-limiting playlist) and it works like a charm. Size limiting playlists are also the thing to use if you do have an iPod, and want some control on how many space is used by pop music, and how many space is used by rock. I'm a happy camper now, and in no hurry to buy an iPod (but that &lt;a href="//store.apple.com/1-800-MY-APPLE/WebObjects/AppleStore?family=iPodnano">8GB red nano&lt;/a> sure looks tempting).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opening iTunes to other players</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today I found an &lt;a href="http://today.reuters.co.uk/news/articlenews.aspx?type=technologyNews&amp;amp;storyID=2007-01-25T155722Z_01_L25510487_RTRIDST_0_TECH-APPLE-ITUNES-NORWAY-DC.XML&amp;amp;WTmodLoc=TechInternet-C3-Technology-2">article about Norway suing Apple&lt;/a> because music bought in the iTunes store could not be played on a non-iPod music player. If Apple looses this legal attack, it would result in an even stranger digital rights management situation than we already have. &lt;!-- more -->First, let me tell you why I think the whole legal case would not be worth persuing anyway:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Music bought through iTunes is in the [AAC format](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Audio_Coding#How_AAC_works), which is an open standard format. Any modern player is capable of playing AAC files. The &amp;quot;problem&amp;quot; lies in the way the songs are stored in an encrypted form invented by Apple, called [Fairplay](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FairPlay). Fairplay resticts the way you use and play the file, but only very limited: You can play a Fairplay encrypted file on your iPod, on up to 3 (three) authorized computers, and (here it comes) can be **copied to a standard audio CD any number of times**. Since when is this called &amp;quot;limiting&amp;quot;?
2. Buying DRM music from iTunes clearly has limitations. Apple is not hiding this fact, as Microsoft is not hiding the fact that WMA has almost the same limitations. Suppose there was no workaround available and you had to play the music on your iPod, you still could not complain. You can almost describe it as not being able to play CD's on your record player. You bough a CD, not a vinyl record, and you knew beforehand that it was not compatible with your record player.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>That said, I think the root cause of these type of lawsuits is often overlooked. It's the way people think about intelectual property and the traditional ways of selling copies where the author received a substantial part of the profits. In a digital age like ours, there is no &amp;quot;physical product&amp;quot;, which makes it very easy for me to give a file I bought to just about an individual out there, without me loosing the original file. The copies of the file are all of the same superiour quality, so re-distributing them is very interesting to anyone wanting to exchange or &amp;quot;trade&amp;quot; music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have allways thought of DRM of crippeling a file because people simply can not behave. The whole proces of crippeling audio and video files has just resulted in me doing the oposite of what the intent was. If I buy a DVD, I have to watch a few minutes of copyrights notices and commercials, without being able to skip them. If I rip it, and re-write it, these notices are gone, but I feel mistreated by the DVD company because I have to de-cripple my DVD's. This makes the ripped illegal copies much more interesting for me, because regardless of the price, I can just pop in the DVD, and watch the movie, like expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same goes for Audio, up to a certain point. When I buy music online, regardless if this is through the or &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windowsmedia/player/stores.aspx?lcid=809">any other WMA selling store&lt;/a>, the store dictates the way I use the audio file. As customer, I feel like I bought a file and I can do with it what I like. As store, they sell you the rights to listen te a recording in a restricted number of ways, a restricted number of times even. That's why I allways try to buy music on a normal audio CD. This gives me the ultimate solution to all problems:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. It is the original regording, in a non-lossy form. I can allways re-rip the audio in any bitrate I see fit for the purpose at hand.
2. I allways have the original and it will last for years as reliable backup. Storing it safely in a cupboard and never using (scratching) it, it will provide me with a 100% safe backup of my digital music library on my Mac, iPod, or USB memory stick player.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If it is not possible to get the music on a normal CD, I can allways resort to people who invent products like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hymn_%28software%29">Hymn (Hear Your Music aNywhere&lt;/a> to remove the DRM for me. As long as I do not copy the file, I see no harm in doing this because the DRM is there to prevent me from doing things I would not easily do anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think crippeling digital content is not the way to protect their content. There will always be people finding methods around this. Furthermore, the prices are very much like the pricing of their physical counterparts, which makes fro very unatractive products. Why would I buy a lossy, digitally crippled version of an audio track I can have on a non-lossy CD for the same price (per track)? The real problem is not being able to proscecute violators of the different copyright acts in various countries. What you actually want to verify is that the user of the audio file has paid some money to the original artist(s). That's the only problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What if the stores selling these audio tracks just gave every song a serial number. No DRM, just a tracking number. The store can administrate which serial number was bought by whom. By doing this, officers at my door can just extract these ID's from my library, upload them to the store and see if I paid for them, or somebody else did. This will probably not be the case for 100% of my tracks (since somebody else could have bought it for me on another computer). To prevent overhead lets say that the law states that 80% of my bought songs should have been bought by myself. If more than 20% of my library is not accountable for, investigation is started and could result in me paying fines for every song in my library which is considered to be an &amp;quot;illegal copy&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole sales model needs to be reinvented, and I think DRM is not the way to go. It has been around for long time, and I have never been tempted enough to buy a track, nor were any of my friends. As music stores go, the iTunes store is about the only store I &lt;em>would&lt;/em> buy tunes from, because this guarantees me that they will be playable on my machine and my music player. Apple is very maticulate about the correct functioning of their hard and software, much more so than Microsoft or any other smack-together-a-WMA-music-store out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Somebody should sue CD labels for producing CDs which can not be played on a computer for exactly the same reasons as in all these other lawsuits. I bought music, and the store has no right deciding when I can do what with it or how many times (no pun intended). I understand they don't like illegal copies, but they can not punish me for making illegal copies before actually doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe music should just be free alltogether, and make it &amp;quot;donation-ware&amp;quot; or something alike. Most artists make more money in a single concert than all the years CD profits. You could see the CD as a commercial. Give it away for free, print the concert dates on it and make people go to your concert!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way this is already what higher powers are doing for us. On every CD-writable I buy in the Netherlands, I pay a fee to &lt;a href="http://www.bumastemra.nl/en-US/Home.htm">buma-stemra&lt;/a>, because I could &lt;em>potentially&lt;/em> place (illegal) music on that CD. If I payed for it allready, then why not do it anyway? I have less and less problems with copying digital content with all these organisations charging fees and taxes for things I did not buy or am not intending to do. There was even a discussion going on about &lt;a href="http://www.portablegear.nl/nieuws/2/120/2533/Nederlands_belastingvoorstel_draait_MP3_de_nek_om.htm">adding mp3 taxes to harddisks&lt;/a> because you can place music in mp3 form on a harddisk. Is that sick or what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the issue is covered by many others allready, and there are no new insights in this article. So I'll just return to my iTunes library, make a few backups and hope they'll never make playback of my tracks impossible...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tangerine BPM Analyzer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/10/22/tangerine-bpm-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 19:51:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/10/22/tangerine-bpm-analyzer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today I discovered &lt;a href="http://www.potionfactory.com/blog/2006/10/18/introducing-tangerine/">Tangerine&lt;/a>, a BPM (Beats Per Minute) analyzer for use with iTunes on a mac. I downloaded it, and it works as advertised. It scans your iTunes music library, and analyzes the BPM (and intensity of the pattern) of each track. It does this in the background, and on my Mac mini Core duo I can continue wih my normal programs while Tangerine analyzes the tracks. The BPM values get saved to your iTunes library, so they will also show up in iTunes if you have the BPM column visible there. The &amp;quot;Intensity&amp;quot; will not be visible in your normal iTunes lists.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![Tangerine Screenshot](o_afbeelding-1.thumbnail.jpg)
&lt;p>](o_afbeelding-1.jpg)Tangerine presents itself with a very iTunes like feel, showing your iTunes playlists on the left, and a track listing will eat the larger part of the top right side. Directly beneath the playlist and track list there is a space in which you can build your playlist. This is a new way of presenting a playlist, which I think is a very welcome way of editting playlists for &lt;a href="http://www.nike.com/nikeplus/">Nike+&lt;/a> owners (which I am not by the way). It shows the tracks played in &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronological">chronological&lt;/a> order, with a timeline at the top (numbers displayed are minutes, see screenshot). This will enable you to plan your workout, since you will know when that 160 BPM track will hit your ears. The only suggestion I have to the evelopers is to put the BPM of the added track below the image, so you can see where the BPM's are going in the playlist. And the &amp;quot;180&amp;quot; I see displayed in the top left makes no sense to me, maybe this needs polishing in the 1.0 version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me as a programmer, this saves me a lot of time finding my &amp;quot;getting in the zone&amp;quot; tracks. It will also prove to be a good tool while creating your iDVD movies or slideshows, helping you find that uptempo track for your great surfing shots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some tracks Tangerine tends to miscalculate the BPM, resulting in values like &amp;quot;4&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;3491234&amp;quot; as BPM. Luckaly, the &amp;quot;intensity&amp;quot; value not only tells something about the contrast the bassdrum has with the rest of the music, but also on how sure Tangerine is about the accuracy of the BPMs. The higher the &amp;quot;intensity&amp;quot;, the more sure Tangerine is about it's BPM. Intensities of 60 and higher are pretty accurate most of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release of Tangerine (0.9.2) is a free beta, so start downloading now! The next release will probably cost a few dollars, I don't expect it to eat your yearly income. As with most Apple software I expect it to sell for between 10 and 30 euro's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Want those CD boxes back?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/04/23/want-those-cd-boxes-back/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 16:11:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/04/23/want-those-cd-boxes-back/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When I used iTunes on XP, I was jealous of the terrific plugins for iTunes running on OS X. Now that I have a Mac Mini, I was looking for a plugin to update the album art automatically. &lt;a href="http://www.zwet.com/">Pim&lt;/a> showed me an even better alternative: &lt;a href="http://www.sprote.com/clutter/">Clutter&lt;/a>! Not only can it search and update album art automatically for you, it also gives you the option to put your albums on your desktop. This is the best virtual alternative to having CD's lying on your desk. A must have for iTunes users I think. Very nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidebar: My file server still runs Windows, and it has been working flawlessly for the past 5 years, being constantly &amp;quot;on&amp;quot; and storing family pictures and music. My laptop is an XP machine and works quite nicely too. So maybe it's because I don't need to, but for now I don't want to &lt;a href="http://zwet.com/2006/04/20/apple-switch-complete-but-the-demon-is-still-here/">install XP on my Mac&lt;/a>. It feels like a step back, it adds a sour taste to your strawberry icecream :-). XP is nice, but not as a desktop. Too much bloatware.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>