<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ichat on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/ichat/</link><description>Recent content in ichat on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 20:32:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/ichat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iChat saves the day</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/05/21/ichat-saves-the-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 20:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/05/21/ichat-saves-the-day/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_bw2.jpg">&lt;img src="o_bw2.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Bruce Willis on iChat">
&lt;/a>So you are on a nice forum, discussing stuff with people you don't even know, or even don't care to get to knowing. They're just there to exchange thoughts with, and you don't even care that he's called &amp;quot;g0d1s.4.f4g&amp;quot; (or worse), and you even don't know if he is a she. Then in comes this guy and actually uses a readable name, tells you who he is, and talks like he talks in real life. No shorthand, no l33t sp33k, just plain English with typo's, like any normal, sane person. Even worse, he claims to be a celebrity, wanting to talk to some of his fans without all the security, press and other stuff.It sounds too good to be true, but for Die Hard fans out there, &lt;a href="http://www.freezedriedmovies.com/blog/index.php?/archives/81-Is-Bruce-Willis-a-talkbacker.html">it has really happened!&lt;/a>. Complete with screenshots of a video iChat session where Bruce Willis prooves who he is to non-believers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/talkback_display/32511">thread itself&lt;/a> is rather lengthy (more than 1000 posts) and contains a lot of off-topic childish crap before the iCat moment, and after that contains even more crap with people posting useless &amp;quot;Oh my god&amp;quot; messages. But there are &lt;a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/talkback_display/32511#comment_1495231">some&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/talkback_display/32511#comment_1496610">funny&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/talkback_display/32511#comment_1500195">comments&lt;/a> if you have the time to skim through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting iChat to work with Googletalk</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/23/getting-ichat-to-work-with-googletalk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 16:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/04/23/getting-ichat-to-work-with-googletalk/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This is probably the 1001st post about this subject, but I can't help thinking that some people actually give up on this. It is a simple protocol, simple program and should be simple to get working. I spent a few hours (!) before I finaly found the solution. I searched the internet but this answer never seems to be given on forums. I'll try to be complete, so here it goes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configure iChat as &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/talk/bin/answer.py?answer=24076">described by Google&lt;/a>. If you still can not connect, there is a good chance you have started the firewall on your mac, and it is blocking iChat. Open the system preferences, and in the &amp;quot;Internet and network&amp;quot; section select &amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;. You will notice a firewall tab in the middle. Select it, and make sure there is a thickmark next to &amp;quot;iChat Bonjour&amp;quot;, like in this screenshot:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_firewall-ichat.gif" alt="iChat settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Sorry for the Dutch layout, I'm sure you'll find it with this pointer.)
This action solved my iChat connection problem. I also installed &lt;a href="http://www.adiumx.com/">Adium&lt;/a>, which also had connection problems. The firewall setting solved the Adium problems aswell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm not sure which chat client to choose. iChat is more integrated into OSX, and imported my google contacts without a problem. Adium did not import any contacts. I'm sticking to iChat for now, hoping that the integration with the rest of the system will give me some pleasant surprises.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh and yes, you've noticed correctly, I've bought a Mac. The desktop PC at home crashed one time too many.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>