<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshop on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/workshop/</link><description>Recent content in Workshop on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 09:56:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Useless Machine</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/12/18/the-useless-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 09:56:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/12/18/the-useless-machine/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The past year, you may have seen me tweeting some &amp;quot;#secretproject&amp;quot; tweets. Last week, the project was finally revealed, and here is the video, in case you've missed it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7nkebVQL5zc]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what is known on the internet as a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z86V_ICUCD4">&amp;quot;Useless Machine&amp;quot;&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.leavemealonebox.com/">&amp;quot;Leave-me-alone Box&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. In case you want to make one, there are plenty of instructions online. I think you can build a basic version of this in about a weekend, and it will cost you less than ten euros. &lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="1-img_0272.jpg">&lt;img src="1-img_0272.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
The tea box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="2-img_0268.jpg">&lt;img src="2-img_0268.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Servo, dismantled&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3-img_9316.jpg">&lt;img src="3-img_9316.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Servo mounted to switch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-img_0294.jpg">&lt;img src="4-img_0294.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Wooden arm on the sander&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-img_9329.jpg">&lt;img src="4-img_9329.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Aluminum arm offset bushing in the lathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="5-img_9331.jpg">&lt;img src="5-img_9331.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Arm mounted on the servo&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="6-img_9337.jpg">&lt;img src="6-img_9337.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Assembly in front of the tea box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="7-img_0314.jpg">&lt;img src="7-img_0314.jpg?w=225" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Cutting the decorative ventilation holes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="8-img_0381.jpg">&lt;img src="8-img_0381.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Painting sanding painting sanding painting sanding...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="8-img_3259.jpg">&lt;img src="8-img_3259.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Assembly painted black for cool looks&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="9-img_3291.jpg">&lt;img src="9-img_3291.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Waiting for glue to set&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3288.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3288.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
Last minute hack: on/off switch for transport&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3305.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3305.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>
The &amp;quot;Useless Machine&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Leave me alone box&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now go build your own. Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anti-fog Helmet Visor Tip</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/04/19/anti-fog-helmet-visor-tip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 20:39:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/04/19/anti-fog-helmet-visor-tip/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="accessories-icon-street-helmet-universal-original-shield-fog-free-light-smoke.jpg" alt="">
In some biker magazines you'll see some cheap journalists write that the &amp;quot;dish washing soap anti-fog is an urban myth&amp;quot;, and that it will &amp;quot;blur your vision&amp;quot;, some may even say it's downright dangerous. This blogpost is to show that if done right, dish washing soap is actually the absolute best anti-fog treatment money can buy. If you've tried this and still don't like it, there are some easier alternatives at the bottom for your convenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**Why this post**
&lt;p>The Netherlands. A damp and cold country where even the most high-tech coated visors fog up at the most inconvenient moments. Particulary at the start of this season it was terrible. Because of the longer and colder than normal winter, I was very eager to get on the bike early. As soon as the snow was gone, I was riding. Because I forgot to take care of the visor, it fogged up. Badly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went out to find ways of preventing the fogging up of the visor. A friend told me that pinlock works, but when the airtight seal is gone, you're in deep trouble. It also adds extra layers of Lexan, meaning more glare. Then, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/cityjohn">@CityJohn&lt;/a> pointed me to FogTech wipes. I ordered a few at &lt;a href="visorvision.co.uk">Visorvision&lt;/a>, and got them very promptly (customer service is A-ok at Visorvision, thanks again Paul!). The wipes work as advertised and add almost unvisible glare to the visor. Good value for money, but the wipes themselves dry out quickly. To keep the effect you have to re-apply the coat, but you will rarely find yourself using the same wipe twice. Not that the price is a problem, but it may become a burden on roadtrips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my surprise, I found a longer lasting solution on my kitchen sink. I heard of the dish washing soap tip before but never actively tried it. To my surprise, with a little care, you can coat the inside of your helmet with this stuff, it will be invisible, and will stay on for at least a week. Even better: your visor will actually become clearer when you breathe against it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Before you do anything:&lt;/strong>_ Check if your visor has a special coating. If this is the case, you are probably better off just cleaning it according to the owners manual. If you're not sure, try this stuff on a small unused part of the visor._&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Clean your visor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1175&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;140&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;The clean visor should fog up evenly when breathing against it&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-30-46.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-30-46.png?w=200" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before applying any product to your visor, you need to carefully clean it. Taking the visor off and washing it with a soft detergent is probably best. On the road this can be a bit more problematic, so you might want to consider taking a damp sponge with you in a watertight bag, and some dry wipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can test if your visor is clean by breathing on it. If it fogs up nice and evenly, it's clean enough for the next step.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 2: Apply (very little!) dishwashing soap&lt;/strong>
Take a soft rag (cotton t-shirt or such) and put a small  drop of washing up liquid on it. The less you apply, the easier the final step will be.&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" align="center" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1177&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;60&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;The Magic Stuff&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-48.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-48.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1178&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Apply a very small drop of detergent on a soft rag to the inside of the visor.&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-12.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-12.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1179&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;After applying, your visor now looks somewhat smudgy, like this.&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-38.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-31-38.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
**Step 3: Buffing**
Take a new, clean, soft rag and gently rub the inside of your visor. You'll see the detergent disappear, and the visor will become clear. As soon as the visor is clear, stop. You don't want to remove all the detergent.
&lt;table width="100%" align="center" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1181&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;100&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Buff the inside of the visor with a clean soft rag&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-08.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-08.png?w=100" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1182&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;99&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Stop when you think it's clear enough&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-33.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-33.png?w=100" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_1183&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;120&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;The result. No visible traces of detergent, clear vision for at least a week.&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-41.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-04-19-om-21-32-41.png?w=120" alt="">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
Now try it. Put your helmet on, close the visor and breathe on it like your neighbors dog after a run in the park. It will not fog up. Nice huh? Imagine how many coats you can do with one bottle of dish washing soap? And you don't even have to take it on the road trip, because every household, hotel or grocery store will have this!
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Advanced tips:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. After a while, very small dirt particles from your breath will attach to the detergent. This can be seen as a light mist, like you also see on the inside of the windshield of your car. You can re-buff the inside of the visor at least once before re-applying the soap, but it has to be absolutely dry before buffing.
2. When you are riding, you might notice you didn't buff the inside quite enough. If it bothers you too much, breathe against your visor to clear it up. Yes, with soap on the visor it will actually become clearer when breathing against it.
3. If you don't have the time to do all this, and are going for quick-and-easy, I'd recommend the FogTech wipes, as mentioned earlier.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Ride safely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wiimote Whiteboard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:28:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/wiimote-whiteboard">&lt;img src="wiimotewhiteboard_128.png" alt="WiimoteWhiteboard">
&lt;/a>For people wanting to have an interactive whiteboard but don't have the money, &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/">Johnny Chung Lee&lt;/a> has found the solution. Using a Wiimote, he can track an infrared lightsource (like an LED) and use that to control the mousecursor. I tried some software on the Mac and the PC, and I actually got both to work without too much trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The infra-red pen&lt;/strong>
Please note that you need some kind of Infra-Red emitting device. In my first tests to see if the software works, I used a TV remote. This is a bit clunky, so next on my list is to build a simple infra-red pen this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I noticed a lot of people building infra-red pens by directly connecting an LED to a battery, which will possibly ruin your LED very quickly because there's too much current running through it. An LED is a diode, and it needs to be limited in current. The only right way to do it is follow &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/pen.jpg">Johnny's schematic&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the Mac:
I was amazed about how well this worked. I was expecting a lot of experimental stuff, but instead, this is all you have to do:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![](afbeelding-21.png?w=47)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](afbeelding-21.png)Download &lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/files/WiimoteWhiteboard.dmg">WiimoteWhiteboard for the Mac&lt;/a> by Uwe Schmidt.
2. Enable bluetooth on your mac.
3. Start the WiimoteWhiteboard.app
4. On the Wiimote, press buttons 1 and 2 simultaniously to put it in &amp;quot;detectable&amp;quot; mode. If the Wiimote was already on, you may need to press the red button in the battery compartment.
5. After pairing is complete, press the &amp;quot;calibrate&amp;quot; button and follow the instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did these steps on an intel  Mac mini and it worked beautifully. You can pair up to 2 Wiimotes to increase reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the PC:
This is slightly more work, but does not include steps which are strange to regular Windows users:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Download and install the [.Net framework version 3.5](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=333325FD-AE52-4E35-B531-508D977D32A6&amp;amp;displaylang=en)
2. Download Boon Jin's [Smoothboard](http://www.boonjin.com/wp/2008/08/14/wiimote-smoothboard-045-beta) for Windows.
3. [![XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 1](clipboard02.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](clipboard02.png)Install the .Net framework, and unpack the smoothboard zipfile in a convenient location. It has no setup.exe (thank god)
4. In the system tray on your Windows, right-click the bluetooth icon, and choose &amp;quot;Add a Bluetooth Device&amp;quot;
5. Click the &amp;quot;My device is set up and ready to be connected&amp;quot; checkbox.
6. &lt;a href="clipboard03.png">&lt;img src="clipboard03.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 2">
&lt;/a>Press the red button of the Wiimote (in the battery compartement) to unpair it from anything else and get into &amp;quot;detecable&amp;quot; mode.
7. Click the &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button in the Wizzard
8. Select the &amp;quot;Nintendo RVL-CNT-01&amp;quot; device and click &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;
9. &lt;a href="clipboard04.png">&lt;img src="clipboard04.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 3">
&lt;/a>Select the &amp;quot;Don't use a passkey&amp;quot; radio button and DON'T press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;.
10. Press the little red button on the Wiimote again, so that all blue lights start flashing, and then press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; on the wizard.
11. In the tray, you should now see popups saying &amp;quot;Found new hardware&amp;quot; and something like &amp;quot;New HID device&amp;quot;. They will dissapear after a while. If the popups did not show, start the whole process again from step 4.
12. Press &amp;quot;Finish&amp;quot; in the Wizard, notice that the Wiimote keeps flashing all the lights.
13. Start Smoothboard. The Wiimote should stop flashing, and you can click on the &amp;quot;Calibrate&amp;quot; button to start the fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="clipboard05.png">&lt;img src="clipboard05.png?w=33" alt="Smoothboard Screenshot">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've tested the Windows setup on a Dell 530 laptop with the built-in bluetooth device, and it works fine, although I did have to reboot once because the bluetooth stack got confused and refused to detect my Wiimote. Smoothboard also allows you to pair 2 Wiimotes to improve reliability. It also has many features which are tailored to controling Powerpoint and other software, but I haven't tried that yet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ducati Desmodesi Supersport</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2005/10/16/ducati-desmodesi-supersport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2005 12:13:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2005/10/16/ducati-desmodesi-supersport/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3368.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3368.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>A few weeks ago I completed a small model of a Ducati race bike. I did do some modelling some years ago, but it gradualy lost my interest. Then, a friend of mine came along and brought this small model of a motobike because I just got my motorbike driverslicense. He didn't expect I'd really build it, but I did, and I think the result is pretty decent, considering it's size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3195.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3195.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>And yes, it was really a model. Here you can see some parts during the build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really got the taste building bikes, so I bought a 1:9 scale Italeri model of a Ducati Monster S4 Fogerty. I will upload images during the build in the next few days/weeks. I also found my old airbrush, and made an adapter to connect it to my compressor. The compressor has a 24 liters airtank, and a pressure reducing device so I can make the pressure going into the brush between 1 and 8 bar. It really works great, and I have allready painted the frame, the tank and the engine of the Ducati Monster with it. More pictures to come!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_airbrush-adapter-1.gif">&lt;/a>Here is a picture of the adapter. On the right, there is a large (1/4&amp;quot;) connector to connect the compressor airhose to. On the left, there is a small connector to which a Badger or Revell airhose can be connected which leads to the airbrush. I got the small connector by destroying the Badger aircan connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_airbrush-adapter-1.gif" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>