<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vacation on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/vacation/</link><description>Recent content in vacation on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 20:06:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/vacation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The €2800,- Roaming Gigabyte</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 20:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjf-6p76rhA">&lt;img src="burnmoney.jpg" alt="T-Mobile is scum">
&lt;/a>We all know the stories about how vacationing smartphone users became the victim of high &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roaming">roaming&lt;/a> charges, resulting in monthly bills sometimes exceeding €1000. To put an end to this, the EU has come up with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_on_roaming_charges_in_the_European_Union">rule&lt;/a> stating that carriers can no longer charge more than €50 per month for roaming, and are obliged to warn the user before reaching this limit. That all sounds nice and consumer friendly, but I recently tested this, and received an &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; monthly bill from T-Mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I've got an iPhone 4, and like many Dutch iPhone users, I got mine with a T-Mobile contract. I always used Vodafone because it has much better coverage, but when the iPhone 3 came out, T-Mobile was the only way to go and after some hesitation, I switched providers. To this day, the network coverage is not as good as Vodafone's, I miss calls even when I have full bars, and even if I can get "3G", the speeds are not nearly as good as friends with iPhones on the Vodafone network.
&lt;p>Having said that, my contract is an old contract which means I have a truly unlimited data plan, for a reasonable price. That is, until you cross the border.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks ago, we went to France for a week of Eurodisney with the kids and grand kids. Because of the project stress at work, and de possibility to share pictures with my parents, I decided to enable roaming on my iPhone. I did try to check the T-Mobile site for data plans and bundles, but these were either not meeting my needs (day passes), or were too hard to compare with each other. I checked my contract and the roaming charges seemed only slightly higher than the blocks, box-packs, travel-smurf, stack-bundles, or whatever convoluted pricing schemes these carriers were trying to trick me in to. I decided to reset the usage info on my iPhone and keep an eye on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2117-all.png">&lt;img src="img_2117-all.png" alt="Welcome to France">
&lt;/a>I crossed the border and received the usual SMS, about rates everybody ignores. I did see that data was €2,- per MB (yes mega-byte) but it looked more like a typo to me, surely they didn't mean mega-byte, did they? During my stay in France, I got he absolute worse network coverage and data speeds you can imagine. No matter where I was, reading text-only email turned into a chore taking sometimes minutes to load. Twitter feeds were barely coming through, and sending a downscaled 100kB image actually took several retries, and multiple minutes. It was horrible. And then, on day 4, it all came to a halt. No SMS, no warning, no mail, no phone call, just total data shutdown. I could still make &lt;a href="http://www.rense.com/general79/metal.htm">robot-voice calls&lt;/a>, but all data traffic stopped and I had no idea how to get that going again. And that turned out to be a good thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2114.png">&lt;img src="img_2114.png?w=100" alt="Data usage">
&lt;/a>I checked my usage, and guessed that I must have crossed the €50,- mark somewhere, and the carrier shut me down to &amp;quot;protect me&amp;quot; from high roaming charges. I tried to SMS a few people to let them know I was still alive, and that was that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks after I got home, I got the bill, and yes, there it was: I had reached the €50,- mark. It was an expensive experiment, and well worth this blogpost. Here's why. On my home &lt;a href="http://www.xs4all.nl/consument/internetbellen/start.php">entry-level 8Mbit ADSL connection&lt;/a>, I have free VOIP, and unlimited data. I checked our ADSL traffic and my family seems to be doing about 20GB a month combined. My monthly bill is €45,- so if I don't use the phone you could say that a GB of traffic costs me (€45 / 20 GB) &lt;strong>€2,25 per GB.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="factuur_30082011.png">&lt;img src="factuur_30082011.png" alt="The amazing T-Mobile roaming charges">
&lt;/a>As you can see in my data usage screenshot on the iPhone, and the bill on the right, I hardly made use of voice or sms. So we can roughly do the same calculation, assuming that 99% of the bill is data. The monthly bill was €89,45, and that got me 31.450MB of data (yes, again: mega-byte). So the price of a roaming Gigabyte in Europe is (€89,45 / 0.031450 GB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>€ 2844,20 per GB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you see is no typo. Almost €3000,- per GB. So what the Phone company is telling me here, is that even though the networks in all countries are reaching right up to the border, and we live in an interconnected world where data travels freely across the globe, phone companies charge more than 1000x the regular price to get a bit of information across that border?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think carriers need to be seriously investigated by the EU and Trading committees, because they are using their monopoly to charge us prices which are totally unrealistic. It also proves that privatization of public services like communication networks doesn't work. It nearly always results in a few greedy companies cobbling up a system which delivers crappy service for an outrageous price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step for these leeches is to come back from &lt;a href="http://rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/">whatever cave they were in&lt;/a>, move forward in time to 2011, and replace the &amp;quot;MB&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;GB&amp;quot; on my bill, without changing anything else. That would &lt;em>still&lt;/em> make them 26% more expensive than my internet provider, but at least it would take the roaming charges to an acceptable level, even for the crappy data speeds they blatantly market as &amp;quot;high speed&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fixing Photo Creation Dates</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.perpetualkid.com/beach-vacation-countdown-timer.aspx">&lt;img src="timr-1003.jpeg" alt="Count down to your vacation">
&lt;/a>You know how it is on vacation. You take your camera, shoot pictures, and when you get home you see that you forgot to set the date/time on your camera. Even worse: your wife also took a camera with her, and she actually read the manual and set the time correctly. So now you have two sets of photos with mismatching date/times. Now what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that there is actually a pretty simple trick to solve this, and you don't even haven to install &lt;a href="http://www.sno.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/index.html">exiftool&lt;/a> or do funny command line voodo. If you have iPhoto and a mouse, here's what you do:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![The Apple Clock](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)Open &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time Preferences&amp;quot; on your Mac and click on the &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time&amp;quot; tab. You should see a clock like the one on the right. With each camera you took on your trip, take a picture of this clock. You don't have to press the shutters all at once, just do this one camera at a time. It also doesn't have to be your Mac's clock, as long as you shoot the same clock with all the cameras.
2. Import the images of all the cameras in iPhoto.
3. Make smart albums (File, New, Smart album…)per Camera type. So if you have a Canon and an Olympus, make one smart album called &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; with only the Canon's photos in it, and one &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album with only the Olympus photo's in it:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png?w=300" alt="iPhoto Smart Album for Canon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png)
4. For each smart album, reverse the sort order so that the photo of the clock you just took is the first in the album. (View, Sort order, Descending).
5. Select all the photo's in the &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; smart album, open the &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; menu, and select &amp;quot;Adjust date and time&amp;quot;. You'll see the clock you shot with this camera in the thumbnail. Copy the time of the clock in the &amp;quot;Adjusted:&amp;quot;field. All other photo's for that camera will be adjusted, because you selected all photo's in the album:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png" alt="iPhoto set date and time">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png)
6. Repeat step 5 for the &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album.
7. Click on the iPhoto &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; library where all your photos are. Your photos should now sync up perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some caveats with this procedure you should remember:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * This only works if nobody changed the date/time settings in the camera between the time they took the photo's and the time you are importing them in iPhoto.
* When cameras are in different time zones, the times will still be off. You'll have to compensate this yourself by adding/subtracting the timezone difference between the camera and the clock of your Mac.
* Remember to select all photos of a specific camera before adjusting the time, or the trick won't work.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Happy editting!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to share Garmin routes with your friends</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/06/30/how-to-share-garmin-routes-with-your-friends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 21:19:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2010/06/30/how-to-share-garmin-routes-with-your-friends/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png" alt="Recalculated route (green) does not match the original (pink)">
I've been struggling to get routes into my Garmin Zūmo® in such a way that it matches the plans of the original author, while at the same time setting the Garmin to &amp;quot;recalculate&amp;quot; so that when I take a wrong turn, it will send me back to the track. After reading a lot on the Garmin forums, and experimenting with this on my two recent road trips (one to Eifel and one to Sauerland in Germany) I can say I have found a way to do this. It's a bit of work, but it will make your trip a lot more trouble-free. Here's the recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Needed:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nice motorcycle route in a GPX or GDB file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www8.garmin.com/support/download_details.jsp?id=4435">Garmin BaseCamp&lt;/a> (BaseCamp 3.0.1.0 for OSX at time of writing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://buy.garmin.com/shop/shop.do?cID=135&amp;amp;pID=15000">Garmin Zūmo®&lt;/a> (model 660 at time of writing)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- more -->**Before you begin:**
&lt;p>Open &amp;quot;Preferences...&amp;quot; in Garmin BaseCamp on the Mac and make sure you selected &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Dinstance&amp;quot;&lt;/em> on the routing tab. This is to prevent routing errors because of changed maximum speeds on different maps. Speeds may differ, but distances are always the same.
On the Zūmo, make sure you matched the BaseCamp routing settings as well as you can.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Import the route&lt;/strong>
You friend sends you a file with a great motorcycle route, in this case &lt;em>&amp;quot;Demo.GPX&amp;quot;&lt;/em>
You import the file into BaseCamp by clicking on &lt;em>&amp;quot;File&amp;quot; -&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Import...&amp;quot;&lt;/em> and selecting the file. Basecamp loads the route and it shows up as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-26-19.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-26-19.png?w=450" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Copy the route&lt;/strong>
In order to make sure your Zūmo will re-calculate the route as your friend intended it, you may need to correct for mismatches in maps, software versions or settings influencing the calculation. To correct the route, we copy it. Select the imported route (it will highlight on the map), right click it and select &lt;em>&amp;quot;Duplicate&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. You should now have 2 routes in the List on the left side of the screen:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-33-11.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-33-11.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, right click the copied route (in this case &lt;em>&amp;quot;Demo Route 1&amp;quot;&lt;/em>) and choose &lt;em>&amp;quot;Get Info&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. On the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Summary&amp;quot;&lt;/em> tab, choose a different color for the copied route, so we know what we are editing. In this case, I choose green.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Recalculate and fix the copy&lt;/strong>
Close the info screen and right-click the copied route again, this time choosing &lt;em>&amp;quot;Recalculate&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. To demonstrate what happens when settings differ, I exported the route with the (wrong) &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Time&amp;quot;&lt;/em> setting, and imported/recalculated it with the (correct) &lt;em>&amp;quot;Shortest Distance&amp;quot;&lt;/em> setting. We see that the copied route is now recalculated and does not match the original:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-40-16.png" alt="Recalculated route (green) does not match the original (pink)">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because your friend will likely be riding the pink route, you want to correct your copy of the route so that both BaseCamp and the Zūmo will send you down the roads you intended to ride. You can do this by selecting the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Selector Tool&amp;quot;&lt;/em> and dragging the green route towards the purple one. Each time you do this, it will create a new waypoint in your copied route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-42-51.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-42-51.png" alt="Selector tool">
&lt;/a>When placing a new waypoint, try to avoid placing waypoints on intersections. This will give both BaseCamp and the Zūmo more room to choose different routes, which you don't want. Think of it this way: You want to be driving on a certain road, not on a certain intersection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you think you are ready, zoom in to about 300m level, and carefully scan the route so that you can correct the final details of the route. Because we selected different colors, the differences are easy to spot, and it's easy to see how to correct them. This is what it looks like when making corrections, note that I'm dragging the new waypoint to the middle of the road, as mentioned earlier:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-49-20.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-49-20.png" alt="Dragging waypoint to correct route">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Fine-tune the waypoints&lt;/strong>
After the route looks as intented, you need to make sure that the waypoints are placed perfectly on the road. This is particularly important on 2-way highways, where a misplaced waypoint can make your Zūmo think you want to be riding in the other direction on this highway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right-click the copied route and select &lt;em>&amp;quot;Get Info&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. If not already selected, choose the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Via Points&amp;quot;&lt;/em> tab and place a checkmark on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Center on Selected&amp;quot;&lt;/em> option. Now click on the first waypoint, and see if it is placed exactly where you want it to be. If it is not, press the &lt;em>&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;&lt;/em> (also called &lt;em>&amp;quot;option&amp;quot;)&lt;/em> key on your keyboard and use the Selector Tool to drag the waypoint to the correct location. Below you can see a misplaced waypoint that needs to be corrected:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-52-51.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-06-16-om-20-52-51.png?w=450" alt="Misaligned waypoint">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Export the route&lt;/strong>
If you placed the copied route in the same List as the original route (like in this example), you might want to delete the original route from the list (or from your Collection if you choose), and save the resulting list into a GPX file. This is an extra safety measure, giving you a backup of the route to take along on your trip on an SD card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have 2 options in BaseCamp for transporting the route to the Zūmo. Either you send it directly to the device, or you save the exported GPX file onto the SD card in the &lt;em>/Garmin/GPX&lt;/em> folder. Doing the latter will enable you to recover from a crashing Zūmo, because you can re-import the route from the SD card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6. Check the imported route in the Zūmo&lt;/strong>
Whether you exported it directly to the Zūmo, or you put it onto the SD card, a few seconds after booting the Zūmo will tell you that it found new user data. You choose &amp;quot;import&amp;quot; and select the route(s) you want to import. I did notice that selecting &amp;quot;&lt;em>Import all&amp;quot;&lt;/em> for larger routes, the Zūmo tells you after 5 routes or so that it failed. This is probably a memory problem. Importing them one-by-one nearly always works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the route is imported and you're still behind your Mac, you might want to compare the route in the Zūmo with the one on your screen. In some cases the Zūmo is still stubborn enough to select a different route. Most of the time this is because of incorrect settings in the Zūmo, causing it to avoid ferries or take the faster route.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Have fun!&lt;/strong>
The most important thing of all this work is to have fun. No matter where Garmin sends you, remember that you're on your bike to have fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you want a Polarizer Filter</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 23:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently bought a 50mm lens with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photographic_filter#Polarizer">circular polarizer&lt;/a>. I though I'd share some quick examples to show what a polarizer filter does for your photo's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarization effect is probably one of the few (if not only) effect which you can not reproduce in photoshop or any other image processing program. Most applications try by increasing saturation, which is nowhere near the effect of a real polarizer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By rotating the filter, you have the luxury of choosing how much effect you want to have, anywhere between 0% and 100%. The shots below give you an idea what the range of the effect is:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_965&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="cluds-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="cluds-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Landscape photographers never leave home without a polarizer. It will render better detail in the clouds, and give better overal colour saturation. When there is a lot of reflection in water, the polarizer should be used with caution. Removing all reflection in favour of a beautiful sky can result in an unrealistic feeling in the shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_966&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="leafs-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="leafs-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A little less obvious, but a great tip to give your portrait shots an extra edge: When you shoot portraits of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marinshe/1130799762/in/set-72157594224391770/">people against foliage&lt;/a>, use your polarizer to get the highlights out of the foliage. This will make sure the viewer is not distracted from the subject. As bonus, the skin tone of your model will be slightly warmer, making your model look &amp;quot;healthier&amp;quot; :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse with portraits you don't want to &amp;quot;overdo&amp;quot; it. It's easu to over-saturate the photo, and the polarizer will &amp;quot;eat&amp;quot; one to two stops of light, which will make it harder to keep everything crispy sharp. I think I'd go for the (much cheaper) &amp;quot;magic hour&amp;quot; and a little fill-flash instead of a polarizer, but sometimes there is no choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarizer I used here is a 58mm circular polarizer from Tiffen, which you can find for just above €40,- new, which is quite a bargain. If your glass has a larger mount, the filters can get pretty expensive (€150 and up), probably because it is harder to get an even polarization effect over a larger piece of glass with light coming in from a wider angle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A polarizer filter needs to be rotated to get the right effect, so it's nice if the front element of your lens does not rotate during focussing. In the case of the Canon 50mm lenses (th f1.2, the f1.4, and the f1.8), the front element will not rotate. The f1.2 will even not extend during focussing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other dramatic examples of shots using polarizers are &lt;a href="http://shutterbug.com/equipmentreviews/accessories/0109hoya/">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.travel-to-crete.com/gallery_images/395.jpg">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://i3.photobucket.com/albums/y51/Rayfromalaska/fall8.jpg">here&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.photographyiseasy.com/blg/273/polarizing-filters--do-you-need-one.html">here&lt;/a>. A nice combo-filter comparison is &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/jpeper/image/32267513/original.jpg">here&lt;/a>. (Links to external sites, get them while they last!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Linear Polarier
A linear polarizer is a single piece of glass which only passes light which is polarized in 1 direction. Reflected light normally tends to polarize parpendicular to the surface it reflected from. So a lake will produce horizontally polarized light, and a window vertically polarized light. You can choose to filter this out bu rotating your linear polarizer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Circular Polarizer
**Some camera's make use of partial reflection in their metering or focussing systems. Since reflection means polerization, you can get into trouble if there is a linear polarizer in front of your camera. In some orientations, light will not be able to be reflected into the metering system, which renders it useless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To circumvent this problem, we need to convert the linear polarized light into circular polarized light (hence the name circular polarizer). This is done by adding an extra piece of glass behind the linear polarizer. This extra piece of glass is called a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_plate">&amp;quot;Quarter Wave Plate&amp;quot;&lt;/a> which turns linear polarized light into circular polarized light. This allows your metering system to reflect it as if it were normal light coming into the lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Quarter Wave Plate is expensive to make, and it needs to be neatly glued to the linear polarizer in front of it. That's why circular polarizers are generally more expensive. It is also why linear polarizers are observed to be &amp;quot;more effective&amp;quot;, because it's simply a thicker polarizer. The Circular Polarizer needs to have 2 pieces of glass in the same space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So to sum it up: Linear Polarizer is a single sheet of glass, while a Circular Polarizer is a Linear Polarizer with a Quarter Wave Plate glued to it (Over-simplified ofcourse). The only reason to buy a circular polarizer is because your metering system requires it. This is the case in most DSLRs, but not in many point and shoots.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shooting 16:9 with a 4:3 Camera</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 10:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you have a Canon Ixus 80IS, like me, and you shoot video for your widescreen television at home (like me), you may want to try out this little trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canon Ixus is a 4:3 camera. The video that comes out of it is almost square shaped. When you try to make a 16:9 video, you can stretch it, or crop it. Cropping is far better, but you need some &amp;quot;headroom&amp;quot; to do that. If you made a closeup, chances are that you do not have enough room to crop to a 16:9 format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aspect-ratios.jpg">&lt;img src="aspect-ratios.jpg?w=150" alt="aspect-ratios">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I solved this by making this little chart, which I placed on a memorycard and put in my camera. By previewing the image on the camera's display, you know where the &amp;quot;16:9 limit&amp;quot; is. I put two pieces of half-translucent tape on the camera, so I can tell what fit's inside the 16:9 frame. I also included the other formats, like 3:2, and 2.39:1, should you want to make wide-screen theater movies :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I load up the movie in iMovie, and it will be cropped perfectly. Suppose you missed the 16:9 frame or want to re-center your shot, you can always press the &amp;quot;crop&amp;quot; button in your project to tell iMovie which piece of the image you want.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New York online...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/06/04/new-york-online/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 17:37:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/06/04/new-york-online/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We have returned from our trip to New York. Actually, we've been staying in Weehawken, New Jersey to visit Manhattan. Today I maxed out my upload limit for this month to put the pictures online. You can see them at &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/album/3167072">my 32hq account&lt;/a> (because &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/10/12/23-kicks-flickrs-ass/">Flickr hurts my eyes&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy the pictures. When the monthly upload limit expires I'll upload some more, so maybe it's wise to subscribe to &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rss/rolfje">my photo feed&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1 week Gran Canaria</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/09/27/1-week-gran-canaria/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 19:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/09/27/1-week-gran-canaria/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week in Gran Canaria, I...&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Shot 158 photo's, some of which available [here&amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;](http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/2507668/view-large?album%5fid=2507681)
* Walked approx. 35 km while checking out Maspalomas and Playa del Ingles:[
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.png" alt="Google Map">
](&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;hl=nl&amp;amp;geocode=18135507299316498239,27.757912,-15.580931%3B8148948577166084863,27.738580,-15.598140&amp;amp;saddr=Av+de+los+Estados+Unidos+%4027.757940,+-15.580840&amp;amp;daddr=&amp;amp;mra=mr&amp;amp;sll=27.748076,-15.582862&amp;amp;sspn=0.032093,0.040383&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;ll=27.753127,-15.583248&amp;amp;spn=0.06426,0.07596&amp;amp;z=14)%5B">http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;hl=nl&amp;amp;geocode=18135507299316498239,27.757912,-15.580931%3B8148948577166084863,27.738580,-15.598140&amp;amp;saddr=Av+de+los+Estados+Unidos+%4027.757940,+-15.580840&amp;amp;daddr=&amp;amp;mra=mr&amp;amp;sll=27.748076,-15.582862&amp;amp;sspn=0.032093,0.040383&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;ll=27.753127,-15.583248&amp;amp;spn=0.06426,0.07596&amp;amp;z=14)[&lt;/a>
](&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;hl=nl&amp;amp;geocode=18135507299316498239,27.757912,-15.580931%3B8148948577166084863,27.738580,-15.598140&amp;amp;saddr=Av+de+los+Estados+Unidos+%4027.757940,+-15.580840&amp;amp;daddr=&amp;amp;mra=mr&amp;amp;sll=27.748076,-15.582862&amp;amp;sspn=0.032093,0.040383&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;ll=27.753127,-15.583248&amp;amp;spn=0.05317,0.072956&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;source=embed">http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;amp;hl=nl&amp;amp;geocode=18135507299316498239,27.757912,-15.580931%3B8148948577166084863,27.738580,-15.598140&amp;amp;saddr=Av+de+los+Estados+Unidos+%4027.757940,+-15.580840&amp;amp;daddr=&amp;amp;mra=mr&amp;amp;sll=27.748076,-15.582862&amp;amp;sspn=0.032093,0.040383&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;ll=27.753127,-15.583248&amp;amp;spn=0.05317,0.072956&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;source=embed&lt;/a>)
* Found out that on Gran Canaria, you want to eat at Danish restaurants, particularly those that don't have the irritating waiters walking outside to talk people into eating at their restaurant.
* Played &amp;quot;Everybody's Golf&amp;quot; from beginner to EG Instructor level. Everybody's Golf is also known as &lt;a href="http://www.metacritic.com/games/platforms/psp/hotshotsgolf?q=everybody%27s%20golf">Hot Shots Golf: Open Tee&lt;/a>.
* Added ratings to 374 (three hundred and seventy four) songs, exhausting my &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/archive/2007/08/01/268856.aspx">&amp;quot;never played&amp;quot; playlist&lt;/a> for the first time.
* Saw a lot of people happily walking on their butt-ugly, fluorescent green or pink &lt;a href="http://www.crocs.eu/shop/step1/details.php?id=10001&amp;amp;lang=EN&amp;amp;Itemid=0">&amp;quot;Crocs&amp;quot;&lt;/a>.
* Amazed myself at how much room a baby needs on a plane, and how many people need to get out of the way to change diapers at the very same place the food is prepared (no thank you, just coffee please).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>