<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>photo on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/photo/</link><description>Recent content in photo on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:34:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/photo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing Photo Creation Dates</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.perpetualkid.com/beach-vacation-countdown-timer.aspx">&lt;img src="timr-1003.jpeg" alt="Count down to your vacation">
&lt;/a>You know how it is on vacation. You take your camera, shoot pictures, and when you get home you see that you forgot to set the date/time on your camera. Even worse: your wife also took a camera with her, and she actually read the manual and set the time correctly. So now you have two sets of photos with mismatching date/times. Now what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that there is actually a pretty simple trick to solve this, and you don't even haven to install &lt;a href="http://www.sno.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/index.html">exiftool&lt;/a> or do funny command line voodo. If you have iPhoto and a mouse, here's what you do:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![The Apple Clock](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)Open &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time Preferences&amp;quot; on your Mac and click on the &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time&amp;quot; tab. You should see a clock like the one on the right. With each camera you took on your trip, take a picture of this clock. You don't have to press the shutters all at once, just do this one camera at a time. It also doesn't have to be your Mac's clock, as long as you shoot the same clock with all the cameras.
2. Import the images of all the cameras in iPhoto.
3. Make smart albums (File, New, Smart album…)per Camera type. So if you have a Canon and an Olympus, make one smart album called &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; with only the Canon's photos in it, and one &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album with only the Olympus photo's in it:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png?w=300" alt="iPhoto Smart Album for Canon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png)
4. For each smart album, reverse the sort order so that the photo of the clock you just took is the first in the album. (View, Sort order, Descending).
5. Select all the photo's in the &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; smart album, open the &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; menu, and select &amp;quot;Adjust date and time&amp;quot;. You'll see the clock you shot with this camera in the thumbnail. Copy the time of the clock in the &amp;quot;Adjusted:&amp;quot;field. All other photo's for that camera will be adjusted, because you selected all photo's in the album:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png" alt="iPhoto set date and time">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png)
6. Repeat step 5 for the &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album.
7. Click on the iPhoto &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; library where all your photos are. Your photos should now sync up perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some caveats with this procedure you should remember:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * This only works if nobody changed the date/time settings in the camera between the time they took the photo's and the time you are importing them in iPhoto.
* When cameras are in different time zones, the times will still be off. You'll have to compensate this yourself by adding/subtracting the timezone difference between the camera and the clock of your Mac.
* Remember to select all photos of a specific camera before adjusting the time, or the trick won't work.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Happy editting!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you want a Polarizer Filter</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 23:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently bought a 50mm lens with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photographic_filter#Polarizer">circular polarizer&lt;/a>. I though I'd share some quick examples to show what a polarizer filter does for your photo's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarization effect is probably one of the few (if not only) effect which you can not reproduce in photoshop or any other image processing program. Most applications try by increasing saturation, which is nowhere near the effect of a real polarizer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By rotating the filter, you have the luxury of choosing how much effect you want to have, anywhere between 0% and 100%. The shots below give you an idea what the range of the effect is:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_965&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="cluds-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="cluds-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Landscape photographers never leave home without a polarizer. It will render better detail in the clouds, and give better overal colour saturation. When there is a lot of reflection in water, the polarizer should be used with caution. Removing all reflection in favour of a beautiful sky can result in an unrealistic feeling in the shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_966&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="leafs-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="leafs-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A little less obvious, but a great tip to give your portrait shots an extra edge: When you shoot portraits of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marinshe/1130799762/in/set-72157594224391770/">people against foliage&lt;/a>, use your polarizer to get the highlights out of the foliage. This will make sure the viewer is not distracted from the subject. As bonus, the skin tone of your model will be slightly warmer, making your model look &amp;quot;healthier&amp;quot; :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse with portraits you don't want to &amp;quot;overdo&amp;quot; it. It's easu to over-saturate the photo, and the polarizer will &amp;quot;eat&amp;quot; one to two stops of light, which will make it harder to keep everything crispy sharp. I think I'd go for the (much cheaper) &amp;quot;magic hour&amp;quot; and a little fill-flash instead of a polarizer, but sometimes there is no choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarizer I used here is a 58mm circular polarizer from Tiffen, which you can find for just above €40,- new, which is quite a bargain. If your glass has a larger mount, the filters can get pretty expensive (€150 and up), probably because it is harder to get an even polarization effect over a larger piece of glass with light coming in from a wider angle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A polarizer filter needs to be rotated to get the right effect, so it's nice if the front element of your lens does not rotate during focussing. In the case of the Canon 50mm lenses (th f1.2, the f1.4, and the f1.8), the front element will not rotate. The f1.2 will even not extend during focussing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other dramatic examples of shots using polarizers are &lt;a href="http://shutterbug.com/equipmentreviews/accessories/0109hoya/">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.travel-to-crete.com/gallery_images/395.jpg">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://i3.photobucket.com/albums/y51/Rayfromalaska/fall8.jpg">here&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.photographyiseasy.com/blg/273/polarizing-filters--do-you-need-one.html">here&lt;/a>. A nice combo-filter comparison is &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/jpeper/image/32267513/original.jpg">here&lt;/a>. (Links to external sites, get them while they last!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Linear Polarier
A linear polarizer is a single piece of glass which only passes light which is polarized in 1 direction. Reflected light normally tends to polarize parpendicular to the surface it reflected from. So a lake will produce horizontally polarized light, and a window vertically polarized light. You can choose to filter this out bu rotating your linear polarizer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Circular Polarizer
**Some camera's make use of partial reflection in their metering or focussing systems. Since reflection means polerization, you can get into trouble if there is a linear polarizer in front of your camera. In some orientations, light will not be able to be reflected into the metering system, which renders it useless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To circumvent this problem, we need to convert the linear polarized light into circular polarized light (hence the name circular polarizer). This is done by adding an extra piece of glass behind the linear polarizer. This extra piece of glass is called a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_plate">&amp;quot;Quarter Wave Plate&amp;quot;&lt;/a> which turns linear polarized light into circular polarized light. This allows your metering system to reflect it as if it were normal light coming into the lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Quarter Wave Plate is expensive to make, and it needs to be neatly glued to the linear polarizer in front of it. That's why circular polarizers are generally more expensive. It is also why linear polarizers are observed to be &amp;quot;more effective&amp;quot;, because it's simply a thicker polarizer. The Circular Polarizer needs to have 2 pieces of glass in the same space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So to sum it up: Linear Polarizer is a single sheet of glass, while a Circular Polarizer is a Linear Polarizer with a Quarter Wave Plate glued to it (Over-simplified ofcourse). The only reason to buy a circular polarizer is because your metering system requires it. This is the case in most DSLRs, but not in many point and shoots.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shooting 16:9 with a 4:3 Camera</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 10:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you have a Canon Ixus 80IS, like me, and you shoot video for your widescreen television at home (like me), you may want to try out this little trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canon Ixus is a 4:3 camera. The video that comes out of it is almost square shaped. When you try to make a 16:9 video, you can stretch it, or crop it. Cropping is far better, but you need some &amp;quot;headroom&amp;quot; to do that. If you made a closeup, chances are that you do not have enough room to crop to a 16:9 format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aspect-ratios.jpg">&lt;img src="aspect-ratios.jpg?w=150" alt="aspect-ratios">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I solved this by making this little chart, which I placed on a memorycard and put in my camera. By previewing the image on the camera's display, you know where the &amp;quot;16:9 limit&amp;quot; is. I put two pieces of half-translucent tape on the camera, so I can tell what fit's inside the 16:9 frame. I also included the other formats, like 3:2, and 2.39:1, should you want to make wide-screen theater movies :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I load up the movie in iMovie, and it will be cropped perfectly. Suppose you missed the 16:9 frame or want to re-center your shot, you can always press the &amp;quot;crop&amp;quot; button in your project to tell iMovie which piece of the image you want.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DLNA on OSX, done right</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PlayStation_3">&lt;img src="200x150_playstation3_logo1.jpg" alt="Sony PS3 Logo">
&lt;/a>My wife bought me a playstation 3 last year, and I've enjoyed many hours of gaming on it, finishing Tomb Raider underworld, and now making decent progress in Ratchet and Clank: Tools of Destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dlna.org/home">&lt;img src="afbeelding-22.png" alt="DLNA logo">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a bit sceptical about the DLNA capabilities of the PS3, because I read a lot of bad news on this fairly new  &amp;quot;Interoperability Guidelines&amp;quot; concept. It sounded like a lot of trouble to go through to simply watch the photos and home videos on a TV. For weeks, I was not able to find a single site telling me how to install a DLNA server on my Mac, or where to find a decent one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Altgough they're hard to find, there are a few OSX DLNA servers out there. One of them is actually very good. Here's what I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**CyberMediaGate**
&lt;p>I found a DLNA server implemented in Java, and didn't get it to work. It misses a Xerces library and I can not seem to get the right version added to the classpath. I decided this was not very &amp;quot;Mac like&amp;quot; and dumped it. Not being able to install software &amp;quot;out of the box&amp;quot; may be normal on Linux, but is unaccepatble on a Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TwonkyMedia&lt;/strong>
Then, I came across TwonkyMedia. This was the first DLNA server I actually got to work on my Mac, and had it serving video to my PS3. It is a strange (wonky?) piece of software, had no native GUI and only lives on your machine as a webapplication. The installer copies &amp;quot;TwonkyMediaServer.app&amp;quot; in your application folder, starts it, and then opens a browser which points to the local URL of it's configuration screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that moment, it already is serving clients, but when you try to access it with the PS3, you will get a protocol error. This is because TwonkyMedia does not come with a default server name. The PS3 aparently can not handle an empty server name. After filling it in and restarting Twonky, I could access it with the PS3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TwonkyMedia does not look very Mac-like, and I don't like the looks of the webpage it is serving. The installer leaves two webloc files on your desktop which point to the configuration screens. It's a bit strange but it gets the job done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Potentially Twonky can do a bit more than CyberMediaGate. Twonky can do some transcoding and other streaming stuff, but I did not try that because I simply wanted to see my photo's and home video's on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trial version of Twonkymedia last for 30 days, but on the first day it already started acting up on me, and I had to restart it a few times while watching video. The look and feel, and the crashes didn't feel like it was worth the $40 to me, so I uninstalled it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uninstalling TwonkyMedia requires you to kill the process from the Terminal, and then drag TwonkyMediaServer.app to your trashcan. Another way is dragging the app to the trashcan and then restarting your Mac (not mac-like but it works).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>MediaLink&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink">&lt;img src="printablelogo.png" alt="Nullriver Logo">
&lt;/a>The nullriver homepage looked very elegant, and promising. A simple page explains what it is, what it does, and what it costs. Nullriver also allows you to send requests and reports on their site without registering (in contract with TwonkyMedia, to which you have to &amp;quot;sell your soul&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nullriver Medialink comes as a preference pane application, and has a beautifuly simple interface, with not many options. It integrates with your mac applications like iTunes, iPhoto and now even Aperture. It does not have all the fancy configuration options of TwonkyMedia. One of my small complaints is that your content is shared to all DLNA clients on your local network, which may not be what you want if you have more than one DLNA client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me MediaLink is a perfect fit. I control my own network, my PS3 is my only DLNA client so I don't need the fancy stuff. Most people will be perfectly happy with Medialink. It's simple, transparent, drag-and-drop, has a &amp;quot;stop&amp;quot; button and is cheap. It does not have all the fancy features, but all the features that are in there work flawlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played with it for more than a week now, and so far it hasn't crashed on me. I did need to buy a registration key, because the trial version only lasts you for about 30 minutes of watching content (which should be plenty to try it out, and it's not like the 20 bucks are going to kill you).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
Once again, all DLNA servers I tried put together:&lt;/p>
&lt;table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="1" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[CyberMediaGate](http://www.cybergarage.org/net/cmgate/java/index.html)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Free
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Terrible, unable to install.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[TwonkyMedia](http://www.twonkyvision.de/)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$40
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Works, lots of features, no GUI, buggy/ Crashed on me more than once.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[MediaLink](http://www.nullriver.com/products/medialink)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >$20
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Simple, stable, nice GUI, best value for money. Just works.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
So if you have a PS3 and a Mac, it's a no-brainer. Buy Medialink!</description></item><item><title>Zoom Experience 2008</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/11/11/zoom-experience-2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 22:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/11/11/zoom-experience-2008/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last sunday, I was at the &lt;a href="http://www.zoomexperience.nl/">Zoom Experience 2008&lt;/a> in Utrecht. The organization has learned a lot since last year's debute of the Zoom Experience. There was plenty of room to walk, lots of places to sit down and talk, and the talks were in seperate areas with less noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what the Zoom Experience looked like on Sunday morning:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qy8mXREd7Lo]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New York online...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/06/04/new-york-online/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 17:37:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/06/04/new-york-online/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We have returned from our trip to New York. Actually, we've been staying in Weehawken, New Jersey to visit Manhattan. Today I maxed out my upload limit for this month to put the pictures online. You can see them at &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/album/3167072">my 32hq account&lt;/a> (because &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/10/12/23-kicks-flickrs-ass/">Flickr hurts my eyes&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy the pictures. When the monthly upload limit expires I'll upload some more, so maybe it's wise to subscribe to &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rss/rolfje">my photo feed&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>23 Kicks Flickr's ass!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/12/23-kicks-flickrs-ass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 19:22:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/10/12/23-kicks-flickrs-ass/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Since Wordpress has a 50MB space limit for images uploaded to the blog, I was looking for a place to host my galleries. Some friends of mine have &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/">Flickr&lt;/a> accounts but I really hate it's cluttered and non-intuitive user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday evening I found a very good alternative to Flickr, which actually is much cooler. It has all the features Flickr has, but it's user interface is much, much more intuitive, and less cluttered. It's fast, free and has a very cool upload feature which lets you edit the photo's as they're uploading! It's an amaing feature you'd have to see for yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And where can you find all this wonderfull stuff? It's at &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/">www.23hq.com&lt;/a>. Try it out, it's completely free, has no userspace or download limitation, and no spam is sent to you. The only limitation to free accounts is that you can upload maximum 30 photo's per month. But don't worry, you can upload 300 photo's the first week to get your account started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leave that Flickr account and join &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com">&lt;img src="logo.thumbnail.gif" alt="23 logo">
&lt;/a> !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My photo's on your wall</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/12/24/my-photos-on-your-wall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2006 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/12/24/my-photos-on-your-wall/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3077.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3077.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Jeroen Bleekemolen, A1 GP Zandvoort 2006">
&lt;/a>Hi, I just discovered oypo.nl, an online service for photographers to sell prints of their photographs. It's a simple concept, where a photographer uploads images, and the website sells prints of these images to anybody who orders them. Part of the commision is going back to the photographer, and to some extent the photographer can decide how expensive his photograps are to the public.Because opening an account is free, and because I think my photo's are WAY better than most of the material on oypo.nl, I decided to open an account just for fun. If you like to buy my photographs, take a look at them at&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://rolfje.oypo.nl/">rolfje.oypo.nl&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resolution of he shots should give good to very good results on near poster format, and I try to keep the choice simple by only uploading the interesting ones. Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nice Mac Tools</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/12/21/nice-mac-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/12/21/nice-mac-tools/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As a Mac user, I have absolutely no problem editting, moving and viewing large video, audio and image files. There was one thing I missed though, and that is a tool which is able to quickly view a large JPG (like OSX's own preview) but then skip to the next image in the directory when selecting &amp;quot;next&amp;quot;. Today I have found just that tool, and it is a dream to work with. It called &lt;a href="http://www.macupdate.com/info.php/id/19978">Xee&lt;/a> (not to be confused with the rather lame Xsee).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Xee loads jpg's blindingly fast from my remote fileserver. Then, using just the keyboard, I can easily zoom in, out, skip to the next or previous file in the directory, fit the image to screen, etc. After testing about 20 or so image viewers, It is absolutely the best image viewer I have found.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the search for Xee, I also encountered the &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/frakes/MOSXPT/content/software.html">OSX Power Tools&lt;/a> page, which is a list of very handy utilities for the Mac, and from what I can see all of them are free to use (check license to be sure).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flw.com/merry.htm">Merry Christmas!&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Curing lens envy</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/08/29/curing-lens-envy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 14:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/08/29/curing-lens-envy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Do you still want &amp;quot;that last lens and that's it&amp;quot;? According to the statistics on &lt;a href="http://medfmt.8k.com/bronlensenvy.html">this page&lt;/a>, you probably already have the right lens in your camera bag. Chances are that you are using your cheapest lens most often. The best quote from this page must be &lt;strong>&amp;quot;The cost of the lens is inversely proportional to the frequency of its use.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where did I get that link from? Well, from a brilliant text by Ken Rockwel titled &lt;a href="http://kenrockwell.com/tech/notcamera.htm">&amp;quot;Your Camera Does Not Matter&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. It states that you may not only have overspent on lenses, but on your complete kit alltogether! According to Ken, &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Buying new gear will NOT improve your photography.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="t_img_0303.jpg" alt="Watching the “Odobenus rosmarus” swim">
Next time you see a guy with a D200, don't be impressed. The guy behind him with his old &lt;a href="http://www.apogeephoto.com/july2001/plastic_fantastic.shtml">Holga&lt;/a> camera could be shooting far better pictures!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have had a &lt;a href="http://www.photo.net/ezshop/product?product_id=280">Canon EOS 300 (35mm film)&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/powershot_a20">Canon Powershot A20&lt;/a> and now a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/eos_350d">Canon 350D&lt;/a>. I also have made photo's with some of my dad's camera's, a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/ft_ql">Canon FT-QL&lt;/a>, and an &lt;a href="http://www.classiccamera.com.pl/exa2b.html">Exa IIB&lt;/a>. When changing from one camera to another, my photography (in particular composition) did not change. It just took some trouble away from the process. EOS 200 to Canon A20: no more film hassle. Canon A20 to 350D: Faster bootup and shot-to-shot times. Canon FT-QL and Exa IIB: The romantic feeling of craftsmanship when holding the camera :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="t_img_0223.jpg" alt="Hedge sparrow on a fence, at 200mm, aperture 5.6">
Sure the 350D gives me nice resolution and more freedom to play with aperture and exposure times and I still like the camera after reading Kens article. But he is right. Period. I recently spoke to a guy who owned an EOS 300 just like I did. He looked at one of my photo's from the 350D and said &amp;quot;I've got to have that camera, how did you do that?&amp;quot;. I explained &amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot; to him and told him that he could do that with his own EOS 300 if he had taken the time to learn how to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess some sales people translate &amp;quot;I want a good camera&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;I want to spend a truckload of cash on a camera of which I'll only use the full-auto mode to shoot pictures of uncle Zed with.&amp;quot; People who don't know what &amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;exposure time&amp;quot; means just want a snapshot camera which automatically will produce clear, colorful, crisp foto's of uncle Zed 95% of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before buying a camera, read Ken's article, get out of that chair and start shooting with whatever camera you have right now. That one brilliant moment is waiting for you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Beanbag!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/07/21/free-beanbag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 15:11:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/07/21/free-beanbag/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When you are using a (digital) camera and need to place it on an uneven surface to keep it still long enough for your long shutter speeds, or you want to make a shot on the release timer (or both), you'll need a tripod, or a &lt;a href="http://www.shortcourses.com/equipment/tripods/beanbag.jpg">beanbag&lt;/a>. A beanbag is an ideal option, you can tuck it into your backpack, take it everywhere you need and it fits all camera's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, you can buy a beanbag from a nice company like &lt;a href="http://www.wildlifewatchingsupplies.co.uk/">this&lt;/a>, and spend about 30 euro's or more. But, If you've got a needle, thread, a T-shirt or linnen bag, and some rice, you can make one for free!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->![Beanbag materials](o_img_8641.jpg)
&lt;p>Start by sacrificing your linnen bag or t-shirt, cutting out two square pieces of about 23x23cm (or larger if you want to support a larger camera/lens combination). As you can see here, I saved me some sewing because I used the corner of a linnen bag. Now I only had to stich up 2 sides of the &amp;quot;pillow&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Put the two pieces on top of eachother and sew them together. Don't worry about being close to the edges, leave plenty of room there, because you will turn it inside-out later on. To be able to turn it inside-out and fill it with rice (or other forms of &amp;quot;beads&amp;quot;), leave about 7cm on one edge un-sewed. I also recommend to leave the hole in the middle of an edge. This way you'll have 4 nice sharp corners on the bag lateron.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn the bag inside out. Now the edges look nicer, don't they? Roll up a piece of A4 paper and put it in the hole of your bag, and make it into a funnel. Poor the beads (rice, dries peas or beans, or fatboy filling) into the funnel. Make sure you don't fill the bag totally, because then it will not be flexible enough. I used about 1kg of rice for mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_8647.jpg" alt="Beanbag finished">
Close the bag by sewing the last opening. This takes some attention, this is the part of your sewing which could be visible. You can see where I closed the bag at the bottom right of the picture with the Powershot on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beanbag I made supports my Canon EOS 350D perfectly. There are a few improvements on my list after making it. My next beanbag will:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * be made of a black t-shirt so it's less reflecting
* be filled with [fatboy filling](http://www.serenityhealth.com/bean_filler.html) to prevent problems when getting the bag wet (rice stinks :-)
* be slightly bigger
* will contain a zipper or velcro on the opening so I can (re)fill it
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now make one of your own and go and use the 30 euro's you just saved to buy nice UV lens filters. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_8648.jpg" alt="Beanbag with Canon A20">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_5926.jpg" alt="Beanbag with Canon 350D">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sharpening, denoizing, smoothing, enhancing, vandalizing!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/07/17/sharpening-denoizing-smoothing-enhancing-vandalizing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 15:23:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/07/17/sharpening-denoizing-smoothing-enhancing-vandalizing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To every photo-editing, image-manipulating, red-eye-reducing software developer on the planet: Sharpening photographs by default is NOT a good idea! If images aren't sharp directly from the camera, there was something wrong with them to begin with. Most camera's nowadays make fine pictures which don't need sharpening.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Reason for this post is that just a few minutes ago, I was wondering why my new (and expensive) Canon 350D still showed noise in blue skies, even at 100 ISO. It turned out not to be noise. It was [Lightroom](http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/lightroom/) (the public Beta application for OSX) tries to "Sharpen" and "Smooth" the images by default, and not by a small amount, I might add. So the little dust particles which were perfectly captured by my excelent camera with that excelent lens, were (cough) "enhanced", after which the very nice flat-blue sky turned in to a freckle disaster. I also heard that [Rawshooter](http://www.pixmantec.com/products/rawshooter.asp) does the exact same thing. It's really a shame, because a good lens, a good camera, some experience and a little effort should produce sharp photo's to begin with.
&lt;p>Sure I like the &amp;quot;digital darkroom&amp;quot; idea of being able to do some post-processing of photographs, but I am convinced of the fact that you should have quality material to begin with (meaning a good photo). I think that for every minute you spend trying to make a great shot with the camera in your hand, you save 15 minutes trying to correct mistakes with a mouse in your hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I am not a star photographer. Yes, I need to tweak some photo's to get the effect I was looking for with the camera. Yes, I am trying to learn to do it directly with aperture and shutter speed, and yes, that takes a lot of time and effort because no, I'm not a natural :-) . Just venting some furstrations here. Sorry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Photo Statistics</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/06/21/photo-statistics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 15:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/06/21/photo-statistics/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I am trying to decide what lens to buy for my Canon EOS 350D. The first descision to make is what focal length I need. To do this, I found a nice tool which can display statistical info about your photographs. It shows you how many foto's you've made at certain focal lengths, with which aperture, ISO, metering, and other EXIF fields. It's a windows only tool, and it's called &lt;a href="http://www.softsymphony.com/photostat_descr.htm">Smart Photo Statistics&lt;/a>. It's absolutely 100% free software and works as expected. It can even copy the graphs to the clipboard for you to use elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm gathering statistics right now on all photo's of all digital camera's I've owned, to see what focal lentgths I need. Great tool!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Canon 350D B/W Sepia</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/06/03/canon-350d-bw-sepia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2006 15:44:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2006/06/03/canon-350d-bw-sepia/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Once in a while I like to take black and white pictures because the EOS has a nice built in set of color filters. The easiest example of a nice black and white photo where a color filter produces great results is the classic &amp;quot;blue sky with Yellow filter&amp;quot;. You should really check out the great tutorials on &lt;a href="http://www.cambridgeincolour.com/tutorials.htm">Cambridge in Color&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="r_canon-color.jpg" alt="350D Sepia">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When shooting in B/W mode, I often use the &amp;quot;sepia&amp;quot; filter, to add a little warmth to the photo. A wierd thing I noticed lately about the EOS 350D (besides the film transport sound) is that &amp;quot;Sepia&amp;quot; mode is not really producing pure B/W Sepia images. There is color seeping through! In the top image, you can clearly see residues of red, yellow and blue in a photo of a baby toy (cropped for privacy reasons). The bottom image is converted to pure B/W on a computer and then sort of &amp;quot;Sepia&amp;quot;-d using a hue/saturation tool just for reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read on some forums that camera effects are generally not as good as the effects in image processing programs like PhotoShop or GIMP. This is supposedly because speed/quality tradeoffs. I really like to spend more time with the camera than post-processing, so I'd like to keep using the in-camera effects. A great tip I read somewhere on a forum is to shoot in RAW+JPG mode. The JPG will have all the processing done by the camera, and the RAW will be the raw data from the sensor. Depending on the results of the in-camera effects, you either keep the JPG, or use the RAW image to do the effect in GIMP later on.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>