<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quote on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/quote/</link><description>Recent content in quote on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 11:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/quote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Three Great Virtues of a Programmer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/05/the-three-great-virtues-of-a-programmer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 11:02:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2008/10/05/the-three-great-virtues-of-a-programmer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I ran across &lt;a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?LazinessImpatienceHubris">this wiki page&lt;/a> which has a nice piece on the virtues of a good programmer. I found it so recognizable that I decided to copy it over for you to enjoy:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>_**"We will encourage you to develop the three great virtues of a programmer: laziness, impatience, and hubris."**_** **-- Larry Wall, Programming Perl (1st edition), O'Reilly and Associates
&lt;p>**Laziness
**The quality that makes you go to great effort to reduce overall energy expenditure. It makes you write labor-saving programs that other people will find useful, and document what you wrote so you don't have to answer so many questions about it. Hence, the first great virtue of a programmer. Also hence, this book. See also impatience and hubris. (p.609)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Impatience
**The anger you feel when the computer is being lazy. This makes you write programs that don't just react to your needs, but actually anticipate them. Or at least pretend to. Hence, the second great virtue of a programmer. See also laziness and hubris. (p.608)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Hubris
**Excessive pride, the sort of thing Zeus zaps you for. Also the quality that makes you write (and maintain) programs that other people won't want to say bad things about. Hence, the third great virtue of a programmer. See also laziness and impatience. (p.607)&lt;/blockquote>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(The original context can be found at
&lt;a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?LazinessImpatienceHubris">http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?LazinessImpatienceHubris&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>