<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bonjour on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/bonjour/</link><description>Recent content in bonjour on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 19:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/bonjour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It can be done on Windows, too!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/09/11/it-can-be-done-on-windows-too/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/09/11/it-can-be-done-on-windows-too/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you've ever had the &amp;quot;pleasure&amp;quot; of configuring and sharing a printer between Windows machines, you probably know how tedious it is to get one machine to send a print job to the printer connected to another machine. And don't even get me started on how to do that on a Linux machine, or any mix of these two systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Ever since I migrated from Windows to Mac, I had been avoiding the printer sharing thing. The Ethernet printerserver I bought in my PC days only came with Windows bloatware, so that was a no-go. The Epson Stylus 915 worked nicely, connected with USB to my Mac Mini, so I had no need to solve that problem. My wife however still has a Windows laptop, and every now and then she would send me documents by mail which I then would print for her. Not ideal, but it saved me the stress and trouble of struggling with Windows to get it to talk to a Mac printer.
&lt;p>Today I discovered that I had it all wrong. Apple makes this wonderful little (2MB) piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/support/downloads/bonjourforwindows.html">Bonjour for Windows&lt;/a> which solved the whole printer sharing thing I had been putting off in about 6 mouseclicks! Share the printer on the Mac (about 2 clicks), download and install Bonjour on the Windows (about 2 clicks), and run the Printer wizzard that shows up (also 2 clicks). I had a Windows Testpage rolling out the printer before I knew it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What a good friend pointed out on the phone was something I hadn't realized: &lt;em>&amp;quot;See, you can actually make good software running on Windows, and it doesn't have to come on 4 DVD's. It's just that they don't care&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Well, Apple does care, and they did a brilliant job at it. Small package, simple interface, no fuss, just works, and is good looking too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm very happy I did this, and in fact I'm going to print another testpage, just for the fun of it. On my Apple I am used to be able to edit video, audio, photo's and all at the same time. On Windows I'm glad I can print a testpage. See the difference? (for insiders: at work I'm glad to be able to receive a phonecall ;-)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>