<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>youtube on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/youtube/</link><description>Recent content in youtube on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 16:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hidden "Get a Mac" ads</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/12/02/hidden-get-a-mac-ads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/12/02/hidden-get-a-mac-ads/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I was browsing YouTube the other day, and noticed that there are some &amp;quot;Get a Mac&amp;quot; commercials which are not on the usual &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/getamac/">getamac&lt;/a> website. These commercials are in the original setting with &lt;a href="http://www.justinlong.net/">Justin Long&lt;/a> as the Mac and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Hodgman">John Hodgman&lt;/a> as the PC, but ony published through YouTube or as Flash commercials.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[![PC Hiding](afbeelding-6.png)
](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=HdBB4ekspRg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >A short commercial where PC is hiding from virusses and spyware.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[![Drivers](afbeelding-71.png)
](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=XrppvJcBo98)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Wierd commercial where PC tries to get outside, because he urgently needs new drivers.The joke in this commercial is a bit lame, which is maybe the reason thatit didn't get posted on the getamac gallery.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[![don’t give up on Vista](afbeelding-3.png)
](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=ysHSDiiuWWE)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >By far the most funny commercial I found. It is also a remarkable one, becase Apple does not do these kind of "Flash integrated in website" commercials often.The PC tries to convince people not to giveup in Vista. Guess what happens...
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[![David Pogue on Vista vs OSX](afbeelding-4.png)
](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=TaIUkwPybtM)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Vista got a lot of flac from Apple fans who claimed that Vista is just a bad copy of Apple's Tiger and Leopard. In this video, [David Pogue](http://www.davidpogue.com/) of the New York Times clearly demonstrates that this is not the case. Windows Vista is an operating system with a lot of new, innovative user interface improvements never seen before.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >[![Install Vista](afbeelding-5.png)
](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=FVbf9tOGwno)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >And finally, if David convinced you, and you would like to install Vista on your PC, this guy shows you how simple it is to install Windows Vista in just 2 minutes onto your machine.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
There are a lot of other funny Mac vs Windows videos to be found on YouTube. A lot of these are sometimes excelent copies or spoofs, and there are even [Linux versions](http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=GVOnFdMf0RU) where Linux is played by a beautiful lady.
&lt;p>Choose your poison.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>