<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/categories/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading an ISKRA AM550 P1 Port with a Pi</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/01/18/reading-an-iskra-am550-p1-port-with-a-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2020/01/18/reading-an-iskra-am550-p1-port-with-a-pi/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;figure class="float_right">&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smart_meter">&lt;img src="iskra-am550-gprs-meter.jpg" width="120"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
Although I am the guy with a soldering iron and a bit of software development experience, I am not a fan of the &amp;quot;internet of things&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;smart meters&amp;quot; or smart anything really. Not because I don't like technology, but because of the potential security and privacy problems it brings with it. That said, because of some unfortunate events I now have a smart meter my home. So when life gives you lemons, you make Pi!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've got an &lt;a href="http://www.iskraemeco.com/en/portfolio/electricity-meters/residential-smart-meters/am550/">AM550 Smart meter&lt;/a> with a P1 port. Seeing all the online content and suggestions about reading your smart meter, I decided to have an hour of fun trying to read the P1 data. Here's how I did it:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>The P1 port on the AM550 sends serial data, but the signal is inverted. It is possible to invert that in software, but it is a kludge that requires some &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bit_banging">bit banging&lt;/a>. Bringing the data in the right polarity and connecting it to the Rx serial input on the GPIO port is the cheapest and fastest way to go if you happen to have an RJ11 connenctor, a PNP transistor and a few resistors lying around. Here are my notes on how I wired the P1 to the Raspberry:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schematic-am550.jpg">&lt;img src="schematic-am550.jpg?w=450" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that was left is reading the data from the serial port. Pin 10 maps to GPIO15 and happens to also be the Rx pin on the Raspberry Pi's internal Serial adapter, which is available as a device at /dev/ttyAMA0 (I did not choose this pin by accident ;-). I wrote a simple Python script to read the serial port so I could change it to produce munin graphs later:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span class="ln"> 1&lt;/span>&lt;span class="kn">import&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nn">serial&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 2&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">ser&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">Serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">(&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 3&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">port&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s1">&amp;#39;/dev/ttyAMA0&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 4&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">baudrate&lt;/span> &lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span> &lt;span class="mi">115200&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 5&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">parity&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">PARITY_NONE&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 6&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">stopbits&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">STOPBITS_ONE&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 7&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">bytesize&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">serial&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">EIGHTBITS&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">,&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 8&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">timeout&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="mi">1&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln"> 9&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">)&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">10&lt;/span>&lt;span class="k">while&lt;/span> &lt;span class="kc">True&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">:&lt;/span>
&lt;span class="ln">11&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nb">print&lt;/span> &lt;span class="n">ser&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">.&lt;/span>&lt;span class="n">readline&lt;/span>&lt;span class="p">()&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>When running this program, you should see a whole blob of text scroll by about every second or so. It is readable ASCII and can be parsed by many libraries out there. I tried a few but they were sometimes buggy, or sometimes overengineered and requiring a lot of external resources. So I wrote my own, very crude, parsing. It is not like the meter will be updated every week with new software and ssl certificates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are actually only a few lines in the output that interest me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.7&lt;/strong> contain the current power usage in Watts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.8.1&lt;/strong> are the T1 (low tariff) meter reading in Watt-hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines starting with &lt;strong>1-0:1.8.2&lt;/strong> are the T2 (high tariff) meter reading in Watt-hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A few lines of additional python gave me three separate munin plugins to produce the graphs I wanted. Here is a nice one showing the power usage of last week, split between high and low tariff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="smartmeter_totals_am550-week.png">&lt;img src="smartmeter_totals_am550-week.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This nice graph also shows one of the problems with smart meters: Given enough resolution, you can see at which times devices and lights are switched on. This can provide some interesting patterns, and enables anybody with access to your meter data to determine when you are home or on vacation. Of course there are some tricks to create constant or confusing usage patterns, I'm sure you'll come up with something smart now that you can see the graphs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find all three munin plugins in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/realrolfje/munin-plugins">munin-plugin repository&lt;/a>, in the &amp;quot;plugin&amp;quot; folder. There may also be other interesting stuff there for you munin enthausiasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interdigital Bandpass for RTL2832U Receiver</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/09/interdigital-bandpass-for-rtl2832u-receiver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 21:37:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2018/02/09/interdigital-bandpass-for-rtl2832u-receiver/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="bandpassfilter.gif" alt="">
Building a receiver for a voice repeater system in this area I set up a &lt;a href="https://www.thumbsat.com/thumbnet-radios">thumbsat receiver&lt;/a> connected to a Raspberry Pi. The receiver is part of the repeater system to widen it's receiving range. However, the performance turned out not to be too optimal. I guessed that the GSM and Wifi signals around here could cause the RTL2832U to overload, so I decided to build an intedigital bandpassfilter using &lt;a href="http://www.changpuak.ch/electronics/interdigital_bandpass_filter_designer.php">Ajarn Changpuak&lt;/a>'s excelent interdigital bandpass filter calculator.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>Because size was an issue and the GSM and Wifi bands are not very close to the receive frequency, I decided on a 2 element filter with 8MHz passband and 0.2dB ripple. Playing with the calculator got me the following filter dimensions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
Length interior Element : 54.54 mm or 2.147 inch
Length of end Element : 54.72 mm or 2.154 inch
Ground plane space : 20 mm or 0.787 inch
Rod Diameter : 4 mm or 0.157 inch
End plate to center of Rod : 10 mm or 0.394 inch
Tap to shorted End : 1.41 mm or 0.055 inch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**** Dimensions, mm (inch) ****&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="end-to-center-center-center-gk-qcoup">End to Center Center-Center G[k] Q/Coup&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>0 0.00 (0.000)
1 10.00 (0.394) 35.97 (1.416) 1.038 0.714
2 45.97 (1.810) 0.00 (0.000) 0.675 1.738
3 55.97 (2.204)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**** Box inside dimensions ****
Height : 59.00 mm or 2.323 inch
Length : 55.97 mm or 2.204 inch
Depth : 20.00 mm or 0.787 inch
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I discovered later, forgetting to refresh the calculations one last time resulted in incorrect dimentions (yes, the dimensions are incorrect in the list above).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I built the filter with blank PCB sheet and brass rods I had lying around. The first version looked like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="img_6332.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without the top screwed it performed beautifully, but that turned out to be coincedence. Closing the filter up showed some strange characteristicts and the passband was on a much lower frequency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used my &lt;a href="http://miniradiosolutions.com/54-2/">miniVNA Tiny&lt;/a> to look at the characteristics while fiddling with it. To make it work I used copper shielding of an RG213 cable to close the filter properly, connected the inside and outside copper on the PCB, and added two solid wires to create a stronger coupling and changing the frequency. A bit unconventional and structuraly unsound, but it worked, and it ended up looking like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![](img_6400-small.jpg)
](img_6400-small.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![](img_6413-small.jpg)
](img_6413-small.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
The electrical performance is adequate enough, and a short test confirmed that the RTL2832U has a much better performance, even with the additional 1.3 dB insertion loss of the filter:
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![](1270-mhz-bandpass-s12.png?w=150)
](1270-mhz-bandpass-s12.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![](img_6489-crop.jpg)
](img_6489-crop.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
The receiver with the bandpass filter is installed on the roof and is performing nicely.
&lt;p>It still felt strange that the filter does not behave as designed so I returned to Ajarn Changpuak's page to re-check my calculations and it turned out to be incorrect. The correct dimensions would have been:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
Length interior Element : 54.53 mm or 2.147 inch
Length of end Element : 54.72 mm or 2.154 inch
Ground plane space : 20 mm or 0.787 inch
Rod Diameter : 4 mm or 0.157 inch
End plate to center of Rod : 10 mm or 0.394 inch
Tap to shorted End : 1.78 mm or 0.070 inch&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**** Dimensions, mm (inch) ****&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="end-to-center-center-center-gk-qcoup-1">End to Center Center-Center G[k] Q/Coup&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>0 0.00 (0.000)
1 10.00 (0.394) 32.98 (1.298) 1.038 0.714
2 42.98 (1.692) 0.00 (0.000) 0.675 1.738
3 52.98 (2.086)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**** Box inside dimensions ****
Height : 59.00 mm or 2.323 inch
Length : 52.98 mm or 2.086 inch
Depth : 20.00 mm or 0.787 inch
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aha. This explains it. After re-calculating, the rods should have been closer together and the tap to the shorted end should have been further from the casing. I guess I have to re-do this filter with the correct dimensions some time. After this adventure I'm fairly confident that I can get it to behave nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Make the ESP8266 talk 9600 baud</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2017/01/02/make-the-esp8266-talk-9600-baud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 19:53:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2017/01/02/make-the-esp8266-talk-9600-baud/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/0IRvtw22JIc">&lt;img src="b1262-0.jpg" alt="Surprise video">
&lt;/a>The default serial speed on the ESP8266 WiFi chip is 115200 baud. If you connect this chip to an Arduino and want to use SoftSerial to talk to it, it will not work. The SoftSerial library is limited to 9600 baud because of hardware limitations of the Arduino. If you want to talk to the ESP8266 with an Arduino at lower speeds, you need to tell the ESP8266 to slow down.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[Remco.org](http://remco.org/) noted that sending 115200 baud with SoftSerial works just well enough to throw a command to the ESP8266. So below is a sketch that will do just that for you.
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Load or copy/paste the sketch in your Arduino IDE.
2. Connect the ESP8266 board to the Arduino as follows:
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ESP TX pin to Arduino softRX pin 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ESP RX pin to Arduino softTx pin 5
3. Open the Serial Monitor of the Arduino IDE and set it to 9600 bps and CR/LF.
4. Compile and upload this sketch to the  Arduino.
5. Wait for the Serial monitor to show:
AT
OK
-- Sketch stopped.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can now use your ESP8266 at 9600 baud. The setting is stored in non-volatile memory, so you only need to do this once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here's the sketch:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;cpp&amp;quot; gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
/*&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This sketch switches the ESP8266 from its&lt;/li>
&lt;li>factory-default setting of 115200 bps to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>9600 bps so that we can use SoftSerial to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>communicate with it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Connect the ESP8266:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ESP TX pin to Arduino softRX pin 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ESP RX pin to Arduino softTx pin 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Open the Serial Monitor of the&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arduino IDE and set it to 9600 bps and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CR/LF.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Compile and upload this sketch to the&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arduino.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Sit back and watch the magic.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>If you see &amp;quot;AT OK&amp;quot;, it worked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Settings are stored in Flash memory, you&lt;/li>
&lt;li>only need to execute this sketch once.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Please note: Although softserial is used&lt;/li>
&lt;li>to transmit at 115200 bps, you'll notice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>we never wait for an answer. That is&lt;/li>
&lt;li>because SoftSerial is not built to receive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>at speeds above 9600 bps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You have been warned.
*/
#include &amp;lt;SoftwareSerial.h&amp;gt;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>const long sourcebaudrate = 115200;
const long targetbaudrate = 9600;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>const int softRX = 4;
const int softTX = 5;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SoftwareSerial softSerial(softRX, softTX);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>void setup() {
Serial.begin(targetbaudrate);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serial.println(&amp;quot;Tell the ESP8266 to switch from &amp;quot;
+ String(sourcebaudrate) + &amp;quot; to &amp;quot;
+ String(targetbaudrate) + &amp;quot; bps.&amp;quot;);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>softSerial.begin(sourcebaudrate);
softSerial.print(&amp;quot;AT+IPR=&amp;quot;
+ String(targetbaudrate)
+ &amp;quot;\r\n&amp;quot;);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>delay(500);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serial.println(&amp;quot;Talk to the ESP8266 at &amp;quot;
+ String(targetbaudrate) + &amp;quot; bps.&amp;quot;);
softSerial.begin(targetbaudrate);
softSerial.print(&amp;quot;AT\r\n&amp;quot;);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>delay(500);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serial.println(&amp;quot;Reply from the ESP8266:&amp;quot;);
while(softSerial.available() &amp;gt; 0 ) {
char a = softSerial.read();
if(a == '\0') continue;
if(a != '\r' &amp;amp;&amp;amp; a != '\n' &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (a &amp;lt; 32)) continue;
Serial.print(a);
}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serial.println(&amp;quot;-- Sketch stopped.&amp;quot;);
}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>void loop() {
}
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seeed ESP8266 WiFi Breakout Board Pinout</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2017/01/01/seeed-esp8266-wifi-breakout-board-pinout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 17:02:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2017/01/01/seeed-esp8266-wifi-breakout-board-pinout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_2130&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;450&amp;quot;]&lt;img src="pinout1.png" alt="WiFi Serial Transceiver Module Breakout Board w&amp; ESP8266 pinout">
WiFi Serial Transceiver Module Breakout Board w&amp;amp; ESP8266 pinout[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the pinout for the &lt;a href="https://www.seeedstudio.com/WiFi-Serial-Transceiver-Module-Breakout-Board-w%26amp%3B-ESP8266-p-2081.html#">Seeed WiFi ESP8266 breakout board&lt;/a>. Please be careful, it only accepts 3.3 Volt nominal input voltage and logic. Putting 5 Volts on any of the pins may permanently damage the chip.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ESP8266 on this board is programmed to do serial communications at 115.2 kilobaud, and accepts &lt;a href="https://room-15.github.io/blog/2015/03/26/esp8266-at-command-reference/">AT commands&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Designing a Fox-hunt antenna</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2016/06/19/designing-a-fox-hunt-antenna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 21:47:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2016/06/19/designing-a-fox-hunt-antenna/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3d-radiation-pattern.png">&lt;img src="3d-radiation-pattern.png" alt="3d radiation pattern">
&lt;/a>Many years ago, I used to do some &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rrNXyv134bE">radio fox hunting with cars&lt;/a>. Usually these hunts are at night to make it more exciting, and can be great fun. As I got older I lost interest and moved on to other things. But last year, I decided to have a go at a &lt;a href="http://www.ballonvossenjacht.nl">popular balloon fox hunt&lt;/a> on 144MHz. This is quite a large scale &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_QrDOEXb_ss">and professionally organized fox hunt&lt;/a> by Dutch Radio Amateurs.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the totally different setup and frequency I decided to join a few recreational 144MHz (2 meter) fox hunts to get the hang of it. If you like to play with radios and walk in the woods, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KDN8w7awAkQ">this is your thing&lt;/a>. Lots of small transmitters hidden in the bushes on random frequencies for you to find.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year I used a borrowed receiver and antenna, and this year I decided to build a &lt;a href="http://www.peildoos.nl/?page_id=128">Foxbox receiver kit&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After building the receiver, the age-old discussion among radio amateurs began: What antenna to use? I had a discussion with Remco who just designed his own &lt;a href="http://remco.org/index.php/2015/02/26/145-mhz-2m-moxon-pt-2/">Moxon antenna&lt;/a> using the &lt;a href="http://www.qsl.net/4nec2/">4nec2 antenna modeler and optimizer&lt;/a>. He convinced me to use this software in order to prevent building a lot of failing antennas and not being sure why they fail. So that's what I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 4nec2 software comes with a bunch of example antennas for you to play around with. The antenna I borrowed last year was a 2 element antenna based on a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log-periodic_antenna">Log Periodic Dipole Array antenna&lt;/a>. It worked fine and I had fun with it so I decided to model an antenna like that. (Also because I'm hard-headed and just copying Remco's Moxon would not lead to interesting discussions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: Getting basic dimensions of an LPDA&lt;/strong>
The first thing I needed is a basic, ballpark approximation of a working LPDA antenna for 144MHz so I could get used to the 4nec2 modeling software. I used &lt;a href="http://hamwaves.com/lpda/en/">ON4AA's Log-Periodic Dipole Array calculator&lt;/a> to get an idea of the basic dimensions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I noticed that the length of the first and largest element of the antenna is always 1041 mm, no matter what taper or relative spacing I chose as input. Good news, because that means that the antenna only has a few parameters to change when optimizing in 4nec2, see below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 2: Getting the design into 4nec2&lt;/strong>
So here is where the struggle starts. As I am a Mac user and the 4nec2 software is Windows only, I installed it on a Linux Mint virtual machine running under Wine without problems. The terminal window will log errors but you have to put your OCD aside for a moment and ignore those.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the LPDA antenna itself the struggle was not that bad, as I found an example file and was able to change that around to learn how 4nec2 works. I'll spare you the details. Just remember that you want to use the new NEC editor (Main Window, Settings → NEC Editor (new)).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="1-editor.png">&lt;img src="1-editor.png" alt="4nec2 Editor">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here you see the two wires of my LPDA antenna. As you can see, each line has a start (X1,Y1,Z1) and end point (X2,Y2,Z2) in 3D space. Ignore the funny formulas in the screenshot for now. A counter intuitive thing for me was that lines are made out of &amp;quot;segments&amp;quot;. 4nec2 cryptically complains about too few and too much segments, and you have to choose a number accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important thing to learn about 4nec2 is that you don't &amp;quot;connect&amp;quot; a source to your antenna. Rather, you choose a segment of a line which will then act as a current or voltage source (current source is the recommended default). This is why if you want to have your feed point in the middle of a wire, you need to choose an odd number of segments. In my design, both wires are 61 segments, and the feed point on both wires is on segment 31 (the middle segment of each wire).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting the two wires of the antenna is done using a transmission line, with a twist (literally). We connect segment 31 of both wires with a transmission line, and chose a &lt;em>negative impedance&lt;/em>. This causes the transmission line to &amp;quot;twist&amp;quot; in your geometry window, and you should see something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="2-geometry.png">&lt;img src="2-geometry.png" alt="LPDA Geometry">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 3: Changing the NEC file for optimization&lt;/strong>
4nec2 contains an optimizer which can optimize certain characteristics of your antenna by iterating values. If you hard-coded the X,Y and Z values of the lines, the optimizer can not change the design. To be able to use the optimizer, I chose to have variables for the length of the boom (L), length of the driving/smallest element (D), length of the reflecting/longest element (R) and impedance of the transmission line (TRI). This explains the funny values for the X,Y,Z coordinates in my file. The variables can be found on the &amp;quot;Symbols&amp;quot; tab of the NEC editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 4: Optimize!&lt;/strong>
Close the Editor window, and in the main window, select Calculate -&amp;gt; Start Optimizer. The optimizer parameters can be a bit confusing. Choose the &amp;quot;Optimize&amp;quot; function in the drop-down top left, and leave the Option set to &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;. Below the text &amp;quot;Weighting factors in %&amp;quot; you'll see 7 text fields. Set them all to 0, except for &amp;quot;F/B&amp;quot;, the Front-to-back ratio. That should be set to 100, As we are only interested in maximum directivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3-optimizer.png">&lt;img src="3-optimizer.png?w=450" alt="Optimizer">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we have told 4nec2 what we want (max F/B), we need to tell the optimizer which variables it can play with. In this simple design, you could select all variables by clicking on them, which moves them to the &amp;quot;selected&amp;quot; column. I tried, this does not lead to practical results and takes a bit of time depending on the speed of the computer. All open geometry or 3D view windows will live-update with the calculations. This looks really cool but things go faster if you close them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3a-optimized-radiation.png">&lt;img src="3a-optimized-radiation.png" alt="Optimized radiation">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a bit of playing with the optimizer, I got to the following radiation pattern:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4-radiation-pattern.png">&lt;img src="4-radiation-pattern.png" alt="4. radiation pattern">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 5. Build and field test.&lt;/strong>
At this point, the software will have tried tens, if not hundreds of different antenna variations you didn't have to physically build. But now that we are &amp;quot;certain&amp;quot;, we can build the antenna. The boom is aluminum profile, the radials are made of measuring tape so they can be folded, and the handle is a broomstick:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="5-antenne.jpg">&lt;img src="5-antenne.jpg" alt="Antenna">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've spent extra effort to make sure the dimensions are as close to the simulation as possible, to maximize the chance that it actually works as designed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did a field test together with my dad, where we used a Baofeng handheld (yes &lt;a href="https://rolfje.wordpress.com/2015/05/10/better-modulation-for-the-baofeng-uv-5ra/">that one&lt;/a>) as a &amp;quot;fox&amp;quot;, taking turns in hiding it for the each other. The tests went &amp;quot;sort of okay&amp;quot;, but I noticed that it sometimes felt as if there was not one peak straight in front of the antenna, but rather two peaks left and right. This got me worrying about the accuracy of the build or the simulation. I even started doubting impact of impedance mismatch and cable length. When we got home however, I checked and saw that the 4nec2 software actually predicted this in a different diagram:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="6-vertical-radiation.png">&lt;img src="6-vertical-radiation.png" alt="Vertical radiation">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out, that if the antenna is held horizontally, and the transmitter antenna is a vertical, the whole system behaves exactly as simulated, with the antenna being almost &amp;quot;deaf&amp;quot; right in front of the boom. Solution: Turn the antenna vertical or horizontal while hunting to find the maximum signal. We noticed that without being able to see the radio, I could exactly match the angle of the vertical antenna. My dad hid the fox in a tree at 45 degrees, and without seeing or knowing it I matched the angle of the antenna perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 6. Game on!&lt;/strong>
Just today I tried the whole setup in an actual fox hunt with 24 foxes (yes that many). I was very pleased with the performance of the antenna, and I found 14 of the foxes. With a bit of practice and experience, I'm sure I can improve to find more foxes next time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And last but not least, here is the 4nec2 file for you to play around with:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; padlinenumbers=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
CM Log Periodic Dipole Array for 2m fox hunting
CE
SY L=180 'Boom length
SY D=963 'Driver length
SY R=1041 'Reflector length
SY TRI=70 'Transmission line impedance
GW 1 61 0 -R/2 0 0 R/2 0 10
GW 2 61 L -D/2 0 L D/2 0 10
GS 0 0 0.001
GE 0
GN -1
EK
EX 6 2 31 0 1 0 0
TL 1 31 2 31 -TRI 0 0 0 0 0
FR 0 20 0 0 144 0.1
EN
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Measuring Coax Length and Loss</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/11/01/measuring-coax-length-and-loss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 22:37:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/11/01/measuring-coax-length-and-loss/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=06N-5aUaV9w">&lt;img src="100-1015-bnc-t-connector.jpg" alt="100-1015 BNC T Connector">
&lt;/a>Ever wondered how well your 50Ω coaxial cable is working? If you have a reasonably fast oscilloscope, preferably up to 100MHz and a signal generator which can generate short bursts, you can measure not only the length of your cable, but also the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Return_loss">return loss&lt;/a> at a certain frequency. From that, we can learn the attenuation of the cable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This blog post describes the classic time domain reflection measurement using the following setup:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tdr-measurement.png" alt="Measuring TDR">&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The generator on the left generates a pulse or signal which travels down the cable. This signal is called $latex U_i$, the incident wave. Because the end of the cable at the right is open, there can be no current, and the wave has to travel back to the left. This wave is called $latex U_r$, the reflected wave. When the reflected wave hits the generator, it will disappear into the 50Ω impedance of the generator.
&lt;p>When the wave travels through the cable and back, it encounters resistance and inductance of the copper, and capacitance towards the shielding. If we can measure the returning waveform, we can say something about the cable loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To measure $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$ we need to use a 10x signal probe so that we influence the signal as little as possible. If we would use a 1x signal probe, the load of the probe will make it look like our cable has quite a bit of loss. In reality, it will be the probe that is influencing the measurement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes the signal a certain time to travel through the cable. In a vacuum, the signal travels at the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speed_of_electricity">speed of light&lt;/a>. In a cable, the signal actually travels &lt;em>slower&lt;/em>. Different cables have different speeds. The manufacturer of the cable provides this speed as a factor relative to the speed of light, called the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Velocity_factor">&amp;quot;velocity factor&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. If we know the velocity factor of the cable, and the time the signal took to return, we can say something about its length.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm using an &lt;a href="http://owonchina.en.made-in-china.com/product/XKrECsfAHmUj/China-OWON-50MHz-Dual-Channel-Modulated-Waveform-Generator-AG2052F-.html">OWON AG2052&lt;/a> function generator, and have set it up to generate a &amp;quot;burst&amp;quot;. A 25MHz sinewave, 2 cycles. The voltage is not really important, anywhere from 1 to 5 Volts makes the measurement comfortable, well above the noise floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_1964.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1964.jpg" alt="IMG_1964">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The signal generator is connected through an RG58 cable and a BNC T-connector to the coax we're testing, in this case a few meters of &lt;a href="http://www.hamshop.com/ecoflex-15-coax-kabels.html">Ecoflex 15&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember those funny little springy things you received with your new 10x 100MHz probes? This is a nice example of how to use them:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_1972.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1972.jpg" alt="Proper Probing">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If everything went well, you should see $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$ on your oscilloscope screen. To make an accurate measurement, stretch them out big enough so they just fit the screen of the scope. Since I'm measuring the peak voltage, I don't need the lower part of the wave. Using your scope like this makes better use of your A/D converter resolution, and uses more pixels on the screen, which means better accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="25mhz-2cycles.png">&lt;img src="25mhz-2cycles.png?w=450" alt="25MHz-2cycles">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cursor A and B are on the top of the second sine of $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$. I could also have used the first, it doesn't really matter. The first sine is higher because of a little overshoot in the generator. We see that $latex U_{i (peak)}=654mV$ and $latex U_{r (peak)}=578mV$. To calculate the loss from these two voltages, we use the formula we found for calculating return loss from the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reflection_coefficient">reflection coefficient&lt;/a> $latex \Gamma$ (gamma):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex RL_{(db)}=-20 \times \log_{10}\left(\Gamma \right)$ where $latex \Gamma =\frac{U_r}{U_i}$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which means that in our case:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex RL_{(db)}=-20 \times \log_{10}\left(\frac{0.578}{0.654} \right)=-1.073dB$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We're interested in attenuation, the cable loss one-way, so we need to devide the return loss by two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex \frac{-1.073}{2}=-0.54dB$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This attenuation is meaningless without knowing the length of the cable. To be able to calculate the length, we must know how fast the signal is traveling in the cable. According to the manufacturer, the velocity factor of Ecoflex 15 is 0.86. This means that a signal in this cable travels at 0.86 times the light speed:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex 299,792,458 \times 0.86=257,821,513.9:^m/_s$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cursors A and B are 270nS apart. This means that the signal traveled&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex 257,821,513.9 \times 270 \times 10^{-9}=69.61, m$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is of course twice the length of the cable, so our cable is &lt;strong>34.8 meter&lt;/strong> long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we know the length and the loss of our cable, we can compare it with the manufacturer's specifications. The specifications of Ecoflex 15 say that the typical attenuation is 0.86dB per 100m at 10MHz, and 1.96dB per 100m at 50MHz. Lets assume that the attenuation is linear with the frequency between those two. The attenuation on 25MHz should be approximately 1.3dB per 100m.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a cable of 34.8 meter with 0.54dB attenuation, so per 100 meter that would be:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$latex \frac{100}{34.8} \times -0.54=-1.5,dB$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That's about 15% worse than the specification, but this can be easily explained by inaccuracies in our measurement, the resolution of the oscilloscope, and loss in cables and plugs. When repeating this measurement on my setup it's easy to see variations of 20% in the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What if your generator is slower&lt;/strong>
When your generator can not do short bursts, or can't generate a high enough frequency, you can at least measure the cable length by sending a square wave down the line. This is the most common measurement to do, but doesn't give you much information about the attenuation on a certain frequency. The frequency of the square wave does not matter much, as long as the edges have a decent rise time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="square-wave.png">&lt;img src="square-wave.png?w=450" alt="Square wave">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this measurement you see $latex U_i$ on the left, then a period where the reflected $latex U_r$ is added to $latex U_i$, and then the last part of the $latex U_r$. The length of the first &amp;quot;Step&amp;quot; is the length of your cable, and the difference between $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$ is your DC resistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another possibility is that your generator can generate a burst, but not short enough. You can then still do both the return loss and cable length measurements, but it will look a bit different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="25mhz-20cycles.png">&lt;img src="25mhz-20cycles.png?w=450" alt="25MHz-20cycles">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, the middle section where $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$ are added should not be interpreted in any way. Depending on the length of the cable, and the phase of $latex U_r$ you can even see a lower signal here, where $latex U_r$ cancels out $latex U_i$. Only use the first and last parts of the signal,indicated with $latex U_i$ and $latex U_r$ above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Gotchas:
**Pay attention to more than one reflection: If there is more than one reflection, your generator is not the same impedance of the cable. I made the mistake of adding a 50Ω terminator at the generator side. But since the generator was already 50Ω, I created a 25Ω impedance, which reflected $latex U_r$ and sent it back into the cable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also make sure you always measure an open ended cable. If an antenna is connected, the reflection measurement will work, but the return loss can not be determined. After all, the antenna is made to dissipate energy, and we don't know how much energy is lost in the cable, and how much is lost in the antenna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun experimenting,
Rolf&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P.S. The formulas in this article are rendered by the WordPress LaTeX plugin, and I used the &lt;a href="http://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php">codecogs equations editor&lt;/a> to edit and preview them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Better modulation for the Baofeng UV-5RA</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/05/10/better-modulation-for-the-baofeng-uv-5ra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 10:32:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2015/05/10/better-modulation-for-the-baofeng-uv-5ra/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h73EYcyszf8">&lt;img src="baofeng-uv-5ra-plus.jpg" alt="baofeng-uv-5ra-plus">
&lt;/a>Undoubtedly the Baofeng UV-5Rx delivers a lot of radio for your buck. However some models in the range have a bad reputation for the transmitted audio sounding soft and muffled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2013, Remco PA3FYM obtained the schematics of the radio and &lt;a href="http://remco.org/index.php?s=baofeng">devised a modification&lt;/a> where transistor Q17 of the VOX is re-purposed as preamplifier in the microphone audio circuit. It works wonders for your radio. For people needing a bit more visual guidance, below is a walktrough of how I did this to my Baofeng UV-5RA.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->On the left you find the original schematics of the microphone and vox circuits. On the right, I've marked the modifications we're about to do in red.
&lt;table >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![uv5r-schema-before](uv5r-schema-before.png)
](uv5r-schema-before.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![uv5r-schema-after](uv5r-schema-after.png)
](uv5r-schema-after.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
**Step 1: Open the radio
**Open up the Baofeng UV-5RA. There is plenty information online on how to do this, check out [the teardown at takapart](https://www.takeitapart.com/guide/9) for instance. You need to open the radio up to the point that you can access the components on the back of the keypad.
&lt;p>Remember: the radio comes apart without force. If you feel something is not giving, look for solder joints or screws you missed. For easy removal of the display, I used solder wick to remove the solder on the backlight connections:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-1-desolder-display.jpg">&lt;img src="step-1-desolder-display.jpg" alt="Step 1-desolder-display">
&lt;/a>Just to be sure I desoldered the antenna connection but you can also unscrew the antenna connector and carefully force it over the aluminum ridge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-1-desolder-antenna.jpg">&lt;img src="step-1-desolder-antenna.jpg?w=450" alt="Step 1-desolder antenna">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Step 2: Locate components
**Locate the components in the schematic on the printed circuit board. Use a multimeter to ensure yourself that you are looking at the right components:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-2-locate-components.jpg">&lt;img src="step-2-locate-components.jpg" alt="Step 2 Locate components">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Step 3: Disconnect Emitter of Q17
Take a (very very) small drillbit and carefully disconnect the emitter of Q17:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-3-disconnect-emitter.jpg">&lt;img src="step-3-disconnect-emitter.jpg?w=450" alt="Step 3 disconnect emitter">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end result should look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-3-result.jpg">&lt;img src="step-3-result.jpg" alt="step 3 result">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Step 4: Add 560 Ohm resistor
**Use a very small soldering iron tip and small tweezers or toothpick put the 560 (or 680) Ohm resistor in place:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-4-resistor-in-place.jpg">&lt;img src="step-4-resistor-in-place.jpg?w=450" alt="Step 4 resistor in place">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my case, the 560 Ohm resistor gave a bit too much amplification. For a bit more modest result, choose 680 (like Remco did), or anything up to 1k Ohm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 5: Remove C135 and disconnect L44&lt;/strong>
Using the small tip of your soldering iron, heat up and wipe down on C135 to remove it. Take care to not hit other components, repairs will be almost impossible. Use the small drillbit to disconnect L44 by cutting the little trace between C137 and L44:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-5-disconnect-l44.jpg">&lt;img src="step-5-disconnect-l44.jpg" alt="Step 5 disconnect L44">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Step 6: Connect Q17 to L44
**Take a small piece of enamel coated wire, strip 2mm at the ends and connect the collector of Q17 to L44:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-6-connect-l44.jpg">&lt;img src="step-6-connect-l44.jpg?w=450" alt="Step 6 Connect L44">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 7: Close it up&lt;/strong>
Put your radio back together. Don't forget to solder the antenna connector and backlight connections I mentioned in step 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When snapping the PCB back into the case, make sure that the rubber of the PTT button does not fold behind the PCB board. Make sure the rubber is nice and flat after inserting the PCB, like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="step-7-ptt-buttons.jpg">&lt;img src="step-7-ptt-buttons.jpg?w=450" alt="Step 7 PTT buttons">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun with your new and improved modulation!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>73, Rolf.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arduino and the QVGA 2.2" TFT SPI screen</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/11/17/arduino-and-the-qvga-2-2-tft-spi-screen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 10:37:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/11/17/arduino-and-the-qvga-2-2-tft-spi-screen/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.elecfreaks.com/store/22%C3%82%E2%80%99-tft-lcd-tft0122sp-p-672.html">&lt;img src="2-2sp_a.jpg" alt="QVGA SPI 2.2" 320x240 screen">
&lt;/a>I went through all the struggles everybody else seems to be going through to get this screen connected to my &lt;a href="http://arduino.cc/en/Main/arduinoBoardNano">Arduino Nano&lt;/a>. I had the 5V to 3.3V voltage conversion problem, and the &amp;quot;only works with software interrupts&amp;quot; problem which makes the display run slow. The solutions are not complicated but not very wel documented. Until now.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 1: It's a 3.3V screen&lt;/strong>
Before connecting the screen to your Arduino, it's important to know that this screen uses 3.3V logic. That means that connecting your Arduino to it will likely ruin the screen. If you're not using the CF cardreader on the screen then the communication is one-way to the screen. Converting your 5V outputs to 3.3V is really simple, all you need is a couple of cheap 1N4148 diodes and a few resistors (for alternatives, see below). Connect your screen as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="foto-2.jpg">&lt;img src="foto-2.jpg" alt="Simple Level Conversion">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please make sure you wire &lt;em>all&lt;/em> connections in this schematic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Step 2: Hidden pins in the code&lt;/strong>
The &lt;a href="https://github.com/adafruit/Adafruit_ILI9340">Adafruit ILI9340 library&lt;/a> contains some examples on how to get the screen running. You'll need the SPI and Adafruit_GFX libraries too, as shown in the header of the examples. Let's look at a little code that alternates the screen between black and white:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;cpp&amp;quot;]
/*&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Example code to make the TFT alternate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>between black and white using hardware SPI:
*/
#include &amp;quot;SPI.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;Adafruit_GFX.h&amp;quot;
#include &amp;quot;Adafruit_ILI9340.h&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>// TFT pin mappings for UNO/NANO
#define _sclk 13
#define _miso 12
#define _mosi 11
#define _cs 10
#define _dc 9
#define _rst 8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>// Use hardware SPI
Adafruit_ILI9340 tft = Adafruit_ILI9340(_cs, _dc, _rst);&lt;/p>
&lt;p>void setup() {
tft.begin();
tft.fillScreen(ILI9340_GREEN);
}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>void loop() {
tft.fillScreen(ILI9340_BLACK);
tft.fillScreen(ILI9340_WHITE);
}
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that there is something funny going on here. The constructor for the Adafruit_ILI9340 object only has _cs, _dc, and _rst as parameter. Initially I thought &amp;quot;Great, only 3 connections to the display!&amp;quot;. Alas, this is not the case. &lt;em>&lt;strong>You still need to wire the _sclk and _mosi port to the display&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>. The _miso port can be left out, but you can't use it for anything else on the Arduino side because the library seems to be accessing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have your connections correct and upload the example above to your Arduino, you should see your screen continuously alternate between black and white. You will be able to see the drawing of the screen, but it should not take more than 1 second to fill the whole screen. If it takes more than a second to fill the screen, you're likely using the software SPI method. Check the code and the connections again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how the data on the _mosi pin looks on a &lt;a href="http://www.radiomuseum.org/r/tektronix_storage_oscilloscope_7623a.html">Tektronix 7623A oscilloscope&lt;/a> when drawing graphics on the TFT screen. It's not a perfect square because of the capacitance of the diodes, but the difference between high and low states is good enough and the slope is just fast enough so that the display sees all the bits that are sent to it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="foto.jpg">&lt;img src="foto.jpg" alt="MOSI data">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Alternative 5V to 3.3V conversions:&lt;/strong>
&lt;img src="foto-1.jpg" alt="Zener conversion">
If you don't have enough diodes, you can use zener diodes as shown on the right. I have not tested this on my screen but it should give you similar results, and saves you a few components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A much nicer, two-way level conversion enables you to connect the _miso port to talk to the CF Card Reader. You can make this
with an N-Channel MOSFET. Check Andrew's blog on &lt;a href="http://www.rocketnumbernine.com/2009/04/10/5v-33v-bidirectional-level-converter">how to use an N-channel FET to do the conversion&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rocketnumbernine.com/2009/04/10/5v-33v-bidirectional-level-converter">&lt;img src="level-converter-mosfet.jpg" alt="level-converter-mosfet">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need more speed or less components, you can also check out &lt;a href="http://www.maximintegrated.com/en/app-notes/index.mvp/id/3007">Maxim's range of level conversion ICs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.waterman.com/en/6-pens">&lt;img src="foto-3.jpg" alt="Waterman fountain pen">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IARU Region 1 Bandplan up to 500MHz</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/11/02/iaru-region-1-bandplan-up-to-500mhz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 17:17:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/11/02/iaru-region-1-bandplan-up-to-500mhz/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For some reason I have trouble finding a document which lists the complete &lt;a href="http://www.iaru-r1.org/">IARU Region 1&lt;/a> Band Plans. To end my &amp;quot;can I transmit here&amp;quot; quests, I've combined the information from several resources into a usable graphical representation of all Amateur Radio bands and modes up to 500MHz. I've not listed bands above 500MHz, please post links to those in the comments if you have them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exact use of a frequency may differ in your local region, so always listen first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="iaru-reg-1-bandplan-up-to-500mhz.png">&lt;img src="iaru-reg-1-bandplan-up-to-500mhz.png?w=660" alt="IARU Region 1, Up to 500MHz">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shoot salt at flies</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/08/07/shoot-salt-at-flies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 20:54:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/08/07/shoot-salt-at-flies/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47cWewVcfE4">&lt;img src="screen-shot-2012-08-07-at-10-41-30-pm.png" alt="BUG-A-SALT">
&lt;/a> Lorenzo had a great idea. In stead if being one of those &amp;quot;having fun at the bar&amp;quot; ideas that never actually see the light of day, Lorenzo followed through. Did you ever have that urge to just take a gun and shoot that fly that is constantly buzzing around your head or food? Well now you can. Check out his invention at &lt;a href="http://www.bugasalt.com">www.bugasalt.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing his gun, I remembered making pea-shooters at high school from a roll of tape and a party balloon. I adjusted the idea for flies (smaller nozzle), and it works beautifully. It only holds one shot, and it looks not nearly as cool as the shotgun idea of Lorenzo, but if you can't wait to start shooting those flies, here's how to make your own low-budget, one-shot salt shooter. Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gjI9rTNCRqs]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toyota (Corolla Verso) iPhone Bluetooth connection</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/08/04/toyota-corolla-verso-iphone-bluetooth-connection/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/08/04/toyota-corolla-verso-iphone-bluetooth-connection/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2QawYoignHI">&lt;img src="toyota-iphone-bluetooth.png" alt="Connect your iPhone to your Toyota's Bluetooth system">
&lt;/a>My sisters in law bought a beautiful 2006 Toyota Corolla Verso. They could not get the iPhone to pair with the car's Bluetooth system. The dealer told them that this was an iPhone problem, but after some fiddling, it turns out there is a simple workaround. If you want to pair an iPhone to your car, and the car says &amp;quot;pairing failed&amp;quot; as soon as you tap on your iPhone, this simple trick might help for you. This article contains detailed steps for the Toyota Corolla Verso, but on other cars this might work too.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * &amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;Start the car (don't start driving), and take out your iPhone.
* On the iPhone, tap **&amp;quot;Settings&amp;quot;**, **&amp;quot;General&amp;quot;** and **&amp;quot;Bluetooth&amp;quot;**. Make sure Bluetooth is switched on. Leave the iPhone on this screen.
* Press and hold **&amp;quot;mode&amp;quot;** on the steering wheel of the car.
* When the car says &amp;quot;Setup Menu&amp;quot;, say **&amp;quot;Pair Phone&amp;quot;**
* On the iPhone, tap the **&amp;quot;TOYOTA&amp;quot;** network.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The car will almost immediately say &amp;quot;Pairing failed&amp;quot;. On your phone, the password prompt will show. Do not do anything, let the phone stay on this screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="interior-2008-toyota-corolla-verso-bourgas-pic-2-334.jpg">&lt;img src="interior-2008-toyota-corolla-verso-bourgas-pic-2-334.jpg" alt="Toyota Corolla Verso Dashboard">
&lt;/a>This is because the iPhone probably tries to connect with a default password like &amp;quot;0000&amp;quot;, the car immediately aborts, and doesn't allow a second try. The phone detects the connection failure and will popup a &amp;quot;password&amp;quot; screen for you to enter a number that does work, but the car has already given up. Not to worry, read on:&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Press and hold **&amp;quot;mode&amp;quot;** on the steering wheel again.
* When the system says &amp;quot;Setup Menu&amp;quot;, say **&amp;quot;Pair Phone&amp;quot;**
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The car enters pairing mode for the second time. Because the phone is still in the &amp;quot;Password prompt&amp;quot; screen, it is already past the detection phase,  and will not try to send the default password. Now you can enter your password and the connection will succeed on the &amp;quot;first&amp;quot; try as seen from your car.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * With the iPhone still in the password screen, enter **&amp;quot;1234&amp;quot;** (or whatever password the car tells you) press **&amp;quot;Connect&amp;quot;**.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Congratulations, your phone is now paired.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to make customers blog about you</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/05/02/how-to-make-customers-blog-about-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:59:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/05/02/how-to-make-customers-blog-about-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="laptopaccuslogo.png" alt="">
An informative article for webshop owners this time, all about how to make people blog about your company. Everything you need to know about online customers, the power of the internet, and how good old moral values still work and can be leveraged to your advantage. Or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->1. Create a website (or two)&lt;/strong>
The first step of every professional online webshop is ofcourse the webshop itself. It should give the customer a good feeling about your customer, and what better than to make the website in the customer's local language? Or, if you really want to go all the way, you can register different local domains, like Lawrence did when he registered &amp;quot;laptop-accus.nl&amp;quot;, and probably a bunch of other domains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Combine great presentation with low pricing&lt;/strong>
Create good looking product pages, which are easily linkable, and make it clear to the customer that this is the cheap knockoff, I mean, product he needs. To top it all off, offer your products at an almost unbelievably low price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="a1175-product-page.png">&lt;img src="a1175-product-page.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Put your company name on the payment receipt&lt;/strong>
When the customer chooses to purchase a product, make sure that your company name is on the receipt. Between all the payments on a credit card bill you want your company to stand out, or at least you want the customer to be able to easily check his payments. Clearly, the &amp;quot;hunt360&amp;quot; and the &amp;quot;GB&amp;quot; indicate that this payment is from the &amp;quot;laptop-accus.nl&amp;quot; shop. &lt;em>ahem&lt;/em> Also note the difference between advertized price and the receipt for added customer convenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="visa-receipt.jpg">&lt;img src="visa-receipt.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>4. Use a professional looking email address&lt;/strong>
When people contact you for questions or support, your reply says a lot about your company, starting with the &amp;quot;reply to&amp;quot; address in your mail. In this case, Lawrence went all the way, and even used the word &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot; in his email address for that extra &amp;quot;enterprise&amp;quot; touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="initial-and-only-mail-from-lawrence-censored.png">&lt;img src="initial-and-only-mail-from-lawrence-censored.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>5. Hire the best shipping provider&lt;/strong>
So you made a local website. But to be able to make some profit, you found a cheap manufacturer in Singapore. So to get products from your manufacturer to the customer, preferably without stocking up, you select the absolute best parcel service you can find. For instance, you can select Swiss post to deliver your parcels, door to door, at an incredible speed:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="swisspost-tracking-cropped.png">&lt;img src="swisspost-tracking-cropped.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, you've read those dates correctly. Pretty awesome shipping speeds there. For a handicapped &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sea_snail">sea snail&lt;/a> traveling over land. And handicapped sea snails tend to get caught at the border, so your customers will always pay that extra import tax you never warned about on your site:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="import-tax.jpg">&lt;img src="import-tax.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6. Promptly answer customer mails&lt;/strong>
In the unfortunate circumstance that your customer is not as impressed with the shipping speeds as you are, make sure you answer questions politely promptly. During the shipping process I asked some questions about why it takes way longer than the advertised 10 days to get my battery, and I got exactly 0 (zero) responses. And I even used the &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot; email address! Nothing says &amp;quot;hey I've got your money, now beat it!&amp;quot; like ignoring paying customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7. Let your products speak for themselves.&lt;/strong>
When the customer receives your product, it is your chance to shine. The product will prove itself to be a top-of-the-line knockoff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="nice-fit.jpg">&lt;img src="nice-fit.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this case you can clearly see how beautiful it fits the macbook, sitting &amp;quot;perfectly&amp;quot; flush with the body, having the exact same Aluminum color, and immediately is recognized as a brand new, fresh battery by the OS. (NOT, NOT and NOT).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="not-charging.png">&lt;img src="not-charging.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Should you think this is not enough, you can add some extra pizzaz to the whole customer experience by leaving the original wholesale receipt in the box. It will tell the customer how much you paid for this cheap knockoff ($30 is €22,81).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="actual-wholesale-price.png">&lt;img src="actual-wholesale-price.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you are really the top of the line customer experience perfectionist, you can rig your battery to grow bulges. Is that a battery in your laptop or is it glad to see me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="laptop-bulge-1.jpg">&lt;img src="laptop-bulge-1.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="laptop-bulge-2.jpg">&lt;img src="laptop-bulge-2.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>8. Have a money-back guarantee.&lt;/strong>
When the battery almost explodes, and the customer asks you about your money-back guarantee, politely ignore those mails, just as you did with the shipping inquiries. For good measure, make sure you filter out all messages from paying customers so you can focus on new ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recap:&lt;/strong>
This lengthy article is proof of the fact that you can, in fact, easily convince people to blog about your webshop. Use suspicious names on the receipts, make sure delivery takes weeks or months, ship the cheapest, crappiest products you can find, use a free gmail account to do customer service from, and well, actually, just simply don't do customer service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for my personal story: I have learned to not order the cheapest knockoff battery at some random shop because the price is too tempting. This dead battery arrived a month after ordering, and cost me €56,30 + €16,87 = &lt;strong>€73,17&lt;/strong> instead of the advertized €44,-.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although I did ask about the refund policy, I doubt I'll ever send this battery back, because I don't expect them to refund me, and I probably will have to pay for shipping, which means more loss. Let's just say that this is an just an expensive way to create material for my blog and helping you make the right buying decision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've ordered a proper battery at &lt;a href="http://store.apple.com/nl/product/MA348G/A">Apple&lt;/a> for &lt;strong>€139,-&lt;/strong> but this time I know there will be no extra charges, it will fit perfectly, and it will just work. Learn from this blogpost and please, please order the original battery from the original manufacturer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy shopping!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drobo FS Lion Time Machine Fix</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/01/07/drobo-fs-lion-time-machine-fix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/01/07/drobo-fs-lion-time-machine-fix/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6xe7bIfj7VM">&lt;img src="drobo-bandaid.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Many Drobo FS owners out there who upgraded to Lion were unpleasantly surprised by the fact that their Drobo no longer behaved like they used to. After months, drobo released new firmware, but it didn't improve things all that much. With the new firmware, the Drobo FS:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * is slow or entirely unresponsive, Time Machine backups don't finish at all or take days
* doesn't show up in the Finder of Lion Macbook owners connecting through wifi
* has a transfer speed of 20MB/s, even when connecting through GB Ethernet, regardless of OSX version (tested with Snow Leopard, Lion)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you have one or more of the problems listed above, you will be pleased to hear that there is a &amp;quot;fix&amp;quot;, although it may not be what you were hoping for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->The Good&lt;/strong>
Late 2010 I discovered drobo. Until then, I had always managed my storage space myself, transferring data to &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/09/07/a-bigger-timemachine-without-changing-history/">bigger disks&lt;/a> as time went on. The idea of a device which would automatically do that by just plugging in a new drive sounded like a real time saver. That, and the fact that it could handle a disk failure without data loss, and behave like network Time Machine share made me buy a Drobo FS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On December 19th 2010, I spent a whopping €615,- on a diskless Drobo, and threw another €300,- worth of 1TB disks in there, along with some old disks I had lying around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I moved all &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2010/12/30/move-time-machine-data-to-a-drobo/">backups to the Drobo&lt;/a>. Life would be good. Or so I thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Bad&lt;/strong>
The Drobo does what is called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thin_provisioning">&amp;quot;Thin Provisioning&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. This means that it will tell your computer that it is 16TB in size, although physically it isn't. This means that when you run out of physical storage space, you replace one of the drives with a bigger one and your computer wouldn't even notice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I created a Time Machine share on the drobo, I discovered that this was not entirely true. When you create a Time Machine share on the drobo, you must choose a size in order to keep Time Machine from filling up your drobo. But unlike other shares on the drobo, you can't change the size of the Time Machine share when you decide you need more room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got over it, chose large enough Time Machine shares for all my machines, and everything worked fine for a couple of months. Performance wasn't great, particularly mounting the sparse bundles took quite some time and a lot of disk access on the drobo, but hey. It's seamless automated backup to a redundant disk array so it was acceptable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip forward to July 20th, 2011. The release date of OSX 10.7, Lion. Because I wanted to make sure everything still worked in Lion, I waited until September 2011 before upgrading my Macbook. My other machines are too old and are still running Leopard (OSX 10.5) or Snow Leopard (OSX 10.6).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the reasons I had to wait until September was drobo. They didn't have their software ready for Lion, and drobo actually &lt;a href="http://halmueller.wordpress.com/2011/07/28/drobo-fs-problems-under-mac-os-x-lion/">tried to blame Apple for it&lt;/a>. Yes you read that right. The OSX Lion developer preview had been out since &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2010/">October 20, 2010&lt;/a> but somehow drobo didn't seem to have bothered to check compatibility all that time, and as a result effectively bricked all drobo's for Lion users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Ugly&lt;/strong>
After the storm had passed, and Drobo released a firmware upgrade, I switched to Lion on my Macbook after installing the new firmware on the Drobo FS. The Lion upgrade went very smooth and I happily played with Lion's new features. After a few hours, I noticed that the Drobo stopped working. No backups. Yikes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The drobo wasn't visibile when connecting over wifi and at first Lion was blamed for this problem. But my Mac Mini running Snow Leopard also started complaining about not being able to backup. I filed my first drobo support call at 09/18/2011 04:46 AM with the title &amp;quot;New Drobo FS firmware doesn't work with Snow Leopard TimeMachine&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was downhill from there. Drobo support had me throw away Time Machine shares (losing data), reset the whole drobo (losing ALL data on the drobo), install bleeding edge firmware which was not even available through the normal drobo dashboard, advised me to both up- AND downgrade the drobo and the dashboard, repeatedly closed my support calls without actually solving them, refused to answer to replies not coming from the first email address I used, had me send numerous diagnostic files to them, and told me &amp;quot;they were working on a new firmware&amp;quot; but never when it was scheduled for release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In less than 4 months, I exchanged more than 80 mails with Drobo Support, and the drobo had lost all my data 4 times. It had become more unreliable than any disk I had ever owned before. I was lucky to run backups-of-backups. The drobo may be able to handle drive failures, but the firmware developers and &lt;a href="http://www.stolensnapshots.com/dontdodrobo">drobo support people are a lot less worried about your data&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Fix&lt;/strong>
During these months, I struggled to keep my backups running. On December 13th 2011, I finally bit the bullet and fixed my drobo backup problems. If you want to fix your drobo Time Machine backup problems for once and for all, do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Connect to your drobo with an admin account, and using the Finder, copy all sparse bundles from all Time Machine shares to a location other than the drobo. Do the same for all other data you might have on there.
2. Go the the Apple store and [buy a Time Capsule](http://store.apple.com/us/product/MD032LL/A/Time-Capsule-2TB) (as a bonus, this also upgraded my wifi speed a great deal)
3. If you have just one machine you want to backup, plug it in and open Time Machine preferences on your Mac, and choose the Time Capsule as backup location. If you don't want to transfer your old backups, you're done.
4. For more technically inclined people, you can create encrypted and limited size sparse bundles for each of your machines on the TIme Capsule. Read [this article](http://michaelnozbe.com/mac-osx-lion-secure-backup-to-time-capsule-wi) by Michael &amp;quot;Nozbe&amp;quot; Sliwinski on how to do that. It works beautifully.
5. If you want to transfer the data in your old Time Machine sparse bundle from your drobo, you can use [this tip](http://www.unlikelywords.com/2009/01/05/moving-a-time-machine-backup-to-a-time-capsule/) to do that, but frankly I haven't tried that, I just created new, clean, backups.
6. Now go and sell your drobo to somebody who doesn't care about his data that much, or just wants a NAS for his Windows machine.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="time-capsule.jpeg" alt="">
The Time Capsule has run beautifully out of the box, doesn't have a butt-ugly dashboard like the drobo's, and is actually faster over wifi than the drobo is over GB ethernet. Go figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that some day, somebody will create a drobo-like product which actually works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P.S. If you like a challenge, you can actually already build a drobo-like fileshare with much higher performance at a lower cost by buying an HP proliant server, some disks, installing &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenIndiana">OpenIndiana&lt;/a> on it and run a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS">ZFS array&lt;/a>. A friend of mine has replaced his troublesome drobo with this setup and can reliably copy files to it at 120MB/s over GB ethernet, and swap out drives while he's doing that. Drobo isn't even close.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pan Rant</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 13:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/26/the-pan-rant/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQu5Unc_TNY">&lt;img src="de-buyer-26cm-carbon-steel-mineral-frying-pan-11546-0-1315069074000.jpeg" alt="">
&lt;/a>You may have seen recent tweets from me ranting about my frying pans. I've ruined a few (very expensive) pans and replaced them with dirt-cheap pans which are actually much better. I would like to share my experiences and solutions with you, so that you can buy the right (cheap) pan without having to go through the same thing. Links to all the pans are in the article below.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->In my household, I try to avoid PTFE (Teflon) coated pans as much as I can. In normal consumer stores, it is almost impossible to find good PTFE-free pans. A few years ago I found two [Calphalon pans](http://www.calphalon.com/pages/home.aspx), a small 20cm frying pan of around €90,- (yes you've read that correctly) and a 30cm frying pan of €140,- (yes, you've read that correctly too). I convinced the store owner that this was rather expensive for two pans so he "let me have them" for "just" €200,- These pans are made of hard anodized aluminum, are scratch resistant and have have pretty good non-stick properties.
&lt;p>After a few years, the large Calphalon pan started to show some black stains on the rim, and I wanted to clean those. I regularly clean the pans with abrasive sponges, but this black stuff wouldn't come off. In a strange (and stupid) last effort to clean it, I sprayed the large pan with oven cleaner. The aluminum started oxidizing, and the pan was ruined. I was pretty upset, but luckily I did it with just one pan (albeit the most expensive one).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3113.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Off to the store I went, but this time with a smaller budget. I bought a nice and shiny polished aluminum BK frying pan for €30,- . I used it for a few days and very quickly the pan had some brown spots on the rim of the pan. Being polished aluminum, I could not use abrasive sponges here. So I tried all kinds of tricks from this &lt;a href="http://www.omaweetraad.com/">&amp;quot;grandma's advice&amp;quot; website&lt;/a> without the desired results. The last tip I tried was to kook some washing detergent in it, which should dissolve the brown grease. It did not. Instead, it &lt;a href="img_3135.jpg">ruined the pan completely&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frustrated by the fact that nobody in the world (or at least on &amp;quot;the internets&amp;quot;) seemed to have pan cleaning problems or answers, I started looking for different alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some googling shows that most professional restaurants use rolled steel pans, without any coating. Just plain steel. This is actually pretty funny, when you think about the expensive Teflon and Ceramic coated pans in the stores for well over €30,- while professional cooks use steel pans of around €20,- which survive many years of heavy use and actually become better and better over time. Professional cooks mostly use gas as heat source, but steel pans can be used on &lt;em>any&lt;/em> heat source, even on induction stoves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I already have a rolled steel wok, and am very happy with that, so I decided to get a rolled steel &amp;quot;De Buyer&amp;quot; frying pan at &lt;a href="http://www.kookman.nl/nl/pannen/plaatstaal.html?page=shop.product_details&amp;amp;flypage=flypage.tpl&amp;amp;product_id=991&amp;amp;category_id=28">kookman.nl&lt;/a>. I ordered it on a Saturday, and on Sunday they mailed me that didn't have the 26cm pan and offered to send me the 30cm for the same price. That sounded like a good deal so that's what I received on my doorstep on Tuesday. Very good service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before doing any cooking, you have to prepare the pan in order to keep the meat from sticking to the steel. This is called &amp;quot;seasoning the pan&amp;quot; and is really easy to do: Heat the pan, then add oil, and fry some salt in it. There are different methods but salt blackens the pan quicker, I like that. The good thing about a steel pan is that if you screw it up, you can practically sand it down with your abrasive sponge and try again. and again. and again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3347.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3347.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Here you see my de Buyer pan after seasoning and a few evenings of cooking. This is how your clean pan should look. Washing a non-coated steel pan is generally done without detergent, under extremely hot water with a brush. This keeps the dark &amp;quot;nonstick coating&amp;quot; in the pan. The pans will become darker upon use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you leave the pan dirty overnight, the grease will sometimes come off, or it will start to rust. Don't worry, scrub it and re-season it and you have a new pan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My new steel frying pan will probably outlast me and my kids. And if I can keep the small Calphalon pan away from the oven cleaner, it may do the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="imgres-1.jpeg" alt="">
So that's the pan story. But I hear you ask &amp;quot;Why all this trouble? Why not buy a Teflon pan?&amp;quot; Here's why: I don't trust it to be healthy. Teflon is one of the scariest polymers out there, and anybody knows how Teflon coating degrades, leaving little pieces of Teflon in your food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you search around for the chemical properties of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polytetrafluoroethylene">Teflon&lt;/a>, you will find some interesting facts. Meat is usually fried between 200 and 230 °C. The thermochemical decomposition of PTFE (Teflon) is detectable at 200 °C. If you ever wondered why your canary died early, the degradation by-products can be &lt;a href="http://www.bartcop.com/dead-canary.gif">lethal to birds&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfluorooctanoic_acid">PFOA&lt;/a> is used in the production process of PTFE coated pans to reduce surface tension. Tests with PFOA on laboratory animals showed increased risk of cancer. Recently higher serum levels of PFOA were found to be associated with increased risk of chronic kidney disease in the general United States population. This is consistent with earlier animal studies. It is also recently &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/07/13/us-teflon-component-linked-to-arthritis-idUSTRE76C3WR20110713">linked to Arthritis&lt;/a>. PFOA is a carcinogen, liver toxicant, a developmental toxicant, an immune system toxicant, and also exerts hormonal effects including alteration of thyroid hormone levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, several manufacturers have started selling pans with ceramic coatings and put &amp;quot;PTFE Free&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;PFOA Free&amp;quot; labels on these pans. Why do you think they did that? Maybe it's because PTFE and PFOA aren't all that healthy after all. And apart from the coating in your pan, the production process of PTFE and PFOA is very, very bad for the environment. &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/manufacturing/2005-07-19-teflon_x.htm">Ask Dupont&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it turns out, if you know how to treat a pan, &lt;strong>the best coating is no coating at all&lt;/strong>. It's not only healthier and better for the environment, but top chefs will tell you it actually makes your food taste better. Next time you are in an expensive restaurant, ask what pans they use. You'd be surprised.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review: Lamy Pico pen</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/23/review-lamy-pico-pen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 21:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/23/review-lamy-pico-pen/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="1300_p630491a.jpeg" alt="">
A few weeks ago I saw this amazing pen design by Lamy, the Pico. I'm a heavy computer user so I don't do much handwriting, but I do like nice tools so I thought I'd get this. Particularly the small form factor when retracted and the sleek design attracted me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some things about the Pico that nobody is telling you, so I thought I'd write a little review.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The pen is nicely packaged and looks really cool in the shop display. I bought it at €35,- which is pretty steep for a ballpoint pen. You can probably find a cheaper seller but I haven't seen prices below €30.
&lt;p>Aston Martin also thinks the Lamy Pico looks cool. It is a standard part of the Aston Martin DB9 interior. If you can't afford an Aston Martin, you can get the Lamy Pico with Aston Martin logo as &lt;a href="http://www.astonparts.com/lamy-pico-compressible-pocket-pen-d160234.html">&amp;quot;replacement part&amp;quot;&lt;/a> so you can show off at the bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When unpacking the pen you immediately notice the plastic feel and light weight, something you might not expect from a pen that looks like it is made of massive steel. The mechanics of the pen work, but with that same plastic sound and feel. The &amp;quot;stroke&amp;quot; for retracting the pen is rather large and sometimes you have to click twice. Holding the pen in writing position feels strange, because it is &amp;quot;Stubby&amp;quot;. It feels like he writing end of the pen is not tapered enough, blocking your view on the paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started writing with it, the black ink would not start to flow immediately. It kept doing this, and it became really irritating. Maybe this pen had been in the shop for a very long time, drying out the ink. It gave me a good excuse to buy a blue replacement cartridge because blue stands out when annotating black printed text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="4014519133803_bum-550.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my dismay, the €2,60 Lamy Pico M22 M replacement cartridge was even worse. The ink does not flow immediately when you start writing, and with this blue cartridge, it stops flowing after 3 words. It actually turns out to be a &lt;a href="http://nopenintended.wordpress.com/tag/lamy-pico/">known problem&lt;/a> with these cartridges. If I had only known beforehand. Here you can see some writing with the Lamy Pico compared with a standard Parker Jotter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3320.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3320.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can clearly see in the &amp;quot;T&amp;quot; that the ink did not start to flow immediately. After just a 2 words, the M22 cartridge just gives up. Mind you that this is a new, fresh cartridge. The black cartridge I mentioned  wrote a couple more words before stopping but was worse in starting the ink flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comparison, the good old Parker Jotter immediately starts putting down dark blue ink and stays consistent all throughout the page. The Parker actually sometimes leaves a little blob of ink, which sometimes smudges when you wipe over it with your hand. But it writes, and that is not what we can say for the Pico.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_3324.jpg">&lt;img src="img_3324.jpg?w=109" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the couple of days I (tried to) use the Lamy Pico at work, I started noticing scratches on the end cap. These scratches are made by the pen itself, from the retracting motion. You can clearly the scratches on the image on the right. This is after just a week of very mild office use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compared to my cheap but very reliable all steel &lt;a href="http://www.parkerpen.com/en/discovery/range/performance/jotter">Parker Jotter&lt;/a> which has survived many years in my Filofax, has a nice steel feel, a firm &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; and the very reliable Parker replacement cartridges, the expensive plastic unreliable Lamy Pico is no comparison.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Good&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Very nice design with a high &amp;quot;cool factor&amp;quot;
* Fits nicely in your pocket
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Bad&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Looks metallic but feels plastic
* Makes it's own scratches on the end cap
* Too slippery and feels too &amp;quot;stubby&amp;quot; to be an all-day writing pen.
* Refills are of very poor quality. Ink will not start to flow, and stops flowing after a few words so you can not even use it to write a complete sentence.
* Absolutely unusable as reliable pen.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you are looking for a reliable pen with good looks, don't buy a Pico. The cartridges are terrible, and will fail you every time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catnip Watering System</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/04/catnip-watering-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 20:04:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/12/04/catnip-watering-system/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Here's a one minute how-to on growing catnip without having to water your plants every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6jyqNzNeQeE]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The €2800,- Roaming Gigabyte</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 20:06:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/09/27/the-e2800-roaming-gigabyte/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjf-6p76rhA">&lt;img src="burnmoney.jpg" alt="T-Mobile is scum">
&lt;/a>We all know the stories about how vacationing smartphone users became the victim of high &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roaming">roaming&lt;/a> charges, resulting in monthly bills sometimes exceeding €1000. To put an end to this, the EU has come up with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_on_roaming_charges_in_the_European_Union">rule&lt;/a> stating that carriers can no longer charge more than €50 per month for roaming, and are obliged to warn the user before reaching this limit. That all sounds nice and consumer friendly, but I recently tested this, and received an &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; monthly bill from T-Mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I've got an iPhone 4, and like many Dutch iPhone users, I got mine with a T-Mobile contract. I always used Vodafone because it has much better coverage, but when the iPhone 3 came out, T-Mobile was the only way to go and after some hesitation, I switched providers. To this day, the network coverage is not as good as Vodafone's, I miss calls even when I have full bars, and even if I can get "3G", the speeds are not nearly as good as friends with iPhones on the Vodafone network.
&lt;p>Having said that, my contract is an old contract which means I have a truly unlimited data plan, for a reasonable price. That is, until you cross the border.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks ago, we went to France for a week of Eurodisney with the kids and grand kids. Because of the project stress at work, and de possibility to share pictures with my parents, I decided to enable roaming on my iPhone. I did try to check the T-Mobile site for data plans and bundles, but these were either not meeting my needs (day passes), or were too hard to compare with each other. I checked my contract and the roaming charges seemed only slightly higher than the blocks, box-packs, travel-smurf, stack-bundles, or whatever convoluted pricing schemes these carriers were trying to trick me in to. I decided to reset the usage info on my iPhone and keep an eye on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2117-all.png">&lt;img src="img_2117-all.png" alt="Welcome to France">
&lt;/a>I crossed the border and received the usual SMS, about rates everybody ignores. I did see that data was €2,- per MB (yes mega-byte) but it looked more like a typo to me, surely they didn't mean mega-byte, did they? During my stay in France, I got he absolute worse network coverage and data speeds you can imagine. No matter where I was, reading text-only email turned into a chore taking sometimes minutes to load. Twitter feeds were barely coming through, and sending a downscaled 100kB image actually took several retries, and multiple minutes. It was horrible. And then, on day 4, it all came to a halt. No SMS, no warning, no mail, no phone call, just total data shutdown. I could still make &lt;a href="http://www.rense.com/general79/metal.htm">robot-voice calls&lt;/a>, but all data traffic stopped and I had no idea how to get that going again. And that turned out to be a good thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2114.png">&lt;img src="img_2114.png?w=100" alt="Data usage">
&lt;/a>I checked my usage, and guessed that I must have crossed the €50,- mark somewhere, and the carrier shut me down to &amp;quot;protect me&amp;quot; from high roaming charges. I tried to SMS a few people to let them know I was still alive, and that was that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few weeks after I got home, I got the bill, and yes, there it was: I had reached the €50,- mark. It was an expensive experiment, and well worth this blogpost. Here's why. On my home &lt;a href="http://www.xs4all.nl/consument/internetbellen/start.php">entry-level 8Mbit ADSL connection&lt;/a>, I have free VOIP, and unlimited data. I checked our ADSL traffic and my family seems to be doing about 20GB a month combined. My monthly bill is €45,- so if I don't use the phone you could say that a GB of traffic costs me (€45 / 20 GB) &lt;strong>€2,25 per GB.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="factuur_30082011.png">&lt;img src="factuur_30082011.png" alt="The amazing T-Mobile roaming charges">
&lt;/a>As you can see in my data usage screenshot on the iPhone, and the bill on the right, I hardly made use of voice or sms. So we can roughly do the same calculation, assuming that 99% of the bill is data. The monthly bill was €89,45, and that got me 31.450MB of data (yes, again: mega-byte). So the price of a roaming Gigabyte in Europe is (€89,45 / 0.031450 GB)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>€ 2844,20 per GB&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you see is no typo. Almost €3000,- per GB. So what the Phone company is telling me here, is that even though the networks in all countries are reaching right up to the border, and we live in an interconnected world where data travels freely across the globe, phone companies charge more than 1000x the regular price to get a bit of information across that border?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think carriers need to be seriously investigated by the EU and Trading committees, because they are using their monopoly to charge us prices which are totally unrealistic. It also proves that privatization of public services like communication networks doesn't work. It nearly always results in a few greedy companies cobbling up a system which delivers crappy service for an outrageous price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first step for these leeches is to come back from &lt;a href="http://rolfje.com/2010/11/23/why-phone-comps-fail/">whatever cave they were in&lt;/a>, move forward in time to 2011, and replace the &amp;quot;MB&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;GB&amp;quot; on my bill, without changing anything else. That would &lt;em>still&lt;/em> make them 26% more expensive than my internet provider, but at least it would take the roaming charges to an acceptable level, even for the crappy data speeds they blatantly market as &amp;quot;high speed&amp;quot;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to fix a Krups XN2001 Nespresso machine</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/08/27/how-to-fix-a-krups-xn2001-nespresso-machine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 12:57:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/08/27/how-to-fix-a-krups-xn2001-nespresso-machine/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FpHwCmobz88">&lt;img src="krups_xn20011.jpeg" alt="Click here to see some amazing Latte Art">
&lt;/a>Maybe the title of this post should read &amp;quot;how to open a Krups XN2001 Nespresso machine&amp;quot;. The Krups XN2001 is almost identical to the newer XN2002 and XN2003. While the XN2003 has normal Torx screws, Krups was a bit more &amp;quot;protective&amp;quot; when they built the XN2001. It has screws that can not be gripped by any screwdriver. Still, there is an easy trick you can use to get headless screws out of any machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->My Krups XN2001 Nespresso maker has been working fine for the past few years. I descale it almost monthly with very cheap vinegar, but otherwise it needs no maintenance. Just after I repaired my [free Aeroccino](http://rolfje.com/2011/08/16/aeroccino-motor-replaced/), the power button of the Krups XN2001 started to fail. It was hard to turn the machine on, like there was a bad contact.
&lt;p>When I tried to open the Krups XN2001, I noticed these funny looking screws, which looked more like nails. After I discovered that these were actually normal screws, I needed to figure out how to get to the ones at the bottom.&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Yes, it's a screw, not a nail!](img_2180.jpg)
](img_2180.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![No Dremel in the world could reach those...](img_2181.jpg?w=112)
](img_2181.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
I took the Nespresso machine to a hardware store I frequently visit, and talked to a new hire there. I showed him the machine and he took off on a rant about how I should not open it, that it was dangerous, and it would void the warranty. I told him it was a five year old machine and it was for fun. Just when he got irritated and told me "doesn't matter, you can't open it", a colleague of him overheard our conversation. He looked at the new hire, smiled, and while pointing at me said "but he can".
&lt;p>A few laughs and a short discussion later, it turned out that they did not have tools that would fit or grip the headless screws. I went into &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=09UlB17cgKw">&amp;quot;MacGyver mode&amp;quot;&lt;/a> and got an aluminum rod that fit nicely on top of the screw head without touching the plastics of the case, and grabbed a tube of industrial strength superglue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At home, I cut the rod into a few shorter bushings, and used the lathe to make them nice and flat. I carved a slot on the other end of each bushing with a dremel tool. Then, I carefully superglued the bushings onto the screws without touching the plastic, and let them settle for a few minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Super Glue and a bushing. Note the slot for the screwdriver.](img_2183.jpg)
](img_2183.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Removed screw with the bushing glued to it.](img_2187.jpg?w=200)
](img_2187.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
After the glue set, it was very easy to use a normal screwdriver to get the screws out. I took the screws with the glued bushings back to the hardware store to show them what I did and got me some new philips head screws with matching size.
&lt;p>Once you open it, you can see how simple this machine is. There's not much that can break, and parts look like they can be easily replaced. Instead of just cleaning the contacts in the button, I decided to go a little further and replaced the existing ones. I had to cut away some placeholders for the old pushbuttons, and drill a hole to hold the green led which tells you what the machine is doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;table width="100%" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![All the electronics. Not much to it, really.](img_2191.jpg)
](img_2191.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![I also replaced the "dispense" button](img_2195.jpg?w=112)
](img_2195.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![The repaired Aeroccino and the repaired Nespresso happily together.](img_2205.jpg)
](img_2205.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
As you can see my Krups XN2001 now looks a bit "steampunked" but it works like a charm!</description></item><item><title>Aeroccino Motor Replaced</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/08/16/aeroccino-motor-replaced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 18:56:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/08/16/aeroccino-motor-replaced/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Months ago, I got this broken Aeroccino milk frother for free. This week I fiddled with it for a few hours, and got it to work:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kNEqWH3ILDc]&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->... and this is how you get it apart. First carefully pull out the button on the front:
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aeroccino-button-remove-1.png">&lt;img src="aeroccino-button-remove-1.png" alt="Removing the front button">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then remove the rubber plugs to get to the screws at the bottom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aeroccino-bottom-screws.png">&lt;img src="aeroccino-bottom-screws.png?w=300" alt="Remove rubber plugs to get to the screws">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You're on your own from here. Be careful not to break any wires when you pull it apart, and take pictures along the way so you know how to put it back together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why some App Store apps won't install</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/01/09/why-some-app-store-apps-wont-install/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 13:37:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/01/09/why-some-app-store-apps-wont-install/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://pcweenies.com/tag/mac-app-store-comics/">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-28-53.png" alt="App Store Icon">
&lt;/a>I was happily playing around with the appstore, and came across this funny free game called &amp;quot;Hedgewars&amp;quot;. Originally a free Linux game, it apparently got ported to the Mac and put in the App Store, just as a slew of Flash-based games (yes, Steve has some 'splainin' to do).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried to install Hedgewars on my trusty Mac Mini and got this message saying &amp;quot;This Application can not be installed on this machine&amp;quot;:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2011-01-08-om-16-45-40.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-08-om-16-45-40.png?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->There was no additional information on what was causing this. So the first thing I did was check out my computer information and the requirements for running this game, which seemed to check out fine:
&lt;table width="100%" class="aligncenter" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-00-40-38.png?w=122)
](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-00-40-38.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-15-55.png)
](schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-15-55.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
I was running the correct version of OSX, so what was the problem here? My neighbor came over and I showed him this funny problem. He found out that Hedgewars could be downloaded from the developers site, and so we did. After opening the DMG, we were greeted with the funny Application Icon decoration show on the right:
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-18-25.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2011-01-09-om-12-18-25.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Usually this means that the application is compiled for a different system than you're trying to run it on. This can happen when you have an older generation PowerPC processor and try to run a non-universal-binary Intel application. So we checked the properties on the application, and it looked like OSX had it wrong. It's an Intel app, and we're running an Intel Mac. So what gives?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next step was to open the Terminal so we could dissect this app on the command line, showing it's inner guts. Apps have all kinds of interesting XML and plist files telling the operating system what to do and how to start it up. Here's what we found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1,2,8&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ cd Hedgewars.app/Contents/MacOS/
rolf@Mac-mini$ ls -l
total 21344
-rwxr-xr-x 1 rolf admin 2627208 27 dec 21:39 hedgewars
-rwxr-xr-x@ 1 rolf admin 5913164 27 dec 21:37 hedgewars-server
-rwxr-xr-x@ 1 rolf admin 2381240 27 dec 21:37 hwengine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rolf@Mac-mini$ file *
hedgewars: Mach-O 64-bit executable x86_64
hedgewars-server: Mach-O executable i386
hwengine: Mach-O universal binary with 1 architecture
hwengine (for architecture x86_64): Mach-O 64-bit executable x86_64
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hedgewars package has 3 executables, one 64-bit x86, one i386, and one universal binary which only contains an executable for 64-bit x86. We guess the developers made a bit of a mess of this. As expected, we could start the i386 executable just fine:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hedgewars-server
Listening on port 46631
^C
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the x86_64 executable and the universal binary would not start:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; light=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; highlight=&amp;quot;1,4&amp;quot;]
rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hedgewars
-bash: ./hedgewars: Bad CPU type in executable&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rolf@Mac-mini$ ./hwengine
-bash: ./hwengine: Bad CPU type in executable
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because this Mac Mini runs a Core Duo, we figured the x86 was okay, but we weren't sure about the 64-bit architecture. A quick peek at &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_Core">Wikipedia&lt;/a> confirmed our suspicion: The Intel Core Duo is not a 64 bit processor. In fact, 64-bit is the major difference between &amp;quot;Core Duo&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Core 2 Duo&amp;quot;. Additional &amp;quot;Googling&amp;quot; showes that &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht3696">Apple Support knows that&lt;/a>, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So there you have it. The Mac App Store does not tell you what the problem really is, but chances are that if you get the &amp;quot;Could not install this Application on this machine&amp;quot; error, you have 32-bit architecture (the Core Duo) and the developer compiled the application for 64-bit architecture (the Core 2 Duo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why in god's name hedgewars has to be a 64-bit application beats me, but that's something I'm not going to change I'm afraid. It turns out that this as been &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hedgewars/issues/detail?id=147&amp;amp;q=core%20duo">reported as a bug&lt;/a> to the Hedgewars team, which hasn't been picked up yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good news for older model Intel Mac Mini Core Duo owners out there: You can replace your CPU with a Core 2 Duo processor. You'll need one of these:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7200 (2.00Ghz)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7400 (2.16Ghz)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Core 2 Duo T7600 (2.33Ghz).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The processors are quite pricey, our quick check showed that they're all above the $200 price mark, which may be a bit steep for a processor upgrade. We expected about half that, so that was a bummer. Should you want to upgrade your CPU, buy thermal paste, and follow a good howto. To get a feeling of what you're getting into, check out the &lt;a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/Mac-mini-Model-A1283-Teardown/659/1">iFixit teardown of the Mac Mini&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other option would be to trade in your Core Duo Mac Mini for a Core 2 Duo Mac mini. It's safer and probably about as costly as buying one of the strangely priced Core 2 Duo processors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Move Time Machine data to a Drobo</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/12/30/move-time-machine-data-to-a-drobo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 21:05:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/12/30/move-time-machine-data-to-a-drobo/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6xe7bIfj7VM">&lt;img src="time-machine-drobo.png" alt="Remember, even Drobo's can die. Make sure your files are in at least three different physical locations, one of which preferably off-site.">
&lt;/a>If Santa treated you particularly well this season, or you have put some of your savings to good use, chances are that you have a brand-new Drobo looking at you right now. Meanwhile, your Mac is happily making Time Machine backups to that trusty old local USB disk. So you want to use that new Drobo for Time Machine backups, but don't want to loose history? Here's how (baby steps, no tools required, screenshots included):&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Connect the Drobo (in my case a Drobo FS) to the network and configure an Administrator password for it. You should now have a working Drobo, with at least 2 drives in it, and it shares a &amp;quot;Public&amp;quot; share on the network.
2. Make sure that the free space reported by the Drobo Dashboard is at least as big as your old USB Time Machine drive. Add drives to the Drobo as needed.
3. In the Drobo Dashboard, click on &amp;quot;Advanced Controls&amp;quot;, go to the &amp;quot;Tools&amp;quot; tab, click on &amp;quot;Settings...&amp;quot; and then select the &amp;quot;Shares&amp;quot; tab.
4. Create a new user for your Time Machine backup. It's important to create a non-admin user to keep your data safe. Trust me, you'll thank me later.
5. Create a new Drobo share (the &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; on the bottom left), give it a meaningful name and select &amp;quot;Enable Time Machine on this drive&amp;quot;. Be careful in choosing the size, you can't change this later!
6. Remove &amp;quot;Everyone&amp;quot; from the allowed users for this share (the &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; bottom right) and add the user you just created (the &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; on the bottom right). You should now have something like this:[![Create Time Machine share on the Drobo FS screenshot](schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-03-55.png?w=300)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-03-55.png)
7. Close Drobo Dashboard, we won't be needing it anymore.
8. Open System Preferences on your Mac, and select &amp;quot;Time Machine&amp;quot;
9. Click on the &amp;quot;Select Disk&amp;quot; option. Don't worry, we're not damaging or loosing your existing backup by doing this.
10. In the popup, you'll see your newly created Time Machine share on the Drobo. Select this share and fill in the Userid and Password you just created on the Drobo.&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-05-39.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-05-39.png" alt="Select Drobo Time Machine share">
&lt;/a>
11. Wait for Time Machine to start, or force it by using the &amp;quot;Backup now&amp;quot; menu option. Time Machine will first try to create a sparse bundle and calculate what to back up. As soon as you see the backup starting (the &amp;quot;zebra&amp;quot; stripes turn into a normal progress bar), click on the cancel button. We only used Time Machine to create a sparse bundle with the correct settings.
12. In System Preferences, switch Time Machine off.
13. Go to the Drobo Time Machine share you just created and mount the sparse bundle you see there.
14. Open Disk Utility and select the USB Time Machine disk.
15. Click on &amp;quot;Restore&amp;quot; and drag the partition of the old USB Time Machine drive to the &amp;quot;Source&amp;quot; box. Drag the partition on the mounted Drobo Time Machine disk to the &amp;quot;Destination&amp;quot; box. Double check my screen shot, it's important to get this right. Drag the partitions, not the disks itself. If you're not able to drag the disks as described, you may want to unmount your old Time Machine drive, remount it, and restart Disk Utility.&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-17-22.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-12-28-om-20-17-22.png" alt="Drag partitions in Disk Utility">
&lt;/a>
16. Make sure &amp;quot;Erase Target&amp;quot; is selected and press &amp;quot;Restore&amp;quot;. Disk Utility may ask for your password.
17. Prepare for a long wait. If you have more than a 500GB backup drive, you wish you had invested in Gigabit Ethernet right now (yes that speeds it up tremendously). My restore of 800GB over a 100Mb network took more than 2 days.
18. Once the process is finished, do not forget to switch Time Machine back on in the System Preferences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That's it. Time Machine will automatically mount the Drobo Share if needed. The first backup will take a bit more time, I think Apple built in a file check to see if the backup is still ok after moving it to another disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Tip 1:&lt;/strong> Keep your old USB Time Machine disk next to the Drobo, even if you have an empty slot. By doing this, you can instantly replace a faulty drive without running to the store. Always keep a spare!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Tip 2:&lt;/strong> Storing data on your Drobo, and then backing up to a Time Machine bundle on that same Drobo is not a backup. A file is only safe if it is stored in 3 different physical locations, one of which is preferably off-site.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Drobo days!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Car Buying Story</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2010 22:50:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/10/the-car-buying-story/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-04-om-21-22-13.png" alt="">
Stephen needs a new car. Being dilligent and a car lover, he takes the time to write down all criteria for a great car. When he finishes the list, he notices that the only car matching all his criteria is a Ferrari. Well, he always loved a Ferrari so that makes sense. To make things more realistic he adds another criteria, called &amp;quot;price&amp;quot;, and starts looking for alternatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->The first car he looks at is practical, but hasn't got the speed of a Ferrari. The second car can carry a lot of stuff, but hasn't got the sound of a Ferrari. The third car is really modular, but hasn't got the looks of a Ferrari. The fourth car is very fast, but doesn't handle as a Ferrari. The fifth car is an independant brand, and can be repaired in any shop, but it breaks down much more often than a Ferrari. The sixth car has a cool design-flip-type-clock and integrated MP3 player, but the manual coming with it does not explain how to operate them.
&lt;p>The seventh car looked too good to be true good in the advertisement. The images in the brochure look stunning. It has everything on his list, and also matches the price criteria. Stephen orders it immediately. But when delivered it does not live up to the whole Ferrari design, look and feel. By far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stephen is not really unhappy and has learned to live with the car's shortcomings. When asked about his new car, Stephen kindly shows it, but the first sentence he regretfuly utters is &lt;em>&amp;quot;but ofcourse, it's not a Ferrari&amp;quot;...&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The moral of this story is: If you don't buy a Ferrari, you'll never own a Ferrari.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: car
replace: mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>search: Ferrari
replace: iPhone&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="the-events-in-this-story-are-fictitious-any-similarity-to-any-person-living-or-dead-is-merely-coincidental-i-cannot-emphasize-enough-how-coincidental-the-fictional-entities-are-to-any-real-life-individual-entity-or-character-for-more-disclaimers-id-like-to-refer-you-to-this-sites-about-pagehttprolfjewordpresscomabout">The events in this story are fictitious. Any similarity to any person living or dead is merely coincidental. I cannot emphasize enough how coincidental the fictional entities are to any real life individual, entity, or character. For more disclaimers I'd like to refer you to this site's &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/about/">about page&lt;/a>.&lt;/h6></description></item><item><title>Zūmo Mount for Triumph Speed Triple</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/30/zumo-mount-for-triumph-speed-triple/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 23:57:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/12/30/zumo-mount-for-triumph-speed-triple/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8498.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8498.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>The RAM mount coming with the Garmin zūmo's are fine, but I wanted something more elegant to go with my Triumph Speed Triple. This article contains a detailed description of building your own mount for the &lt;a href="https://buy.garmin.com/shop/shop.do?cID=135&amp;amp;pID=15000">Garmin zūmo 660&lt;/a>. I mounted the zūmo on my Speed Triple, but the mount is universal enough to be center-mounted on any bike which has riser-mounted handlebars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No guarantees ofcourse, you're on your own from here. Bring your tools and read on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8529.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8529.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>WARNING: When I tried to cut one of these rubbers in half, the bottom disk came loose. It was not as securely glued to the rubber as the top disk. When pulling the zūmo on the mount it does not come off, but if you want to be sure order the Garmin 550 mount rubbers (described in article below).&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->Stuff you need to buy:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * [![](img_8444.jpg?w=150)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](img_8444.jpg)A scythe &amp;quot;Harddisk Stabilizer II&amp;quot;. For more info, see &lt;a href="http://www.scythe.co.jp">www.scythe.co.jp&lt;/a>. I got mine at &lt;a href="http://www.ikbenstil.nl">www.ikbenstil.nl&lt;/a>. Buy two of these if you can spare the money, because you're likely to screw one up. Please note that you can also order ready-made M4 dampers at &lt;a href="http://snelbalie.gps.nl/">Waypoint&lt;/a>, but I did not know that at the time, and they are not listed on their shop page.
* a sheet of rubber or an old tyre inner tubing
* A (stainless steel) brace which can fit the handle bars and the rubber at the thickest part. The standard Garmin mount brace is not long enough, I found a perfectly fitting brace sold as some drywall pipe mount (&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5236931">wandputting&lt;/a>).
* two stainless steel self-locking nuts fitting the brace, in my case M6.
* 10x10 aluminum U profile rod, about 50mm length for the counter bracket on the brace
* eight stainless steel M4x15 bolts, with at least four washers.
* 2mm thick aluminum sheet, at least 53x80mm
* at least 30x30mm wood beam, of about 1 meter in length
* wood screws (trust me on these last two items)
* small bottle of mild threadlock (I used &lt;a href="http://www.loctitesolutions.com/index.php?FOLDERID=12096&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=277a20d2714a013c7235e12cade3653e">loctite 243&lt;/a>)
* some &lt;a href="http://www.wd40.com/">WD40&lt;/a> (you should have that in your shop, next to the &lt;a href="http://www.ducttapeguys.com/">duct tape&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**
Tools you need to have:**&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * sharp (new) 3.2mm HSS drill bit and preferably a bench-press drill
* standard set of steel drill bits (1mm to 10mm, whatever you have handy)
* sharp 15mm wood drill but (this needs to be exact)
* M4 inner thread cutter
* firmly attached [bench vise](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vise)
* a set of [metal files](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_(tool))
* a hacksaw
* a wood saw
* a freezer (or rent a small space in that for 24 hours :-)
* an old blanket or towel
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>**
Things you need to do:**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rubber dampers in the harddisk stabilizer have the wrong hole in one end, and a &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5237044?album_id=5237009">piece of thread in the other.&lt;/a> To be able to cut new M4 thread, we need to drill through the steel and the rubber. Drilling rubber is usually a problem, but not if we do some careful preparations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8453.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8453.jpg?w=112" alt="">
&lt;/a>Take the 30x30 wood beam, and cut off four pieces of about 7 to 10 cm length. Drill a 15mm hole in each of them. Then, saw it in half with the wood saw. Be carefull to mark the wood pieces, as they need to fit perfectly back together later on. Drill two small holes in one half of the four clamps, so you can screw it back together perfectly, as if it was 1 piece.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take the rubber dampers from the scythe harddisk stabilizer, put them in the 15mm holes and screw the clamps back together. With the hacksaw, saw off the thread coming out of one end of the damper, and file it so that the metal is &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5237061?album_id=5237009">perfectly flat&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check that the rubber dampers fit the wooden clamps, screw them together pretty tight, and put the four (or eight) assemblies in the freezer for at least 24 hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To protect the paint on your gastank, put an old blanket or towel on it. This will keep you from scratching the tank in the next steps. Extra advantage is that you can put small nuts and washers on your tank without them rolling away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8483.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8483.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>While waiting for the rubbers to cool off, you can prepare the aluminum parts. Take the 10x10 aluminum frame, and drill two holes in it so that the M6 brace fits through it. Mark the perfect middle between the two holes, and use a half-round steel file to file it down so that it fits the handlebars perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be careful to file perpendicular to the aluminum, and re-check your work often. The U profile sits flush against the handlebars, while being perpendicular to them when looking from the riders position. Don't file too deep, allow for some room between the aluminum plate and the handlebars, so that the &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5237030?album_id=5237009">screw heads don't touch the bars&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2009-12-29-om-13-54-41.jpg">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2009-12-29-om-13-54-41.jpg?w=248" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, take the aluminum sheet and make it look like the drawing I made here (this is the shortest sentence in this post, resulting in the most work for the reader).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prepare the benchpress drill by mounting the 3.2mm drill bit. After the rubber dampers in the wood clamps have been in the freezer, take one out and take it to the workshop as fast as you can, make sure to keep it cold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the flat side of the rubber damper (the side where you filed off the thread), drill a hole through the steel, but try not to drill into the rubber too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flip the clamp over, and drill through the original threaded hole, all the way through the rubber. If your benchpress drill is straight, you &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5237076?album_id=5237009">should come out through the hole&lt;/a> you just drilled in the in the other steel plate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Repeat the whole process for each damper. Minimize the time they are out of the freezer. After you've drilled all dampers, they can warm up again by leaving them in the workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8466.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8466.jpg?w=112" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take the dampers out of the wooden clamps. You don't need the clamps anymore, give them to a friend so he can make this cool mount, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Put one of the rubber dampers in the bench vise and use a small drop of WD40 and the M4 thread cutter to cut thread into the 3.2mm holes. Do this on both sides, make sure that you break the cuttings (one turn forward, then 2/3 back, repeat). Repeat this for all dampers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mount up!
You should now have all pieces to mount. Test the fitting of the mount before you use threadlock (loctite) on any of the parts. Because of the construction, there is an order in which you need to assemble the parts, let me take you through it:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8485.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8485.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Mount the rubbers on the zūmo mount, but do not fasten the screws. Attach the aluminum plate to the other side, also not fastening the screws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, tighten the screws on the zumo mount first, then tighten the screws on the aluminim plate. This will make sure that the dampers will align perfectly later on. Take one screw out of the aluminum plate, apply threadlock and a washer, and re-tighten it. Repeat for the other three screws in the aluminum plate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you've done all four screws attaching the dampers to the aluminum plate, take the Garmin zūmo mount off. You should now have an aluminum plate with four dampers firmly attached to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8490.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8490.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>Cut the rubber slab to the correct width and length so that it protects your handlebars from scratches by the mount. Use the brace, the aluminum U profile, two washers and two self-locking nuts to attach the aluminum plate to the handlebars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When compfortable with the position, tighten the bolts and &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/5237129?album_id=5237009">attach the zūmo mount&lt;/a> to the rubber dampers, using threadlock. Everything should match up perfectly, don't force anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And there you have it, all done! More pictures of the whole process are available &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/album/5237009">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_84991.jpg">&lt;img src="img_84991.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Please note:&lt;/strong> At the time of writing I did not thouroghly test the durability and strength of this mount and it's dampers. Mounting the zūmo like this is totally at your own risk, so please be careful. If you're not sure about the dampers, buy ready-made ones fit for this purpose. Your GPS supplier should be able to get a hold of a set.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shooting 16:9 with a 4:3 Camera</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 10:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you have a Canon Ixus 80IS, like me, and you shoot video for your widescreen television at home (like me), you may want to try out this little trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canon Ixus is a 4:3 camera. The video that comes out of it is almost square shaped. When you try to make a 16:9 video, you can stretch it, or crop it. Cropping is far better, but you need some &amp;quot;headroom&amp;quot; to do that. If you made a closeup, chances are that you do not have enough room to crop to a 16:9 format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aspect-ratios.jpg">&lt;img src="aspect-ratios.jpg?w=150" alt="aspect-ratios">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I solved this by making this little chart, which I placed on a memorycard and put in my camera. By previewing the image on the camera's display, you know where the &amp;quot;16:9 limit&amp;quot; is. I put two pieces of half-translucent tape on the camera, so I can tell what fit's inside the 16:9 frame. I also included the other formats, like 3:2, and 2.39:1, should you want to make wide-screen theater movies :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I load up the movie in iMovie, and it will be cropped perfectly. Suppose you missed the 16:9 frame or want to re-center your shot, you can always press the &amp;quot;crop&amp;quot; button in your project to tell iMovie which piece of the image you want.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Packing bags on a Speed Triple</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/18/packing-bags-on-a-speed-triple/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 13:53:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/18/packing-bags-on-a-speed-triple/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_1798.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1798.jpg" alt="my Triumph Speed Triple">
&lt;/a>As you may know, I traded in my Honda Sevenfifty for a nice Triumph Speed Triple. While waiting for the bike to be delivered, I tried to fiend out how I can take my hefty 4-star ART chainlock on this bike. Apparently, nobody uses chainlocks on their bikes because I could find no information at all about transporting chainlocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Ofcourse you can put the chainlock around your body, or in a backpack, but neither of these solutions are without risk. Particularly wearing a chainlock around your neck is pretty dangerous when you fall. You might expect that bike manufacturers would leave some room under the seat to transport a lock. But if you have a Speed Triple, you know how little room there is under the seat.
&lt;p> 
&lt;a href="img_1932.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1932.jpg?w=200" alt="Speed Triple storage... None.">
&lt;/a>    &lt;a href="img_1934.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1934.jpg?w=200" alt="No room in the seat itself... But look! Loops!">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see in these pictures, there is not even enough room to put a pair of summer gloves or a simple disclock under the seat. There is a small compartment at the rear, but my insurance requires me to have an SCM approved alarm, which takes up the remaining space under the seat (the box with the yellow sticker in the top left picture).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_1945.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1945.jpg" alt="Loops sticking out">
&lt;/a>    &lt;a href="img_1942.jpg">&lt;img src="img_1942.jpg" alt="img_1942">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my surprise, Triumph did add a cool feature to the seat itself: loops! Lift the seat, fold the loops out, and put the seat back. Now you can put a backpack on your buddyseat, and strap it to the bike without damaging or even touching any painted parts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Design Gripes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/04/08/design-gripes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Dear Akio Morita,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">&lt;img src="2009-04-08-234308.png" alt="Onion News Network on Sony products">
&lt;/a>Lately I have some small issues with a lot of design decisions being made by the company you founded a while ago. If you look at my irritations seperately they're just small gripes of a grumpy old customer. But the increasing number of design mistakes have me worried about your user acceptance testing and quality assurance processes. Given the sheer size of your company, and the fact that the very same people who are sabotaging your overall product quality can silently delete my complaint, I thought I'd share it with you here, on my very private blog.  Nobody else will read this. Honest.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let me start by saying that I love my Playstation 3. No wait, let me rephrase that. I love playing games on my playstation 3. Because the playstation 3 itself is absolutely not intuitive, logical or even pleasant to use. Both hardware and software wise.
&lt;p>I am very fortunate to have a loving wife who bought a PS3 for me. Because she did not expect to have to do in-depth research about the differences between the models, she bought the 80GB PS3 for me. It was the biggest drive in the store, so she thought that was the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was/am really happy with the very nice present. Not having any PS3 games yet, I slapped in a PS2 game, fully expecting that it would play. Not so. As it turns out, only the 60GB model plays &lt;em>some&lt;/em> of the PS2 games, and most of the time not even perfectly. What's with that? Can this 3-Cell processor huge 80GB machine with metric craploads of memory not emulate the outdated PS2? Did nobody at Sony realize that they can capitalize on people upgrading from the PS2? Not even now that the &lt;a href="http://ps3finder.com/">60GB models actually sell for more money than the 80GB&lt;/a> model retail price?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disapointedly leaving the PS2 compatibility issue, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2009/01/31/dlna-on-osx-done-right/">I got a DLNA server running&lt;/a> on my Mac. When I want to view media on that server, I have to use your &amp;quot;X media bar&amp;quot; menu. For some reason, some designer came up with the brilliant idea to seperate music, photo's and video's in that menu. This means that before browsing my DLNA server, I have to decide what filetype I'm going to browse. If I have folders containing both video and photo's of the same birthday party, I constantly have to back out of the photo viewing mode, get into the video mode, browse all the way back to the folder, and view the video. It's like having to fill in a form to flip the channel on your TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what's with the forgetting of discovered DLNA servers? The PS3 takes ages to re-discover my DLNA server on the network each time I turn the PS3 on, or return to the menu from a game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it even more cringeworthy, the PS3 scares the crap out of me each time I browse to a folder to see that &amp;quot;There are no files...&amp;quot;. The PS3 is lying ofcourse, what it means is that there are MPG's and AVI's there, but I'm in photo viewing mode. The whole X-media-bar design must have never been usability tested by random customers. It's a very common practice nowadays which I can really recommend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By now, I had scored some PS3 games (&lt;a href="http://www.ps3home.nl/products/playstation-3-games/alle-games-a-tot-z/moto-gp-2008-ps3.htm">Moto GP&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.tombraiderunderworld.com">Tomb Raider: Underworld&lt;/a>). After a nice evening of gaming,  I discover that the controller battery is running low. So I connect it to the PS3, and put the PS3 in standby mode, expecting my controller to be charged the next morning. To my huge disapointment, the controller does not charge when the PS3 is not fully on. That strikes me as really strange. To charge my wireless controller, I have to connect it during gaming. Now how did someone on your design team did not notice that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a big old Phillips Matchline TV which worked fine, but was getting a bit dated. The thought of being able to play games in full HD 1080p resolution was very tempting, so I bought a new model Sony Bravia 40 inch TV, thinking that it would interface nicely with the PS3. To my absolute horror, the PS3 video signal looked horrible on this new TV. As it turned out, you are shipping this full HD 300+ dollar gaming machine with a crappy composite video cable. Oh boy. Now I know why people think the difference between a Wii and a PS3 is not that huge. Another obvious commercial win down the drain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and I discovered that HDMI is the best way to go. I bought an HDMI cable and connected the PS3 to the TV with that. The TV manual said it could use some HDMI protocol to discover HDMI connected devices. Surely enough, my brandnew Sony Bravia does not recognize my Sony PS3. How nice is that? Luckaly, after some manual fiddling with the absolutely horrid X-media bar-like menu's in the TV and the PS3, I got everything to play in full HD. Finally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What strikes me as another design flaw is the size of the screen fonts. On my big TV everything looks nice, but I can imagine that the paperboy who emptied his piggybank to get a PS3, and connects it to his little TV in his room, can not read any of the menu items. I take it that the Sony testing department only has Full HD TV's with HDMI cables, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there's the whole casing design thing. Come on. Rounded top? I can not even place a controller on there, it slides off. The ventilation holes are on the side, which makes it imposible to put the PS3 with it's right side against the cupboard. The USB ports are recessed in such a way that if you place the PS3 low to the ground (which happens most), you can not see the ports without having to lie down on the floor eyeballing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you're down there, you can als see the rediculously thick and sturdy mains cable. It can transport enough current to power my microwave. Does the PS3 really use that much current? Now be honest. You could have selected a thinner, more flexible mains lead, and maybe it would even have been cheaper. The current lead almost pushes the PS3 out from the wall. Good thing the PS3 is so heavy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When waking the PS3 from it's sleep mode, there is another interesting thing that strikes me as odd. There is a green and a blue led next to eachother on the top of the button pannel. Not only are those two colors looking horrible next to eachother, and the fact that I have come to loathe any product with a blue led, there is absolutely no way that colorblind people are going to notice the difference in color, which makes them pointless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said, this is just a selection of the gripes I have with the design. For instance, the fact that game makers are allowed to play sounds and video as soon as a game is inserted, is just terrible. It scares the crap out of me each time I insert &lt;a href="http://www.racedrivergrid.com/">Race Driver:GRID&lt;/a>, and there is no way I can turn it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="photo.jpg">&lt;img src="photo.jpg" alt="Sony Bravia remote button misplacement">
&lt;/a>The nicest example of hardware design failure by Sony is the remote control of the Sony Bravia TV. The buttons you use most are in fact unreachable when holding the remote in your hand. The least used buttons are right there by your thumb. What was this designer thinking? Oh and never mind pressing the buttons, because this TV, which can interpolate frames of a 24fps source into 100fps fluid motion while dynamically adjusting sound and backlight, has a very hard time to display a menu or react to the remote. This is absolutely mind boggling to me. It's like a race car which can go from 0 to 300mph in 2 seconds but takes 5 seconds to react to the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I bought all this Sony stuff. I know, I could have bought something else. But there are reasons for me to put up with all this crap. OTHER manufacturers make such great stuff for Sony devices. The games on the PS3 are absolutely beautiful and brilliant. Watching video on the PSP on an airplane is great. Looking at a bluray at 100Hz 1080p on the Bravia is eye-popping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, dear mr. Morita, please, please make the people at Sony aware of these details. They're important. Solving them will set your product apart from the competition in a large way. People may not be able to tell why, but they will like your product better. This is what good designers do. Make a product have a good &amp;quot;feel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will also rid you of online video's describing your products as... well... you've already seen &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/video/sony_releases_new_stupid_piece_of">that video&lt;/a>, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading this rant.
Rolf&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wiimote Whiteboard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:28:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/wiimote-whiteboard">&lt;img src="wiimotewhiteboard_128.png" alt="WiimoteWhiteboard">
&lt;/a>For people wanting to have an interactive whiteboard but don't have the money, &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/">Johnny Chung Lee&lt;/a> has found the solution. Using a Wiimote, he can track an infrared lightsource (like an LED) and use that to control the mousecursor. I tried some software on the Mac and the PC, and I actually got both to work without too much trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The infra-red pen&lt;/strong>
Please note that you need some kind of Infra-Red emitting device. In my first tests to see if the software works, I used a TV remote. This is a bit clunky, so next on my list is to build a simple infra-red pen this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I noticed a lot of people building infra-red pens by directly connecting an LED to a battery, which will possibly ruin your LED very quickly because there's too much current running through it. An LED is a diode, and it needs to be limited in current. The only right way to do it is follow &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/pen.jpg">Johnny's schematic&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the Mac:
I was amazed about how well this worked. I was expecting a lot of experimental stuff, but instead, this is all you have to do:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![](afbeelding-21.png?w=47)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](afbeelding-21.png)Download &lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/files/WiimoteWhiteboard.dmg">WiimoteWhiteboard for the Mac&lt;/a> by Uwe Schmidt.
2. Enable bluetooth on your mac.
3. Start the WiimoteWhiteboard.app
4. On the Wiimote, press buttons 1 and 2 simultaniously to put it in &amp;quot;detectable&amp;quot; mode. If the Wiimote was already on, you may need to press the red button in the battery compartment.
5. After pairing is complete, press the &amp;quot;calibrate&amp;quot; button and follow the instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did these steps on an intel  Mac mini and it worked beautifully. You can pair up to 2 Wiimotes to increase reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the PC:
This is slightly more work, but does not include steps which are strange to regular Windows users:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Download and install the [.Net framework version 3.5](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=333325FD-AE52-4E35-B531-508D977D32A6&amp;amp;displaylang=en)
2. Download Boon Jin's [Smoothboard](http://www.boonjin.com/wp/2008/08/14/wiimote-smoothboard-045-beta) for Windows.
3. [![XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 1](clipboard02.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](clipboard02.png)Install the .Net framework, and unpack the smoothboard zipfile in a convenient location. It has no setup.exe (thank god)
4. In the system tray on your Windows, right-click the bluetooth icon, and choose &amp;quot;Add a Bluetooth Device&amp;quot;
5. Click the &amp;quot;My device is set up and ready to be connected&amp;quot; checkbox.
6. &lt;a href="clipboard03.png">&lt;img src="clipboard03.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 2">
&lt;/a>Press the red button of the Wiimote (in the battery compartement) to unpair it from anything else and get into &amp;quot;detecable&amp;quot; mode.
7. Click the &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button in the Wizzard
8. Select the &amp;quot;Nintendo RVL-CNT-01&amp;quot; device and click &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;
9. &lt;a href="clipboard04.png">&lt;img src="clipboard04.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 3">
&lt;/a>Select the &amp;quot;Don't use a passkey&amp;quot; radio button and DON'T press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;.
10. Press the little red button on the Wiimote again, so that all blue lights start flashing, and then press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; on the wizard.
11. In the tray, you should now see popups saying &amp;quot;Found new hardware&amp;quot; and something like &amp;quot;New HID device&amp;quot;. They will dissapear after a while. If the popups did not show, start the whole process again from step 4.
12. Press &amp;quot;Finish&amp;quot; in the Wizard, notice that the Wiimote keeps flashing all the lights.
13. Start Smoothboard. The Wiimote should stop flashing, and you can click on the &amp;quot;Calibrate&amp;quot; button to start the fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="clipboard05.png">&lt;img src="clipboard05.png?w=33" alt="Smoothboard Screenshot">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've tested the Windows setup on a Dell 530 laptop with the built-in bluetooth device, and it works fine, although I did have to reboot once because the bluetooth stack got confused and refused to detect my Wiimote. Smoothboard also allows you to pair 2 Wiimotes to improve reliability. It also has many features which are tailored to controling Powerpoint and other software, but I haven't tried that yet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zoom Experience 2008</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/11/zoom-experience-2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 22:43:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/11/zoom-experience-2008/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last sunday, I was at the &lt;a href="http://www.zoomexperience.nl/">Zoom Experience 2008&lt;/a> in Utrecht. The organization has learned a lot since last year's debute of the Zoom Experience. There was plenty of room to walk, lots of places to sit down and talk, and the talks were in seperate areas with less noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what the Zoom Experience looked like on Sunday morning:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qy8mXREd7Lo]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replace your mousecable</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/04/replace-your-mousecable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 23:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/11/04/replace-your-mousecable/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="img_0513.jpg" alt="">
I recently tried to purchase a Logitech LS1 mouse from Logitech. After not hearing from them for 3 weeks, I ordered the same mouse at Dynabyte and got it within 5 days. Suddenly Logitech woke up and sent me another LS1 mouse. Because they don't react to mails or calls, I had a spare LS1 to play around with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to replace the long, rigid cable with a short supple one. Here's how you can do that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![](img_0511.jpg?w=59)
&lt;p>](img_0511.jpg)Logitech makes mice, and sometimes nice ones. The trouble is that most mice are for PC users, who have their PC sitting on the floor, far away from the desk. So mouse cables are long, too. Logitech likes to use very ridgid cables for their mice, which sometimes means that the cable will actually have so much &amp;quot;spring&amp;quot; that it will push your mouse back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Normally I'm behind a laptop, so my mousecable can easily be as short as 30cm, and has to be as supple as the wires on your original iPod headphones. Luck has it, that you can actually change the cable on the Logitech LS1 mouse quite easily, with some patience and a soldering iron.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![](img_0517.jpg?w=110)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](img_0517.jpg)Remove the slidepad-stickers to reveal 3 little black screws at the bottom.
2. Open up the mouse.
3. Unplug the white plug and remove the mousecable. The colors on my model were wired &lt;a href="http://pinouts.ru/Slots/USB_pinout.shtml">according to the USB standard&lt;/a>. The leftmost black connects to the housing, the second black is GND, red is VCC, white is D- and green is D+.  
4. Re-use the old plug to solder your own cable onto. I used a very thin mousecable of a very cheap mouse I had lying around, but you can use any supple USB cable you like as long as you get the connections right.
5. &lt;a href="img_0519.jpg">&lt;img src="img_0519.jpg?w=128" alt="">
&lt;/a>Plug the new cable back in, and use a little tie-wrap to keep the cable in place in case you pull it.
6. Put it all back together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the observant reader: No, I did not connect the outer housing to ground, you studied the pictures very well. The new cable only had 4 leads. But given the shorter cable, it works fine without interference. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_05241.jpg">&lt;img src="img_05241.jpg?w=300" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally the mouse with the old and the new cable. See the difference? The old cable almost looks like a sewer pipe compared to the new thinner cable. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you'll excuse me, I'm going to replace the other LS1 mouse with a white USB cable to match my mac :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh and don't order your Logitech mouse directly from Logitech, their webshop is crappy, and their customer support is impossible to reach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>T-Mobile Network Quality</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/31/t-mobile-network-quality/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 23:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/31/t-mobile-network-quality/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_0003.png">&lt;img src="img_0003.png?w=200" alt="">
&lt;/a>As you've noticed, I bought an &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/">iPhone&lt;/a>. When you're living in the Netherlands, you've got two options to get an iPhone. The first one is walk to an Apple reseller, buy an iPhone and sell your soul to T-Mobile. The second option is to drive to Belgium, convince a reseller to sell you a simlock-free iPhone, and get a &lt;a href="http://www.vodafone.nl/prive/favorieten/Super_SIM_Only">Vodafone iPhone &amp;quot;Super Sim Only&amp;quot; contract&lt;/a>. I went for the first option, and to be honest I kind of regret it. The iPhone is brilliant, but the T-Mobile network in the Netherlands sucks. Bigtime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your life depends on somebodies availabilty, please make sure to check they're not using the T-Mobile or Orange network (the companies merged). Don't let T-Mobile fool you with the &amp;quot;iPhone has bad reception hype&amp;quot;. I can make screenshots like you see here each day. I have &amp;quot;No service&amp;quot; but I can see the Vodafone and KPN networks just fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Although the [GSM coverage maps for T-Mobile](http://www.gsmworld.com/cgi-bin/ni_map.pl?x=0&amp;y=0&amp;z=0&amp;cc=nl&amp;net=t3) indicate that the gsm1800 coverage very good, a lot of customers, including me, will tell you otherwise from personal experience. I think the 3G coverage on the map is also unrealistic to say the least.
&lt;p>Here's a short list of locations I went to the last couple of weeks. Please note that in all of these locations, I could reliably see the Vodafone network, inside and outside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;table style="text-align:right;" border="0" >
&lt;tbody >
&lt;tr >
Location
Inside buildings
Outside
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Amersfoort](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.151924,5.411625&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=13&amp;sll=52.140231,5.414543&amp;sspn=0.096926,0.12188&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.142549,5.408363&amp;spn=0.096921,0.12188&amp;z=13)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-4.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Amsterdam, VU hospital](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=nl&amp;q=Vu+Medisch+Centrum,+Nederland&amp;sll=52.373812,4.890951&amp;sspn=0.376443,0.487518&amp;g=Vu+Medisch+Centrum,+Nederland&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;cd=2&amp;geocode=FeKSHgMd9h5KAA&amp;ll=52.334775,4.860184&amp;spn=0.011774,0.015235&amp;z=16)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-2.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Beverwijk](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.481735,4.664254&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=15&amp;sll=52.482754,4.662666&amp;sspn=0.02347,0.03047&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.482101,4.663568&amp;spn=0.02347,0.03047&amp;z=15)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-5.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Haaksbergen](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=Elektrostraat&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=FYwjHAMdZfNmAA%3B&amp;mra=mr&amp;sll=52.156785,6.738631&amp;sspn=0.094573,0.12188&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.166562,6.745605&amp;spn=0.094552,0.12188&amp;z=13)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Haarlem](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.384021,4.63696&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=16&amp;sll=52.382384,4.63505&amp;sspn=0.011762,0.015235&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.384689,4.636724&amp;spn=0.011761,0.015235&amp;z=16)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-5.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >Haarlem
([Parking Central Station](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.386772,4.63902&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=16&amp;sll=52.386785,4.639728&amp;sspn=0.01176,0.015235&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.386366,4.639063&amp;spn=0.011761,0.015235&amp;z=16))
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-4.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[Leusden](http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=52.11457,5.40699&amp;daddr=&amp;hl=nl&amp;geocode=&amp;mra=dme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=0&amp;sz=14&amp;sll=52.117574,5.418062&amp;sspn=0.047328,0.06094&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=52.112673,5.406475&amp;spn=0.047333,0.06094&amp;z=14)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-none.png)
![](edge-no-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >![](bars-3.png)
![](edge-icon.png)
![](3g-no-icon.png)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>&lt;/table>
 
&lt;p>Terrible right? In Amersfoort, Amsterdam, Haaksbergen and Leusden I actually had to walk outside to make calls, or to see if I had missed any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that this will improve significantly, otherwise I have to try to unlock my iPone and buy a Vodafone simcard. T-Mobile will then probably hold my phonenumber hostage until the end of my contract just because they can. I've had the same phonenumber for the past 15 odd years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you've got a choice, try to get an iPhone from Belgium, and avoid T-Mobile because you will be frustrated by the lack of connectivity. The only thing you'll miss is the Visual Voicemail, but if your network is good, you don't need voicemail all that much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For now, I'm going to check if my hart surgeon uses the T-Mobile network. If so, I need to switch to a smarter surgeon ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The iPhone buying experience</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 18:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/10/11/the-iphone-buying-experience/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Ok so I've been &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/10/apple-reinvents-phone-ipod-and-userinterface-in-1-go/">blogging about&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/13/see-the-iphone-demo/">the iPhone&lt;/a> and&lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/08/07/cowbell/"> it's &amp;quot;apps&amp;quot;&lt;/a> for a while now. After a lot of consideration and switching between Nokia and iPod touch, doing nothing and buying a 16GB 3G iPhone, I finally went for the latter. What a bittersweet experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->We have no real Apple stores. They're called "Apple authorized resellers" and may look like an Apple store, but they're not. Because they are run by slow Dutch people (I get to that in a minute), and don't have geniuous bars, and can't seem to be of help unless you want to buy something.
&lt;p>In the Netherlands, you can by an iPhone at T-mobile shops, or at the Apple store. At the T-Mobile stores, there are often no iPhones in stock. At the Apple stores (let's call 'em that, to humor them) the employees know nothing of cellphone contracts. Because I like the interiour of the Apple store better, I decided to get my iPhone there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went for the black 16GB 3G model, because the white one is just a bit to &amp;quot;girly&amp;quot;, and is easy to spot 100 miles away for any bad guys out to steal iPhones. I came prepared with copies of my passport and old SIM card. The guy behind the counter went into the storage room to get one. Then something strange happened: a &lt;a href="http://www.parallels.com/">Parallels&lt;/a> session was started up, and an Internet Explorer browser opened to show a HTTPS page at which we could fill in a contract form. It took ages to start up, and the T-Mobile &amp;quot;special registration form&amp;quot; was teribly slow. The Apple salesman was not very fast either, I had to correct him more than once because he didn't read the instruction on the screen. All in all I spent 37 minutes (measured) in the store to get everything registered and payed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I am still wondering why the T-Mobile registration page could not have been opened in Firefox or Safari on OSX.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a week, T-mobile sent a letter saying that my old number could not be ported. I called customer support and as it turned out, the guy at the Apple store still didn't fill in the form correctly (I wonder what he missed after staring at 2 html forms for 37 minutes). After being on hold for over 28 minutes at the T-Mobile helpdesk, they solved everything and my original number got transfered within 3 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here I am, with an iPhone. Prepare to read a lot about it. ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OSX: Formatting a 1TB USB Drive</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/07/osx-format-1tb-usb-drive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 11:50:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/09/07/osx-format-1tb-usb-drive/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I just bought a Maxtor Basics 1TB drive, and found that I could not seem to format it using the Leopard Diskutility. Then, I found &lt;a href="http://en.kioskea.net/forum/affich-4848-wd-my-book-formattin">this page&lt;/a> which contained the golden tip. I'll save you some reading:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Open Apple's Disk Utility
2. Click on the drive (not the partition in it, if there is any), and select &amp;quot;Partitioning&amp;quot;.
3. Select &amp;quot;1 partition&amp;quot; and then press &amp;quot;Options&amp;quot;.
4. You'll see that &amp;quot;MBR&amp;quot; is the default, which is what's causing the problem. Select the middle option &amp;quot;Apple Partition&amp;quot; and you're good to go.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-2.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Screenshots included. It's in Dutch, but the location of the buttons are identical for all languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Weekend of Crashes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/31/a-weekend-of-crashes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 20:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/31/a-weekend-of-crashes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3413035">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3413035_46466e31d22ffce53207f35d201971fb_thumb.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>This weekend was a lot of fun. Saturday night I got to fly Leo's Walkera 60B electric helicopter. That's one piece of impressive (and scary) machinery. Although it feels easier to fly than my 4#3B, I still &amp;quot;managed&amp;quot; to crash it. Luckaly the blades can be easily replaced, and after tightening a bunch of screws and replacing a pin in the main gear, it was good to fly again. We flew 3 times, and had to repair the helicopter after each flight :-) I hope I can treat you with good shots of the Walkera 60B next time, there are not many high-quality images of it online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3413033">&lt;!-- more -->&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3413033_ea62d55e9fd2d7bf2b3876f1780455d0_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>After getting the hang of the big 60B, I got home and did some flying with my little &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/">Walkera 4#3B&lt;/a>. I can now seem to hover it slightly longer than last week, but I still &amp;quot;landed&amp;quot; the thing in the strangest places. Normally there's not much damage, but this time I broke the tail rotor axle. In the pictures, you can also see the crack in the canopy which I simply repaired with a piece of tape. After I repaired the tailrotor, I crashed it again, this time breaking the rear tail altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third crash this weekend was not mine, but &lt;a href="http://paddocktalk.com/news/html/modules/ew_filemanager/08content/motogp/ducati/gb/motogp-fri-stoner-quickest-641.jpg">Kacey Stoner&lt;/a>'s. In the MotoGP race at Misano, Rossi almost high-sided in the first lap, and that little mistake made the gap with Stoner about 3 seconds. As Rossi was trying to gain, Stoner went down in the hairpin in the 8th lap. I sure would have liked to see Rossi and Stoner battle for the win. All in all &lt;a href="http://www.motogp.com/en/news/2008/Rossi+takes+home+victory+and+75+point+advantage+at+Misano">it was a nice race&lt;/a>, won by Valentino Rossi.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macbook Pro Screen update issues</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/18/macbook-pro-screen-update-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/18/macbook-pro-screen-update-issues/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My wife has this great Macbook Pro 15&amp;quot;, and I &amp;quot;don't mind&amp;quot; using it every now and then. I noticed that when running on batteries, screen updates are a bit strange:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * When scrolling down a webpage, the page get garbled. Scrolling the garbled piece out of the window and in again sometimes fixes it.
* When resizing a Finder window, the icons in the window flicker a lot, you can see them being cleared and redrawn.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I noticed more people having these problems on several forums, and I also read that resetting the PRAM could fix it. Well, I just reset the PRAM and it seems to have fixed it, indeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used the method mentioned on &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1379">Apple's support page&lt;/a>, which tells you to shut the computer down, and boot it up holding the command, option, P and R keys. As soon as you see it shutting down after you've started it up, release the keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is all I did, and it seems to have fixed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Helicopter to Master</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 20:41:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/10/new-helicopter-to-master/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/photo/3362481">&lt;img src="http://www.23hq.com/23666/3362481_59575b58bcabdbf0ca1207bdb4756665_mblog.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>A friend of mine and me ordered 2 Walkera 4#3B electric model helicopters 3 weeks ago. Last frinday, they finally arrived, and this weekend we had some good fun flying them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think flying a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/12/06/helicopter-fun/">PicooZ&lt;/a> is hard, don't even start thinking about one of these. It looks easier on the &lt;a href="http://nl.youtube.com/watch?v=VbvD4OYOqt8">youtube video's&lt;/a> than it seems. I have some experience with RC models (mainly cars and boats), but flying this helicopter is really hard. I can not get it to hover steadily, I need some serious practice to tame this baby. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just took my camera out to shoot make some action shots of the heli's in the air, when one of them crashed so hard that the tail boom broke. We ordered some spare parts for both 'copters, they'll arrive somewhere next week. In the meantime you can check out some of the &lt;a href="http://www.23hq.com/rolfje/album/3362467">photographs I made&lt;/a> of my Walkera on my desk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laptop Stolen? See who did it...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/04/laptop-stolen-see-who-did-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/04/laptop-stolen-see-who-did-it/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In this strange world, people can't seem to leave your stuff alone. All the electronic gadgets of today are too attractive to the lowlife of this world. So what do you do if somebody swipes your laptop? You take a few pictures of him, and trace his IP address!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->This kind of software has been around for a while, and a few companies have made good money of of it. The closed source solutions are also feeding information to those companies when you don't want it to, and you're also not sure what information is send to the company.
&lt;p>There is now a solution for the more paranoid geeks amongst us. It's called &lt;a href="http://adeona.cs.washington.edu/index.html">&amp;quot;Adeona&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, and it is the first Open Source system for tracking the location of your lost or stolen laptop. The software does not rely on a proprietary and/or central service, and is entirely free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What's also nice is that only the owner (that's you) can access the machine should you want to trace it. If you don't trust me, and don't trust Adeona, you can always check the sourcecode yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A laptop is the most logical target of the casual thief, so it makes sence to install it on there. A casual thief is usually not tech savvy, so before he discoveres that Adeona (or any other similar program) you will have usually traced him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burglars also tend to take your desktop machine, so you might aswel install Adeona on there, too. And since Adeona comes as an OSX, Linux and Windows program, most of the computers out there will be covered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I only wish that I could live in a world where people could appreciate other people's toys without touching or stealing them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WWDC 2008 Keynote video</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/10/wwdc-2008-keynote-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 20:25:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/10/wwdc-2008-keynote-video/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-2.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.png" alt="Teribly irritating to see crippled video every 5 minutes like this. Apple come on!">
&lt;/a>I was watching the WWDC2008 text feeds yesterday (like the one from &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/06/09/steve-jobs-keynote-live-from-wwdc-2008/">Engadget&lt;/a>), and today the &lt;a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/0806wdt546x/event/index.html">WWDC2008 video&lt;/a> is online. It's always better to watch this than to read an interpreted &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/theilife">twitter feed&lt;/a>. Today it was a bit of a challenge to view it because a lot of people are probably with me. I always set Quicktime to use the HTTP protocol over port 80, because that forces all the network packets to arrive in the correct order, and does not allow dropped packets.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![How to set Quicktime to use the HTTP protocol](afbeelding-1.png?w=128)
&lt;p>](afbeelding-1.png)On the left, you can see how I've configured to be able to see the keynote without too much problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the middle of all the nerdy &amp;quot;look we've ported a game&amp;quot; presentations, there was actually a very cool one. Mark Terry, a software developer for an English insurance company, has created an incredible piece of music software for the iPhone, called &lt;a href="http://moocowmusic.com/Band/">&amp;quot;MooCow Music Band&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. At about 40 minutes into the WWDC2008 Keynote video, you'll find his really nice demo, with cheers from the crowd.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There's also a nice discussion on background processes and how they influence performance and battery life. It shows how, on a Samsung with Windows mobile, the user has to figure out which process to end. This then all leads to a discussion on the new Push Notification architecture in the iPhone 2.0 software which prevents software from having to poll servers. It also keeps your phonebill low, because there are no bits going back and forth to the phone every 10 seconds to see if the world has changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chinese character recognition was also a nice feature, it solves the problem with the Chinese language characters (of which there are a lot).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.me.com">&lt;img src="keynote_page_mobileme20080609.jpg" alt="Mobile Me logo">
&lt;/a>Finally, after a lot of complaints about .Mac not being up to par, Apple introduces &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/mobileme/">Mobile Me&lt;/a>, which replaces .Mac. Mobile Me finally looks like it expect to be looking for a proper Apple solution. It synchronizes with Apple and Windows platform, aswel as your iPod touch and iPhone. It has push notification, so that everything is synched immediately. The web interface is almost identical to Apple's Mail, contacts is looking like Address Book, etc. etc. Everything looks and feels like a desktop application. Lot's of AJAX-like functionality in there, which allows drag and drop, and on the fly contacts filtering, photo-skimming, image resizing and rotating...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What's also nice is the ability to take a picture with the iPhone (however bad the quality ;-) ) and immediately put it online in your really cool online Apple gallery. Really cool stuff and with the 20GB storage space finally worth considering the subscription. Let's hope they don't get into trouble with the other &lt;a href="http://www.mobileme.com.au/mobileme/index.wl">mobileme&lt;/a>'s &lt;a href="http://www.multiedit.com/mobileME.php">out&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://norman.walsh.name/2007/08/01/mobile">there&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the keynote, the new iPhone is introduced. 3G (UMTS) and built in GPS, better battery life, enterprise integration, and at a lower price. It's been on the news, and you probably have heard about the new iPhone already by now. Good news for me is that it's finally comming to the Netherlands. I only hope that I can buy it unlocked, because I'm not sure I want to switch to T-Mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-3.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png?w=50" alt="The iPhone 3G, finally in White.">
&lt;/a>At 1 hour and 28 minutes into the keynote, there's a funny situation where Steve waits for a large website to load on the (old) EDGE iPhone. The 3G iPhone is about 2 to 3 times as fast as the EDGE phone, and approaches wifi speeds over 3g (UMTS) networks. Steve demonstrates the speed increase of the new iPhone, and the slow competition with the funny layouts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Features which seem to be little but are quite important to people: It has a flush headphone connector so you can use any headphone you'd like, and it's available in white (only if you buy the 16GB model for $299).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wonder when it will be available in Russia... :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sell a Name or an Image?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/30/sell-a-name-or-an-image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 08:45:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/04/30/sell-a-name-or-an-image/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The new marketing &amp;quot;trick&amp;quot; seems to be to give a product a nice name, which sounds &amp;quot;expensive&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;design&amp;quot; like. So the marketing boys come up with a nice name. Compaq for instance has been using &amp;quot;pressario&amp;quot; for a while now. But when I say that I have a &amp;quot;pressario&amp;quot;, do you really know what kind of computer I have? Do you know which computer to buy when you hear my praise on my great new computer?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Probably not. And that's what amazes me at the current marketing tactics. Let me give you a couple of examples. If I say I have a pressario, I could have any of these computers (and this is ony a small selection of the ones I found):
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images.jpg">&lt;img src="images.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="images-1.jpg">&lt;img src="images-1.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-2.jpg">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-2.jpg">&lt;img src="images-2.jpg?w=135" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-3.jpg">&lt;img src="images-3.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So there's a problem for Compaq, which they have created themselves. &amp;quot;Pressario&amp;quot; does not identify anything. It can be a laptop, a desktop, and AMD processor, an Intel processor, with or without DVD player, small or large amounts of memory, and with or without monitor or keyboard. So what does &amp;quot;Pressario&amp;quot; mean?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem seels to be common for modern marketing. Look at the Renault Mégane for example. When Renault just started with the Mégane series, it was really clear what kind of car you were buying. But now, there are many Méganes on the market. Here's a small selection of Mégane models I found:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-4.jpg">&lt;img src="images-4.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-5.jpg">&lt;img src="images-5.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="images-6.jpg">&lt;img src="images-6.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="images-8.jpg">&lt;img src="images-8.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what kind of car you drive? In the old days, when you had a &amp;quot;Mustang&amp;quot;, people knew what car you had. The name was synonym to an image, and people knew what car to ask for if they wanted to have it. And the sales people knew what car to order for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No matter how hard you try to give a product a name, if you use that same name for a different product, people get confused, and you will never be able to build an image.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nokia 6300 and Apple's iSync</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/nokia-6300-and-apples-isync/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 21:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/nokia-6300-and-apples-isync/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-2.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.thumbnail.png" alt="Nokia 6300 and iSync">
&lt;/a>Last week, my trusty &lt;a href="http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony_Ericsson_T610">Sony Ericsson T610 &lt;/a>became a bit awkward to use. The &amp;quot;down&amp;quot; function of the joystick finally gave up on me, after intermitting failures the past month. The only way to select the next menu item was to go &amp;quot;up&amp;quot; through all menu items. It became a pain to use, so I needed a new one.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->With so many phones on the market, the only right way for me to make a selection is to think about what I need in a phone. Last Thursday I sat down to write down the list:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * No &amp;quot;Joystick&amp;quot; as with the T910, it failed way to early and maybe that's because of the construction. The joystick sticks out, and gets a beating when the phone is at the bottom of a pile.
* Has to be absolutely compatible with [Apple's iSync](http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/isync/), I don't want to re-type my 107 contacts into a phone. (This practically only leaves Sony Ericcson and Nokia as contestants)
* Has to have bluetooth
* Has to be a &amp;quot;candybar&amp;quot; (no hinges or sliders which can break, answer a phonecall with the push of a button)
* Has to be simlock-free
* Can not be too expensive (200 euro's maximum, but under 100 is better)
* Can not be a Samsung because of their wierd menu structures and ugly UI design
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I went to tweakers.net, and used the pricewatch functionality to search for Sony Ericsson and Nokia phones, starting at 60 euro's and up, meeting the requirements from my list. This was a great excersise, it prevents you from buying a phone which in the top of the sponsored Google search.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I found this nice &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6300">Nokia 6300&lt;/a>, but the thing was, that it seemed not to be supported by iSync. I noticed some people had gotten it to work because it seems that only the model number is missing in the iSync plist files. The Nokia 6300 is a &amp;quot;40's series&amp;quot; firmware and perfectly compatible with iSync.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could have gotten a slightly cheaper model, but I selected the Nokia 6300 because it had another nice feature: it has a standard mini-USB plug, and a micro SD slot, which enables it to double as a memory-stick. Nice. That also means that I don't need extra software to move stuff onto or off of the phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The online price for a Simlock free Nokia 6300 is &lt;a href="http://www.2call.nl/telefoons_detail.php?ID=455">EUR 149,- including taxes&lt;/a>. I thought I'd save some time and went to a few local phoneshops. The only shop where I could get it simlock free was at the &amp;quot;T for telecom&amp;quot; shop, and they had the balls to charge EUR 280,- for it. So I ordered it online and waited patiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, I found a good Nokia 6300 site, which provides a &lt;a href="http://nokia6300.net/22/nokia-6300-isync-and-leopard">free Nokia 6300 iSync plugin &lt;/a>which allows the Nokia 6300 to sync with iSync. I installed it, and it works flawlessly. 20 minutes after the delivery guy rang the doorbell, my Nokia 6300 is paired with my Mac Mini, and all my contacts are on the phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nice tip: I also moved the &lt;a href="http://www.adiumxtras.com/index.php?a=xtras&amp;amp;xtra_id=602">&amp;quot;Tokyo Trainstation&amp;quot;&lt;/a> audio set for Adium onto the phone. These make for great unobtrusive ringtones. Normally my phone has no ringtone at all (vibrate only) but the vibrate function of the Nokia 6300 is a bit weaker than the Sony Ericsson T610.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. I also noticed that he shop I ordered my phone from has the &lt;a href="http://www.2call.nl/telefoons_detail.php?ID=628">simlock free iPhone&lt;/a> in stock, although a bit pricey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OSX 10.5.2 Solved SMB problems (for me)</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/1052-solved-smb-problems-for-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 20:47:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/1052-solved-smb-problems-for-me/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/11/16/osx-1051-update-still-smb-problems/">previous post&lt;/a> on this blog, I indicated that the 10.5.1. update of Apple's OSX did not fix my network and SMB problems with my Iomega drive. In the comments underneath, some readers kindly pointed out that &lt;a href="http://download.iomega.com/english/storcenter_home_firmware-k104w11.bin">Iomega's K104w11 Firmware update&lt;/a> is available for the Iomega drive I have. Now that 10.5.2 is out, I reconnected the Iomega drive to my network. And suddenly the world changed...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I didn't upgrade the drive, because I thought that was rediculous. It works with Windows, it works with Tiger, why shouldn't it work with Leopard? Right now I'm glad that I didn't go through the trouble of upgrading my drive:
&lt;p>With the OSX release 10.5.2, my Iomega drive is accesable, and I can drag files on and off as I like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have created a &amp;quot;sparse bundle&amp;quot; disk image on the drive, so that I can copy files onto it which are bigger than 4GB, and have (very very) long names. So it's finally there: A network mounted 500GB HPS+ partition to which I can backup my backups using an rsync script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that everything works, I might even be tempted to do that Iomega software upgrade, but then again: &amp;quot;if it ain't broke, don't try to fix it&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next thing on my list to find out: What if I upgraded my Tiger fileserver to Leopard, and had TimeMachine running there. Could I rsync the TimeMachine disk to an off-site location without sending the double-hardlinked files twice?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Philips Wake-up Light review</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/26/philips-wake-up-light-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 14:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/26/philips-wake-up-light-review/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="wake-up-face.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Philips Wake-up Light">
With the &amp;quot;Wake-up Light&amp;quot;, Philips has taken the &amp;quot;dawn simulator&amp;quot; from &amp;quot;alternative/hippie&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;trendy&amp;quot;. Cleverly marketing it as simply a pleasant way to wake up, making it available in many stores and adding &amp;quot;trendy&amp;quot; pricing, Philips has a lot of people looking into one of these. But is it worth the money?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**What is a Wake-up Light?**
&lt;p>The Wake-up light can be categorized as a &amp;quot;dawn simulator&amp;quot;. Dawn simulators are nothing more than an alarm clock with the ability to slowly increase the intensity of an attached lightbulb. Dawn simulators generally take 30 minutes to reach 100% light intensity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Why do I need a Wake-up Light? **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several reasons why you would want to by a Wake-up Light. These range from simply being comfortable waking up to a lit room, to really having problems waking up and staying awake during the day. If you have problems waking up in the dark and have sort of a jetlag feeling all winter, you are categorized as having &amp;quot;SAD&amp;quot; (Seasonal Affective Disorder). Usually this will not be a big problem and dissapear somewhere in the spring. There are some cases where people actually are having problems functioning and/or get into a serious depression, in which case the Wake-up Light is not likely to be helpfull and can even make the problems worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are sleeping, you go through various &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep">sleeping phases&lt;/a>. Some of these phases are easier to wake up from than others. When the Wake-up light slowly lightens your room, chances are that somewhere in that halfhour, you reach a phase in which you are easier to wake up. In this phase you'll note the light and feel like you've &amp;quot;naturally&amp;quot; woken (assuming you've had a normal night's rest). This will feel a lot better than your alarm clock suddenly going &amp;quot;BEEP-BEEP&amp;quot; at full volume, scaring the crap out of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There's also another, more scientific fact. The day-night rythm, or &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm">&amp;quot;Circadian rythm&amp;quot;&lt;/a> of your body is regulated by your &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypothalamus">Hypothalamus&lt;/a> which is located in your head, just above your brain stem. This organ regulates several metabolic processes and controls production of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melatonin">Melatonin&lt;/a> in the evening and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cortisol">Cortisol&lt;/a> in the morning. The day-night rythm is partially controled by the dark/light cycle of daylight. When traveling to different timezones, your body can have trouble resetting the Circadiam rythm, contributing to jetlag. In space, Astronouts are helped to keep this rythm by artificial day/night light simulation inside the spacecrafts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep the Circadian rythm in sync with your daily activities, even when there is no light, you need to do two things, one of which is hard. The first and easiest thing you can do is buy a Wake-up Light and set it to wake you every day at the same time, even in the weekends. The second, harder, thing to do is try to refrain from staring into bright lightsources before you are going to sleep. This means no staring at computer screens or TV's. By staring at your white computer screen, your body will delay the production of Melatonin. By the time you need to wake up, there's still too much Melatonin in your body, and the Cortisol will not work or not even produced. This will give you that &amp;quot;Why did you wake me in the middle of the night&amp;quot; feeling in the morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Does the Wake-up Light use a special Lightbulb?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No. The Philips Wake-up Light uses a normal Softone T55 &amp;quot;warm white&amp;quot; lightbulb, and it seems to work fine for a lot of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="neodymium-a21-bulb.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Neodymium A51 Bulb">
Many dawn-simulator manufacturers believe in the exact reproduction of daylight, and ship their devices with &lt;a href="http://members.misty.com/don/oddbulb.html#nd">Neodymium lightbulbs&lt;/a>. These bulbs claim to have a more faithful reproduction of daylight, and are believed to be the best bulbs to use in dawn simulators. Neodymium bulbs look purple to clear blue when turned off. If you really want to, you can replace the bulb in the Wake-up Light with a Neodymium bulb of the same power. &lt;a href="http://www.toolsforwellness.com/verilux.html">Verilux&lt;/a> makes some nice bright daylight blubs, one of which is in my old &lt;a href="http://www.lumie.com/shop/products/dawn-simulators/Bodyclock-SUNRAY-100">Lumie Sunray 100 Bodyclock&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="http://art-craft-uk.daylightcompany.com/store/bulbs-tubes-3">Daylight(tm)&lt;/a> also produces Neodymium bulbs, but these are generally darker than the Verilux ones because of the thicker blue coatings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Product look and feel&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides waking you up in the morning, you also want a nice looking device, good audio quality, build quality and ease of use. I'm afraid the Wake-up Light does not score all that well in that department. The most important thing to note is that the Wake-up Light is miles ahead of it's competitors from the &amp;quot;alternative&amp;quot; sector, where &amp;quot;usability&amp;quot; is generally translated into &amp;quot;ugly&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;clunky&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;robust&amp;quot; is translated into, well, &amp;quot;ugly&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;clunky&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="wake-up-snooze.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Turn off the light">
Although it is better than the competition in terms of it's looks and features, there are a few things which need mentioning. The most important thing being the way you control the alarm when you've just woken up. In the morning you're probably not at your best, so finding a tiny knob you can't see on the top of a device which is almost out-of-reach can be frustrating. The &amp;quot;snooze&amp;quot; button is on the top and can easily be &amp;quot;found&amp;quot; by slapping your hand anywhere on the top of the light. Resetting the alarm takes a bit more control, you need to find one of the 4 buttons on the top of the device. Judging from Philip's own advertisement pictures (shown here on the right), this button is clearly not within your field of vision when lying in your bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other buttons are located on the front of the base and allow you to control the brightness of the light and the volume of the radio or other sounds you choose when waking up. The processor in the Wake-up Light is a very-very slow one, because after pushing a button will take a while before the device reacts. This is very irritating for a device of well over a 100 Euros. When choosing an alarm sound, you can not go click-click-click to switch to the third. The Wake-up Light makes you listen to the sound before accepting a new click. Very irritating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are no radio-presets. This would be not a big problem if the radio would be scanning stations fast, but that's not the case. To scan the whole band for a suitable radio station will take a lot of button presses, and a lot of time (5 minutes is not uncommon). Without presets,switching between stations which are far apart in radio-frequency terms will take a lot of time and frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When pressing the buttons, there is a very cheap plastic feel to them, and you have to push them relatively hard before they make the cheap &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; sound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other irritating &amp;quot;design features&amp;quot; include the fact that it does not make a difference between your alarm settings and the things you do to the clock when listening to the radio or reading a book. Say you want to wake up to light intensity &amp;quot;10&amp;quot; (it goes from 0 to 20) and the radio at volume &amp;quot;6&amp;quot;. You set the alarm accordingly. After setting the alarm, you decide to read a book before going to bed. When you turn the light up to 20 to read your book, and turn up the volume of the radio, you are in for a surprise the next morning... The Wake-up light will use intensity 20 and whatever radio volume your clock was last set to. I circumvented this by having a reading light and using a seperate radio.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most dawn-simulators have a mode where they also do a &amp;quot;dusk&amp;quot; simulation, slowly turning down the light while you fall asleep. If you have any form of SAD, this is not a good feature to use because of the day/night rythm discussed earlier. With the Wake-up Light, you don't even have the choice. It can only wake you up, but not put you to sleep. No features whatsoever. No sleep mode on the radio, no sleep mode on the light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A really nice feature is the &amp;quot;preview&amp;quot; button where the Wake-up light shows you what is going to happen next morning, but than in a &amp;quot;fast forward&amp;quot; mode. It goes through the whole wakeup process in 90 seconds, so you can see and hear if you set it up correctly. Do not forget to push the button again after you're ready, because it repeats the preview indefinetely. I would find it more obvious to do 1 preview on each button press.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In preview mode, I noticed that the intensity of the light does not increase perfectly. At some points, the light intensity seems to decrease briefly. I also noticed this in the 30-minute cycle in the morning, although it is not irritating. I think this has to do with the built-in dimmer frequency interfering with the 50Hz of the mains, and is a slight design flaw.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The funniest of all was the fact that after spending by 119 Euros, I found out that there was only a German and Italian quick-start card in the box, and no trace of a usermanual. The manual is available as a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/01/22/philips-wake-up-light-hf356001-manual/">seperate download&lt;/a>. It's strange to see that Philips assumes that everybody who buys an alarm clock also owns a computer and has an internet connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Beep-Beep?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the Wake-up Light has turned up the light, it will start the audio alarm you selected at the volume you selected (and the time you selected). Thank god Philips has banned the terrible 50Hz buzzer &amp;quot;beep-beep&amp;quot; sound in this one. The waking sounds available on the 100Watt HF3461 model are:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>radio - Plays your chosen station.
birds - An approx. 20 second looping sample of tjirping birds in a quiet surrounding.
forest - 20 second loop of animal sounds in a forrest.
sea - 20 second loop of the sea washing against the shore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All sounds will start on a low volume, and slowly increase to the volume you selected before you went to sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>400 Lumen or not?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two general versions of the Wake-up Light. A 75 Watt without, and a 100 Watt with radio. The 100 Watt model is claimed to put out 400 &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lumen_%28unit%29">Lumen&lt;/a> (not to be confused with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lux">Lux&lt;/a>) at the highest setting (20). Although the Wake-up Light will always produce the same light (aging of the bulb not considered), you will notice that you will not wake up to the same &amp;quot;light sensation&amp;quot; each morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="wake-up-position.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Waking up in the shade">
According to the manual, you need to place your Wake-up Light about 30-40 cm from your head, in such a way that your pillow will not block the light. Even when doing this, there is about a 50% chance that you are not facing the bodyclock in the morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I bought my Lumie bodyclock in 2005, I noticed after a while I automatically wake up facing the lamp. It seems I like bright light, even when I sleep ;-) For that matter, the Wake-up Light is brighter than my Lumie (100 vs 60 Watt), so that's an improvement I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the &lt;a href="http://www.wakeuplight.philips.nl/">Wake-up Light&lt;/a> is a step in the right direction, but it's not there yet. If you like slowly waking up to a simulated sunrise, or are having trouble waking up in the winter, this one is for you, provided you can spend the whopping 119 Euro's I payed for the 100Watt version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'd really like to see a version where I can connect external lightsources and have my &lt;a href="http://www.builderssquare.com/xp_4465732-Craftsman_500_watt_Tripod_Light_with_Portable_Stand_WL500SPT_S.aspx">500Watt Halogen lamp&lt;/a> slowly light the whole room.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Philips Wake-up Light HF3461/01 Manual</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/22/philips-wake-up-light-hf356001-manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/22/philips-wake-up-light-hf356001-manual/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For some strange reason, Philips doesn't provide you with a manual when you buy a Wake-up light. For those of you who want to download the full manual, you can do so by browsing through the directory at:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.p4c.philips.com/files/h/hf3461_01/">http://www.p4c.philips.com/files/h/hf3461_01/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The filenames are a bit strange, but looking at the last three letters in the filename will generaly give you a manual containing the language you can read. (&amp;quot;fra&amp;quot; for France, &amp;quot;nld&amp;quot; for the Netherlands, etc.). The Manuals describe the models HF3451, HF3461 and HF3462.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Funny detail: After downloading the manual and opening it, it says &lt;em>&amp;quot;Read this manual carefully before using this device&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macworld 2008 thin as air</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/17/macworld-2008-thin-as-air/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 20:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/17/macworld-2008-thin-as-air/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hi, I've read the writeups on Steve's keynote this year, and listened to some podcasts of people who were in the audience. Personally I'm a bit dissapointed by the features introduced at this Macworld. Surely it's hard to live up to the ever rising expectations every year, but I do have some comments to make on the introduced products.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**TimeCapsule**
&lt;p>This is the worst product Apple has introduced in years. Not that it's crappy hardware or a lousy idea, but the way they are artificially forcing you to buy their $299 500GB harddrive (0r $499 for the 1TB version) in stead of the 100's of readily available, $150 to $200 cheap ethernet connected harddrives out there which would perfectly perform this task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Quick tip: Should you have an Ethernet connected FAT32 drive on which you want timemachine to run, create a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_disk_image">sparse disk image&lt;/a> on that disk (no need to commandline, can also be done with the disk utility). A sparse disk image is effectively a DMG file in 8MB chunks. You can mount that DMG file and have a network connected (strong encrypted if you like), HFS+ journalled drive. After the &lt;a href="http://andreas.louca.org/2007/11/10/time-machine-and-network-drives/">Timemachine network trick&lt;/a>, you're probably good to go at no cost at all. The only difference is that you can't connect your printer to that drive. Well I have my Airport extreme for that, which also streams audio to my stereo.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Macbook air&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Very cool looking laptop with lots of potential for journalists and the occasional &lt;a href="http://www.ijustine.tv/">life blogger&lt;/a>, but I have some doubts about the intended audience. The most obvious is the lack of a CD/DVD drive. This is not a big problem for most users, and with the added tools to connect to any DVD drive on a remote Windows or Apple machine it will not be as big as a problem as one would think. For my wife this is a no-go, she watches DVD's on her laptop, so she's not getting this Macbook air anytime soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My next problem is the configuration options. The cheap model is a 1.3GHz machine, 2GB memory and 80GB Harddrive. It is priced at $1799, which is pretty steep compared to a normal Macbook. For $700 less, you can get a 2.0GHz macbook with a combo drive, which is much nicer in my opinion. Should you want the Macbook air and have a heftier processor, you're in for a surprise. The 1.8GHz model (still not as fast as the cheapest macbook) is priced at a staggering $3098! This is not because of the processor, but it contains a 64GB flash-based harddrive. Less storage space, but more battery life and crash-resistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with the 1.8GHz model of the Macbook air is that you effectively get a smaller harddrive, a marginally better processor, for $3098. Compared to that, for $2799, you can get the 17&amp;quot; Macbook pro at 2.4 GHz, with a superdrive. I know what I would get. Additionaly, the 64GB flash-based drive has a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid_state_disk#Disadvantages">limited amount of write-cycles&lt;/a>. This means that the solid state drive will probably wear out faster than any cheap traditional HD in the market. Based on the write cycles, a normal HD will likely last 5 times longer than a flash-based disk under the same circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need a really thin laptop with good battery life for simple word processing, or simply something to match your gucci wardrobe and your &lt;a href="http://www.owensworld.com/funnyimages/files/I_beat_anorexia_big.jpg">perfect figure&lt;/a>, get the Macbook air. If you need anything marginally better, go for the normal macbook, which is still in my opinion the best value for money and a darn cool, acceptably thin and very portable laptop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me, the Macbook air is a no-go even if it was priced at $1000. Why? **IT HAS NO ETHERNET!**What were they thinking? Many companies have wired-only policies because of security and troughput reasons. This means you can't take your Macbook air to the office for the occasional showing off. It's helpless in a wired-only environment. No DVD, and no means of connecting to the network?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the Macbook air becomes a succes, Apple is clearly into some voodoo-market-magic because I don't get it. It also doesn't have Audio in, to put off the mobile podcasters or radio journalists out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Apple TV&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;quot;all new&amp;quot; software for the Apple TV is very cool for people who already own an Apple TV. It looks like a big improvement, and not needing a PC or Mac is a step in the right direction. No need to explain &amp;quot;syncing&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;connecting&amp;quot; to newcommers, just plug and play. Nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The missing thing here is that they could have chosen to make the Apple TV the TimeCapsule. It has a harddrive, USB ports, and wifi. Why do I need another machine with anothe power brick if I have a harddisk onderneath my TV which is doing nothing 80% of it's time? Selling a 1TB Apple TV with a smart disk usage policy would make much more sense to me. As an added benefit, people who are looking for a backup solution get sucked into the &amp;quot;Movie Rentals&amp;quot; scheme on the go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>One missing thing:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The iPhone. It was mentioned, but still I was expecting 2 major announcements. The first, and most obvious announcement would be a 16 or 32 GB model. This was anticipated to happen for over a year now, but it didn't. I think it's not that big of a deal because I have a 8GB nano and it stores more than enough music to listen to in between syncs. Just use &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/08/01/ipod-synchronization-techniques/">really smart playlists&lt;/a> and iTunes will take care of it for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second thing I missed was the introduction of the iPhone in more European countries. Hello Apple, Europe doesn't consist of Great Brittain, France and Germany alone! Over here in the Netherlands, a lot of people have hacked grey import iPhones because they are dying to buy one, but can't get it legally. Maybe Apple thinks it's done beccause they reached their targets, but I think they are missing out on a big market of wealthy (west-) European consumers easily wanting to pay for the legal version of the iPhone, no matter which provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To top that, the free software update for the iPhone will cost $20 dollars for iPod touch owners, while new iPod touch's will have that included for free. I wonder what &amp;quot;marketing genius&amp;quot; is behind that. It almost looks like Steve has been on a year's vacation, leaving business to somebody else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just noticed that the complete video of the keynote is online at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/qtv/keynote/">http://www.apple.com/quicktime/qtv/keynote/&lt;/a>. Have fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Edit:  I see that there is an USB Ethernet adapter and an external DVD drive available as options to the Macbook air. But still, I think the ethernet port should be in there, I don't want to have to carry all kinds of adapters with my Macbook.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Irritating "Features": Philips Matchline TV</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/17/irritating-features-phillips-matchline-tv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 20:11:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/17/irritating-features-phillips-matchline-tv/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Okay, I have to get this out of my system. It is something I've been complaining about for months, and it is really an example of the utter dumbness of some product designers. What am I talking about? Simply turning on my TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have this very nice big heavy 100Hz 4:3 Phillips Matchline TV, which I bought 8 or so years ago. For that time, it was a feature-rich TV which could store all kinds of user settings through on-screen menus, and keep them stored even when the power went out. A few weeks ago I noticed a new TV at a friends house has the same &amp;quot;feature&amp;quot; as my old Matchline. You can't turn it on!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens? Monday evening, you are done watching TV and use the remote to switch it to &amp;quot;Stand By&amp;quot; mode. Before you go to bed, you walk by the TV and hit the power button to completely turn it off. Now on Tuesday, after dinner, you decide to watch TV. You walk to the TV, hit the power button, and what happens? The TV goes from &amp;quot;off&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Standby&amp;quot;. What complete and utter IDIOT designs a TV which goes to &amp;quot;standby&amp;quot; after turning it on with the power button? It wouldn't surprise me that a junior programmer was showing off his l33t skills by remembering the state of the TV before it was turned off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, after 8 years of introducing the wierdest features to TV's, the usability labs in this world have still not found the most obvious feature to a TV: Turning it on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real guitar game: Guitar Wizzard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:35:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>No, I'm not a guitar player, but I noticed this cool post on TUAW where the &amp;quot;Guitar Hero&amp;quot; game has been taken a notch up. &lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/09/guitar-wizard-coming-for-mac/">TUAW reports&lt;/a> that the guys at &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com">www.musicwizard.com&lt;/a> have built &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com/guitar_wizard/updates.php">&amp;quot;Guitar Wizzard&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, a game with which you can learn to play popular songs on a &lt;em>real guitar&lt;/em>. From what I can see in the video, this looks way less frustrating than doing the same excersizes over and over to learn to play the guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, you might not turn in to Mark Knopfler in a week, but isn't it a much better feeling to hold a real guitar in your hand, in stead of that plasticky, toy-like mini quitar with the bright colored buttons? And the price is about right for a game including hardware aswell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tips for European Apple customers</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/03/tips-for-european-apple-customers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2007 22:06:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/03/tips-for-european-apple-customers/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For me as a european consumer, the low Dollar (or: high Euro) is a good thing. Particularly when travelling to the U.S., or buying American consumer electronics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Apple, as a big company with complete control over it's retail prices, the low Dollar (or: high Euro) is a good thing. Particularly when the conversion rates sneak up on the consumers and you &amp;quot;forget&amp;quot; to adjust your 1-to-1 Euro-to-Dollar conversion in your stores. Time to wake up the European Apple consumers.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->So how good is the Euro to Dollar converison rate for Apple? At the time of writing, €1.00 equals $1.4443. Comparing actual product prices between the online [U.S. Apple store](http://store.apple.com/) and the [Dutch Apple store](http://store.apple.com/Apple/WebObjects/nlstore.woa/), we can see how Apple's margin has increased with the exact 1.4443 conversion rate, baring the MacBook:
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
Product
US Price
Dutch price
Difference
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Mac Pro
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$2499.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€2499.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($3609.31)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$1110.30
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(44%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >20" iMac
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$1199.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€1199.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($1731.72)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$532.72
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(44%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >13" MacBook
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$1099.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€1049.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($1515.07)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$416.07
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(38%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >iPod touch 16GB
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$399.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€399.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($576.28)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$177.28
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(44%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >iPod nano 8GB
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$199.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€199.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($287.42)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$88.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(44%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Wireless keyboard
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$79.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >€79.00
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >($114.10)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >$35.10
&lt;/td>
&lt;td align="right" valign="top" >(44%)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
This is nice for Apple, but how can we make this nice for us consumers? Apple certainly is not going to lower it's prices in Europe, because Steve is in it for the money (prove me wrong soon, will you, Steve)? As far as I see, the European Apple consumer has 4 options:
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Option 1:&lt;/strong> Just buy the stuff you want, pay the Euro price and be happy with the value for money. Added bonus: you helped &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs">Steve&lt;/a> invest in future products, and maybe he'll &lt;a href="http://www.gadgetopia.com/post/2992">give away another mansion&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Option 2:&lt;/strong> Wait for the € to drop. This is a nice option if you were planning on an Apple free diet anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Option 3:&lt;/strong> Order the product you want in the U.S., and see if they'll send it to Europe. Maybe you'll have to have your product sent to a friend living in the U.S., and have him send it to you. Sometimes a hotel in which you stayed recently can be tricked into receiving and forwarding your package, as long as it's not to big. They'll charge your creditcard, so be carefull.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Option 4:&lt;/strong> Say you'd want the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macpro/">Mac Pro double core duo&lt;/a> (the cheapest Mac Pro model). Say you would like to buy that in the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/retail/lincolnroad/week/20071028.html">Miami Apple Store&lt;/a> at Lincoln road. You could buy 2 oneway tickets at &lt;a href="http://www.exit-reizen.nl/reizen/vliegtickets/vliegtickets.html">exit-reizen&lt;/a>, which would set you back about €820.00 ($567.75). Because it's a long flight and you'd like to do some sight-seeing, you book 2 nights at the beautiful &lt;a href="http://www.secure-res.com/res/vn3/hchgs.aspx?hotelid=1599&amp;amp;roomid=6754&amp;amp;checkindate=11/10/2007&amp;amp;nights=2&amp;amp;rooms=1&amp;amp;trr=CFFFFFDA6F9EA1&amp;amp;adults=1&amp;amp;children=0&amp;amp;culture=1&amp;amp;culturename=nl-NL&amp;amp;site=SEO&amp;amp;wtpid=dcs5l6fkf00000omppulmk93o_3n3q">Clay hotel&lt;/a> at South Beach Miami at &amp;quot;Budget&amp;quot; rate, which totals to $172,89 including tax. During the trip, you spend about, say, $350.00 on cab fares, tips, food and souvenirs for the family. When you return home, you will have spent $1090.64 for the tip, including the purchase of your Mac Pro. At the current European price, &lt;em>you still have saved $19.66!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For iPods and other gadgets, I'd say option 1 and 3 are the best options, because I know you can't wait once you are an Apple addict. If you're planning on buying anything more expensive than an iMac, I would seriously consider option 4. You can get away with flying from Europe to Miami and back, picking it up yourself and still spending the same amount of money as you would have spent just picking it up in Amsterdam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How's that for Currency Market?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Headphone search</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/01/headphone-search/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week I've been complaining about the capped volume on the iPod nano and the inability to circumvent it. At the end of that very week, the iPod earbuds solved the problem for me by breaking down. The rubber rings started comming off, and the right speaker produced only 10% of the sound the left speaker was producing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided that this was enough reason to go looking for a nice set of in-ear headphones (earbuds) which would sound nice, and also improve on produced volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8110.jpg">&lt;!-- more -->&lt;img src="img_8110.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Apple ear-buds">
&lt;/a>After reading some reviews on in-ear headphones ranging from €40,- to €140,- I decided on the Apple in-ear headphones. Judging from reviews, these should compare to Sony Fontopia's, seal of surrounding noise and produce more sound. I payed the €40,- (that's $58,- at the current Dollar-to-Euro rate) and plugged them into the ipod, and my ears. Although I have pretty standard ears,  I couldn't get the Apple earbuds to fit comfortably. Apple provides 3 different size caps, of which the middle size was the least uncomfortable, and sealed off my ear properly. You can tell this by the pressure you feel in your ear when inserting the buds. The pressure will slowly go away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I noticed is that by sealing off your earcanal, you can hear everything going on with the cords to the earbuds. Move your head, and you hear the cord move accross your clothes at a pretty uncomfortable volume. When playing music, don't move. The cord movement sounds will sometimes be louder than the music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sitting perfectly still and trying to judge the sound quality, I found that the Apple ear-buds are actually not good at all. Yes they provide lots of bass (which is a measure of quality nowadays I guess) but everything else is lacking. They sound flat, and miss the sharpness I expect from expensive earbuds. They are absolutely sounding worse than the standard earbuds that came with the iPod. If I had too choose between the two, I'd go for the standard iPod earphones in stead of the more expensive ear-buds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem with headphones in general and in-ear headphones in particular, is that you can't return them, because they can't be sold as new after you've jammed them in your ears. For that same reason I'm probably not going to sell them second hand, making these buds one of the more expensive pieces of trash in my bin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8111.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8111.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Sony earphones">
&lt;/a> Last weekend I passed through a hardware store to buy a new harddrive for my fileserver. Next to the cash register I found a pair of &lt;a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/headphones-headsets/sony-mdr-e818lp/4505-6468_7-6900020.html">Sony MDR-E818LP&lt;/a> earphones for about €10,-. I bought them so that I could at least listen to music until I found a set of decent earphones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And guess what? These sound great! They've got too much bass (probably a fashion thing), but that can be cured with the &amp;quot;less bass&amp;quot; setting on the iPod. By doing that, these earphones are the right thing for your iPod, at the right price. The sound is clear and crisp, and these buds produce a LOT more sound than the Apple ones. They don't seal off your ear, which I've come to beleive is a good thing, because of the cord-sound I described above. They come with a set of soft cushions which make for a comfortable fit, and I can wear them for hours at an end without getting sore ears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To get some of the €40,- spent on the Apple ear-buds back, I am using the Apple ear-bud carying case to store the Sony earphones in. The Sony's are worth it. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse this isn't the best set of earphones I've ever had. The old Sony fontopids that came with the first walkmans were absolutely the best in-ear headphones I've ever had. Comfortable fit, supple silicone cords, with red and blue stripes on the earpieces to mark right and left, but other than that perfectly symmetrical. Too bad they don't make those anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_8113.jpg">&lt;img src="img_8113.jpg" alt="Sony MDR-CD770">
&lt;/a>The absolute best set of earphones I've ever had, and in fact still own after some odd 20 years, is a set of &lt;a href="http://www.epinions.com/content_6730518148">Sony MDR-CD770 Digital Reference&lt;/a> earphones. They (still) sound amazing, you feel like you can point out the location of every instrument in the band you're listening too, like they were in the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem with these are that they are big, expensive, and fragile. You won't be taking these with you when you're on vacation. They wouldn't survive the suitcase, and they're impossible when you are trying to lay your head down to sleep while listening to good music. Even if you did, you'd never wake up again, being strangled by the many meters of audio cable dangling off of your left ear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you're sitting at home on the couch, these will beat the * out of any soundsystem anyday, without annoying the neighbours. You'll be amazed at how good a high-bitrate AAC track sounds comming out of your iPod.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No Such Thing: Harddisk Warranty</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/no-such-thing-harddisk-warranty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/no-such-thing-harddisk-warranty/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A while ago the drives in my fileserver (PPC Mac Mini) began dying on me, one after one. The disks were somewhat old (approx. 4 years) so I replaced them with 2 new Maxtor 500GB USB drives, and restored all data from my backups. The server came up and looked and worked like it had never died, but now had more diskspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a few months of trouble free operation, one of the Maxtor disks seemed to have died this morning. I had kept the receipt, so I thought I'd get the drive and bring it in for repairs, because after all, this is well within the warranty period. While disconnecting the drive, it occured to me that I could never bring that harddisk in for repairs, particularly if I was not able to access it.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Why? Because of the data on that disk. My iTunes library, purchased software and licenses, family pictures and taxes, everything is on there. Sure I have a backup, but what are the people in the store going to do with my data? No matter how you think about it, the disk is probably going to be checked by a store employee, and maybe later by a technician at the repair shop. Who's to say that these people don't steal my data?
&lt;p>The easiest target would be &amp;quot;casually copying&amp;quot; my music because that's what people do nowadays without seeing any harm in it. On my disk are more than a few iTunes DRM-free tracks which can be copied off there. These tracks are not DRM-ed, but they do contain information about me purchasing them. Should these tracks be found on the internet, the problem is mine, because I can never prove that I did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> put them there. Still my name is in there. This is the simplest scenario, but imagine what a clever person could do with your tax forms, or your personal foto's, or legally bought license keys...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole point is, that there effectively is no such thing as harddisk warranty, because you can't turn in your disk exactly for the reasons described above. After realizing this, the only tactics I can advise are:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. 8% of all harddisks die within the first 2 years of operation, according to some [research done by Google](http://tastyresearch.wordpress.com/2007/08/09/hard-drive-failure-statistics-at-google/) on a large set of disks. Harddisks do not die because of heat or use. So the only thing you can do after you buy a harddisk, is test it by writing to all sectors, erasing, and making some partitions with useless data. You can use [Disk Utility](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_Utility) for this for example.
2. After you've tested it and it prooved to be working, start using the disk normally and hope that noting happens. Backup. Backupbackup. Backup. Backup. I have absolutely no mercy for people who did not make backups. Don't call me if you loose data because you did not have backup plan. Backups are the Airbags, seatbelts and bullrack of your computer.
3. Start saving money for a replacement disk.
4. When the disk dies within the warranty period, try to erase it by writing bit patterns to it with the [Disk Utility](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_Utility). If this succeeds and you are satisfied that your data is [erased to a reasonable degree](http://www.whitecanyon.com/newsletter-hard-drive-erase-multiple-overwrites.php#Article), go find your receipt, go to the store and try to get it repaired.
5. Bullet 4 is very unlikely to happen, because if you can write bits to a drive, you can use it. So, by the time you read this, the drive probably contains sensitive data, but you can't access the drive. No way to delete data there. The only option you have now is to [Slag your Drive](http://driveslag.eecue.com/), get the money you saved for a new one and buy a new one. Chances are that you can buy a bigger drive for the same money.
6. Restore your backups on the new drive and start saving for your next one.
7. Always try to use your new drive as the backup drive, and your old drive as the data drive. This gives you the advantage of your backup drive not being likely to fail, and because it is bigger, will easily hold (multiple) copies of the data stored on your data drive.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Back to my faulty drive: I connected it to my desktop Mac Mini (Intel) and it mounted, and did not seem to have any problems at all. I ran a diskcheck and listened to it for a while. No problems, nice sound. I reconnected it to the fileserver. Every sign of the problems I had earlier dissapeared. The only thing I could think of is to remove the cheap Trust USB hub because I ad USB trouble a few weeks ago, and I was suspecting that the drive access troubles could very well be caused by the cheap hub. Let's see if that does the trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One other thing to remember, is that CD's and DVD's written on a computer &lt;a href="http://forums.cnet.com/5208-10149_102-0.html?forumID=7&amp;amp;threadID=152618&amp;amp;messageID=1698511">will not hold their data forever&lt;/a>, so they are too unreliable as backup media. A second harddisk is more reliable, because the magnetic information can be retrieved long after it has been written. Personally I backup to a spare harddisk daily (automatic) and every once in a while I do a manual backup to a third drive just to ease my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For good measure I have an automatic off-site backup in the making, and I have a proof of concept working where I share an AFP:// share over an SSL connection, and backup into an encrypted DMG at the remote location. The owner of the remote computer can not see my data, and by only connecting with private/public keys using SSL the data is fairly safe from being stolen. The scripts need polishing, but in effect are no different than my local daily incremental rsync backup. I will always have an extra copy stored far away from my home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even a fire does not hurt me now, and scanning important documents becomes interesting, beause even if they get lost in a fire, you can &amp;quot;prove&amp;quot; to the insurance company that you had a policy, how much it was worth and what the insurancenumber was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Birthday!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 20:36:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/10/24/happy-birthday/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I know you've been playing with your ultra-cool iPhones, but did you realize that it only is 6 years ago that Apple showed is the first iPod? It's amazing how fast technology advances nowadays. Today I read that 128GB flashdrives are not far away, so how about an 128GB iPhone, or even a MacBook with a solid state disk? We've got a nice future ahead...&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Meanwhile, you can watch Steve announce the first ever iPod, and notice the difference with the existing devices at that time. It's not strange that the iPod changed the way people listen to music.
&lt;p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kN0SVBCJqLs&amp;amp;rel=1]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lathe Spindle rebuild, part 1</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/08/28/lathe-spindle-rebuild-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/08/28/lathe-spindle-rebuild-part-1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_7615.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7615.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7615.jpg">
&lt;/a>Past few weeks I noticed that the spindle bearings of my lathe were becomming warmer than I liked, particularly when working with higher rpm. Last weekend I decided to take the spindle out, clean the old grease out, and rebuilding it. It turned out to be more work than I expected. The tight fit of the pully made me use the hammer-and-wood trick on the spindle, which I did not like. After a few hours of tapping and fiddling, the pully came of. The spindle gear and the left hand bearing were no fun job either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, the whole thing is apart now, and I cleaned out all the grease. I test-fitted the spindle sundaynight, but I can feel a slight &amp;quot;bump&amp;quot; when turning it, I think the grease must have picked up some dirt, most likely a wood chip from the bench. So I have to take it apart again, it has to be perfectly smooth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After I re-fit the spindle, I have to adjust it with my micrometer to have a play of between 0.004 and 0.005 mm, no more, and no less, while being able to turn it by hand. Sounds like an interesting excercise which will take up more than a few minutes :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_7613.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7613.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7613.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7617.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7617.jpg" alt="o_img_7617.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7618.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7618.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7618.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="o_img_7620.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_7620.thumbnail.jpg" alt="o_img_7620.jpg">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TomTom One v2 earphone modification</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/06/25/tomtom-one-v2-earphone-modification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/06/25/tomtom-one-v2-earphone-modification/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_tomtomonev2-modded.jpg">&lt;img src="o_tomtomonev2-modded.jpg" alt="TomTom One v2 with earphone modification">
&lt;/a>TomTom decided to remove the earphone plug from their newer version One. This blog entry will describe how you can add your own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why would TomTom remove the earphone plug? There are a few simple reasons, one being that the new version has a slimmer formfactor with less room for plugs, and the other being that they probably don't want it to compete too much with the XL and Rider versions.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When my iPaq PDA died on me a few weeks ago, I was in desperate need of a new navigation system, and it already was clear that it had to be a TomTom, because I like the simple user interface and the clean look of the map and information when I'm driving. I also wanted to use it on my motorcycle, but wasn't ready to shell out 600 euro's for the occasional bike trip. Compared to the 600 euro's I had financial room to screw up three 200 euro TomTom Ones :-), so I had a go at one, and here's how it worked out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_tomtom-opened.jpg">&lt;img src="o_tomtom-opened.thumbnail.jpg" alt="TomTom Opened">
&lt;/a>First I opened it up and looked for a spot to place a 3.5mm earphone jack. There was (ver little) room at the bottom of the unit just behind the SD slot. An ordinary 3.5mm Jack wasn't going to fit, so I &lt;a href="o_ipaq-opened.jpg">canibalized my iPaq&lt;/a> for a small 3.5mm connector. Some careful measurements later, I decided it would fit, and started the electrical investigation before drilling holes in the unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_schema-tomtom.jpg">&lt;img src="o_schema-tomtom.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Schematic">
&lt;/a>I cut the read wire to the internal speaker and tried a couple of resistors in series with my earphones to get the right audio level. With the earphone's left and right speakers in series, a resistor of 470 Ohms sounded nice. Loud enough to be heard on a motorcycle, not so loud it would ruin my earbuds and -drums, and the volume slider controls the volume nicely. As you'll see this is an unorthodox connection for earbuds, since the ground lead is not connected. It is a matter of choice, you can connect the earbuds in parallel if you like, the impedance only changes a few Ohms. Compared to the 470 Ohms resistor you will probably not notice the difference. I didn't bother to change it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the 3.5mm plug from the iPaq there is a nice switch to disconnect the internal speaker. When I insert the earphones, the internal speaker is turned off, just like you'd expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With all planning and preparation done, it was now time to drill the hole in the TomTom case, the official point of no return. After the drilling, removing the battery and some fiddling with glue, the connector would not sit still while the glue was drying. I &lt;a href="o_connector-glue.jpg">taped it to the base&lt;/a> so the glue could settle. Be careful not to smear glue into the 3.5mm connector, the casing is not 100% closed because of it's size. You can actually see the metal of the connector for the left earphone piece in the picture. Glue that and you have a useless connector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the glue dried, I reinstalled the battery with a fresh piece of double sided tape, and did the wiring properly. To prevent wires and the connector from hitting the copper shield of the circuit bord, I strategically &lt;a href="o_battery-back-in-place.jpg">placed some isolation tape&lt;/a> on the bare soldering joints. After that, the TomTom could be cloded up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_tomtom-mod-bottom.jpg">&lt;img src="o_tomtom-mod-bottom.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Modification, bottom view">
&lt;/a>As you can see on the right (click on it for larger image), the end result is pretty neat. As it turns out, the connector is not in a very different spot compared to the older model TomTom one. I tried it on my bike today, and it works nicely. I put the TomTom in a pocket of my jacket so I can not see or touch the display, but the spoken instructions are good enough compared to the money it cost me to do this (10 cents for the resistor, not counting the 3.5mm jack I got from my iPaq). You can hear the instructions while driving 120km/h on the freeway, unless you've got very loud pipes...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now go and roll your own!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technology does not sell</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/09/technology-does-not-sell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 20:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/09/technology-does-not-sell/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/">Seth Godin&lt;/a> did a talk at Google campus in Februari last year. I recently stumbled upon &lt;a href="http://video.google.nl/videoplay?docid=-6909078385965257294">this video of his talk&lt;/a>, in which he explains to the Google people why Google sells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He is very clear in explaining to technology people that &lt;strong>technology does not sell&lt;/strong>. It's technology that gives you a shot at marketing, nothing more. He makes some very good points which I'll try to summarize, because the video takes 48 minutes to watch :-)&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * People don't care about cool technology, they care about their problem being solved.
* When buying a product, people actually are buying a feeling or experience. Apple and Google are good examples of &amp;quot;solve the problem&amp;quot; products, which gives more &amp;quot;feeling&amp;quot; than &amp;quot;product&amp;quot;.
* People who buy &amp;quot;feeling&amp;quot; and are happy with that, will market the product for you. You just plant a seed, and if the product is good enough for the right people, it will sel itself
* You can only sell answers to people who have questions. The classic &amp;quot;tv show interruption commercial&amp;quot; is way less efficient than the [Add-Sense](https://www.google.com/adsense) commercials which presents relevant products to people who are searching.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>When reading back this list, I think it is clear that Seth should speak to you, and not me ;-). My summary is lousy compared to the talk, maybe you're better of watching it. But the main conclusion for me still is that technology does not sell, nor does a product. It's the (happy) feeling people get from buying the product, making them want to tell other people about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He brings up a nice example still true today: If you wanted to search for something on the web, and go to &lt;a href="http://www.yahoo.com/">Yahoo!&lt;/a>, you'll see a page with 100 links, and somewhere on the page (you have to look for it) is a search query entry field and a search button. When you go too &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/">Google&lt;/a>, it's very clear that you can search there. Almost no links, and the search functionality is in the middle of the page and everybody knows how to use it. This will make you come back at that page, and even better: If your friends wanted to search for something, you'd send them to Google, because you know they will know how to use that page, and not come bother you with questions about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google's page is becomming slightly more cluttered with links, I just hope they paid attention to Seth and will remove some soon. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Edit:&lt;/strong> This is also a nice addition of Seth. Only 10 minutes, about &lt;a href="http://video.google.nl/videoplay?docid=-4101280286098310645">stuff that's &amp;quot;broken&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. I whish people would not only watch it and laugh, but actually use it while designing/building/doing things! You can also visit his website on &lt;a href="http://broken.typepad.com/">Stuff that's broken&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Give me spots on my Apples</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 20:43:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/05/02/give-me-spots-on-my-apples/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_ilove-apple-green.jpg">&lt;img src="o_ilove-apple-green.thumbnail.jpg" alt="I love my Apple">
&lt;/a>Lately Greenpeace has started a &lt;a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/apple/">campaign&lt;/a> against the usage of hazardous materials by Apple. The campain setup is friendly, nicely designed and urges Apple to choose materials which are less hazadous to the environment.As a spinoff of the Greenpeace campain all kinds of so called &amp;quot;journalists&amp;quot; have begun to put Apple on the &amp;quot;wrong end of the scale&amp;quot; of their &amp;quot;environment-o-meter&amp;quot;, and are happily writing doom articles about what will happen to your Karma if you buy any Apple product. But how environmentally unfriedly are Apple's computers really?&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Let's say you believe the hype, and avoid Apple like the plague because of it's [environmentally unfriendly plastics](http://www.apple.com/hotnews/agreenerapple/), it's [huge pricetag](http://kurafire.net/log/archive/2006/04/25/debunking-the-price-myth-apple-vs-dell) and the risk of becomming a brainwashed [cult member](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cult_%28religious_practice%29) worshipping Apple for te rest of your life.
&lt;p>So you buy a &lt;a href="http://www.shivaranjan.com/shivaupload/trashcanpc/musor_02.jpg">shiny new $800 PC&lt;/a> to run Vista, with that new 8 zillion transistor processor, dual &amp;quot;Energy Star&amp;quot; power supply and an &amp;quot;Energy Star&amp;quot; screen. When you turn the computer on, it starts to warm up your room with the 80 Watts it's consuming. When you really put it through it's paces, it consumes up to 150 Watts, or more if you bought that superduper video card which is more of an &amp;quot;audio card&amp;quot; when the fan starts blowing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a year of happy computing, your computer bogs down under the weight of all the &amp;quot;uninstalled&amp;quot; programs still on your drive. Vista 2 is released, and requires this all new Chipset to run, so you decide to buy a new PC. You give your old PC to your nephew, who totally turns it into an expensive $100 paper weight in 5 months, and it ends up in the trash because it can not be sold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously your new PC is way cooler than your old one, so it runs way hotter and uses more enery than ever. So there you are. Lot's of money spent, lot's of energy wasted, and lots of plastic in the environment, all in under a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your mother is also in the market for a new computer to read your emails and watch your photographs. You try to push her into buying a &lt;a href="http://www.theage.com.au/articles/2003/08/25/1061663718447.html">&amp;quot;man's computer&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, but before you know it she falls for the slick designs and smoothtalk sales at the Apple store. She buys an &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/imac/">iMac&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She installs the heidonous toxic pastic bomb in her living room because &amp;quot;it looks lovely&amp;quot;. You put on your ear protection to turn it on, but your mother warns you that is already up and running. Yes that's right, you can't hear an Apple when it's on (and that goes for the fruit aswell). You don't believe her, and measure the &lt;a href="http://www.eworld.com/environment/energyefficiency/">power consumption&lt;/a>, which is less than half of the power of your PC, at comparabe system load. And the iMac has a built in screen to that, as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your mother uses the iMac for a year, and you stop by for your yearly 15 minute &amp;quot;tea-and-bisquits-with-mom&amp;quot; session only to discover that the iMac is still running as fast as last year, and is looking just as good as it did when it came out of the box. In fact, the next 2 yearly visits are the same. The iMac does not deteriorate, and judging by eBay, it holds it's value much longer than the average PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each next version of the operating system hapilly runs on the &amp;quot;old hardware&amp;quot;, so your mother does not need to upgrade her hardware each time a new OS is released, apart from not needing to switch to the new OS anyway because it just works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having read all this, let's see how PCs and Macs compare:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;p>PC
Mac&lt;/p>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Life expectancy:
&lt;td valign="top" >1 year.
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >2 to 3 years.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
End of life:
&lt;td valign="top" >Ends up as worthless trash or power-gulping server.
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Gets sold to a happy new user for a good price.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
Power usage:
&lt;td valign="top" >More than 100 Watts (Pentium 4 PC without screen).
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Less than 50 Watts (Intel Core Duo Mac Mini without screen).
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
So which one is environmentally unfriendly I ask you? There are way more environmentally unfriendly PCs in the world, which use more energy and end up in the trash more often. I still remember how my electricity bill changed when I switched from PC to Mac, and how it is still running smoothly today.
&lt;p>Just a thought...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Samba shares and USB drives</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/09/25/samba-shares-and-usb-drives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 14:54:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/09/25/samba-shares-and-usb-drives/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I am very close to migrating the data on my bulky PC to my new Mac Mini fileserver and mounting the IDE drives in the USB drive brackets. Once I've done this, I will have the screenshots and data to write a nice &amp;quot;how to&amp;quot; on using the Mac Mini as a file server. There is however one slight problem which could prove to be a showstopper...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Samba test 1: local directories.&lt;/strong>
I created a directory in the root of the HD in the mac mini, and made it R/W for everybody. Then, I used SharePoints to make it available to all password-less Guest users on the network (which happens to be the default Windows user for connecting to drives without asking for a password). All was well. I could access the share, and could copy as many files from as many machines imultaniously as I wanted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Samba test 2: USB mounted volumes.&lt;/strong>
I mounted a HFS+ formatted USB disk to the Mac Mini, and made it available to the network in the same way as in test 1. Everything seemed to be working fine and as expected, but while running some tests I discovered a strange thing: I can only copy files onto the USB drive from 1 machine at a time, 1 file at a time. When starting a new copy while allready in the process of copying an older file, one or both copy jobs crashed with a &amp;quot;file in use&amp;quot; error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am now trying to find out what is causing this problem. I have a firewire drive I can use to determine if it is the USB protocol or driver which is causing this problem, or if it is the fact that it is a mounted volume alltogether. If anybody has tips I'm glad to hear them. Meanwhile I'll be searching the web...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>
Using a firewire drive does not solve the problem. I did find some articles on fast user switching which state that only 1 user can access pheripherals at a time. This seems to be related to this problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 2&lt;/strong>
Creating a symlink to the mounted volume and sharing the link through samba will not change behaviour. I was expecting this, but tried anyway because it only costs 1 minute to test. Maybe a virtual drive would be an option. I can create virtual RAID disks in OSX, but I don't want my setup to be complex. This will add to the complexity when recovering from a sever crash. Simple, full and fast recovery from hardware problems is my top priority.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Curing lens envy</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/08/29/curing-lens-envy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2006 14:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/08/29/curing-lens-envy/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Do you still want &amp;quot;that last lens and that's it&amp;quot;? According to the statistics on &lt;a href="http://medfmt.8k.com/bronlensenvy.html">this page&lt;/a>, you probably already have the right lens in your camera bag. Chances are that you are using your cheapest lens most often. The best quote from this page must be &lt;strong>&amp;quot;The cost of the lens is inversely proportional to the frequency of its use.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where did I get that link from? Well, from a brilliant text by Ken Rockwel titled &lt;a href="http://kenrockwell.com/tech/notcamera.htm">&amp;quot;Your Camera Does Not Matter&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. It states that you may not only have overspent on lenses, but on your complete kit alltogether! According to Ken, &lt;strong>&amp;quot;Buying new gear will NOT improve your photography.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="t_img_0303.jpg" alt="Watching the “Odobenus rosmarus” swim">
Next time you see a guy with a D200, don't be impressed. The guy behind him with his old &lt;a href="http://www.apogeephoto.com/july2001/plastic_fantastic.shtml">Holga&lt;/a> camera could be shooting far better pictures!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have had a &lt;a href="http://www.photo.net/ezshop/product?product_id=280">Canon EOS 300 (35mm film)&lt;/a>, a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/powershot_a20">Canon Powershot A20&lt;/a> and now a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/eos_350d">Canon 350D&lt;/a>. I also have made photo's with some of my dad's camera's, a &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/cameras/canon/ft_ql">Canon FT-QL&lt;/a>, and an &lt;a href="http://www.classiccamera.com.pl/exa2b.html">Exa IIB&lt;/a>. When changing from one camera to another, my photography (in particular composition) did not change. It just took some trouble away from the process. EOS 200 to Canon A20: no more film hassle. Canon A20 to 350D: Faster bootup and shot-to-shot times. Canon FT-QL and Exa IIB: The romantic feeling of craftsmanship when holding the camera :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="t_img_0223.jpg" alt="Hedge sparrow on a fence, at 200mm, aperture 5.6">
Sure the 350D gives me nice resolution and more freedom to play with aperture and exposure times and I still like the camera after reading Kens article. But he is right. Period. I recently spoke to a guy who owned an EOS 300 just like I did. He looked at one of my photo's from the 350D and said &amp;quot;I've got to have that camera, how did you do that?&amp;quot;. I explained &amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot; to him and told him that he could do that with his own EOS 300 if he had taken the time to learn how to use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess some sales people translate &amp;quot;I want a good camera&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;I want to spend a truckload of cash on a camera of which I'll only use the full-auto mode to shoot pictures of uncle Zed with.&amp;quot; People who don't know what &amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;exposure time&amp;quot; means just want a snapshot camera which automatically will produce clear, colorful, crisp foto's of uncle Zed 95% of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before buying a camera, read Ken's article, get out of that chair and start shooting with whatever camera you have right now. That one brilliant moment is waiting for you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Beanbag!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/21/free-beanbag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2006 15:11:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/07/21/free-beanbag/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When you are using a (digital) camera and need to place it on an uneven surface to keep it still long enough for your long shutter speeds, or you want to make a shot on the release timer (or both), you'll need a tripod, or a &lt;a href="http://www.shortcourses.com/equipment/tripods/beanbag.jpg">beanbag&lt;/a>. A beanbag is an ideal option, you can tuck it into your backpack, take it everywhere you need and it fits all camera's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, you can buy a beanbag from a nice company like &lt;a href="http://www.wildlifewatchingsupplies.co.uk/">this&lt;/a>, and spend about 30 euro's or more. But, If you've got a needle, thread, a T-shirt or linnen bag, and some rice, you can make one for free!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->![Beanbag materials](o_img_8641.jpg)
&lt;p>Start by sacrificing your linnen bag or t-shirt, cutting out two square pieces of about 23x23cm (or larger if you want to support a larger camera/lens combination). As you can see here, I saved me some sewing because I used the corner of a linnen bag. Now I only had to stich up 2 sides of the &amp;quot;pillow&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Put the two pieces on top of eachother and sew them together. Don't worry about being close to the edges, leave plenty of room there, because you will turn it inside-out later on. To be able to turn it inside-out and fill it with rice (or other forms of &amp;quot;beads&amp;quot;), leave about 7cm on one edge un-sewed. I also recommend to leave the hole in the middle of an edge. This way you'll have 4 nice sharp corners on the bag lateron.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turn the bag inside out. Now the edges look nicer, don't they? Roll up a piece of A4 paper and put it in the hole of your bag, and make it into a funnel. Poor the beads (rice, dries peas or beans, or fatboy filling) into the funnel. Make sure you don't fill the bag totally, because then it will not be flexible enough. I used about 1kg of rice for mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_8647.jpg" alt="Beanbag finished">
Close the bag by sewing the last opening. This takes some attention, this is the part of your sewing which could be visible. You can see where I closed the bag at the bottom right of the picture with the Powershot on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beanbag I made supports my Canon EOS 350D perfectly. There are a few improvements on my list after making it. My next beanbag will:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * be made of a black t-shirt so it's less reflecting
* be filled with [fatboy filling](http://www.serenityhealth.com/bean_filler.html) to prevent problems when getting the bag wet (rice stinks :-)
* be slightly bigger
* will contain a zipper or velcro on the opening so I can (re)fill it
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now make one of your own and go and use the 30 euro's you just saved to buy nice UV lens filters. :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_8648.jpg" alt="Beanbag with Canon A20">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_img_5926.jpg" alt="Beanbag with Canon 350D">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Canon 350D B/W Sepia</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/06/03/canon-350d-bw-sepia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2006 15:44:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/06/03/canon-350d-bw-sepia/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Once in a while I like to take black and white pictures because the EOS has a nice built in set of color filters. The easiest example of a nice black and white photo where a color filter produces great results is the classic &amp;quot;blue sky with Yellow filter&amp;quot;. You should really check out the great tutorials on &lt;a href="http://www.cambridgeincolour.com/tutorials.htm">Cambridge in Color&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="r_canon-color.jpg" alt="350D Sepia">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When shooting in B/W mode, I often use the &amp;quot;sepia&amp;quot; filter, to add a little warmth to the photo. A wierd thing I noticed lately about the EOS 350D (besides the film transport sound) is that &amp;quot;Sepia&amp;quot; mode is not really producing pure B/W Sepia images. There is color seeping through! In the top image, you can clearly see residues of red, yellow and blue in a photo of a baby toy (cropped for privacy reasons). The bottom image is converted to pure B/W on a computer and then sort of &amp;quot;Sepia&amp;quot;-d using a hue/saturation tool just for reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read on some forums that camera effects are generally not as good as the effects in image processing programs like PhotoShop or GIMP. This is supposedly because speed/quality tradeoffs. I really like to spend more time with the camera than post-processing, so I'd like to keep using the in-camera effects. A great tip I read somewhere on a forum is to shoot in RAW+JPG mode. The JPG will have all the processing done by the camera, and the RAW will be the raw data from the sensor. Depending on the results of the in-camera effects, you either keep the JPG, or use the RAW image to do the effect in GIMP later on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac Support... is... slooowww</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/16/mac-support-is-slooowww/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2006 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/16/mac-support-is-slooowww/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As you've probably read, my brand new Mac Mini has a memory problem. I have brought it in for repair, but I am &amp;quot;slightly irritated&amp;quot; by the speed at which the guys from the &lt;a href="http://www.macsupport.nl/home.php">www.macsupport.nl&lt;/a> stores pick things up.&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Friday, May 6th:
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >I've found out that the mini has a consistent, reproducable memory problem. I suspect a technician could even tell which of the two memory modules it is judging from the faulty address (faulty single bit even, for the technical readers amongst us). It's late in the evening so I have to wait for the next day to call. I printed out a screenshot of the memory error and location, and put that in the box with the mini, to make sure they have a clear problem description.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Saturday, May 7th:
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Started calling the shop. They state that the tech support guys are not in on saturday. Strange, since they installed the memory modules on a saturday when I bought the thing. Can't the same guy swap out both modules so I have my machine back? Finding out which module is faulty can be done in the shop without me waiting. No apperantly not. I tried to call 3 of their shops, of which Amsterdam didn't even return my call even though I asked the operator to tell them to call me back.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Sunday, May 8th:
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Although the shop in Amsterdam claims to be open, they are to busy to pick up the phone.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Monday, May 9th:
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >I tried to call the new shop in Haarlem, but I get a "Sorry all lines are busy" message all day. At the end of the day I decide to drive to the shop. The shop is open, but they have network and phone problems (thanks to KPN, they claim). Because it is a new shop eveybody is uncertain as to what to do, and it takes me 45 minutes (!) to get the Mac mini to be taken in for repairs, even though I was helped the moment I entered the shop. They warn me that the repair is going to take a week (!).
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Tuesday, May 16th
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >Still no call from the shop in Haarlem. When I try to call, I notice they still have the same phone line problems. So, I drive to the shop again to find out how the repairs are going. They in form me that my Mac is "scheduled for repair on the 19th"!. So it has been sitting there for almost 2 WEEKS! And then they haven't even begun to look at the problem. They expect it to be repaired and ready to be picked up at Monday, May 22nd at the earliest.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
As you can read, this is not a happy start of my 1600+ euro Apple adventure. I really hope they can get their logistics and repair process in shape. I really like the Mac mini, but I sure don't like the way Mac support takes their time to switch to memory modules and run a diagnostics tool.</description></item><item><title>Mac Mini Crash: Maxtor not the problem</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/06/mac-mini-crash-maxtor-not-the-problem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 15:56:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/06/mac-mini-crash-maxtor-not-the-problem/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="r_img_4139-cutout.jpg" alt="Memtest">
In my &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2006/05/04/mac-mini-crash-cause-located/">last post&lt;/a>, the Maxtor OneTouch drive was the prime suspect of the spontanious crashing of the Mac. Tonight the Mac mini crashed again, but this time without the Maxtor connected to it. So I set out to do a thourough memory test in single user mode, running &lt;a href="http://www.memtestosx.org/">memtest&lt;/a>. And after a few iterations it was there: The dreaded memory failure. I guess I have to bring my mini back to the store to get replacement memory.Intermitting problems like this are terrible. They are hard to find, and you loose all trust in your computer, saving every 3 seconds, hoping you don't loose anything. If the external drive was really to blame, I would seriously have doubted the implementation of the USB drivers, because the system crashes without warning, without logging or anything. A memory failure was actually the more plausible casue all the time, since the kernel just stops because the processor(s) reach a part of the memory where there was supposed to be code, but has become garbage. To be able to log, the processor has to execute code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac Mini Crash: cause located</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/04/mac-mini-crash-cause-located/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 15:54:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/05/04/mac-mini-crash-cause-located/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="o_maxtorfs.gif" alt="Windows screenshot showing Maxtor drive stats">
Today I spent some more time using Google to find information on why my Mac suddenly crashed. I am now 99% that the cause of this all is my &lt;a href="http://www.nextag.com/Maxtor-ONE-TOUCH-II--zz68645598zB2z2--COMPARE-PRICES-html">Maxtor OneTouch 250GB&lt;/a> drive, which was formatted as one big Fat32 partition (screenshot). Although I connected it to a friend's iMac for a short period without problems, and it has worked on my Mac mini for a while, I keep finding discussions about people with &lt;a href="http://forums.dpreview.com/forums/readflat.asp?forum=1017&amp;amp;message=16514032&amp;amp;changemode=1">crashed Macs&lt;/a>. I have not installed the Maxtor software, so that's &lt;a href="http://www.macintouch.com/tiger10.html">not the problem&lt;/a>.I have disconnected the Maxtor drive last Saturday, and my Mac has been up and running ever since, without problems. I can almost rule out memory related issues, because when I startup Eclipse while running &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ilife/imovie/">iMovie&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ilife/idvd/">iDVD&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.com/thunderbird/">Thunderbird&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/">Firefox&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/download/">iTunes&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/archive/2006/04/23/88885.aspx">Clutter&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/textwrangler/">TextWrangler&lt;/a> (yes all at the same time), the system keeps on running. In fact, it is still responding to user input as if I had only one of those programs running. Only very minimal swapping with 2GB memory, and when swapping, OS X is very efficient about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, my plans are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Only connect the maxtor to a PC while it is still Fat32.
2. Share the drive on the PC, and try to empty it as much as possible (move data to Mac and the fileserver)
3. Run [Rember](http://www.kelleycomputing.net:16080/rember/) in single user mode for a few iterations this weekend to rule out memory problems.
4. Decide on a filesystem to use on the Maxtor, and reformat it.
5. Re-connect the Maxtor OneTouch to the Mac and see if the gremlin is killed.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>It is very likely that the drive is going to be formatted with the &lt;a href="http://www.whoi.edu/CIS/services/desktop/macintosh/about/extended_format.html">&amp;quot;Mac Os Extended&amp;quot; filesystem&lt;/a>, but I'm not sure about &lt;a href="http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=107249">journalling&lt;/a> yet. The disadvantage of all this is that the drive can not be used to transfer files between a PC and a Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still it feels funny. Some people actually can create 100GB+ Fat32 partitions they can use on their Macs. I can read and write to the drive too, but at some point my Mac decides it has been enough and kills itself (probably after finding the windows crud ;-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sorry for the linking-frenzy, I had a lot of links I wanted to share with you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Airbus 330 Entertainent system</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/31/airbus-330-entertainent-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2006 19:36:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/31/airbus-330-entertainent-system/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently went to Vegas, which is a very long trip (about 20 hours including stopover). I don't like flying that much, my ears hurt and it is very boring to be crammed in a chair for 10 hours, with a headrest that makes your chin touch your chest no matter how you adjust it. However, on this flight (and the one back) there was a nice personal entertainment system installed in each chair.Below are some images of the personal entertainment system which is installed on the Airbus 330's of Northwest Airlines. These are a real treat on long distance flights. There is a fair selection of on-demand movies, music, some simple games and flight information. It lets you choose a movie, and you can pause and skip as much as you like. You can use your own 3.5mm jacked headphones, no more of that adapter-buying-if-you-are-lucky-you'll-get-stereo crap you see in the older planes. The menu even contained an item called &amp;quot;email&amp;quot;, but it was not functioning at the time I tried it. Besides you had to swipe your credit card for it, which I didn't find worth trying even if it would work.&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >[![Bejeweled](r_img_3683.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3683.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Controller](r_img_3686.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3686.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Flight information](r_img_3692.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3692.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >[![Movies](r_img_3688.thumbnail.jpg)
](r_img_3688.jpg)
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
&lt;td valign="top" >Nice little game, Bejeweled
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >The controller (has to be turned 90 degrees sometimes, confusing!)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Guess where we are? Travelling at 950km/h there :-)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td valign="top" >Watched Chicken Little. It does not live up to it's commercial by a long shot.
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
Funny thing is, that my wife's entertainent system actually crashed during flight. It got stuck for about 5 minutes, after which it automatically rebooted, and guess what? I saw a Tux! It is actually a Linux system. A bit of googling revealed that a few people even have seen the system crash on [all monitors at the same time](http://www.flickr.com/photos/milliped/116393699/). Good thing they aren't using this system for the flight controls yet. ;-)
&lt;p>But it does make sense. It doesn't cost anything, and being open source, Panasonic (the manufacturer of the system) has full controll on getting all the glitches out. Now they actually do need to do that still, but I bet they got a nice (remote?) update procedure for that. After all, they also need to upload new movies every now and then. Maybe they use the same connection as they use for email? 100% remote update would be nice. No &amp;quot;downtime&amp;quot; for the planes!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I for one liked the system very much. It actually has games which let you compete with other passengers, but that didn't seem to be popular on my flights to Las Vegas. I didn't even had to get my PSP out of my bag :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now if they only could make those stupid headrests removable so I can put my head back when I want to sleep (like most normal people), flying wouldn't be all that bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soybean racer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/12/soybean-racer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The big car manufacturers could have done &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2006/02/17/eveningnews/main1329941.shtml">this&lt;/a>, but they didn't, because they are sponsored by the big oil companies. And your local governement is swimming in taxmoney that's added to your oil price. And no, they don't want to get rid of the cars, despite of what they say. The nicest thing for governements would be the complete population sitting in single-seated, gas guzzling cars in a traffic jam accross the country!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that a few school kids have proven that you don't need oil to race, and several American race series run on methanol (no that's not an oil product), can we please stop making cars that run on gasoline? And by the way, also stop pumping money into the super-dangerous liquid nitrogen cars? All that is purely to keep the oil companies in the same place: monopoly. Do you really think they do it for the environment? What if I told you that your current petrol car can run on bio-degradable methanol, with almost no changes? If you have a very modern car, the fuel system will even auto-adapt! But noooo, they won't tell you that, because the oil companies and governements want to keep the monopoly intact!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not that you can really do anything about it though. Except maybe not buying liquid-nitrogen or hybrid cars. There are better technical alternatives, although not on the market yet. Boycot the &amp;quot;environmentally friendly&amp;quot; car, force them into making a &lt;em>real&lt;/em> environmentally friendly car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I'm driving a diesel, and a motorbike. And no, I'm not worried about oil-shortage. It's all bullshit from the oil companies, who could have come up with alternatives a long while ago, but chose not to. If there really was an oil shortage, we all would have been driving on methanol for quite some time now. And co2 emmisions would have been reduced to absolutely 0.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to replace the headlights on a Citroen Xsara</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/11/how-to-replace-the-headlights-on-a-citroen-xsara/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 19:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/03/11/how-to-replace-the-headlights-on-a-citroen-xsara/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Recently my left headlight broke. I thought I'd change it quickly, but after half an hour of fiddling I decided to ask my dealer to do it for me, while I was looking. That was not a bad idea. It turned out to be not so straightforward after all, and you actually need tools (which you don't get when buying the car) to do this! This lead me to write a &amp;quot;small&amp;quot; article on how to replace the headlights of a Citroen Xsara. Enjoy.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![My Citroen Xsara 1.4 Hdi](r_citroen-xsara-break-14-hdi.thumbnail.jpg)
&lt;p>](r_citroen-xsara-break-14-hdi.jpg)** The Car**
This is my Citroen Xsara break 1.4 HDi. No, that's not the picasso model, you've seen that right. I think car manufacturers need to stop naming a complete line of cars with just one name. Nobody knows what car you are driving, even if you tell them. Good examples are the Citroen Xsara and the Renault Megane. But that's not what this article is about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently my left headlight broke. I thought I'd change it quickly, but after half an hour of fiddling I decided to ask my dealer to do it for me, while I was looking. That was not a bad idea. It turned out to be not so straightforward after all, and you actually need tools to do this! You will need a 10mm wrench and a screwdriver. If you have thick fingers, I'd recommend a pair of pliers as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote the whole procedure down here, for other Xsara owners to read. It can save you a costly trip to the garage, or a trip without headlights in a very dark area. The left headlight is the hardest to replace, the right headlight can be done without tools (although still a bit hard to reach).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Click on the images to zoom in)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-headlight-booklet-picture.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-headlight-booklet-picture.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Headlight from the manual">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>1. Check the manual&lt;/strong>
The first thing you need to do (if you care for a laugh) is check the manual on &amp;quot;changing lights&amp;quot;. You will find a nice picture of the back of the headlight unit, with arrows pointing to the different lights. Surely this is to motivate you to do it yourself, but they kindly &amp;quot;forgot&amp;quot; to include the 9 missing steps to even get to the rear of the headlight unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-cover-arrow.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-cover-arrow.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Left Engine Cover clips">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>2. Remove left engine cover&lt;/strong>
Open up the hood (or stop reading here if you can't ;-). You will see some plastic engine covers. Yes, those are the same covers you need to remove on the right side to fill up your windshield wiper fluid. The first sign the designer must have been a complete and utter idiot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the left headlight, remove the left engine cover (that's the right one if you are facing the front bumper ;-). Turn the little knobs 90 degrees counter clockwise and carefully lift up the plastic. The knobs are very flimsy, be careful not to break them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-tube-arrows.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-tube-arrows.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Aire Intake Tube">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>3. Remove air intake tube&lt;/strong>
The air intake tube is connected to a plastic box behind the headlight, with a bajonet lock. Turn the top of the tube slightly towards you, and then pull it out of the plastic box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-box-screw-arrow.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-box-screw-arrow.thumbnail.jpg" alt="air intake box nut">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>4. Remove air intake box nut&lt;/strong>
Below where the air intake tube was, you will find a 10mm nut hodling the bottom of the air intake box. Use a 10mm wrench to undo it. Be careful not to drop it into the engine compartment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-peg.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-air-intake-peg.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Remove air intake box peg">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="r_citroen-air-intake-peg.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-air-intake-peg.thumbnail.jpg" alt="The peg after removal">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>5. Remove air intake box peg&lt;/strong>
The top of the air intake box is held by a plastic peg. To pull the center pin out, you'll need to lift the pin with a screwdriver (look carefully at the picture). It should not take much force to take it out, please be carefull with this piece of plastic. I think Citroen will charge a pretty unfair amount of money to replace it should you've broken or lost it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-abs-plug-cover-arrow.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-abs-plug-cover-arrow.thumbnail.jpg" alt="ABS plug cover">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>6. Remove ABS plug cover&lt;/strong>
Allways wanted to know what that aluminum box is with those steel lines comming out the top? Well that's your anti-blocking system unit, and you're about to disconnect it. First, you need to remove the cover which protects the plug from moisture. You better change your headlights while it is not raining, because chances are that your ABS will stop working if you get the connector to corrode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-unlock-abs-plug-arrows.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-unlock-abs-plug-arrows.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Unlock and remove ABS plug">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>7. Unlock and remove ABS plug&lt;/strong>
Pull out the red handle. The ABS connector plug should almost immediately loosen, and removing the connector should take absolutely &lt;em>no force&lt;/em>. If it sticks, you probably didn't pull out the red handle enough. Carefully look at the picture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-remove-rear-headlight-cover-arrow.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-remove-rear-headlight-cover-arrow.thumbnail.jpg" alt="headlight cover">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>8. Remove rear headlight cover&lt;/strong>
The lamp cover is a simple plastic lid. Just pull it away from the headlight unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-unplug-main-headlight-arrow.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-unplug-main-headlight-arrow.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Unplug headlight">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>9. Unplug headlight&lt;/strong>
Remove the grey and brown wired plug from the rear of the lamp.
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-lamp-clip.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-lamp-clip.thumbnail.jpg" alt="How to remove the clip">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>10. Remove lamp clip&lt;/strong>
With a flashlight, you can see that the lamp is held in place by a clip. This clip has two handles at the top of the lamp. Push them towards the headlight unit, and then outward. The lamp can now be taken out. Please take note on it's orientation when taking it out, there is only one way of putting it back in without damaging your headlight unit or blinding oncomming traffic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-headlight-h7-out.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-headlight-h7-out.thumbnail.jpg" alt="The H7 Lamp out of it’s reflector">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>11. Replace lamp&lt;/strong>
Replace the lamp with a H7 type lamp, again note the orientation of the lamp. Don't touch the glass with your fingers. Touching the glass will leave grease on the glass. When the lamp heats up, it will become hotter than normal, shortening it's lifetime. Even worse: the grease will vaporize and leave a non-removable milky deposit on your reflectors. Reflectors are very expensive to replace. The dealer will charge you for a complete headlight unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="r_citroen-reinstall-air-intake-box-arrows.jpg">&lt;img src="r_citroen-reinstall-air-intake-box-arrows.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Reinstall Air Intake Box (arrows)">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>12. Put it all back together&lt;/strong>
Connect the lamp and make sure it is working. After that, re-install all parts in revers order. Make sure that when you re-install the air intake box, the clips (pointed out by arrows 1 and 2 in the picture) are around the steel rimm. If the air intake box is not correctly placed, the plastic pin will not go through the misaligned holes, and the bottom slot will not align with the thread on which the 10mm nut goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope this will help other owners of Citroen Xsara's in replacing their own headlights. If you do not feel confident of something when replacing your headlights, please contact your local dealer. Needless to say, messing aroung with your brake system should be done with care and professionalism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take care!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Can't Fix What You Don't Measure</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/25/you-cant-fix-what-you-dont-measure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/25/you-cant-fix-what-you-dont-measure/</guid><description>
&lt;p>... maybe the title should be &amp;quot;Two Stupidities A Week&amp;quot;, but since both stupid actions had to do with measurement, or rather the lack thereof, let's stick with the proverb.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3626.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3626.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Selfmade rotorpuller next to old one">
&lt;/a>&lt;strong>Stupidity #1&lt;/strong>
Last Saturday my brother and I went to a motorbike scrapyard for some advice, and maybe a new rotorpuller we could borrow. While talking to the guy, it became clear that either I am treating the rotor with too much love and care, or this guy turns into the Hulk when he pulls rotors. He gave us the advice to try again, and:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;quot;Don't force it, get a larger hammer!&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we set out to get the larger hammer. While getting the hammer I got the brilliant idea to only use the outer bolt of the rotorpuller, so that it sat against the flat outer end of the crank. That way we could hit it harder without the risk of tearing up the threads inside the crank.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I turned the puller into the rotor, tightened it, and started hitting it with the hammer. Nothing happened. After hitting it, I could hardly remove the puller from the rotor. It appeared to be forged shorter and thicker by the hammering. The threads looked strangely damaged. When I overlooked the damages a day later, it occured to me that the rotor puller was rather short. And yes, mesaurements confirmed that it never could have touched the crank. It turns out that I was actually hammering the rotor &lt;strong>onto&lt;/strong> the crank, and killing the puller in the process. The thread in the rotor still looked pertty intact. Phew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stupidity #2&lt;/strong>
The rotor puller now being officially useless, I started browsing the internet to see what type of bolt I would need to pull the rotor of a Kawasaki KL650B block. I found a site, telling me I needed a 20mm bolt, with 1.5mm thread. That's an ISO fine M20x1.5 bolt. So I set out to get one. 20mm bolts are not common in your local hardware store. One hardware store could actually find where he could order it, but refused to do that (I will never walk into WALCO hardware store next to Haarlem Central Station again). I would have gladly payed any shipping costs, he had no idea, and he never asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I have a lathe, I decided to put some time in it. My local favourite hardware store had 20mm round steel (the thickest they had) , so I bought a meter of it. With my lathe I cut the 1.5mm thread onto it, which actually worked quote nice. I only broke a cutter on the last pass, stopping too late. I have to find out how to prevent that from happening the next time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I removed the workpiece from the lathe, and tried to screw it into the rotor. Guess what? It was too small! If I had taken 15 seconds to measure the rotor before buying the steel, I would have saved myself a lot of work. After uploading this story I will try to order a puller online, because I can't find larger steel rods today, and the rotor puller is nothing more than a $3,00 bolt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe I feel like using my lathe again next week, who knows... But then I will use my measure calipers first, last, and very often in between, because: &lt;em>You Can't Fix What You Don't Measure!&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotten Rotor</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/14/rotten-rotor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 20:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/14/rotten-rotor/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3581.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3581.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki KL 650 Tengai crankshaft drawing">
&lt;/a>Last week I tried to pull the rotor by using a rotor puller, and a socket (from a socket wrench set) to block it. The socket burried it's way into the first thread of the crankshaft. After realising this, I tried to fit the rotor bolt, and it wouldn't go in. Since only the first thread was damaged, I carefully drilled it out (only needed to go 2 mm deep), and now the rotor bolt fits nicely again.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3574.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3574.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki Rotor bolt made into Rotor puller stub">
&lt;/a>To prevent this from happening again, I ordered a new rotorbolt, and changed the old one to a stub to rest the rotor puller against. You can see the stub on the left. This is needed because the crankshaft is hollow, and the rotor puller has nothing to press against.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This evening, I spent another few hours of battering the crankshaft and the rotorpuller, still nothing. No matter what I do, the rotor does not want to let go of the crankshaft. I even tried heating the rotor up until the point I could not touch it with my hands. I protected the magnets from direct heat of the flame with a strip of aluminium, but I didn't want to take the risk to melt the plastic holding them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3580.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3580.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Rotor puller side view">
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="r_img_3579.jpg">&lt;img src="r_img_3579.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Rotor puller after failed attemt to pull kawa rotor">
&lt;/a>In the process, my trusty old rotor puller even almost gave up on me, I think it is time for it's retirement. The thread inside the nut is defintely at it's end, and the handle is bent out of shape from the force applied to try to seperate the rotor from the crank. That, and the beating of the hammer on the inside bolt has turned this rotor puller into a paper weight (almost).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to give it another rest, I'm going to a motorbike exposition/dealer show next friday, maybe I can talk to people there about my problem. Sometimes the experienced bike repair shops have simple but effective tips to solve seemingly impossible problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make my evening productive I measured the valve clearances. They are pretty nice, only 1 valves is slightly low on their clearance. This strikes me as funny because usually the clearance increases because of wear. Maybe the original clearance was allready low, or the disassembly and reassembly of the head has changed the clearing because I tightened the bolts a bit harder, I don't know. I am fairly sure I measured the clearances correctly, and at the correct camshaft angles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clearances are:&lt;/p>
&lt;table >
&lt;tr >
&lt;td >
&lt;/td>
left
right
Allowed
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
exhaust
&lt;td >0.15mm (just enough)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.09mm (0.06 too little)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.15~0.25mm
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr >
inlet
&lt;td >0.12mm (spot on)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.15mm (spot on)
&lt;/td>
&lt;td >0.10~0.20mm
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
So, I probaly need to buy a 0.06mm to 0.1mm thinner shim for the right exhaust valve cam to be on the safe side, but I will re-measure the clearances once the head is on the bike, to see how much the wrenching influences the measurements.</description></item><item><title>195Nm Victory!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/07/195nm-victory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 20:46:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/02/07/195nm-victory/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3569.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3569.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Kawasaki Rotor Holder (from workshop manual)">
&lt;/a>For some strange reason, my brother's Kawasaki KLR Tengai dead-stopped. After starting it again, it made some strange noises. It also had lost a lot of oil somewhere along the way, so we decided to not run it again before we found the cause of the trouble. A few weeks ago we encountered a funny problem, we couldn't loosen the rotor-bolt. In the Kawasaki KLR workshop manual is a picture of a strange wrench to hold the rotor. Ofcourse we're cheap, so we wouldn't spring for a nifty and probably expensive Kawasaki specialty tool for a very old bike which not worth more than the petrol that's in the tank (okay, okay, but you get the point).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3565.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3565.thumbnail.jpg" alt="32mm wrench, colored from heating">
&lt;/a>The rotor bolt is tightened to 195Nm. That's a lot of force there, so it's not surprising we couldn't loosen it by holding the flywheeel with our hands. So we set out to create a tool of our own. We even ended up trying to bend an old 32mm Chrome-Vanadium wrench, which resulted in an empty gas can, a very hot workbench and nice colors on the wrench, without it bending even the slightest. We we barely able to heat it to the point it got red-hot, because the metal just conducts the heat away from the point you want to heat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3567.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3567.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Holding the piston to loosen the rotor-bolt (overview)">
&lt;/a>So I started mailing with Vincent, a good friend of mine which happens to be &lt;a href="http://www.zodiac.nl/dragrace/index2.htm">&amp;quot;quite handy&amp;quot; with motorbikes&lt;/a> . He pointed out that you could also stop the rotor from turning by holding the piston. Because we wanted to measure the play in the bigend bearing we needed to remove the sleeve anyway, so I immediately went back to the workshop to do this. After removing the sleeve, I could easily make some wood pegs to block the piston. The wood would have to have a big surface and be strong enough to hould the piston, without damaging the piston or the engine casing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3566.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3566.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Holding the piston to loosen the rotor-bolt (detail)">
&lt;/a>It turned out to work great! I needed to attach a long bar to the socket wrench to be able to apply enough force to the bolt, but in the end I got it! In the picture on the left you can see a detail of how the wood blocks are resting on the engine casing. After loosening the bolt, there was absolutely no visible damage to the piston or the engine. Even greater news is that there is also virtually no play on the bigend bearing, so we don't have to disasemble the crank.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3568.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3568.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Wearmarks from applying 195Nm to the bolt">
&lt;/a>When looking at the bolt, the results of applying so much force to the faces of the socket wrench become visible. We know for a fact that this bolt has been removed once before, so these wearmarks are from tightening and loosening the bolt just two times. I think we can tighten it one more time, but after that it needs to be replaced.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Server cleaning.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/12/20/server-cleaning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2005 21:15:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2005/12/20/server-cleaning/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_3448.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_3448.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Dust in the powersupply of the fileserver">
&lt;/a>...or should I say &amp;quot;Fire prevention&amp;quot;. Nowadays, more and more fires come from computers left running overnight. Sure it seems harmless, and you have probably gotten away with it for the past 10 years without anything happening. Still, chances are that it will happen someday.&lt;!-- more -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fire is a simple thing. All you need is fuel, oxygen and heat. In a computer, there is some heat (which is hopefully kept down by the fans), and a lot of oxygen (also kindly fed by the fans). So now, all we need is a fuell. The steel casing isn't going to light up very soon, and generally the materials of the chips and bits aren't that flamable either. The wire insulation is most likely to catch fire. Or is it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suppose your computer is an &amp;quot;allways on&amp;quot; fileserver, like mine. Only the disks spin down when it is not used for a long time, but everything else remains powered on. The fans of the system start to collect dust over the years, and are beginning to make more and more noise, and less and less revolutions. Before you know it, the dust is everywhere in your system, and the airflow is deminished to the sigh of a hamster, and the heat starts to build up. Dust is an excelent fuel, so all you have to do is get your marshmellows and wait for the fire to ignite&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Personally, I don't like roasted marshmellows, or my house burning down. So I informed the users of the server, shut it down, and cleaned it, power supply and all. Not only is the computer (somewhat) less of a fire-hazard, the advantage is also that it has become slightly less noisy.
So be honest with me, which of you readers work for a company which actually has a policy for shutting down and cleaning servers in the server room? Or a dust-free server room? I don't think there are that much, but it would be something to think about with all these heat-generating machines in a single well-ventilated room...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Milling aluminum housing</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/11/14/milling-aluminum-housing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2004 13:29:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/11/14/milling-aluminum-housing/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_2708.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_2708.jpg?w=128" alt="">
&lt;/a> Today I found the first good use for the milling machine. I had this cast aluminum housing for an electronics project, with ridges on the inside. I made a hole for a connector in it, but I never got the nut on the inside flat to the surface because of the ridges on the inside of the housing. I decided to use the mill to flatten the surface on the inside of the housing. The housing did not fit in the clamp, so I had to find a way to get it attached to the bed of the mill in a different way. I took a piece of wood, drilled two holes in it and bolted that to the bed of the mill. Then, I used long plywood screws and another piece of wood to hold the housing. In the picture on the right you can see this construction. I used a test indicator to align the house to the X-axis of the bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_2710.jpg">&lt;img src="o_img_2710.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a>Since I only needed a plane large enough to place a ring and nut on, I roughly adjusted the 6mm mill to just not touch the bottom of the housing. I milled down to the point where the ridges were not visible. The image on the left is the result of the work. The mill is a very nice tool to adjust ready-made electronics housing to your likings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Miling machine</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/11/07/miling-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 18:36:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/11/07/miling-machine/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl//images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4030/t_IMG_2695.jpg" alt="16mm mill detail">
Yes, that's right. That's a mill you're looking at. And yes, that photo was taken at my workshop. Last week I took a couple of days off from work, and decided to do another workshop upgrade session. After buying some decent wrenching tools, I spent some hours on the web looking for a nice bench drill. I was thinking of buying a cheap mill later on, but I found a nice combination of the two at the &lt;a href="http://www.locloods.demon.nl/">locloods&lt;/a>. This small mill, the HMD Black &amp;amp; Red X1-super, is a nice hybrid. It operates like a bench drill, but when the handle is locked, you can use the wheels to precisely control X and Y movement of the working piece and Z movement of the mill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl//images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4030/t_IMG_2704.jpg" alt="Milling Machine">
I made a nice sturdy table for the mill to rest on and bolted it on. It was a bit hard to get the mill on the high table, because it weighs about 45 kilograms and it's really hard to grab on to. I've put a piece of white MDF board on the wall to hold the tools that go with the mill. Putting pieces of wood against the wall to hold tools is terrific. I've also done this with the tools for my lathe, see the zundapp image gallery for more pictures of the workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was once a gray and dark place to just park a car in, is now almost a solarium with lots of tools. There's still a lot of work to be done to get the workshop completely ready, and I wonder if it will ever be finished, but it's becomming more practical every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl//images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4030/r_garage-panorama.jpg" alt="Workshop panorama">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mopeds are cool</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/10/31/mopeds-are-cool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2004 21:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2004/10/31/mopeds-are-cool/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="o_img_2662.jpg">&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4030/t_IMG_2662.jpg" alt="">
&lt;/a> Today I picked up my old moped at my parents house. Yes, that's right, I'm 33 and I still have my very first moped. It's a real special one. I belonged to my grandfather, who passed it on to my nephew, who passed it on to me when I turned 15. When I got it it needed a lot of work. I spent some months taking it completely apart with my dad. We didn't have a workshop back then, so we took it apart in the kitchen, of my parent's apartment on the 7th floor :-)When I turned 16 it was ready and better than new. It was really cool to have a classic Zundapp CS50. At that time, it looked like a motorbike next to my friend's puchs and peugeots. It really was a dream to ride, you could sit for hours on it without getting tired. I drove it for a good 6 years before it went in to &amp;quot;hibernation&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/images/blogger_xs4all_nl/rrolfje/4015/t_IMG_2371.JPG" alt="">
So, having my own home and my own workshop right now, I decided it was a good time to pick it up and make it run once again. These German mopeds are made to last, I can tell you. When I get it running again I am sure it will be able to run for at least another 20 years or so, provided it gets reasonable maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Browse through the &lt;a href="http://blogger.xs4all.nl/rrolfje/gallery/4030.aspx">&amp;quot;Zundapp&amp;quot; gallery&lt;/a> to see more pictures.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>