<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 13:57:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open a port in OSX Mavericks' Firewall</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/05/10/open-a-port-in-osx-mavericks-firewall/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 13:57:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2014/05/10/open-a-port-in-osx-mavericks-firewall/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=at6HrV5CTo8">&lt;img src="security.png" alt="Firewall">
&lt;/a>The new firewall in Mavericks is great. For the common user. For a developer, not so much. If you are a Java developer like me, and you just need to open one port (say, 8080) so that the web application you’re working on is accessable from another computer, you can’t. I disabled the Firewall altogether for a few days, but it didn't feel right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled around and to make a long story short, here’s how to open port 8080 on any interface to any application on your OSX Mavericks installation in 3 steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>sudo vim /etc/pf.conf&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then add the following lines at the end of the file:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code># Open port 8080 for TCP on all interfaces pass in proto tcp from any to any port 8080&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Test (and, according to the documentation, load) your edits with:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>sudo pfctl -vnf /etc/pf.conf&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reboot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I have found at least 5 pieces of voodoo to make the Firewall restart and reload, but none of them seemed to work reliably, so pardon the reboot)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can close it by commenting out the lines in pf.conf and reboot again. If anybody knows of an easier way to do this, preferably in one terminal command, and without rebooting, let me know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope this helps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Script: Text-to-NATO-spelling</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/05/27/script-text-to-nato-spelling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 19:11:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2013/05/27/script-text-to-nato-spelling/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dyWbu2y4QL4">&lt;img src="straight-key.jpg" alt="Straight Key">
&lt;/a>In my morse training adventure on &lt;a href="http://lcwo.net/">lcwo.net&lt;/a>, I hit a slight bump in the road. At Koch lesson 33 (of 40 lessons total), I can't seem to copy with 90% accuracy, which is the criterea for moving to the next lesson. See my downward trend here. It is partly because of gradually speeding up the &lt;a href="http://www.justlearnmorsecode.com/farnsworth.html">Farnsworth timing&lt;/a> from 10wpm to 12wpm so I can be on 20wpm at lesson 40. It is also because of shorter, less focussed daily training sessions, I must confess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="terrible-progress-lcwo.png">&lt;img src="terrible-progress-lcwo.png?w=450" alt="LCWO.net progress">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I experimented a bit, and it seems I can recognize characters easily at &lt;a href="http://cgi2.lcwo.net/cgi-bin/cw.mp3?s=37&amp;amp;e=37&amp;amp;f=600&amp;amp;t=This%20is%2037wpm%20morse%20code%20%20%20%20%5E">37wpm&lt;/a>, but I can't form the words and recognize letters at the same time. More accurately: I can't seem to be able to remember 3 to 5 characters, form a word and listen to new characters at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->To see if this was morse or memory related, I wrote a small program which spells out a text in speech, [NATO phonetic alphabet style](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NATO_phonetic_alphabet). I converted some text with it, and proved that my analysis of my own morse problem was correct. This script can also be used to train "word building", so that's why I thought I'd share it with you.
&lt;p>As for me, I am going to switch to morse word training on lcwo.net for a while, see if that helps. Here is the code for spelling out a text using Apple's built-in text-to-speech synthesizer. It takes a single argument as text file:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;quot;bash&amp;quot; wraplines=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; gutter=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;]
#!/bin/bash&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-input-text-file-to-parse-first-argument">The input text file to parse (first argument)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>inputfile=&amp;quot;${1}&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="temporary-files-to-write">(Temporary) files to write&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>outputfile=&amp;quot;${1}.m4a&amp;quot;
lowercase=&amp;quot;${1}.lowercase.txt&amp;quot;
tempfile=&amp;quot;${1}.spelled.txt&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="clean-up-in-case-we-crashed-last-time">clean up in case we crashed last time&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>rm ${tempfile}
rm ${lowercase}
rm ${outputfile}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="everything-to-lower-case">everything to lower case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>tr '[:upper:]' '[:lower:]' &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${inputfile}&amp;quot; &amp;gt; &amp;quot;${lowercase}&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="spell-all-the-letters-change-or-add-as-needed">spell all the letters (change or add as needed)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>spell=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
while IFS= read -n1 char; do
case &amp;quot;${char}&amp;quot; in
&amp;quot;a&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, alpha&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;b&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, bravo&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;c&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Charley&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;d&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, delta&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;e&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, echo&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;f&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, foxtrot&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;g&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, golf&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;h&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, hotel&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;i&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, India&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;j&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Juliet&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;k&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, kilo&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;l&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, leehma&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;m&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Mike&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, November&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;o&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Oscar&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;p&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, papa&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;q&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Quebec&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;r&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Romeo&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;s&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Sierra&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;t&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, tango&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;u&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, uniform&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;v&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Victor&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;w&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, whiskey&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, X-ray&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;y&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Yankee&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;z&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, Zulu&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, zero&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, one&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, two&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, three&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, four&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, five&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;6&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, six&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;7&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, seven&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, eight&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;9&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, nine&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}. period&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}. comma&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, equals&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}, slash&amp;quot; ;;
&amp;quot;?&amp;quot;) spell=&amp;quot;${spell}. questionmark&amp;quot; ;;
*) if [ -n &amp;quot;$spell&amp;quot; ]; then
echo &amp;quot;${spell:2}.&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;${tempfile}&amp;quot;;
spell=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
fi
;;
esac
done &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${lowercase}&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="take-the-tempfile-convert-it-to-spoken-text">Take the tempfile, convert it to spoken text.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>say -r 250 -v Alex -f ${tempfile} -o ${outputfile}&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="files-left-for-further-processing-if-you-like">Files left for further processing if you like.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>ls -l ${inputfile}*
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drobo FS Lion Time Machine Fix</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/01/07/drobo-fs-lion-time-machine-fix/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2012/01/07/drobo-fs-lion-time-machine-fix/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6xe7bIfj7VM">&lt;img src="drobo-bandaid.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Many Drobo FS owners out there who upgraded to Lion were unpleasantly surprised by the fact that their Drobo no longer behaved like they used to. After months, drobo released new firmware, but it didn't improve things all that much. With the new firmware, the Drobo FS:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * is slow or entirely unresponsive, Time Machine backups don't finish at all or take days
* doesn't show up in the Finder of Lion Macbook owners connecting through wifi
* has a transfer speed of 20MB/s, even when connecting through GB Ethernet, regardless of OSX version (tested with Snow Leopard, Lion)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you have one or more of the problems listed above, you will be pleased to hear that there is a &amp;quot;fix&amp;quot;, although it may not be what you were hoping for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- more -->The Good&lt;/strong>
Late 2010 I discovered drobo. Until then, I had always managed my storage space myself, transferring data to &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/09/07/a-bigger-timemachine-without-changing-history/">bigger disks&lt;/a> as time went on. The idea of a device which would automatically do that by just plugging in a new drive sounded like a real time saver. That, and the fact that it could handle a disk failure without data loss, and behave like network Time Machine share made me buy a Drobo FS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On December 19th 2010, I spent a whopping €615,- on a diskless Drobo, and threw another €300,- worth of 1TB disks in there, along with some old disks I had lying around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I moved all &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2010/12/30/move-time-machine-data-to-a-drobo/">backups to the Drobo&lt;/a>. Life would be good. Or so I thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Bad&lt;/strong>
The Drobo does what is called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thin_provisioning">&amp;quot;Thin Provisioning&amp;quot;&lt;/a>. This means that it will tell your computer that it is 16TB in size, although physically it isn't. This means that when you run out of physical storage space, you replace one of the drives with a bigger one and your computer wouldn't even notice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I created a Time Machine share on the drobo, I discovered that this was not entirely true. When you create a Time Machine share on the drobo, you must choose a size in order to keep Time Machine from filling up your drobo. But unlike other shares on the drobo, you can't change the size of the Time Machine share when you decide you need more room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got over it, chose large enough Time Machine shares for all my machines, and everything worked fine for a couple of months. Performance wasn't great, particularly mounting the sparse bundles took quite some time and a lot of disk access on the drobo, but hey. It's seamless automated backup to a redundant disk array so it was acceptable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip forward to July 20th, 2011. The release date of OSX 10.7, Lion. Because I wanted to make sure everything still worked in Lion, I waited until September 2011 before upgrading my Macbook. My other machines are too old and are still running Leopard (OSX 10.5) or Snow Leopard (OSX 10.6).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the reasons I had to wait until September was drobo. They didn't have their software ready for Lion, and drobo actually &lt;a href="http://halmueller.wordpress.com/2011/07/28/drobo-fs-problems-under-mac-os-x-lion/">tried to blame Apple for it&lt;/a>. Yes you read that right. The OSX Lion developer preview had been out since &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/apple-events/october-2010/">October 20, 2010&lt;/a> but somehow drobo didn't seem to have bothered to check compatibility all that time, and as a result effectively bricked all drobo's for Lion users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Ugly&lt;/strong>
After the storm had passed, and Drobo released a firmware upgrade, I switched to Lion on my Macbook after installing the new firmware on the Drobo FS. The Lion upgrade went very smooth and I happily played with Lion's new features. After a few hours, I noticed that the Drobo stopped working. No backups. Yikes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The drobo wasn't visibile when connecting over wifi and at first Lion was blamed for this problem. But my Mac Mini running Snow Leopard also started complaining about not being able to backup. I filed my first drobo support call at 09/18/2011 04:46 AM with the title &amp;quot;New Drobo FS firmware doesn't work with Snow Leopard TimeMachine&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was downhill from there. Drobo support had me throw away Time Machine shares (losing data), reset the whole drobo (losing ALL data on the drobo), install bleeding edge firmware which was not even available through the normal drobo dashboard, advised me to both up- AND downgrade the drobo and the dashboard, repeatedly closed my support calls without actually solving them, refused to answer to replies not coming from the first email address I used, had me send numerous diagnostic files to them, and told me &amp;quot;they were working on a new firmware&amp;quot; but never when it was scheduled for release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In less than 4 months, I exchanged more than 80 mails with Drobo Support, and the drobo had lost all my data 4 times. It had become more unreliable than any disk I had ever owned before. I was lucky to run backups-of-backups. The drobo may be able to handle drive failures, but the firmware developers and &lt;a href="http://www.stolensnapshots.com/dontdodrobo">drobo support people are a lot less worried about your data&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Fix&lt;/strong>
During these months, I struggled to keep my backups running. On December 13th 2011, I finally bit the bullet and fixed my drobo backup problems. If you want to fix your drobo Time Machine backup problems for once and for all, do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Connect to your drobo with an admin account, and using the Finder, copy all sparse bundles from all Time Machine shares to a location other than the drobo. Do the same for all other data you might have on there.
2. Go the the Apple store and [buy a Time Capsule](http://store.apple.com/us/product/MD032LL/A/Time-Capsule-2TB) (as a bonus, this also upgraded my wifi speed a great deal)
3. If you have just one machine you want to backup, plug it in and open Time Machine preferences on your Mac, and choose the Time Capsule as backup location. If you don't want to transfer your old backups, you're done.
4. For more technically inclined people, you can create encrypted and limited size sparse bundles for each of your machines on the TIme Capsule. Read [this article](http://michaelnozbe.com/mac-osx-lion-secure-backup-to-time-capsule-wi) by Michael &amp;quot;Nozbe&amp;quot; Sliwinski on how to do that. It works beautifully.
5. If you want to transfer the data in your old Time Machine sparse bundle from your drobo, you can use [this tip](http://www.unlikelywords.com/2009/01/05/moving-a-time-machine-backup-to-a-time-capsule/) to do that, but frankly I haven't tried that, I just created new, clean, backups.
6. Now go and sell your drobo to somebody who doesn't care about his data that much, or just wants a NAS for his Windows machine.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="time-capsule.jpeg" alt="">
The Time Capsule has run beautifully out of the box, doesn't have a butt-ugly dashboard like the drobo's, and is actually faster over wifi than the drobo is over GB ethernet. Go figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really hope that some day, somebody will create a drobo-like product which actually works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>P.S. If you like a challenge, you can actually already build a drobo-like fileshare with much higher performance at a lower cost by buying an HP proliant server, some disks, installing &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenIndiana">OpenIndiana&lt;/a> on it and run a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS">ZFS array&lt;/a>. A friend of mine has replaced his troublesome drobo with this setup and can reliably copy files to it at 120MB/s over GB ethernet, and swap out drives while he's doing that. Drobo isn't even close.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The rumors can stop now. iPad is here.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2010/01/27/the-rumors-can-stop-now-ipad-is-here/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png">&lt;img src="schermafbeelding-2010-01-27-om-21-18-02.png?w=119" alt="">
&lt;/a>So the word is finally out, it's going to be the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/">iPad&lt;/a>. I was kind of worried about this, and my worries are not completely taken away by the news currently oozing out of the Apple keynote. I see some problems with this device, although they are well hidden under Steve's reality distortion field, the Apple secret sauce and the &amp;quot;gee why didn't we think of that&amp;quot; features.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * The dock for the iPad is has me worried about mechanical failure. A large device resting on a small connector.
* Most people I know have a macbook and/or an iPhone. The iPad overlaps both the macbook and the iPhone in functionality, and it requires an extra data subscription. So they will probably hold out for a bit.
* Although the rest of the pad looks beautiful, the &amp;quot;home&amp;quot; button makes it into a big iPhone which I personally think is not a plus.
* The carriers will try to sell you the 3G models, subsidized. Don't go for that, buy the wifi instead, or try to get the wifi+3G sim-lock free. I'm glad Apple did not go for the carrier lock in construction on this one.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I admit, the video looks stunning. The UI is very polished (look at the pinch to peek in a stack of photo's), the device is nice and thin. Notice how the screen does not go all the way to the edge, so that you can put your thumb somewhere to hold it. And although it lacks a camera, it has all other iPhone features (yes, including GPS) so almost all iPhone apps will work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The additional $130 for the 3G option may be a bit steep, but the overall pricing is pretty good, almost competing with the netbooks, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/pricing/">starting at $499&lt;/a> at the 16GB wifi only model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Judging from the very young information right now, I understand that I may not be target audience for this advice. I need a keyboard and a large screen. But if you're in the (American) market for a netbook or something to browse a bit on the couch, have a look at &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/ipad-video/#medium">the video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rip and Convert FLAC, M4A, MP3, AAC files</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/14/rip-and-convert-flac-m4a-mp3-aac-files/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&lt;img src="afbeelding-8.png" alt="Max Audio Transcoder">
&lt;/a>I recently found an old harddisk which used to be in one of my old PC's. I discovered some &lt;a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">FLAC&lt;/a> files on there, which were rips of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOU8GIRUd_g">old CD's&lt;/a> I used to have. iTunes is not too happy with importing them into my library, and the original CD's are in a box in a deep dark corner of my garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I searched for a converter and found this wonderful converter which can just about convert any audio format out there. It's called &lt;a href="http://sbooth.org/Max">&amp;quot;Max&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, it's Open Source, free to use, and available as bundled OSX application. Brilliant! It does have a bunch of options, but as long as you go for the &amp;quot;MP4 Audio&amp;quot; output format, high quiality, 256 bits and VBR, you can't go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to their website &lt;em>&amp;quot;Max can generate audio in over 20 compressed and uncompressed formats including MP3, Ogg Vorbis, FLAC, AAC, Apple Lossless, Monkey's Audio, WavPack, Speex, AIFF, and WAVE&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy transcoding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choose: AFP or SMB</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/11/choose-afp-or-smb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 01:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/11/choose-afp-or-smb/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afp-or-smb.png">&lt;img src="afp-or-smb.png" alt="Choose AFP or SMB, not both.">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently upgraded the operating system on my trusty &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2006/09/20/tryout-mac-mini-as-fileserver/">Mac Mini G4 home fileserver&lt;/a> from Tiger to Leopard. In addition to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_Machine_%28Apple_software%29">out-of-the-box backup&lt;/a>, I no longer have to use &lt;a href="http://www.hornware.com/sharepoints/">SharePoints&lt;/a> to manage my network shares. In Leopard, I can just right-click them and arrange the sharing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In doing so, I decided to switch on both SMB and AFP sharing for all shares. The idea was that my Macs all would use AFP automatically, and all Windows machines would see the SMB mounts. After a few hours, iTunes began acting up on me, because it decided to switch between the SMB and AFP protocol (or so it seemed). Finder also seems to have some trouble listing network shares if the exact same name on the same server is shared with two different protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because there are people on my network with Windows machines, I decided to switch off the AFP protocol and only go with SMB. I haven't had problems since.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're sharing drives like I'm doing, go for SMB. It may not be the technically superior solution, but it will &amp;quot;just work&amp;quot;. You can easily switch to AFP when the world is freed of Windows machines. ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We are Free! Free, I tell you!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/07/we-are-free-free-i-tell-you/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">&lt;img src="afbeelding-21.png" alt="iTunes icon">
&lt;/a>Regular readers know that I've been ranting about the way  the music and movie industry are selling us crippled content, which actually feels like &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/01/25/opening-itunes-to-other-players/">punishing you&lt;/a> for honestly buying your digital content. Coincidentally, a month after that rant, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-gets-it/">Steve wrote a mail&lt;/a> to the music industry in which he stated that DRM clearly was not working, and we needed to approach things differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months later, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2007/04/03/apple-and-emi-follow-up/">Apple and EMI actually started&lt;/a> a new service in iTunes called iTunes plus, selling &lt;strong>256kbps DRM-free AAC files&lt;/strong>. If you've seen the latest &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=275834665">Macworld 2009 Keynote Address&lt;/a> by Philip (Phil) Schiller, you will have noticed that Apple hasn't been sitting still. At the end of this quarter, all songs in the iTunes store will be available as DRM-free iTunes plus version. And there's an easy button in iTunes which let's you upgrade all your DRM-ed music automatically (payed, ofcourse). The link is in the iTunes Quick Links box, top right. I tried it, works fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://my.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZPersonalizer.woa/wa/upgradeMyLibraryPage">&lt;img src="afbeelding-3.png" alt="Upgrade to iTunes Plus">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, your music will travel with you and play anywhere, just like those trusty CD's did. Even better: with your iPhone you're now able to buy music anywhere you are, because Apple has added 3G to the iTunes store on the iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nokia 6300 and Apple's iSync</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/nokia-6300-and-apples-isync/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 21:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/16/nokia-6300-and-apples-isync/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-2.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.thumbnail.png" alt="Nokia 6300 and iSync">
&lt;/a>Last week, my trusty &lt;a href="http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony_Ericsson_T610">Sony Ericsson T610 &lt;/a>became a bit awkward to use. The &amp;quot;down&amp;quot; function of the joystick finally gave up on me, after intermitting failures the past month. The only way to select the next menu item was to go &amp;quot;up&amp;quot; through all menu items. It became a pain to use, so I needed a new one.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->With so many phones on the market, the only right way for me to make a selection is to think about what I need in a phone. Last Thursday I sat down to write down the list:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * No &amp;quot;Joystick&amp;quot; as with the T910, it failed way to early and maybe that's because of the construction. The joystick sticks out, and gets a beating when the phone is at the bottom of a pile.
* Has to be absolutely compatible with [Apple's iSync](http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/isync/), I don't want to re-type my 107 contacts into a phone. (This practically only leaves Sony Ericcson and Nokia as contestants)
* Has to have bluetooth
* Has to be a &amp;quot;candybar&amp;quot; (no hinges or sliders which can break, answer a phonecall with the push of a button)
* Has to be simlock-free
* Can not be too expensive (200 euro's maximum, but under 100 is better)
* Can not be a Samsung because of their wierd menu structures and ugly UI design
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I went to tweakers.net, and used the pricewatch functionality to search for Sony Ericsson and Nokia phones, starting at 60 euro's and up, meeting the requirements from my list. This was a great excersise, it prevents you from buying a phone which in the top of the sponsored Google search.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I found this nice &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6300">Nokia 6300&lt;/a>, but the thing was, that it seemed not to be supported by iSync. I noticed some people had gotten it to work because it seems that only the model number is missing in the iSync plist files. The Nokia 6300 is a &amp;quot;40's series&amp;quot; firmware and perfectly compatible with iSync.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could have gotten a slightly cheaper model, but I selected the Nokia 6300 because it had another nice feature: it has a standard mini-USB plug, and a micro SD slot, which enables it to double as a memory-stick. Nice. That also means that I don't need extra software to move stuff onto or off of the phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The online price for a Simlock free Nokia 6300 is &lt;a href="http://www.2call.nl/telefoons_detail.php?ID=455">EUR 149,- including taxes&lt;/a>. I thought I'd save some time and went to a few local phoneshops. The only shop where I could get it simlock free was at the &amp;quot;T for telecom&amp;quot; shop, and they had the balls to charge EUR 280,- for it. So I ordered it online and waited patiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, I found a good Nokia 6300 site, which provides a &lt;a href="http://nokia6300.net/22/nokia-6300-isync-and-leopard">free Nokia 6300 iSync plugin &lt;/a>which allows the Nokia 6300 to sync with iSync. I installed it, and it works flawlessly. 20 minutes after the delivery guy rang the doorbell, my Nokia 6300 is paired with my Mac Mini, and all my contacts are on the phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nice tip: I also moved the &lt;a href="http://www.adiumxtras.com/index.php?a=xtras&amp;amp;xtra_id=602">&amp;quot;Tokyo Trainstation&amp;quot;&lt;/a> audio set for Adium onto the phone. These make for great unobtrusive ringtones. Normally my phone has no ringtone at all (vibrate only) but the vibrate function of the Nokia 6300 is a bit weaker than the Sony Ericsson T610.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. I also noticed that he shop I ordered my phone from has the &lt;a href="http://www.2call.nl/telefoons_detail.php?ID=628">simlock free iPhone&lt;/a> in stock, although a bit pricey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real guitar game: Guitar Wizzard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:35:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/01/10/real-guitar-game-guitar-wizzard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>No, I'm not a guitar player, but I noticed this cool post on TUAW where the &amp;quot;Guitar Hero&amp;quot; game has been taken a notch up. &lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2008/01/09/guitar-wizard-coming-for-mac/">TUAW reports&lt;/a> that the guys at &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com">www.musicwizard.com&lt;/a> have built &lt;a href="http://www.musicwizard.com/guitar_wizard/updates.php">&amp;quot;Guitar Wizzard&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, a game with which you can learn to play popular songs on a &lt;em>real guitar&lt;/em>. From what I can see in the video, this looks way less frustrating than doing the same excersizes over and over to learn to play the guitar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, you might not turn in to Mark Knopfler in a week, but isn't it a much better feeling to hold a real guitar in your hand, in stead of that plasticky, toy-like mini quitar with the bright colored buttons? And the price is about right for a game including hardware aswell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tangerine BPM Analyzer</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/10/22/tangerine-bpm-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 19:51:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/10/22/tangerine-bpm-analyzer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today I discovered &lt;a href="http://www.potionfactory.com/blog/2006/10/18/introducing-tangerine/">Tangerine&lt;/a>, a BPM (Beats Per Minute) analyzer for use with iTunes on a mac. I downloaded it, and it works as advertised. It scans your iTunes music library, and analyzes the BPM (and intensity of the pattern) of each track. It does this in the background, and on my Mac mini Core duo I can continue wih my normal programs while Tangerine analyzes the tracks. The BPM values get saved to your iTunes library, so they will also show up in iTunes if you have the BPM column visible there. The &amp;quot;Intensity&amp;quot; will not be visible in your normal iTunes lists.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->[![Tangerine Screenshot](o_afbeelding-1.thumbnail.jpg)
&lt;p>](o_afbeelding-1.jpg)Tangerine presents itself with a very iTunes like feel, showing your iTunes playlists on the left, and a track listing will eat the larger part of the top right side. Directly beneath the playlist and track list there is a space in which you can build your playlist. This is a new way of presenting a playlist, which I think is a very welcome way of editting playlists for &lt;a href="http://www.nike.com/nikeplus/">Nike+&lt;/a> owners (which I am not by the way). It shows the tracks played in &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronological">chronological&lt;/a> order, with a timeline at the top (numbers displayed are minutes, see screenshot). This will enable you to plan your workout, since you will know when that 160 BPM track will hit your ears. The only suggestion I have to the evelopers is to put the BPM of the added track below the image, so you can see where the BPM's are going in the playlist. And the &amp;quot;180&amp;quot; I see displayed in the top left makes no sense to me, maybe this needs polishing in the 1.0 version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me as a programmer, this saves me a lot of time finding my &amp;quot;getting in the zone&amp;quot; tracks. It will also prove to be a good tool while creating your iDVD movies or slideshows, helping you find that uptempo track for your great surfing shots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For some tracks Tangerine tends to miscalculate the BPM, resulting in values like &amp;quot;4&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;3491234&amp;quot; as BPM. Luckaly, the &amp;quot;intensity&amp;quot; value not only tells something about the contrast the bassdrum has with the rest of the music, but also on how sure Tangerine is about the accuracy of the BPMs. The higher the &amp;quot;intensity&amp;quot;, the more sure Tangerine is about it's BPM. Intensities of 60 and higher are pretty accurate most of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release of Tangerine (0.9.2) is a free beta, so start downloading now! The next release will probably cost a few dollars, I don't expect it to eat your yearly income. As with most Apple software I expect it to sell for between 10 and 30 euro's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>