<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/categories/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 22:09:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/categories/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Having fun at J-Fall 2011</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 22:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2011/11/03/having-fun-at-j-fall-2011/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2973-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2973-small.jpg?w=150" alt="J-Fall 2011">
&lt;/a>This year's Dutch Java Nerd event called &lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/">J-Fall&lt;/a> was held in Nijkerk, in a beautiful location called &lt;a href="http://www.regardz.nl/locaties/event-centers/regardz-hart-van-holland-nijkerk.aspx?gclid=CK7bg8zwmKwCFUMm3godUFpdPQ">&amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;&lt;/a> . With plenty of sessions by speakers from all over the world it promised to be a great day for Java enthusiasts, at a great location for meeting friends and colleagues. I took a day off from work and it was well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00024/">&lt;!-- more -->Opening by Bert Ertman&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Bert starts the day by welcoming the 1000+ attendees in the main presentation room in &amp;quot;Hart van Holland&amp;quot;. After explaining what the day is going to bring and where to find rooms, food, drinks, and company booths, he goes on to tell how they tried to get better network coverage. All these nerds with their smartphones in one single place is asking for trouble. It turns out it's too expensive to get good data network so they didn't do that. Network connections proved to be spotty at best in the main building, but I had good 3G coverage outside the main building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The organizer of &lt;a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Home">Devoxx&lt;/a> came by to say hi, and also told us that the J-Fall presentations are being professionally captured and the most popular ones are going to be online soon at &lt;a href="http://www.parleys.com/">parleys.com&lt;/a>. He closed off with the hilarious &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b-Cr0EWwaTk">&amp;quot;Java Life&amp;quot; Rap Music Video&lt;/a> . By the way if you liked that, you certainly will like the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2UFc1pr2yUU">&amp;quot;Whole foods Parking Lot&amp;quot; video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00025/">Java 7 Directors Cut&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
After the cool opening and videos the whole room was ready for some kick-ass sessions. Tomas Nilsson said that he would have a hard time topping the Java Life music video. And he did. Opening with a laughable slide containing a full page mandatory disclaimer text, the presentation was a terrible erratic drive through his very personal memory lane, and after 15 minutes he lost about 80% of the audience. I had absolutely no idea what point he was trying to make, and why nobody advised him to revise his presentation after he gave the same talk at JavaOne. The good thing was that because of the spotty network coverage, not all tweets during this presentation reached the twitter servers, and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23jfall">#jfall&lt;/a> was not trending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the small coffee break we gather around to see what sessions each of us want to join. Scanning the company booths in the main lobby learns that the world didn't change: Booths luring you with pens, mints, stickers, iPads and nice ladies in the booth who are almost always never representing the companies' people or culture. I did score some nice ball pens though :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00071/">Building Highly Scalable Java Applications on Windows Azure&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Microsoft being a big sponsor of this year's J-Fall, they have to have a keynote. And so they did. And it was a good one. Certainly after the below par presentation skills of Oracle, Microsoft has a nicely polished slides and a demo of Azure, a good story and good pace. During the demo the DNS switching is a bit slow and prevents some things to be shown. At the end of the talk, the speaker confidently retries and it now works. This results in a well-deserved warm applause from the audience. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/doortje123/status/131721454352998400">Well done Microsoft&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00050/">The Java EE7 Platform: Developing for the Cloud&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
With &amp;quot;Cloud&amp;quot; being the new buzzword nowadays, &lt;a href="http://www.java.net/blogs/arungupta/">Arun Gupta&lt;/a> did a keynote on where Java 7 is going, and how applications would fit in this cloud structure. I never heard the term &amp;quot;tenants&amp;quot; being used in this respect, which was interesting. The whole talk was a bit erratic, and after Java EE 6 fixing all the EJB gripes of EJB 3, I couldn't help but feeling that all these &amp;quot;enterprisey&amp;quot; terms are re-introduced in Java 7. The whole idea that you build an application but other people configure the actual building blocks that your application will be instantiated with, is a proven failure to me. Administrators don't have developer knowledge. Changing configuration of key components in your application will severely break it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I came out of this session not feeling to hot about Java 7 and the whole components-in-the cloud and people renting instances idea. Too many roles, academic, over engineered, very Sun Enterprise EJB 2 feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00066/">Don't call us - we'll push&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
A colleague advised be to go see &lt;a href="http://technology.amis.nl/blog/author/lucas">Lucas Jellema&lt;/a>. Lucas was the first speaker of the day who actually seemed to know what he was doing on stage. Although his slides were a bit crowded, he had a good story with many demos. It was a welcome change after Tomas and Arun, although Lucas didn't have any real new stuff. Polling, long-polls, asynchronus AJAX calls and the old request/response problem in http, and database triggers firing Java programs. Except for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket">Web Sockets&lt;/a> there was nothing new but nice to be reminded how these things actually work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Lucas' talk we went to get our complimentary lunch. Because we were relatively early, we had no problems getting the lunch package, and enjoyed our tasty sandwiches, milk, apples and Mars. Another free coffee and we're recharged and ready for the afternoon sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00053/">Migrating Spring to Java EE 6&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/paulb01">Paul Bakker&lt;/a> &lt;a href="img_2974-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2974-small.jpg?w=150" alt="">
&lt;/a>had clearly prepared his slides well, and insisted in giving his talk in English because it would be recorded. I thought this was a nice touch (in case you haven't noticed, I have this idea that everything you want to share with technical people should be in English). Paul explained the tactics to use when converting a Spring application to Java EE 6. Where to start, and how to keep your code compiling while doing the conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have worked on some large projects and although Paul mentions that some parts of the conversion will take a bit more time than others, I am not looking forward to convert my current 250+ thousand lines of code to Java EE 6 just yet. A plain Spring application may be easy, but as soon as you have Spring AOP, interesting Proxy beans and Custom Factory beans, you'd have to rewrite that code in Java EE6, which could take quite some time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I predict converting to Java EE 6 will be much more expensive than upgrading to the next version of Spring for most serious enterprise level applications. I have a home project I'd try to convert first, maybe more on that later on this blog, who knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00056/">Extreme performance with the Disruptor&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
Although the title and the talk description in the schedule didn't hint too much about it, this talk was 100% about Queues. After some high level talk about Producers, Consumers and Queues, &lt;a href="http://blog.dutchworks.nl/author/allard/">Allard Buijze&lt;/a> drops a bomb and introduces some circle and the name &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot;, without introduction. After a few slides everybody understands that this is some kind of &amp;quot;Circular Queue&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a bit of a laugh when Allard uses 4 slides to explain about dirty cache line reads at CPU level and how the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/disruptor/">Disruptor&lt;/a> prevents all that, which he then dismisses with &amp;quot;but that doesn't help much&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The talk was entertaining and what I got from it is that the main reason why the &amp;quot;Disruptor&amp;quot; works faster than regular Queues, is that Producers and Consumers can inform each other about their position in the queue, which prevents Queue polling. I can't help but think that this can be done with regular Queue implementations as well, so maybe I missed something here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.nljug.org/pages/events/content/jfall_2011/sessions/00058/">Java Tuning Puzzlers&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>
For the final session for today most of us decided to go to &amp;quot;Java Tuning Puzzlers&amp;quot;, because it looked like fun. And it was. The presentation by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/kjkoster">Kees Jan Koster&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/jpinpointcom">Jeroen Borgers&lt;/a> was fast, funny, interactive, hands-on and very refreshing. They showed some real-life performance problems they encountered in their work, and asked the audience to solve them. All Java nerds lit up and started shouting answers and funny remarks. Jeroen and particularly Kees Jan were very good in answering questions and snarky comments from the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the talk went into overtime and the organization was trying to cut it short, Jeroen and Kees Jan asked the audience &amp;quot;are we going to get beer, or are we going to finish this?&amp;quot;. The whole audience shouted &amp;quot;Finish it!&amp;quot; and we finished the last Puzzler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No fancy new frameworks, no buzzword bingo, just plain old dry-coding and a plug for one of my favorite tools, findbugs &lt;a href="http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/">http://findbugs.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a> . It was the best session I had all day, and I actually went back to Kees Jan and Jeroen to compliment them with their awesome talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>
I might sound a bit critical here and there, but I had a great day. Being amongst fellow-nerds, talking tech talk, sharing funny stories, listening to interesting new developments and hearing other people's views on things was really refreshing. Next thing on my list: Try to get Kees Jan Koster to do at least one big main-track keynote at J-Spring or J-Fall next year, about any subject. Because he will at least keep the audience awake.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks Bert and all of the NLJug people and sponsors who made this possible. See you all at J-Spring!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="img_2978-small.jpg">&lt;img src="img_2978-small.jpg" alt="Oracle J-Fall flowers">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bill's Mosquitoes</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/02/06/bills-mosquitoes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">&lt;img src="afbeelding-4.png" alt="Bill Gates Releases Musquitoes">
&lt;/a>Bill Gates found a very good way to get the news reporters to pay attention to the malaria problem. In his talk at the TED conference, he released a few mosquitoes, stating that malaria should not be just for poor people to experience. People who did not see the whole performance may react shocked, because when placed out of context it sounds like an outrageous thing to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that's the case, you should maybe &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/view/id/451">have a look at his talk&lt;/a>, available (for free, without registering) at TED.com. You'll see that the audience is actually laughing when he releases the mosquitoes, and at the end of the talk Bill gets a standing ovation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to the malaria problem, Bill also makes a very good case about how important good teachers are, and what we can do to help teachers become just that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remote Desktop Connection updated</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/25/remote-desktop-connection-updated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2009 01:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2009/01/25/remote-desktop-connection-updated/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.png" alt="Remote Desktop Connection icon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;Remote Desktop Connection.app&amp;quot; allows you to see the desktop of a remote Windows machine on your mac. This application will not update itself automatically, unless you have it installed as part of the Microsoft Office for Mac suite. If you've downloaded the 1.0.3 version you probably did not notice that &amp;quot;Remote Desktop Connection.app&amp;quot; was updated somewhere last year by microsoft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the latest version of Remote Desktop Connection on the &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/mac/products/remote-desktop/default.mspx">Microsoft Mactopia&lt;/a> site. Version 2 is an improvement over 1.0.3 (which I had). Notable differences are:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Nicer configuration screens, makes configuring your resolution and shares easier.
* Now a Universal Binary, which should improve performance on Intel Macs. I have not noticed improvement, but that's probably because the network is the bottleneck.
* Supports the new RDC 6.0 protocol used by Vista.
* Can do authentication of the remote machine (if it's a Vista machine).
* Your Mac printer can be exposed to the Windows machine so you can print documents on your local printer.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I played with it for a while, and apart form the new looks I can not say it's very different from the 1.0.x version. It could load my old RDC 1.0.3 configuration files. If you need to connect to a Windows desktop from your Mac, this does the job just fine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wiimote Whiteboard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:28:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/12/12/wiimote-whiteboard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/wiimote-whiteboard">&lt;img src="wiimotewhiteboard_128.png" alt="WiimoteWhiteboard">
&lt;/a>For people wanting to have an interactive whiteboard but don't have the money, &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/">Johnny Chung Lee&lt;/a> has found the solution. Using a Wiimote, he can track an infrared lightsource (like an LED) and use that to control the mousecursor. I tried some software on the Mac and the PC, and I actually got both to work without too much trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The infra-red pen&lt;/strong>
Please note that you need some kind of Infra-Red emitting device. In my first tests to see if the software works, I used a TV remote. This is a bit clunky, so next on my list is to build a simple infra-red pen this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I noticed a lot of people building infra-red pens by directly connecting an LED to a battery, which will possibly ruin your LED very quickly because there's too much current running through it. An LED is a diode, and it needs to be limited in current. The only right way to do it is follow &lt;a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/pen.jpg">Johnny's schematic&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the Mac:
I was amazed about how well this worked. I was expecting a lot of experimental stuff, but instead, this is all you have to do:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![](afbeelding-21.png?w=47)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](afbeelding-21.png)Download &lt;a href="http://www.uweschmidt.org/files/WiimoteWhiteboard.dmg">WiimoteWhiteboard for the Mac&lt;/a> by Uwe Schmidt.
2. Enable bluetooth on your mac.
3. Start the WiimoteWhiteboard.app
4. On the Wiimote, press buttons 1 and 2 simultaniously to put it in &amp;quot;detectable&amp;quot; mode. If the Wiimote was already on, you may need to press the red button in the battery compartment.
5. After pairing is complete, press the &amp;quot;calibrate&amp;quot; button and follow the instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did these steps on an intel  Mac mini and it worked beautifully. You can pair up to 2 Wiimotes to increase reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Whiteboard app on the PC:
This is slightly more work, but does not include steps which are strange to regular Windows users:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Download and install the [.Net framework version 3.5](http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=333325FD-AE52-4E35-B531-508D977D32A6&amp;amp;displaylang=en)
2. Download Boon Jin's [Smoothboard](http://www.boonjin.com/wp/2008/08/14/wiimote-smoothboard-045-beta) for Windows.
3. [![XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 1](clipboard02.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](clipboard02.png)Install the .Net framework, and unpack the smoothboard zipfile in a convenient location. It has no setup.exe (thank god)
4. In the system tray on your Windows, right-click the bluetooth icon, and choose &amp;quot;Add a Bluetooth Device&amp;quot;
5. Click the &amp;quot;My device is set up and ready to be connected&amp;quot; checkbox.
6. &lt;a href="clipboard03.png">&lt;img src="clipboard03.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 2">
&lt;/a>Press the red button of the Wiimote (in the battery compartement) to unpair it from anything else and get into &amp;quot;detecable&amp;quot; mode.
7. Click the &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; button in the Wizzard
8. Select the &amp;quot;Nintendo RVL-CNT-01&amp;quot; device and click &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;
9. &lt;a href="clipboard04.png">&lt;img src="clipboard04.png?w=124" alt="XP Bluetooth Wizard Screen 3">
&lt;/a>Select the &amp;quot;Don't use a passkey&amp;quot; radio button and DON'T press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot;.
10. Press the little red button on the Wiimote again, so that all blue lights start flashing, and then press &amp;quot;Next&amp;quot; on the wizard.
11. In the tray, you should now see popups saying &amp;quot;Found new hardware&amp;quot; and something like &amp;quot;New HID device&amp;quot;. They will dissapear after a while. If the popups did not show, start the whole process again from step 4.
12. Press &amp;quot;Finish&amp;quot; in the Wizard, notice that the Wiimote keeps flashing all the lights.
13. Start Smoothboard. The Wiimote should stop flashing, and you can click on the &amp;quot;Calibrate&amp;quot; button to start the fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="clipboard05.png">&lt;img src="clipboard05.png?w=33" alt="Smoothboard Screenshot">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've tested the Windows setup on a Dell 530 laptop with the built-in bluetooth device, and it works fine, although I did have to reboot once because the bluetooth stack got confused and refused to detect my Wiimote. Smoothboard also allows you to pair 2 Wiimotes to improve reliability. It also has many features which are tailored to controling Powerpoint and other software, but I haven't tried that yet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Censorship: here to stay</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/12/free-information-guess-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 06:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/12/free-information-guess-again/</guid><description>
&lt;p>For those of you who think that media and information are free and uncontroled, guess again. Lately I have been seeing more and more incidents of large corporations hiding information, and even telling other people to hide it for them. I think this is plain wrong, and the guys involved should have been fired or punished otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have information which is of interest to the public, and somebody is making you sign a paper with which he can force you to shut up, you should think twice (and then not do it). Not because of the money, not because of the information itself, but for the sheer principle. Information should not be controled in that way. By anyone. It is dangerous.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Examples:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Blackhat Conference 2005: **Cisco** orders [tearing Michael Lynn's slides](http://cachefly.oreilly.com/make/cisco.mov) on leaks in Cisco's IOS out of the handouts.
* June 2006: **Microsoft** is [censoring Chinese blogs](http://www.wired.com/culture/lifestyle/news/2005/06/67842)
* July 2007: **India** is [censoring certain blogs](http://in.rediff.com/news/2006/jul/17blog.htm)
* Blackhat Conference 2007: Thomas Dullien (known as Halvar Flake), [was denied access](http://addxorrol.blogspot.com/2007/07/ive-been-denied-entry-to-us-essentially.html) to the **US** because he carried his presentation and some slides with him.
* Blackhat Conference 2007: **HID Global** [prevents Chris Paget to do a presentation](http://www.securityfocus.com/news/11444/1) on the [security flaws in RFID](http://www.theregister.co.uk/2008/04/08/e_passports_fingerprinted/)
* Blackhat Conference 2008: **Apple** [prevents Charles Edge](http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1616) from doing a presentation on a zero-day exploit in Apple's filevault by having him sign a non-disclosure agreement.
* 2008: The search results in [China are still censored](http://effortlessenglishclub.blogspot.com/2007/11/microsoft-censorship-lessons.html) by **Microsoft**, **Yahoo** and **Google**.
* 2008: India and China are not the only ones, judging [this wikipedia page](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_censorship)...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>When do these people realize that witholding information is only postponing the inevitable fact that people are going to hear about the stuff they are trying to hide? Are they really thinking that people all over the world, connected in all kinds of different ways, aren't going to notice what you are doing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse, they are doing a pretty darn good job so far, but it will break down eventually. Small are the minds of people who fear free flow of information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laptop Stolen? See who did it...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/04/laptop-stolen-see-who-did-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/08/04/laptop-stolen-see-who-did-it/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In this strange world, people can't seem to leave your stuff alone. All the electronic gadgets of today are too attractive to the lowlife of this world. So what do you do if somebody swipes your laptop? You take a few pictures of him, and trace his IP address!&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->This kind of software has been around for a while, and a few companies have made good money of of it. The closed source solutions are also feeding information to those companies when you don't want it to, and you're also not sure what information is send to the company.
&lt;p>There is now a solution for the more paranoid geeks amongst us. It's called &lt;a href="http://adeona.cs.washington.edu/index.html">&amp;quot;Adeona&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, and it is the first Open Source system for tracking the location of your lost or stolen laptop. The software does not rely on a proprietary and/or central service, and is entirely free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What's also nice is that only the owner (that's you) can access the machine should you want to trace it. If you don't trust me, and don't trust Adeona, you can always check the sourcecode yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A laptop is the most logical target of the casual thief, so it makes sence to install it on there. A casual thief is usually not tech savvy, so before he discoveres that Adeona (or any other similar program) you will have usually traced him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burglars also tend to take your desktop machine, so you might aswel install Adeona on there, too. And since Adeona comes as an OSX, Linux and Windows program, most of the computers out there will be covered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I only wish that I could live in a world where people could appreciate other people's toys without touching or stealing them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrate from Windows to OSX</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/18/migrate-from-windows-to-osx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 19:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/18/migrate-from-windows-to-osx/</guid><description>
&lt;p>My wife got tired of her Windows/Compaq laptop. So 2 weeks ago, she decides to go out and buy a &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macbookpro/">15&amp;quot; macbook pro&lt;/a> (an excelent choice I might add). She was a bit worried about getting used to the new machine, but decided to take the risk. After no more than 3 days, with surprisingly little help, she figured out how to do everything she did on the Windows machine, and even installed her own software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last thing to do was to migrate all the stuff from her old Windows machine to her new &amp;quot;lappie&amp;quot; (yes, she actually gave this one a nickname :-) ). Although Microsoft tries hard to keep Outlook Express users &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vendor_lock-in">locked in&lt;/a>, I did find a tool that solved the problem completely for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->**Bookmarks**
&lt;p>&lt;a href="menubarcheck.jpg">&lt;img src="menubarcheck.jpg?w=77" alt="Turn on IE7 Menu Bar">
&lt;/a>This is an easy thing to do. Most browsers can export their bookmarks easily, and Safari can import them easily. There was one little thing that took some time figuring out: IE7 hides your menu bar, which prevents you from finding the &amp;quot;File -&amp;gt; Export Bookmarks...&amp;quot; option. You can turn the menubar back on by clicking on the &amp;quot;Tools&amp;quot; menu, and selecting &amp;quot;Menu bar&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that you've got the &amp;quot;File&amp;quot; menu in Internet Explorer, I think you can figure out the rest for yourselves. Import the resulting HTML into Safari by using the &amp;quot;Archive -&amp;gt; Import Bookmarks...&amp;quot; option and you're done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Outlook Express export
**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="outlook-mappen.png">&lt;img src="outlook-mappen.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Outlook Express is a bit trickier. First, you need to find your mailbox files. Normally, finding files is not a big problem, but Microsoft has crippled the &amp;quot;Search&amp;quot; functionality in Explorer to such a degree that you can't actually find your mailbox files with it. So, Choose &amp;quot;Start -&amp;gt; Run...&amp;quot; and type in &amp;quot;cmd&amp;quot;. The black box you'll see is a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmEvPZUdAVI">DOS Prompt&lt;/a>. Open your Outlook express and take a look at the names of your mailbox Folders. On yor filesystem, there are &amp;quot;dbx&amp;quot; files which correspond with these. For the example on the right, we can find all dbx files with the following commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#999999;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;C:\Documents and Settings\YourLoginName&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;cd \
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#999999;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;C:\&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;dir /s /b *.dbx
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>You'll get a list of complete filenames (drive, directory and filename) of the Outlook Express dbx files found on your system. Close Outlook Express, find the corresponding files and copy them into a temporary folder for convenience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we've got the dbx files containing all the mail, we need to convert those into a format which can be read by Mail.app. To do that, download &lt;a href="http://freenet-homepage.de/ukrebs/english/dbxconv.html">DbxConv&lt;/a> and unzip it in the same temporary folder you just created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go back to your DOS Prompt, go into the directory where your dbx files and DbxConv are, and use the following command to convert everything into &lt;a href="http://www.qmail.org/man/man5/mbox.html">mbox files&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#999999;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;C:\temp\&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;DbxConv *.dbx
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Take the resulting mbox files and put them on your new Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mail.app import&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="afbeelding-11.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-11.png" alt="">
&lt;/a>Open &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/mail.html">Mail.app&lt;/a> and configure it without worrying about it getting your mail or creating mailboxes. All done? Good. Select &amp;quot;Archive -&amp;gt; Import Mailbox...&amp;quot; from the menu at the top of your screen. Select the &amp;quot;mbox&amp;quot; format, and then select all the mbox files you've just put on your Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mail.app will import all the mailboxes, and place them in a folder called &amp;quot;Imported Mailboxes&amp;quot;. In this folder, you'll find additional Folders, one per mbox file. All your mail will be in those folders, including the correct dates, attachments and even read/unread information. Drag the mails to any Folder you like, for instance the &amp;quot;Inbox&amp;quot; folder contents can be dragged to... you guessed it, your Mail.app &amp;quot;Inbox&amp;quot;. It will merge perfectly, like you've always been using Mail.app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>MSN and GoogleTalk&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're a GoogleTalk user, you can get away with &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/ichat.html">iChat&lt;/a> , the built-in chat client in Leopard. Just &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/talk/bin/answer.py?answer=24076">set it up&lt;/a> to use the google server and youre good to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're an MSN user, you can try &lt;a href="http://www.amsn-project.net/download.php">aMSN&lt;/a>, which should look very familiar to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you use both GoogleTalk and MSN, and possibly other chat clients, your best bet is to go with &lt;a href="http://www.adiumx.com/">Adium&lt;/a>. Adium is the chat client of my choice, but it can not do audio or video, so be warned (to me this is a big plus by the way :-) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Make a Disk Image&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to migrating your mail and bookmarks, you need to move your data to your new machine, too. There's always a chance that you forget to move stuff. So keep your old PC for another month or so, or even better: Make a &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/06/06/clone-windows-hd-on-apple-osx-machine/">disk image&lt;/a> from the harddisk. You can now safely trash your PC (&lt;a href="http://dban.sourceforge.net/">wipe that harddisk first&lt;/a>) without having to worry about lost data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do yourself another favour: Buy a 500GB (or bigger) harddisk, and reserve it for backups only. Hook it up to your new Mac and you'll be automagically introduced to Apple's excelent zero-setup, zero-fuss &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/timemachine.html">TimeMachine&lt;/a>. You'll be very happy, &lt;a href="http://rolfje.wordpress.com/2008/02/21/time-machine-to-the-rescue/">trust me&lt;/a>. Or &lt;a href="http://blog.bernardkowalski.com/?p=3">trust others&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun with your new computer!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clone Windows HD on Apple OSX machine</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/06/clone-windows-hd-on-apple-osx-machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 21:07:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/06/06/clone-windows-hd-on-apple-osx-machine/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last week, lightning struck at my parents apartment building (literaly). Other damages aside, my dad's PC also died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guy at the PC repair shop warned my dad that &lt;em>&amp;quot;we may need to wipe the HD, do you have a backup&amp;quot;?&lt;/em> Ofcourse, all data was backed up daily and &amp;quot;off-site&amp;quot; at my house so all important data was safe. But just in case, we wanted to make an exact disk image of the drive, so that we could easily restore it when the PC returns from the store&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->I wanted to have a future proof process, run on a Mac, something as follows:
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. Make an image file of the complete source harddisk including all partitions (in our case there were 3 NTFS partitions on the disk). The image file includes any boot records or loaders if they exist, and is an Apple DMG file so it can be mounted on OSX.
2. Store the image file on a server disk (so it in turn gets backed up)
3. When there's trouble, we now have 2 options, which are
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>a) mount the image and restore 1 or 2 important files
b) write/restore the image to a new disk&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we bought a second 500GB drive to play around with, and try the restores on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the Mac Disk Utility, I made an &amp;quot;MBR&amp;quot; disk image of a drive. Mounting this image gave me the access to all 3 NTFS partitions and data on them. However, for some strange reason, Disk Utility could not restore it's own disk image to the drive,  because it does not allow me to drag the target disk into the target disk field (use google to find more people having this problem). Mucking around with the command line tool &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dd_(Unix)">&amp;quot;dd&amp;quot;&lt;/a>, I actually managed to restore the DMG back onto a physical drive, but for some reason, the primary partition was damaged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digging around on the internet, I found that the following method may be the only reliable way to do this and meet all my requirements. It's relatively simple, although it does take a trip to the command line (which is really not very Apple like).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Backup the DRIVE, not a PARTITION&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What Apple calls a &amp;quot;drive&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;disk&amp;quot; is actually often just a partition on a physical disk. A physical disk can have multiple partitions, which appear as multiple &amp;quot;disks&amp;quot; in the Finder or Disk Utility. Because we want to make an image of the physical disk, we need to find out where that disk is. In the Terminal, use to following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>diskutil list
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>You'll get a list of all the physical drives, and the partitions which are on there. For example, our testdisk shows up as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>/dev/disk3
   #:                   TYPE NAME      SIZE     IDENTIFIER
   0: FDisk_partition_scheme          *465.8 Gi disk3
   1:             DOS_FAT_32 TESTDISK 465.8 Gi disk3s1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The physical disk is known to the system as /dev/disk3, and the first (and only) pastition on there is a FAT32 partition, and the name of the partition is TESTDISK. To make a DMG of the complete disk with all it's partitions, the following command is enough:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>dd if=/dev/disk3 of=/Users/rolf/MyCompleteDisk100GB.dmg
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The command will take a (long, long) while to complete. I've read some posts where people were waiting for days for dd to complete their image. There's also no progress bar. Terrible, but for now I can't help you with this without getting into rediculous trickery as found on some &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_b1cyNigny8">l33tsp34k&lt;/a> hippie h4xor blogs out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fun thing about this trick is, that OSX is able to mount that DMG file. You just double-click it, and &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.boomcounter.org/">boom&lt;/a>&amp;quot;. There are your partitions. A big problem is that these images are uncompressed. So you'll need 500GB free space to backup a 500GB drive. That's not funny. You can circumvent that by having the data zipped before writing it to disk but that means you'll not be able to mount it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing it in compressed form (which is even slower) can be done like so:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>dd if=/dev/disk3 | gzip -9 &amp;gt; /Users/rolf/MyCompleteDisk100GB.dmg.gz
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Restore the DRIVE (not the partition)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To restore a dmg onto a physical disk, get a disk which is at least the size as the original disk. Having the original disk's size in the filename like in the example above helps you to remember that in a few months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After checking which disk you need to write to with the diskutil (as shown abve), restoring an uncompressed disk image merely requires you to swap input and output parameters, like so:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>dd if=/Users/rolf/MyCompleteDisk100GB.dmg of=/dev/disk3
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Please note that this works because in my case I haven't rebooted or reconnected drives, so the drive I need to write to is still /dev/disk3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you did the gzip compression trick mentioned above, you need to get a bit more fancy:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>cat /Users/rolf/MyCompleteDisk100GB.dmg.gz | gzip -d | dd of=/dev/disk3
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Although all of this works, I hope that somebody, somewhere can show me a simple, clean, OSX native, GIU based solution to this, meeting the 3 requirements in this article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Difference between Windows and OSX</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/27/difference-between-windows-and-osx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 04:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/05/27/difference-between-windows-and-osx/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Another great example showing the differences between OSX and Windows. Bot applications synchronize your phone over bluetooth. Both applications are simple to use, but one is simpler. And contrary to expectations, this time the Windows version (left) will cost you money, and the OSX version (right) is free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="sync.gif">&lt;img src="sync.gif" alt="">
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="afbeelding-2.png">&lt;img src="afbeelding-2.png?w=128" alt="">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although you'd expect the Windows version to do more with all these bells and wistles on the screen, but it's actually &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISync">iSync&lt;/a> that also synchronizes the calendar to my phone, and back. Automatically. No configuration needed, it does what is considered logical to the sensible mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple and OSX are just like a &lt;a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Image:Volkswagen_New_Beetle_Germany.jpg">Volkswagen New Beetle&lt;/a>. Either you like it, or you don't. But either way, it's good that it's here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>For the record: I don't like the Volkswagen New Beetle, and I do like OSX. My Mac Mini is absolutely by far the best computer I have bought in the past 5 years, maybe even the best computer I've bought ever. No kidding.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DOCTYPE is a myth...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/25/doctype-is-a-myth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 22:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2008/03/25/doctype-is-a-myth/</guid><description>
&lt;p>... and other wisdom from Joel. Finally, after weeks of slightly boring posts about travel, speeches and FogBugz, Joel has an article on his blog he was so famous for: &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2008/03/17.html">Martian Headsets&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article discusses the problems with the HTML spec, and numerous other problems developers are facing these days. That, and the Martians' strange fascination for all kinds and shades of red.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At times, the article remembered me of some thoughts I have during my dayjob:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * Minimize. (also known as the [KISS](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle) principle)
* Have a contract early in the process. Make it testable. Find a way to handle problems in the contract.
* Be strict and transparent. Fail early and explain.
* Using a standard and conforming to it are two different things.
* Communicate.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Although all are true to some degree, they aren't going to solve all problems, because everybody has their own set of thoughts and rules. For every problem there is a nice, clean, simple, cheap, wrong answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now go read the &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2008/03/17.html">article&lt;/a>, it's much better than my writing...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If Gmail Had Been Designed by Microsoft?</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/22/what-if-gmail-had-been-designed-by-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 20:53:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/22/what-if-gmail-had-been-designed-by-microsoft/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Philipp Lenssen from the Google Blogoscoped blog does some iterations on the Google Mail userinterface while he investigates the question &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://blogoscoped.com/archive/2007-11-20-n35.html">What If Gmail Had Been Designed by Microsoft?&lt;/a>&amp;quot;. He ends up with a userinterface which is very much like the hotmail I knew before I replaced it with my current gmail account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have fun reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>p.s. Did you notice that the gmail space has increased to around 5GB lately? Google continues to amaze (frighten?) me at how much data they can store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clonezilla: m4d Sk!lZ</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/06/clonezilla-m4d-sklz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 00:09:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/11/06/clonezilla-m4d-sklz/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A few weeks ago, my Dad and my Brother both bought identical Windows Vista machines, at the same shop, at the same time. Although the hardware specs of these computers were terrific, the performance of Windows Vista was &amp;quot;moderate&amp;quot; to say the least. An even bigger problem was that some of the older XP programs my dad had been using did no longer work on the shiny new Vista machine. The shiny 3D effects had to go in favour of something that &amp;quot;just worked&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Having just spent a lot of cash on these now paperweights, a new Apple was not an option (hey, I tried). So my dad bought a Windows XP install CD and started installing on his machine. The shiny new hardware was so new, that the XP divers were hard to find, if they existed at all. After 2 weeks of fiddling with drivers, the machine was "up and limping". The display was at a nice resolution, and it could produce a sort of audio, and the prio 1 software packages were installed and working (mainly some simple calendar and assembly-development tools).
&lt;p>My brother also was fed up with Vista, and asked if we could mirror the harddisk in my dad's machine to his machine. I figured that this should be no problem, since the machines were exactly identical. Because of earlier problems with Norton Ghost and SATA drives, I decided to give Clonezilla a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please note that I am NOT linking to the Clonezilla site in this article, which is for your own good. Why? I will tell you why! For people who are so smart that they can read partition tables before morning coffee, understand 32 different partition types, and can do on-the-fly custom compression of a datastream to an USB disk, they shure have never heard of &amp;quot;user experience&amp;quot;. There is absolutely no way that normal people are ever getting this thing to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>...You may take a pause here to reflect on that if you like...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When booting the Clonezilla CD, it shows you what it's doing my scrolling text accross your screen at a speed at which you need bionical implants to be able to follow. I did manage to catch a few lines, and I must not be smart enough because I don't know what &amp;quot;Loading NVIDIA Video Driver&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Setting System Clock&amp;quot; have to do with reading bits from a disk and writing them to another disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="1.png">&lt;img src="1.thumbnail.png" alt="Clonezilla splash screen">
&lt;/a>After the frantic scrolling is done, you are presented with an ever so nice menu screen, designed by a colorblind handicapped rhinoceros with a Sinus problem. The first time I looked at this sceen I waited for a menu option to get highlighted, and before I realized that the light pink bar was the highlighted menu item, it started booting by itself. Yes, if you do nothing, it does &amp;quot;something&amp;quot; but since you're not sure what, you have to reboot and start over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other fun part of this menu screen is that it gives you no less than 8 options to boot your system, 4 of which are Clonezilla. There's even an option which contains the word &amp;quot;framebuffer&amp;quot;, which is a video card thing and again has absolutely no other purpose than to confuse you. Framebuffers have nothing to do with (re)storing disk partitions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="2.png">&lt;img src="2.thumbnail.png" alt="Clonezilla language options">
&lt;/a>After having made the right choice (I took a wild guess) you are presented with another nice screen. The design of this screen is from a whole different erra, almost van-Gogh-esque. All the video drivers which were loaded during the &amp;quot;frantic scrolling&amp;quot; fase earlier are clearly working together on this screen to present you the nicest resolution and the clearest colors, so that you can peruse the long list of language options available to perfectly support you during the following screens. At the bottom of the menu are two aptly named &lt;ok> and &lt;cancel> buttons, start over if you didn't use the correct one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="3.png">&lt;img src="3.thumbnail.png" alt="Keymap menu">
&lt;/a>Now that the Clonezilla is running in the language of your choice (which is very likely not to be traditional Chinese), you'd expect to enter the realm of disk options. Not so. Take out your &amp;quot;Linux Unleashed&amp;quot; books class, because we're presented with... nobody? no? The keymap option! Yes, that's right. No program can start without asking what keymap it should use. Turn to page 346 of the &amp;quot;Advanced&amp;quot; section to find out what keymap the &amp;quot;Kernel keymap&amp;quot; is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading the instructions 3 times you learn that you can just hit &amp;quot;enter&amp;quot; on this screen, just like you did on the silly language options menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="4.png">&lt;img src="4.thumbnail.png" alt="Start Clonezilla?">
&lt;/a>Off to cloning, right? Wrong. Clonezilla will ask you if you'd want to start Clonezilla, or just enter the prompt. Exactly the one credible extra option on the first &amp;quot;designer&amp;quot; screen is presented after 3 menus. And no, we don't want a prompt, so it's not a good option here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'll spare you the rest of the menus. There are just way too much, containing anything ranging from spelling and grammar errors, to cryptic messages and listing command line options to tools you've never heard of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay one more small example: In stead of using the screen real-estate and the nice fonts to indicate what disks are in the system and what partitions are on there, it just lists &amp;quot;sda1, sda2, sda5, sde1&amp;quot; and their formats. When you are a windows user, and are backing up or restoring your precious data, you are likely to stop here. How do you know for sure that you're reading from and writing to the right disk?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If Clonezilla was made for people, I would have expected a list according to these lines:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Harddisk 1 (320GB Seagate, SATA)
Partition 1 (120GB, FAT32, Volume label &amp;quot;My Windows&amp;quot;)
Partition 2 (100GB, NTFS, Volume label &amp;quot;My Data&amp;quot;)
Partition 3 (100GB, NTFS, Volume label &amp;quot;My Music&amp;quot;)
Harddisk 2 (500GB Iomega, USB)
Partition 1 (500GB, FAT32, Volume label &amp;quot;Backupdisk&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Anyway, struggling through the menu's, reading through command line options and Googling for manual pages on the used commands I eventually got Clonezilla to make a backup of the entire disk of my Dad's XP installation. The disk image was stored on a large harddrive, and we took it to my brother's machine to restore it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before restoring the XP disk image, we made another disk image, from the original Vista installation on my brothers machine. Should something happen, we would have an option to restore the machine to it's prestine state.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We restored the XP image on my brothers Vista machine (which was, like I said, an exactly identical machine). And you guessed it: it failed. We tried playing with the MBR and Grub options, and every try we neede to wait the full 20 minutes only to find out that the restore did not work. We even tried restoring the partition tables and/or MBR's using the Windows XP installation disk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After 6 frustrating hours on Saturday, and another 3 gruelling hours today, we gave up. Clonezilla is now restoring Vista to my brother's computer, and I sure hope that will work, but wether it does or doesn't, it leaves him with a useless computer. Either way we're destined to use &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leet">&amp;quot;m4d sk!lz&amp;quot;&lt;/a> to get it running normally again, just like we need &amp;quot;m4d sk!lz&amp;quot; to be able to use Clonezilla.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Sidenote to Linux developers: Just because you know a lot about Linux or any freaking back-from-the-60's command line tool there is out there, doesn't mean you can expect others to have that same knowledge. As long as Linux fanboys are creating these crappy user interfaces, Linux is not going to stand up against Microsoft or Apple on the desktop. Ever. And creating &amp;quot;Yet Another Window Manager&amp;quot; will also not help. Period. Together you stand, &lt;a href="http://apcmag.com/6735/interview_con_kolivas">devided you'll fall&lt;/a>. So far, devision by childish stubborn ego flamewars is where every non-commercial Linux project has ended.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next option for my brother and dad is to buy Norton Ghost 12, and hope that the people at Norton understand how to make a user interface, and working software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the arrival of Vista, Windows more and more turning into a Tamagochi, where you are spending more time maintaining the system, than working &lt;em>with&lt;/em> the system. I'm glad I dumped Windows a long time ago. For those who are thinking of switching: I can promise you that Switching from XP to Vista will give you &lt;a href="http://apcmag.com/6649/vista_150_problems_0_solutions">more problems&lt;/a> than &lt;a href="http://www.utilware.com/switching.html">switching from XP to Mac&lt;/a>. And once you go Mac...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It can be done on Windows, too!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/09/11/it-can-be-done-on-windows-too/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/09/11/it-can-be-done-on-windows-too/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you've ever had the &amp;quot;pleasure&amp;quot; of configuring and sharing a printer between Windows machines, you probably know how tedious it is to get one machine to send a print job to the printer connected to another machine. And don't even get me started on how to do that on a Linux machine, or any mix of these two systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Ever since I migrated from Windows to Mac, I had been avoiding the printer sharing thing. The Ethernet printerserver I bought in my PC days only came with Windows bloatware, so that was a no-go. The Epson Stylus 915 worked nicely, connected with USB to my Mac Mini, so I had no need to solve that problem. My wife however still has a Windows laptop, and every now and then she would send me documents by mail which I then would print for her. Not ideal, but it saved me the stress and trouble of struggling with Windows to get it to talk to a Mac printer.
&lt;p>Today I discovered that I had it all wrong. Apple makes this wonderful little (2MB) piece of software called &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/support/downloads/bonjourforwindows.html">Bonjour for Windows&lt;/a> which solved the whole printer sharing thing I had been putting off in about 6 mouseclicks! Share the printer on the Mac (about 2 clicks), download and install Bonjour on the Windows (about 2 clicks), and run the Printer wizzard that shows up (also 2 clicks). I had a Windows Testpage rolling out the printer before I knew it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What a good friend pointed out on the phone was something I hadn't realized: &lt;em>&amp;quot;See, you can actually make good software running on Windows, and it doesn't have to come on 4 DVD's. It's just that they don't care&amp;quot;&lt;/em>. Well, Apple does care, and they did a brilliant job at it. Small package, simple interface, no fuss, just works, and is good looking too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm very happy I did this, and in fact I'm going to print another testpage, just for the fun of it. On my Apple I am used to be able to edit video, audio, photo's and all at the same time. On Windows I'm glad I can print a testpage. See the difference? (for insiders: at work I'm glad to be able to receive a phonecall ;-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disable Windows Native Zip support</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/09/11/disable-windows-native-zip-support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 06:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/09/11/disable-windows-native-zip-support/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you have large or many zipfiles in a folder, windows seems to lock up when opening the folder containing the zipfiles. This is because Windows is &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; and decides to pre-scan the zipfiles and display them as folders. Installing free zip tools like &lt;a href="http://www.zipgenius.it/eng/index.php">zipgenius&lt;/a> will not change this behaviour, although you would expect that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To unregister the Windows zipfile support service, use the following command (Start -&amp;gt; Run...):
regsvr32 /u zipfldr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable the Windows zipfile support again (I can't imagine why), use the command:
regsvr32 zipfldr&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source of this brilliant tip is &lt;a href="http://blog.pengoworks.com/blogger/index.cfm?action=blog:530">dans blog&lt;/a>, which I found after some googling ofcourse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disabling the Windows Clipboard</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/17/disabling-the-windows-clipboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 21:12:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/04/17/disabling-the-windows-clipboard/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When copy-pasting in Windows, sometimes the clipboard bar appears, and if you're really &amp;quot;lucky&amp;quot;, it also pops up a waring, distracting you from your work. The clipboard holds only 12 items, and I have never met anyone who used more than one. There is no way to turn this irritating feature off, unless you want to use the dreaded registry editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feeling brave? Follow the instructions at &lt;a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/207438">http://support.microsoft.com/kb/207438&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The truth about Switching To Mac</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/28/the-truth-about-switching-to-mac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 21:22:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2007/02/28/the-truth-about-switching-to-mac/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thinking about switching to a Mac? I'd say go for it, but read &lt;a href="http://utilware.com/switching.html">this article&lt;/a> first. It really sums it all up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X for Vista...</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/12/17/x-for-vista/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2006 15:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/12/17/x-for-vista/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hi, do you also think Windows Vista gets too much credit for stealing Apple's Mac OSX, a.k.a. Tiger? Here's a &lt;a href="http://video.on.nytimes.com/ifr_main.jsp?nsid=a718aabc2:10f910eed23:52c4&amp;amp;rf=bm&amp;amp;fr_story=d14603c1e23e6ce37920a8134a2e27b1405a4991&amp;amp;st=1166372773007&amp;amp;mp=FLV&amp;amp;cpf=false&amp;amp;fvn=8&amp;amp;fr=121706_112553_718aabc2x10f910eed23x52c5&amp;amp;rdm=749375.7441141073">funny little movie&lt;/a> on nytimes.com with proof that Windows is &amp;quot;not&amp;quot; an OSX ripoff. Very funny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ati SUCKS! Windows SUCKS!</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/11/26/ati-sucks-windows-sucks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 19:42:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/2006/11/26/ati-sucks-windows-sucks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Just to share some frustration with you guys, I just spent 4 hours trying to update the Ati video drivers for my Mobility Radeon 9200 video card in my laptop from version 6.14 to 6.5. And all this just because Second Life crashes on my laptop every 3 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ati installer just crashes because there is already an old version of the driver on the system. Any normal manufacturer would be able to upgrade the driver, no? No. This is a windows system, and even with the slightest sign of problenms, you end up digging forums where people have found how to edit the registry to get things done. And then it will still not work. Windows is so full of crap, I even found a driver cleaner tool. And no, that also did not work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can not wait to replace my shoddy PC laptop with an iBook or macbook pro. Mind you, this is an Acer Ferrari 3000 laptop I'm typing this on, which should be a decent laptop. But the Windows way just screws it all up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every 10 hours of PC, I spend 2 to 4 fixing problems or upgrading drivers. Every 10 hours of Mac, I spend 0 hours updating drivers and 0 hours fixing things. I see an easy winner here in the productivity departement....&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>