<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>photography on www.rolfje.com</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/photography/</link><description>Recent content in photography on www.rolfje.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © rolfje.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:34:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing Photo Creation Dates</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 22:34:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2011/08/15/fixing-photo-creation-dates/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.perpetualkid.com/beach-vacation-countdown-timer.aspx">&lt;img src="timr-1003.jpeg" alt="Count down to your vacation">
&lt;/a>You know how it is on vacation. You take your camera, shoot pictures, and when you get home you see that you forgot to set the date/time on your camera. Even worse: your wife also took a camera with her, and she actually read the manual and set the time correctly. So now you have two sets of photos with mismatching date/times. Now what?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that there is actually a pretty simple trick to solve this, and you don't even haven to install &lt;a href="http://www.sno.phy.queensu.ca/~phil/exiftool/index.html">exiftool&lt;/a> or do funny command line voodo. If you have iPhoto and a mouse, here's what you do:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;pre>&lt;code> 1. [![The Apple Clock](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>](schermafbeelding-2011-08-14-om-23-13-28.png)Open &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time Preferences&amp;quot; on your Mac and click on the &amp;quot;Date &amp;amp; Time&amp;quot; tab. You should see a clock like the one on the right. With each camera you took on your trip, take a picture of this clock. You don't have to press the shutters all at once, just do this one camera at a time. It also doesn't have to be your Mac's clock, as long as you shoot the same clock with all the cameras.
2. Import the images of all the cameras in iPhoto.
3. Make smart albums (File, New, Smart album…)per Camera type. So if you have a Canon and an Olympus, make one smart album called &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; with only the Canon's photos in it, and one &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album with only the Olympus photo's in it:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png?w=300" alt="iPhoto Smart Album for Canon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-00-01-57.png)
4. For each smart album, reverse the sort order so that the photo of the clock you just took is the first in the album. (View, Sort order, Descending).
5. Select all the photo's in the &amp;quot;Canon&amp;quot; smart album, open the &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; menu, and select &amp;quot;Adjust date and time&amp;quot;. You'll see the clock you shot with this camera in the thumbnail. Copy the time of the clock in the &amp;quot;Adjusted:&amp;quot;field. All other photo's for that camera will be adjusted, because you selected all photo's in the album:[&lt;img src="screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png" alt="iPhoto set date and time">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>](screen-shot-2011-08-14-at-23-47-15.png)
6. Repeat step 5 for the &amp;quot;Olympus&amp;quot; smart album.
7. Click on the iPhoto &amp;quot;Photos&amp;quot; library where all your photos are. Your photos should now sync up perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some caveats with this procedure you should remember:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> * This only works if nobody changed the date/time settings in the camera between the time they took the photo's and the time you are importing them in iPhoto.
* When cameras are in different time zones, the times will still be off. You'll have to compensate this yourself by adding/subtracting the timezone difference between the camera and the clock of your Mac.
* Remember to select all photos of a specific camera before adjusting the time, or the trick won't work.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Happy editting!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why you want a Polarizer Filter</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 23:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/06/16/why-you-want-a-polarizer-filter/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I recently bought a 50mm lens with a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photographic_filter#Polarizer">circular polarizer&lt;/a>. I though I'd share some quick examples to show what a polarizer filter does for your photo's.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarization effect is probably one of the few (if not only) effect which you can not reproduce in photoshop or any other image processing program. Most applications try by increasing saturation, which is nowhere near the effect of a real polarizer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By rotating the filter, you have the luxury of choosing how much effect you want to have, anywhere between 0% and 100%. The shots below give you an idea what the range of the effect is:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_965&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="cluds-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="cluds-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Landscape photographers never leave home without a polarizer. It will render better detail in the clouds, and give better overal colour saturation. When there is a lot of reflection in water, the polarizer should be used with caution. Removing all reflection in favour of a beautiful sky can result in an unrealistic feeling in the shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_966&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect&amp;quot;]&lt;a href="leafs-polarizer.png">&lt;img src="leafs-polarizer.png?w=300" alt="Left Minimal polarizer effect. Right: Maximal polarizer effect">
&lt;/a>[/caption]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A little less obvious, but a great tip to give your portrait shots an extra edge: When you shoot portraits of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marinshe/1130799762/in/set-72157594224391770/">people against foliage&lt;/a>, use your polarizer to get the highlights out of the foliage. This will make sure the viewer is not distracted from the subject. As bonus, the skin tone of your model will be slightly warmer, making your model look &amp;quot;healthier&amp;quot; :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ofcourse with portraits you don't want to &amp;quot;overdo&amp;quot; it. It's easu to over-saturate the photo, and the polarizer will &amp;quot;eat&amp;quot; one to two stops of light, which will make it harder to keep everything crispy sharp. I think I'd go for the (much cheaper) &amp;quot;magic hour&amp;quot; and a little fill-flash instead of a polarizer, but sometimes there is no choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The polarizer I used here is a 58mm circular polarizer from Tiffen, which you can find for just above €40,- new, which is quite a bargain. If your glass has a larger mount, the filters can get pretty expensive (€150 and up), probably because it is harder to get an even polarization effect over a larger piece of glass with light coming in from a wider angle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A polarizer filter needs to be rotated to get the right effect, so it's nice if the front element of your lens does not rotate during focussing. In the case of the Canon 50mm lenses (th f1.2, the f1.4, and the f1.8), the front element will not rotate. The f1.2 will even not extend during focussing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other dramatic examples of shots using polarizers are &lt;a href="http://shutterbug.com/equipmentreviews/accessories/0109hoya/">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.travel-to-crete.com/gallery_images/395.jpg">here&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://i3.photobucket.com/albums/y51/Rayfromalaska/fall8.jpg">here&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.photographyiseasy.com/blg/273/polarizing-filters--do-you-need-one.html">here&lt;/a>. A nice combo-filter comparison is &lt;a href="http://www.pbase.com/jpeper/image/32267513/original.jpg">here&lt;/a>. (Links to external sites, get them while they last!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Linear Polarier
A linear polarizer is a single piece of glass which only passes light which is polarized in 1 direction. Reflected light normally tends to polarize parpendicular to the surface it reflected from. So a lake will produce horizontally polarized light, and a window vertically polarized light. You can choose to filter this out bu rotating your linear polarizer.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Circular Polarizer
**Some camera's make use of partial reflection in their metering or focussing systems. Since reflection means polerization, you can get into trouble if there is a linear polarizer in front of your camera. In some orientations, light will not be able to be reflected into the metering system, which renders it useless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To circumvent this problem, we need to convert the linear polarized light into circular polarized light (hence the name circular polarizer). This is done by adding an extra piece of glass behind the linear polarizer. This extra piece of glass is called a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave_plate">&amp;quot;Quarter Wave Plate&amp;quot;&lt;/a> which turns linear polarized light into circular polarized light. This allows your metering system to reflect it as if it were normal light coming into the lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Quarter Wave Plate is expensive to make, and it needs to be neatly glued to the linear polarizer in front of it. That's why circular polarizers are generally more expensive. It is also why linear polarizers are observed to be &amp;quot;more effective&amp;quot;, because it's simply a thicker polarizer. The Circular Polarizer needs to have 2 pieces of glass in the same space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So to sum it up: Linear Polarizer is a single sheet of glass, while a Circular Polarizer is a Linear Polarizer with a Quarter Wave Plate glued to it (Over-simplified ofcourse). The only reason to buy a circular polarizer is because your metering system requires it. This is the case in most DSLRs, but not in many point and shoots.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shooting 16:9 with a 4:3 Camera</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 10:03:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2009/05/03/shooting-169-with-a-43-camera/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If you have a Canon Ixus 80IS, like me, and you shoot video for your widescreen television at home (like me), you may want to try out this little trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Canon Ixus is a 4:3 camera. The video that comes out of it is almost square shaped. When you try to make a 16:9 video, you can stretch it, or crop it. Cropping is far better, but you need some &amp;quot;headroom&amp;quot; to do that. If you made a closeup, chances are that you do not have enough room to crop to a 16:9 format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="aspect-ratios.jpg">&lt;img src="aspect-ratios.jpg?w=150" alt="aspect-ratios">
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I solved this by making this little chart, which I placed on a memorycard and put in my camera. By previewing the image on the camera's display, you know where the &amp;quot;16:9 limit&amp;quot; is. I put two pieces of half-translucent tape on the camera, so I can tell what fit's inside the 16:9 frame. I also included the other formats, like 3:2, and 2.39:1, should you want to make wide-screen theater movies :-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I load up the movie in iMovie, and it will be cropped perfectly. Suppose you missed the 16:9 frame or want to re-center your shot, you can always press the &amp;quot;crop&amp;quot; button in your project to tell iMovie which piece of the image you want.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Easy Image Resizing in OSX</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/12/31/easy-image-resizing-in-osx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 16:24:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/12/31/easy-image-resizing-in-osx/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A little heads-up for Apple OSX users who have lots of images to resize. There's a free tool available to do this at &lt;a href="http://www.eagle-of-liberty.com/resizeemall/">http://www.eagle-of-liberty.com/resizeemall/&lt;/a>. It's donationware, if you like it you can send the author money by paypal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've used it, and it works as advertised. Drag a bunch of images on the application, and batch-resize them without touching your originals. You can save the images with a postfix, and even in a different format if you like. Very easy for mailing a bunch of photo's.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Translators ruin good books.</title><link>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/12/29/translators-ruin-good-books/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 11:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://realrolfje.github.io/rolfje.com/2007/12/29/translators-ruin-good-books/</guid><description>
&lt;p>On Christmas day, Santa gave me a very nice book about digital photography, by Michael Freeman. The book contains lots of interesting information and tips for the digital SLR photographer. The only problem with the book is, that the Dutch translation of it is absolutely terrible to read. The sentences do not &amp;quot;flow&amp;quot; naturaly, and almost feel as if they were litteraly translated word-by-word from the English version.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->Because the book contains information I'm interested in, I tried a bit harder to read the kindergarten translation method by translating the sentences back to English in my head. Suddenly the book made much more sense. But every now and then, about once every page, the translators use Dutch words which I have never ever heard of, which often aren't even close to the correct translation of the technical term originally used by the author.
&lt;p>An example: On page 23, the dutch word &amp;quot;conjugatie&amp;quot; is used. I never heard of this word so I looked it up in the dictionary, wikipedia and some other online sources. The word seems to be a mostly medical term, and can be a synonym for the Egnlish words &amp;quot;relation&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;connection&amp;quot;. This is realy strange, because the word is used in a text where the focal point is discussed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another example. On page 31, the Dutch term &amp;quot;fotosiet&amp;quot; is used. I couldn't even find a definition of this word, but when searching for the Dutch word &amp;quot;siet&amp;quot;, I found that this word is used mostly in very old scripts, from the year 1700 to 1800, and the word is not used in normal Dutch nowadays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, John Degen and Ammerins Moss-de-Boer of &amp;quot;Deul &amp;amp; Spanjaard&amp;quot; should give up translating technical photography books like these. It is ruined. I'll try to get an English copy of this book, and maybe even talk to Michael Freeman about the way this book is not fit for the Dutch market in the current translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book information:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Title: Digitale Fotografie, de spiegelreflexcamera
Author: Michael Freeman
Translators: John Degen and Ammerins Moss-de-Boer
Translation Company: Deul &amp;amp; Spanjaard, Groningen
ISBN: 978-90-5764-637-9
Publisher: Libero&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**Do not buy the Duth version of this book! **&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>